<level type="section">
  <num>31-5606.04</num>
  <heading>Criminal penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who violates § 31-5605.01 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall pay a fine of not more than $1,000, be imprisoned for not more than one year, or both. All prosecutions under this subsection shall be upon information filed in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District by the Corporation Counsel or any of his or her assistants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person who knowingly or intentionally violates any of the provisions of § 31-5605.02, § 31-5605.03, § 31-5605.04, or § 31-5605.05(b), shall be guilty of fraud in the second degree, as defined in § 22-3221(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person who knowingly or intentionally violates any of the provisions of § 31-5605.02, § 31-5605.03, § 31-5605.04, or § 31-5605.05(b), by use of a plan, program, or campaign that is conducted using one or more telephones or other electronic means of communication for the purpose of inducing the purchase or sale of securities, shall be guilty of fraud in the first degree, as defined in § 22-3221(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No prosecution for a violation of this chapter shall bar, or be barred by, a prosecution for the violation of any other law. All prosecutions under this chapter, or based upon any provision of this chapter, shall be commenced within 3 years after the violation upon which the prosecution is based. If the accused person has intentionally concealed evidence of a violation of § 31-5605.02, § 31-5605.03, § 31-5605.04, or § 31-5605.05(b), the period of limitation prescribed in this subsection shall be extended up to an additional 2 years after the prosecuting officer becomes aware of the offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall limit the power of the District to punish a person for conduct constituting a crime under other law.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, § 604, 47 DCR 7837.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-203</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-203, see notes following § 31-5601.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
