<level type="section">
  <num>31-5606.03</num>
  <heading>Enforcement - Judicial.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever it appears to the Commissioner that a person is about to engage in any act or practice constituting a violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule or order adopted under this chapter, the Commissioner may request the Corporation Counsel to bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to obtain one or more of the following remedies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Temporary restraining order; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Temporary or permanent injunction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever it appears to the Commissioner that a person has engaged in any act or practice constituting a violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule or order hereunder, the Commissioner may request the Corporation Counsel to bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to obtain one or more of the following remedies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Temporary restraining order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Temporary or permanent injunction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A civil penalty not to exceed $10,000 for a single violation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A declaratory judgment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Appointment of a receiver or conservator for the defendant or the defendant's assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A freeze of the defendant's assets; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any other relief as the court deems just, such as rescission, restitution, or disgorgement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court shall not require the Commissioner to post a bond in any action under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-203, ยง 603, 47 DCR 7837.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-203</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-203, see notes following ยง 31-5601.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
