<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section-start>3-2901</section-start>
  <section-end>3-2943</section-end>
  <section-range-type>range</section-range-type>
  <heading>Definitions; license required; Commission on Licensure to Practice the Healing Art; boards of examiners; appointment; composition; term of office; qualifications; compensation; officers; rules; Board of Examiners in Basic Sciences; Board of Examiners in Medicine and Osteopathy; boards of examiners in drugless methods of healing; Board of Examiners in Midwifery; examinations; issuance of licenses based on reports of boards; examination papers open to inspection; retention of papers; record of licenses issued; numbering of licenses; display; applications for licenses; contents; fees; exemption from fees; refunds; licensees in medicine, surgery, or midwifery under prior law to be relicensed; osteopaths, chiropractors, and those who practice the healing art to apply for license; license without examination to those engaged in practice of drugless method of healing; issuance of license by endorsement; certificate or diploma from national examining board or completion of examination by Federation of State Medical Boards; evidence required with application for license; temporary licenses; procedures and standards for imposition of sanctions against licensees; filing false data with Commission; disclosure of applicant's identity number; impersonation of applicant; premature disclosure of examination; impersonation of licensee; altering or forging diploma, certificate, or seal of Commission; unfair rating of applicants; false swearing; license or registration refused for cause; procedure; penalties; subsequent offenses; suspension or revocation of license upon conviction of felony; enjoining unlawful practice of healing art; procedure; exemptions from subchapter; money paid to Director of Department of Finance and Revenue; deposits; payment of expenses; compensation of members of boards and employees of Commission; transfer of records, property, and money to Commission; enforcement; annual report to Congress; short title; transfer of provisions; inconsistent laws repealed.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 1104(e), 33 DCR 729.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., §§ 2-1301 to 2-1343.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
