<level type="section">
  <num>31-2996.02</num>
  <heading>Dependent child coverage.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A group health plan or an individual health plan, and a health insurer offering health insurance coverage that provides coverage for dependent children, that delivers, issues for delivery, amends, or renews a health insurance policy in the District of Columbia shall make health insurance coverage available and, if requested by the policyholder, extend coverage to any dependent child of a policyholder until the dependent child is no longer a dependent child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The health insurance coverage shall provide:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The same health insurance coverage benefits to a dependent child that are available to any other covered dependent; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Health insurance coverage benefits to a dependent child at the same rate or premium applicable to any other covered dependent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Coverage for services provided to a dependent before October 26, 2010; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That an employer or other group policyholder pay all or part of the cost of coverage for a dependent as provided pursuant to this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2010, D.C. Law 18-252, ยง 3, 57 DCR 8064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>Section 3 of D.C. Law 18-203 added a section to read as follows:</text>
        <text>"Sec. 3. Dependent child coverage.</text>
        <text>"(a) A group health plan or an individual health plan, and a health insurer offering health insurance coverage that provides coverage for dependent children, that delivers, issues for delivery, amends, or renews a health insurance policy in the District of Columbia shall make health insurance coverage available and, if requested by the policyholder, extend health insurance coverage to any dependent child of a policyholder until the dependent child is no longer a dependent child.</text>
        <text>"(b) The health insurance coverage shall provide:</text>
        <text>"(1) The same health insurance coverage benefits to a dependent child that are available to any other covered dependent; and</text>
        <text>"(2) Health insurance coverage benefits to a dependent child at the same rate or premium applicable to any other covered dependent.</text>
        <text>"(c) Nothing in this act shall be construed to require:</text>
        <text>"(1) Coverage for services provided to a dependent before the effective date of this act; or</text>
        <text>"(2) That an employer or other group policyholder pay all or part of the cost of coverage for a dependent as provided pursuant to this section."</text>
        <text>Section 6(b) of D.C. Law 18-203 provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 3 of Health Insurance for Dependents Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-384, April 29, 2010, 57 DCR 3835).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-252, see notes under ยง 31-2996.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
