<level type="section">
  <num>1-1171.03</num>
  <heading>Political activities on duty; prohibition.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An employee shall not engage in political activity:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>While the employee is on duty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In any room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties in the District government, including any agency or instrumentality thereof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>While wearing a uniform or official insignia identifying the office or position of the employee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Using any vehicle owned or leased by the District of Columbia, including any agency or instrumentality thereof.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An employee may not coerce, explicitly or implicitly, any subordinate employee to engage in political activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "political activity" is not limited to activities regulated by the District and includes soliciting, accepting, receiving, or making political contributions or other political activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-335, § 4, 58 DCR 599; Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-80, § 2(c), 61 DCR 169.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-1171.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-80 designated the existing text as (a); and added (b) and (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-4, May 18, 2013, 60 DCR 4624, 20 DCSTAT 1268).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-25, March 7, 2013, 60 DCR 3986, 20 DCSTAT 485).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-231, December 20, 2013, 61 DCR 3, 20 DCSTAT 2633).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-335</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1171.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-80</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1171.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
