<level type="section">
  <num>1-1171.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Board" means the Board of Elections and Ethics established by § 1-1001.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Employee" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any individual paid by the District government from grant or appropriated funds for his or her services or holding office in the District of Columbia, other than the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Employees of the courts of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The Mayor;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>The Attorney General, after January 1, 2014;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>The members of the Council;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissioners; [or]</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(vi)</num>
        <text>Members of the State Board of Education;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A member of a board or commission who is nominated for a position pursuant to § 1-523.01(e); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A member of a board or commission who is nominated for a position pursuant to § 1-523.01(f), when the member is engaged in political activity that relates to the subject matter that the member's board or commission regulates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Partisan political office" means any office for which any candidate is nominated or elected as representing a party any of whose candidates for Presidential elector received votes in the last preceding election at which Presidential electors were selected, but shall exclude any office or position within a political party or affiliated organization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>"Political activity" means any activity directed toward the success or failure of a political party, candidate for partisan political office, partisan political group, ballot initiative, or referendum.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The Board of Elections and Ethics may, by rule, define certain basic activities as nonpolitical activities.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The term "nonpolitical activities" shall include:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(I)</num>
          <text>Media inquiries;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(II)</num>
          <text>Answering questioners; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(III)</num>
          <text>Scheduling.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>"Political contribution" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>A gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money, or anything of value, made for any political purpose;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>A contract, promise, or agreement, express or implied, whether or not legally enforceable, to make a contribution for any political purpose;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>A payment by any person, other than a candidate or a political party or affiliated organization, of compensation for the personal services of another person which are rendered to any candidate or political party or affiliated organization without charge for any political purpose; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>The provision of personal services, paid or unpaid, for any political purpose.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term "political contribution" shall not include the value of services provided without compensation by any individual on behalf of any candidate, campaign, political party, or partisan political group.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-335, § 2, 58 DCR 599.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Hatch Act retention, § 1-625.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-4, May 18, 2013, 60 DCR 4624, 20 DCSTAT 1268).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-25, March 7, 2013, 60 DCR 3986, 20 DCSTAT 485).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-335</heading>
      <text>Law 18-335, the "Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Act of 2010, " was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-460. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Nov. 23, 2010, and Dec. 21, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 12, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 18-679 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-335 became effective on Mar. 31, 2011.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
