<level type="section">
  <num>1-1171.02</num>
  <heading>Political activity authorized; prohibitions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An employee may take an active part in political management or in political campaigns; provided, that an employee shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Use his official authority or influence for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Knowingly solicit, accept, or receive a political contribution from any person, except if the employee has filed as a candidate for political office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>File as a candidate for election to a partisan political office; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Knowingly direct, or authorize anyone else to direct, that any subordinate employee participate in an election campaign or request a subordinate to make a political contribution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor and each member of the Council may designate one employee while on leave to perform any of the functions described in subsection (a)(2) of this section; provided, that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The employee shall not perform the activities while the employee is on duty or in any room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties in the District government, including any agency or instrumentality thereof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any designation pursuant to this subsection shall be made in writing to the Secretary of the District of Columbia or the Secretary to the Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any designated employee shall file a report within 15 days of being designated and as otherwise required pursuant to § 1-1162.24; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor and the Council shall issue standards of conduct implementing this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-335, § 3, 58 DCR 599; Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-80, § 2(b), 61 DCR 169.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-80, substituted "§ 1-1162.24" for "§ 1-1106.02" in (b)(3); and repealed (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-4, May 18, 2013, 60 DCR 4624, 20 DCSTAT 1268).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-25, March 7, 2013, 60 DCR 3986, 20 DCSTAT 485).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the Prohibition on Government Employee Engagement in Political Activity Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-231, December 20, 2013, 61 DCR 3, 20 DCSTAT 2633).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-335</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1171.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-80</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1171.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
