<level type="section">
  <num>31-737.01</num>
  <heading>Mergers and acquisitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 35-3727.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to applicable requirements of this subchapter and subchapter I of this chapter, a mutual insurance holding company may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Merge or consolidate with, or acquire the assets of, a mutual insurance holding company licensed pursuant to this subchapter or any similar entity organized pursuant to laws of any other state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Either alone or together with one or more intermediate stock holding companies, or other subsidiaries, directly or indirectly acquire the stock of a stock insurance company or a mutual insurance company that reorganizes under this subchapter or the law of its state of organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Together with one or more of its stock insurance company subsidiaries, acquire the assets of a stock insurance company or a mutual insurance company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Acquire a stock insurance company through the merger of such stock insurance company with a stock insurance company or interim stock insurance company subsidiary of the mutual insurance holding company; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Acquire the stock or assets of any other person to the same extent as would be permitted for any District stock corporation or, if the mutual insurance holding company writes insurance, a mutual insurance company.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A merger or acquisition pursuant to this section is subject to the applicable procedures prescribed by the District laws applying to mutual insurance companies, except as otherwise provided in this subsection. The Commissioner may retain, at the expense of the mutual insurance company, any attorneys, actuaries, accountants, and other experts not otherwise a part of the Commissioner's staff as may be reasonably necessary to assist the Commissioner in reviewing the proposed merger or acquisition.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The plan and agreement for merger shall be submitted to and approved by vote of 2/3rds of those members of any domestic mutual insurance holding company involved in the merger who vote either in person or by proxy thereon at a lawful meeting called for the purpose pursuant to such reasonable notice and procedure as has been approved by the Commissioner.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No such merger shall be effectuated unless in advance thereof, the plan and agreement therefor have been filed with the Commissioner and approved by him. The Commissioner shall give such approval unless he finds such plan or agreement:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is inequitable to the policyholders of any domestic insurer involved in the merger or the members of any domestic mutual insurance holding company involved in the merger; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Would substantially reduce the security of and service to be rendered to policyholders of a domestic insurer in the District.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(September 20, 1996, D.C. Law 11-159, § 8a, as added Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-188, § 2(e), 45 DCR 7807.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 35-3727.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2(e) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-119, June 11, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 4036).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 2(e) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-295, March 4, 1998, 45 DCR 1764), § 2(e) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12- 364, June 5, 1998, 45 DCR 3877), and § 2(e) of the Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisition Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-550, December 18, 1998, 46 DCR 512).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 12-188, the "Mutual Holding Company Mergers and Acquisitions Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-541, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second reading on July 7, 1998, and September 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 2, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-459, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for review. D.C. Law 12-188 became effective on March 26, 1999.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
