<level type="section">
  <num>7-2361.03</num>
  <heading>Regulation of services during emergency.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>While an emergency declaration is in effect, the Mayor may issue a Mayor's order that limits, restricts, or otherwise regulates:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The duration of practice by volunteer health practitioners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The geographical areas in which volunteer health practitioners may practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The types of volunteer health practitioners who may practice; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other matter necessary to coordinate effectively the provision of health or veterinary services during the emergency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An order issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may take effect immediately, without prior notice or comment, and is not a rule within the meaning of subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A host entity that uses volunteer health practitioners to provide health or veterinary services in the District shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Consult and coordinate its activities with the Mayor to the extent practicable to provide for the efficient and effective use of volunteer health practitioners; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Comply with all District laws relating to the management of emergency health or veterinary services, including Chapter 23 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 1, 2010, D.C. Law 18-184, ยง 4, 57 DCR 3655.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-184, see notes following ยง 7-2361.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 4 of the Uniform Emergency Volunteer Health Practitioners Act. See Vol. 9, Part 1B, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
