<level type="section">
  <num>47-2851.03</num>
  <heading>Endorsement categories; exemptions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-2851.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Endorsements to a basic business license shall be issued in the following license endorsement categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Educational Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Entertainment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Environmental Materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Financial Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Housing: Transient; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Housing: Residential;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Inspected Sales and Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Manufacturing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Motor Vehicle Sales, Service, and Repair;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Health Care Facility;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Human Services Facility;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Child Health and Welfare;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Public Accommodations;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmacology;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Funeral Establishment;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Radioactive Materials;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Biohazard;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Food Establishment Wholesale; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Public Health: Food Establishment Retail;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Public Safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Employment Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>General Sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>General Services and Repair; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>General Business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All Class A or Class B license endorsements to master business licenses issued by the Department prior to the effective date of the Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003, passed on an emergency basis on July 8, 2003 (Enrolled version of Bill 15-317) [August 11, 2003], are hereby redesignated as license endorsements, without designation of class, to a basic business license. Nothing in the foregoing shall be read as eliminating the criteria, established either by rule or statute, that govern the awarding of any license endorsement affected by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall maintain and periodically update a roster of all businesses which have been issued a basic business license, indicating the license endorsements appended to each basic business license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The following licenses shall not be a part of the basic business license system and shall be regulated by the Department of Health:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Dog-Spayed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Dog-Unspayed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 101(b), 45 DCR 1172; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2002(e), 46 DCR 3142; Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 2(e), 50 DCR 6913; Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 302(b), 51 DCR 6525.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2851.3.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-38 rewrote the section which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"§ 47-2851.03. Classes of license.</text>
        <text>"(a) All licenses issued in accordance with this subchapter shall be either Class A Licenses or Class B Licenses.</text>
        <text>"(1) Businesses licensed as Class A shall be subject to inspection and approval by the District government and may be fined, suspended, or closed for failure to pass each inspection or approval.</text>
        <text>"(2) Businesses licensed as Class B shall not require inspection in order to be issued a master business license under the master business license system.</text>
        <text>"(b) All business licenses issued by the Department prior to the effective date of this act are hereby consolidated into and redesignated as Class A or Class B license endorsement categories. Nothing in the foregoing shall be read as eliminating the criteria, established either by rule or statute, that govern the awarding of any license affected by this section.</text>
        <text>"(c) Class A licenses shall be required of businesses engaged in the following license endorsement categories:</text>
        <text>"(1) Alcoholic beverages, except that a master business license bearing an Alcoholic Beverages endorsement shall also indicate the class of endorsement applicable for the licensed business;</text>
        <text>"(2) Educational Services;</text>
        <text>"(3) Entertainment;</text>
        <text>"(4) Environmental Materials;</text>
        <text>"(5) Financial Services;</text>
        <text>"(6)(A) Housing: transient; and</text>
        <text>"(B) Housing: residential;</text>
        <text>"(7) Inspected Sales and Services;</text>
        <text>"(8) Manufacturing;</text>
        <text>"(9) Motor Vehicle Sales, Service, and Repair;</text>
        <text>"(10)(A) Public Health: health care facility;</text>
        <text>"(B) Public Health: human services facility;</text>
        <text>"(C) Public Health: child health and welfare;</text>
        <text>"(D) Public Health: public accommodations;</text>
        <text>"(E) Public Health: pharmacy and pharmacology;</text>
        <text>"(F) Public Health: funeral establishment;</text>
        <text>"(G) Public Health: radioactive materials;</text>
        <text>"(H) Public health: biohazard;</text>
        <text>"(I) Public Health: food establishment wholesale; and</text>
        <text>"(J) Public Health: food establishment retail; and</text>
        <text>"(11) Public safety;</text>
        <text>"(d) Class B licenses shall be required of businesses engaged in the following license endorsement categories:</text>
        <text>"(1) Employment Services;</text>
        <text>"(2) General Sales;</text>
        <text>"(3) General Services and Repair; and</text>
        <text>"(4) General Business.</text>
        <text>"(e) The following licenses shall not be a part of the master business license system, and shall be regulated by the Department of Health:</text>
        <text>"(1) Dog-Spayed; and</text>
        <text>"(2) Dog-Unspayed.</text>
        <text>"(f) Any business, not required to obtain a Class A license, whether or not defined in any District statute or regulation, must obtain a Class B license. A business whose practice does not come under the coverage of one of the above named categories, and which is not subject to inspection, must obtain a Class B license under the 'General business' endorsement category.</text>
        <text>"(g) Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing the Director by regulation, or the Council by statute, from establishing new Class A license or Class B license categories or eliminating existing categories as the Director or Council deems necessary and appropriate. The Department shall maintain and periodically update a schedule of current license categories and classes.</text>
        <text>"(h) The Department shall maintain and periodically update a roster of all licensed businesses, indicating whether they possess Class A licenses or Class B licenses."</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-187 repealed par. (1) of subsec. (a) which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(1) Alcoholic beverages, except that a basic business license bearing an Alcoholic Beverages endorsement shall also indicate the class of endorsement applicable for the licensed business;"</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(l) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001, 48 DCR 9947).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003, 50 DCR 6896).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-86, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2851.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2801.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-38, see notes following § 47-2404.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-187, see notes following § 47-2820.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
