<level type="section">
  <num>50-2531.01</num>
  <heading>Performance Parking Program Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Performance Parking Program Fund ("Fund"), which shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in § 50-2534, and shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fees collected for the parking of vehicles where meters or devices are installed shall be deposited into the Fund in accordance with § 50-2603(8)(B).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in § 50-2534 without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>((Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-279, § 2a, as added Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6083(b), 58 DCR 6226; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6042(b), 59 DCR 8025; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 6032, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-2603.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-168 rewrote (a); and added "projects within the zone from which revenues were raised for" in (b).</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote (a)(2); and deleted "for projects within the zone from which revenues were raised" following "continually available" in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6032 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-21</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-21, see notes under § 50-231.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-2531.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 6031 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle D of Title VI of the act may be cited as the "District Department of Transportation Parking Meter Revenue Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
