<level type="section">
  <num>34-1505</num>
  <heading>Licensing requirements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All electricity suppliers must obtain a license issued by the Commission in order to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An application for an electricity supplier license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be made to the Commission in writing on a form adopted by the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be verified by oath or affirmation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be accompanied by an application fee determined by the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Contain the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Proof of technical and managerial competence;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Proof of compliance with all applicable requirements of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and any independent system operator or regional or system transmission operator to be used by the applicant;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Proof of compliance with all applicable federal and District of Columbia environmental laws;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Proof of financial integrity;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Proof that the applicant has registered with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs to do business in the District of Columbia;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>An agreement or promise to be subject to all applicable taxes;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>An agreement or promise to comply with all of the requirements of this chapter and all orders and regulations of the Commission issued under this chapter; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Any other information required by the Commission.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Require an applicant to post a bond or other similar instrument if, in the Commission's judgment, the bond or similar instrument is necessary to insure an applicant's financial integrity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establish the duration of a license issued under this section, procedures and requirements for license renewal, and provisions regarding the surrender and lapse of a license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establish any other requirements for an applicant that the Commission determines to be in the public interest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A license may not be transferred without the prior approval of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All monies collected by the Commission under this section shall be used exclusively for the daily operations of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a consolidator may be required by the Commission to file a statement of intent to serve as a consolidator and to provide to the Commission such other information as reasonably may be related to the requirements of the Commission for monitoring the activities of consolidators.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, ยง 105, 47 DCR 1091.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 34-1504 and ยง 34-1513.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-107</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-107, see notes following ยง 34-1501.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
