<level type="section">
  <num>34-1517</num>
  <heading>Renewable energy sources.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, "renewable energy source" means one of the following sources of energy:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Solar;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Wind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Tidal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Geothermal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Biomass;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Hydroelectric facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Digester gas.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every 6 months after the initial implementation date, each licensed electricity supplier doing business in the District of Columbia shall report to the Commission on the fuel mix of the electricity sold by the electricity supplier, including categories of electricity from coal, natural gas, nuclear, oil, hydroelectric, solar, biomass, wind, and other resources, and on the percentage of electricity sold by the electricity supplier which comes from renewable energy sources.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning on the initial implementation date, the Commission shall track the fuel mix of the electricity sold in the District of Columbia and the amount of electricity from renewable sources sold in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Before July 1, 2003, and every 2 years after that date, the Commission shall provide a report to the Council on the overall fuel mix of the electricity sold in the District of Columbia, the amount of electricity sold in the District of Columbia which comes from renewable energy sources, and on the feasibility of requiring each licensed electricity supplier doing business in the District of Columbia to provide a minimum percentage of electricity sold from renewable energy sources.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, ยง 117, 47 DCR 1091.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-107</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-107, see notes following ยง 34-1501.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
