<level type="section">
  <num>34-1518</num>
  <heading>Net metering.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission may establish a program which affords eligible customer-generators the opportunity to participate in net energy metering.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any net energy metering program established by the Commission shall be subject to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The program may include, as the Commission determines will facilitate the provision of net energy metering, requirements for:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Retail sellers;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Owners or operators of distribution or transmission facilities;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Providers of default service; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Eligible customer-generators.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall ensure that the metering equipment installed for net metering shall be capable of measuring the flow of electricity in 2 directions, and shall allocate fairly the cost of such equipment and any necessary interconnection. An eligible customer-generator's net metering system for renewable resources, cogeneration, fuel cells, and microturbines shall meet all applicable safety and performance standards. The Commission may adopt by regulation additional control and testing requirements for customer-generators that the Commission determines are necessary to protect public safety and system reliability.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the electricity supplied by an electricity supplier exceeds the electricity generated by the customer-generator and fed back into the electric grid during the billing period, the customer-generator shall be billed for the net electricity supplied by the electricity supplier in accordance with net metering rules established by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If electricity generated by the customer-generator and fed back into the electric grid exceeds the electricity supplied by the electricity supplier, the customer generator may receive compensation based on the net metering rules established by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, ยง 118, 47 DCR 1091.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-107</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-107, see notes following ยง 34-1501.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
