<level type="section">
  <num>34-1507</num>
  <heading>Consumer protections.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unless a customer consents in writing, a market participant or the electric company may not disclose information that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is about the customer; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Was supplied to the market participant or electric company by the customer.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This restriction shall not apply to lawful disclosures for bill collection or credit rating reporting purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unless a customer consents in writing, a market participant or the electric company may not use information of the type specified in subsection (a)(1) of this section for any purpose other than the purpose for which the information was originally acquired.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This restriction shall not apply to lawful disclosures for bill collection or credit rating reporting purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the customer consents, a market participant may not change a customer's electricity supplier.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Unless the customer consents, a market participant may not add services or new charges to a customer's existing retail electric service options.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A market participant may not engage in marketing, advertising, or trade practices that are unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A market participant must provide adequate and accurate information to each customer about the market participant's available services and charges.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A market participant may not discriminate against any customer based wholly or partly on the race, color, creed, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, or gender identity or expression of the customer, or for any arbitrary, capricious, or unfairly discriminatory reason.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A market participant may not refuse to provide service to a customer except by the application of standards that are reasonably related to the market participant's economic and business purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A market participant shall post on the Internet information that is readily understandable about its services and rates for small commercial and residential electric customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 107, 47 DCR 1091; June 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-177, § 18(b), 55 DCR 3696.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 34-1504.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-177, in subsec. (f), substituted "sexual orientation, or gender identity or expression" for "or sexual orientation".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-107</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-107, see notes following § 34-1501.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-177</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-177, see notes following § 32-401.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
