<level type="section">
  <num>1-1162.19</num>
  <heading>Advisory opinions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon application made by an employee or public official subject to the Code of Conduct, the Ethics Board or the Director of Government Ethics shall, within a reasonable period of time, provide an advisory opinion as to whether a specific transaction or activity inquired of would constitute a violation of a provision of the Code of Conduct over which the Ethics Board has primary jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An advisory opinion shall be published in the District of Columbia Register within 30 days of its issuance; provided, that the identity of a person requesting an advisory opinion shall not be disclosed in the District of Columbia Register without the person's prior consent in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If issued by the Director of Government Ethics, an advisory opinion may be appealed for consideration by the Ethics Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>There shall be no enforcement of a violation of the Code of Conduct taken against an employee or public official who relied in good faith upon an advisory opinion requested by that employee or public official; provided, that the employee or public official, in seeking the advisory opinion, made full and accurate disclosure of all relevant circumstances and information.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, ยง 219, 59 DCR 1862.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see ยง 2(a) of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-3, May 18, 2013, 60 DCR 4622, 20 DCSTAT 1266).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see ยง 2(a) of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-24, March 7, 2013, 60 DCR 3984, 20 DCSTAT 483).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-124</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-124, see notes under ยง 1-1161.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
