<level type="section">
  <num>15-302</num>
  <heading>Period during which writ of execution may issue; returnable period.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A writ of execution on a judgment in a civil action may be issued within three years after:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>the expiration of any stay of execution agreed to by the parties; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>it first might have been issued under applicable provisions of law or rules of court.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A writ of execution shall be returnable on or before the sixtieth day after its date.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 525, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Disability insurance benefits, exemption from execution, see § 31-4716.01.</text>
      <text>Exemptions from executions generally, see § 15-101 et seq.</text>
      <text>forfeited recognizances and judgments, executions upon, see § 16-709.</text>
      <text>Fraternal benefit association benefits, exemption from execution, see § 31-5711.</text>
      <text>Group life policies and proceeds, exemption from execution, see § 31-4717.</text>
      <text>Landlord's lien for rent, enforcement by execution, see §§ 42-3214 and 42-3215.</text>
      <text>Public assistance, exemption from assignment and execution, see § 4-217.01.</text>
      <text>Seizure by execution of goods located on leased premises, payment of rent due as prerequisite, see § 42-3216.</text>
      <text>Teacher retirement annuities, exemption from assignment or execution, see § 38-2001.17.</text>
      <text>Unemployment compensation benefits, exemption from execution, except for debts accrued for necessaries, see § 51-118.</text>
      <text>Wrongful death damages, exemption from appropriation for payment of debts and liabilities, see § 16-2703.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 15-301 and § 15-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 15-302.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 15-302.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
