<level type="section">
  <num>24-602</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this subchapter:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term "chronic alcoholic" means any person who chronically and habitually uses alcoholic beverages to the extent that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>They injure his health or interfere with his social or economic functioning; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>He has lost the power of self-control with respect to the use of such beverages.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term "Court" means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term "Mayor" means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 4, 1947, 61 Stat. 744, ch. 472, § 2; Aug. 3, 1968, 82 Stat. 618, Pub. L. 90-452, § 3(a); July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 3-509 and § 47-2885.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 24-522.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 24-522.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
