<level type="section">
  <num>7-503.02</num>
  <heading>Executive Director--Appointment; compensation; staff.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-2212</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The Office shall be headed by an Executive Director, who shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, from a list of not more than 3 names submitted to him by the Commission. The Director shall devote his full time to the duties of his office. His annual compensation shall be fixed in accordance with Chapter 51 of Title 5, United States Code (relating to the classification of government employees and related matters), but shall be not less than a GS-15, Step 1 or the equivalent compensation pursuant to the provisions of subchapter XI of Chapter 6 of Title 1. He shall have such staff as is approved in the current District government budget and federal grants, plus any temporary staff approved by the Office of Budget and Management Systems.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 29, 1975, D.C. Law 1-24, title III, § 302, 22 DCR 2457; Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(t), 25 DCR 5740.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-2212.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-1712.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-24, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 7-501.01.</text>
        <text>Law 2-139, the "District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-10, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 17, 1978, and October 31, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 22, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-300 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>"GS-15, Step 1," referred to in the second sentence, is contained in the General Schedule, which is set out following § 5332 of Title 5, United States Code.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority under D.C. Law 7-218, the "District of Columbia Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program Act of 1988", see Mayor's Order 89-86, April 28, 1989.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
