<level type="section">
  <num>20-109</num>
  <heading>Effective date.</heading>
  <text>This title shall apply only to an estate of a decedent who died on or after January 1, 1981. Title 20 of the D.C. Official Code enacted by virtue of An Act To enact Part III of the District of Columbia Code, entitled "Decedents' Estates and Fiduciary Relations", codifying the general and permanent laws relating to decedents' estates and fiduciary relations in the District of Columbia, approved September 14, 1965 (79 Stat. 703), and An Act To amend chapter 19 of title 20 of the District of Columbia Code to provide for distribution of a minor's share in a decedent's personal estate where the share does not exceed the value of $1,000, approved August 11, 1971 (85 Stat. 307), shall apply to an estate of a decedent who died before January 1, 1981.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, ยง 402, 27 DCR 2155; Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-24, ยง 3, 30 DCR 3341.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 20-109.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-72</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 20-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 5-24</heading>
      <text>Law 5-24, the "Technical and Clarifying Amendments Act of 1983," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 5-169, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 10, 1983, and May 24, 1983, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 9, 1983, it was assigned Act No. 5-41 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>"Chapter 19 of title 20", referred to in this section, did not exist in the 1981 Edition at the time of the recodification into the 2001 Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
