<level type="section">
  <num>10-306</num>
  <heading>Establishment of Recreation Assistance Board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is hereby created a Recreation Assistance Board ("Board") that shall consist of 9 members that represent the following interests:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Two members from the corporate or business sector;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two members who are District residents that have demonstrated a sincere interest in recreational activities with 1 member being an advocate for youth issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A representative of the District of Columbia Board of Education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A representative from the arts or music community;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A representative of therapeutic or senior citizens;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The President and Chief Executive Officer of the Washington Convention and Sports Authority; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Recreation and Parks or that person's designee who shall serve as the Secretary of the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Board members shall be appointed by the Mayor for 4 year terms of office and shall serve without compensation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall appoint a member of the Board as its Chairperson. The Committee may elect other officers from its membership as it deems necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall provide resources and expertise on all matters relating to the mission of the Department with special emphasis on fundraising assistance, marketing of programs, and recommendations regarding the expenditure and growth of the Fund established in § 10-303.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Board may provide guidance on methods of developing and improving recreation programs, conduct public meetings, promote public awareness of recreational programs, and assist on other issues relating to the general purpose of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Board shall act as a liaison with the existing Recreation Council Community Management Committees, and other focus groups relative to issues associated with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-246, § 7, 42 DCR 452; Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 20(c), 43 DCR 530; June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-285, § 4(l), 46 DCR 1355; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2082(k), 57 DCR 181; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-356, § 4, 58 DCR 760.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 10-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 8-306.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-111 rewrote subsec. (a)(6), which had as follows: "(6) The Executive Director of the District of Columbia Sports Commission; and"</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-356 rewrote subsec. (a)(6), which formerly read:</text>
      <text>"(6) The Chief Executive Officer and General Manager of the Washington Convention and Sports Authority; and"</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of D.C. Law 18-266 rewrote subsec. (a)(6) to read as follows:</text>
      <text>"(6) The President and Chief Executive Officer of the Washington Convention and Sports Authority; and".</text>
      <text>Section 5(b) of D.C. Law 18-266 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 10-301.</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(l) of the Confirmation Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-25, March 15, 1999, 46 DCR 2971).</text>
      <text>Section 6 of D.C. Act 13-25 provides for the application of the act.</text>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4(l) of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999, 46 DCR 5330).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(k) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(k) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Washington Convention and Sports Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-504, July 30, 2010, 57 DCR 7578).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Washington Convention and Sports Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-580, October 19, 2010, 57 DCR 10113).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-246</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-246, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 10-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-110</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-110, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 10-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-285</heading>
      <text>Law 12-285, the "Confirmation Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-261. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Vetoed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, Council overrode the veto on January 5, 1999, and the bill was assigned Act No. 12-622 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-285 became effective on June 12, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 10-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-356</heading>
      <text>Law 18-356, the "Washington Convention and Sports Authority Amendment Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-1046, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 7, 2010, and December 21, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 19, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 18-706 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-356 became effective on April 8, 2011.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to Mayor's Order 2000-20, the agency formerly known as the Department of Recreation and Parks shall be known as the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
