<level type="section">
  <num>38-781.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Chancellor" means the chief executive officer of DCPS, as established by ยง 38-174.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"DCMR" means the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools agency established by ยง 38-171.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Parent" means a natural parent, adoptive parent, step-parent, or any person who has legal custody of a student by court order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Passing grade" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For pre-kindergarten through 5th grade, achieving proficient or advanced grades in a subject or content area; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For 6th through 12th grade, receiving credit for a course.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Principal" means a principal at a DCPS school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Promoted" describes students in pre-kindergarten through 11th grade who are advanced to the next grade level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"Promotion" means advancement to the next grade level for students in pre-kindergarten through grade 11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Retained" describes students who are required to repeat their current grade level due to their failure to meet promotion criteria.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>"Retention" means repetition of a student's current school grade level due to the student's failure to meet promotion criteria.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>"School year" means the school term beginning in August of one year and ending in the following year. The term "school year" does not include summer school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>"Subject" and "content area" mean a particular course of study, such as mathematics, English language arts, writing, or literature.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-84, ยง 202, 61 DCR 178.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-84</heading>
      <text>Law 20-84, the "Focused Student Achievement Amendment Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-311. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 2013, and December 3, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-254 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-84 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
