<level type="section">
  <num>50-211.04</num>
  <heading>Program goals.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director, in coordination with the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT ") and other agencies, shall balance the following goals in performing the Director's responsibilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Providing vehicles that meet the mission of the client agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enhancing the overall cost and energy efficiency of the District government's vehicle fleet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reducing the total number of passenger vehicles in the standing fleet and reduce their use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Encouraging transit use and multimodal transportation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Promoting the use of Bikeshare for work-related travel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Promoting the use of taxicabs for trips where the cost of a taxi would be less than the cost of using a government vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Ensuring timely reimbursement for work-related transportation expenses incurred by employees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Reducing total fuel use, improving fleet fuel economy, and promoting the use of alternative fuels;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Diversifying the range of fuels used for transportation within the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Using the District's purchasing power to facilitate the availability of alternative fuels for use in private fleets and personal vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Meeting or exceeding the requirements of section 507 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, approved October 24, 1992 (106 Stat. 2891; 42 U.S.C. § 13257) and associated regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>When vehicle acquisition is necessary, acquiring a vehicle with the lowest real cost of ownership.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Factors to consider in determining the real cost of ownership for the purpose of subsection (a)(12) of this section shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The sales price of vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The projected vehicle life;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The projected fuel costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The projected operation costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The projected maintenance costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The vehicle emissions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-223, § 104, 59 DCR 13537.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-211.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-223</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-211.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-223 provided that §§ 101, 102, 104, 105(a), 105(b), 106, 107, 201(a), 201(b), 201(c), 202, 203, and 301 of the act shall apply as of Mar. 5, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
