<level type="section">
  <num>16-1043</num>
  <heading>Nonjudicial enforcement of order.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A law enforcement officer, upon determining that there is probable cause to believe that a valid foreign protection order exists and that the order has been violated, shall enforce the order as if it were the order of a tribunal of the District. Presentation of a protection order that identifies both the protected individual and the respondent and, on its face, is currently in effect constitutes probable cause to believe that a valid foreign protection order exists. For the purposes of this section, the protection order may be inscribed on a tangible medium or may have been stored in an electronic or other medium if it is retrievable in perceivable form. Presentation of a certified copy of a protection order is not required for enforcement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a foreign protection order is not presented, a law enforcement officer may consider other information in determining whether there is probable cause to believe that a valid foreign protection order exists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Registration or filing of an order in the District is not required for the enforcement of a valid foreign protection order pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-296, ยง 2(c), 50 DCR 320.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-296, see notes following ยง 16-1041.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 4 of the Uniform Interstate Enforcement of Domestic Violence Protection Orders Act. See 9, Pt. 1B, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
