<level type="section">
  <num>44-302.01</num>
  <heading>Specialists as primary care providers.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 32-572.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A health benefits plan shall permit a member with chronic disabling or life threatening conditions to choose a health care specialist as the member's primary care provider. The specialist must be a participant in the health benefits plan and be available to attend to the member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A specialist chosen by a member pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be permitted to treat the member without the member first receiving a referral from another health care provider. The specialist may authorize referrals, procedures, tests, and medical services subject to the terms of a treatment plan developed by the specialist and approved by the insurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A health benefits plan shall permit a member with a chronic disabling or life threatening condition to have direct access to a specialist qualified to treat the condition, subject to initial referral by the member's primary care provider and a treatment plan approved by the member's primary care provider. Such treatment plan shall ensure that the member will receive covered medically necessary procedures, tests, and medical services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-274, ยง 201, 46 DCR 1294.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 32-572.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-274, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 44-301.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
