<level type="section">
  <num>21-2207</num>
  <heading>Forms for creating a durable power of attorney for health care.</heading>
  <level type="form">
    <text> Any written form meeting the requirements of § 21-2205 may be used to create a durable power of attorney for health care. The following is offered as a sample form only and its inclusion in this section shall not be construed to preclude the use of alternative language: 
 

 "<span style="font-weight: bold; ">INFORMATION ABOUT THIS DOCUMENT 

</span>
 "THIS IS AN IMPORTANT LEGAL DOCUMENT. BEFORE SIGNING THIS DOCUMENT, IT IS VITAL FOR YOU TO KNOW AND UNDERSTAND THESE FACTS: 


 "THIS DOCUMENT GIVES THE PERSON YOU NAME AS YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACT THE POWER TO MAKE HEALTH-CARE DECISIONS FOR YOU IF YOU CANNOT MAKE THE DECISIONS FOR YOURSELF. 


 "AFTER YOU HAVE SIGNED THIS DOCUMENT, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO MAKE HEALTH-CARE DECISIONS FOR YOURSELF IF YOU ARE MENTALLY COMPETENT TO DO SO. IN ADDITION, AFTER YOU HAVE SIGNED THIS DOCUMENT, NO TREATMENT MAY BE GIVEN TO YOU OR STOPPED OVER YOUR OBJECTION IF YOU ARE MENTALLY COMPETENT TO MAKE THAT DECISION. 


 "YOU MAY STATE IN THIS DOCUMENT ANY TYPE OF TREATMENT THAT YOU DO NOT DESIRE AND ANY THAT YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU RECEIVE. 


 "YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO TAKE AWAY THE AUTHORITY OF YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACT, UNLESS YOU HAVE BEEN ADJUDICATED INCOMPETENT, BY NOTIFYING YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACT OR HEALTH-CARE PROVIDER EITHER ORALLY OR IN WRITING. SHOULD YOU REVOKE THE AUTHORITY OF YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACT, IT IS ADVISABLE TO REVOKE IN WRITING AND TO PLACE COPIES OF THE REVOCATION WHEREVER THIS DOCUMENT IS LOCATED. 


 "IF THERE IS ANYTHING IN THIS DOCUMENT THAT YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND, YOU SHOULD ASK A SOCIAL WORKER, LAWYER, OR OTHER PERSON TO EXPLAIN IT TO YOU. 


 

 * * * * * 


 "YOU SHOULD KEEP A COPY OF THIS DOCUMENT AFTER YOU HAVE SIGNED IT. GIVE A COPY TO THE PERSON YOU NAME AS YOUR ATTORNEY IN FACT. IF YOU ARE IN A HEALTH-CARE FACILITY, A COPY OF THIS DOCUMENT SHOULD BE INCLUDED IN YOUR MEDICAL RECORD.</text>
    <text>
 "<span style="font-weight: bold; ">POWER OF ATTORNEY FOR HEALTH CARE </span>
 "I, __________________________________________________, hereby appoint: 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 name home address 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 home telephone number 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 work telephone number 
 as my attorney in fact to make health-care decisions for me if I become unable to make my own health-care decisions. This gives my attorney in fact the power to grant, refuse, or withdraw consent on my behalf for any health-care service, treatment or procedure. My attorney in fact also has the authority to talk to health-care personnel, get information and sign forms necessary to carry out these decisions. 


 "If the person named as my attorney in fact is not available or is unable to act as my attorney in fact, I appoint the following person to serve in the order listed below: 
 1. ______________________________ __________________________________ 
name home address 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 home telephone number 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 work telephone number 
 2. ______________________________ __________________________________ 
name home address 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 home telephone number 
 ______________________________ ______________________________________
 work telephone number 


 "With this document, I intend to create a power of attorney for health care, which shall take effect if I become incapable of making my own health-care decisions and shall continue during that incapacity. 


 "My attorney in fact shall make health-care decisions as I direct below or as I make known to my attorney in fact in some other way. 


 "(a) STATEMENT OF DIRECTIVES CONCERNING LIFE-PROLONGING CARE, TREATMENT, SERVICES, AND PROCEDURES: 
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________


 "(b) SPECIAL PROVISIONS AND LIMITATIONS: 
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________
 _____________________________________________________________________________


 "BY MY SIGNATURE I INDICATE THAT I UNDERSTAND THE PURPOSE AND EFFECT OF THIS DOCUMENT. 


 "I sign my name to this form on __________________________________________
 (date) 
 

 at: _________________________________________________________________________
 

 _________________________________________________________________ (address). 
 ________________________________________________________
 (Signature) 


 

 "<span style="font-weight: bold; ">WITNESSES 

</span>
 "I declare that the person who signed or acknowledged this document is personally known to me, that the person signed or acknowledged this durable power of attorney for health care in my presence, and that the person appears to be of sound mind and under no duress, fraud, or undue influence. I am not the person appointed as the attorney in fact by this document, nor am I the health-care provider of the principal or an employee of the health-care provider of the principal. 
 <span style="font-weight: bold; ">First Witness </span>
 Signature: __________________________________________________________________
 Home Address: _______________________________________________________________
 Print Name: _________________________________________________________________
 Date: _______________________________________________________________________
 <span style="font-weight: bold; ">Second Witness </span>
 Signature: __________________________________________________________________
 Home Address: _______________________________________________________________
 Print Name: _________________________________________________________________
 Date: _______________________________________________________________________
 (AT LEAST 1 OF THE WITNESSES LISTED ABOVE SHALL ALSO SIGN THE FOLLOWING DECLARATION.) 


 "I further declare that I am not related to the principal by blood, marriage or adoption, and, to the best of my knowledge, I am not entitled to any part of the estate of the principal under a currently existing will or by operation of law. 
 Signature: ________________________________ 
 Signature: ________________________________."</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-189, § 8, 35 DCR 8653; Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 23(h), 40 DCR 6311.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 21-2207.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-189</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-189, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-2201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-68</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-68, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-2201.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
