<level type="section">
  <num>4-208.03</num>
  <heading>Underpayment corrections.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a recipient of public assistance receives a payment or series of payments in an amount less than that for which the recipient is eligible, or does not receive payments for which the recipient is eligible, the underpayment shall be corrected retroactively for not more than 12 months prior to whichever of the following occurs first:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The date the Mayor received a request for restoration of assistance from the recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date the recipient requested a fair hearing concerning the loss of assistance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date the Mayor is notified or otherwise discovered that a loss of benefits to an assistance unit has occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to confer an entitlement to public assistance to any individual. The decision to grant public assistance to an eligible individual lies in the sole discretion of the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 803, 29 DCR 1060; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(aaa), 46 DCR 905.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 3-208.3.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(aa) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-230, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 4143).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(aaa) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998, 45 DCR 4270), § 2(aaa) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998, 45 DCR 5682),§ 2(aaa) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998, 46 DCR 521), and § 2(aaa) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999, 46 DCR 2492).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-101</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-101, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-241</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-241, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
