<level type="section">
  <num>20-501</num>
  <heading>Conditions of appointment.</heading>
  <text>As a condition to appointment, a personal representative, whether in a supervised or unsupervised administration, shall file (a) a statement of acceptance of the duties of the office, (b) any required bond, and (c) a written consent to personal jurisdiction in any action brought in the District of Columbia against such personal representative, where service of process is effected pursuant to the rules of the Court at such representative's address shown in the proceedings or, in the case of a nonresident personal representative, pursuant to the provisions of section 20-303(b)(7).</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 101, 27 DCR 2155; Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-241, § 3(u), 42 DCR 63.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 20-523.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 20-501.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of § 4 of D.C. Law 10-241, see § 2 of the Probate Reform Act of 1994 Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-79, June 28, 1995, 42 DCR 3452).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-72</heading>
      <text>Law 3-72, the "District of Columbia Probate Reform Act of 1980," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-91, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 1, 1980, and April 22, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 7, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-181 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-241</heading>
      <text>Law 10-241, the "Probate Reform Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-649, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-386 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-241 became effective on March 21, 1995.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 10-241:</text>
      <text>10-241: Section 4 of D.C. Law 10-241, as amended by § 2 of D.C. Law 11-54, provided that the act shall be applicable to estates of decedents who died on or after July 1, 1995.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
