<level type="section">
  <num>47-4657</num>
  <heading>The Elizabeth Ministry, Inc. Affordable Housing Initiative; Lots 140 and 141, Square 5252.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The real property described as Lots 140 and 141 in Square 5252, shall be exempt from the taxation imposed under Chapter 8 of this title during the time that the real property is subject to, and in compliance with, a restrictive covenant or regulatory agreement associated with an affordable housing program that is fully or partially funded by the District or an instrumentality of the District, including the Department of Housing and Community Development, restricting the use of the real property to affordable housing for low-income residents and a child development center; provided, that at the beginning of the 31st real property tax year following the commencement of the exemption, the tax shall be abated to the extent it exceeds 10% of the tax otherwise levied under Chapter 8 of this title, with the tax liability increasing 10 percentage points in each subsequent real property tax year until the tax equals 100% of the tax levied under Chapter 8 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The exemption provided by subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009 as if it had been granted administratively.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-253, § 2(b), 60 DCR 982.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-253, § 4, see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-253, § 4, see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-253</heading>
      <text>Law 19-253, the "Elizabeth Ministry, Inc. Affordable Housing Initiative Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-443. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 14, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-589 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-253 became effective on Apr. 20, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the "Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of D.C. Law 19-253 provided that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against The Elizabeth Ministry, Inc., or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by The Elizabeth Ministry, Inc., on the real property described as Lots 140 and 141 in Square 5252, since July 1, 2007, through May 1, 2013, be forgiven and any payments already made for this period be refunded.</text>
      <text>Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-253 provided that the act shall apply upon inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <text>Section 7005 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 19-253, § 4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
