<level type="section">
  <num>29-307.06</num>
  <heading>Abandonment of a domestication.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided in a plan of domestication of a domestic business corporation, after the plan has been adopted and approved as required by this subchapter, and at any time before the domestication has become effective, it may be abandoned by the board of directors without action by the shareholders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a domestication is abandoned under subsection (a) of this section after articles of charter surrender have been filed with the Mayor but before the domestication has become effective, a statement that the domestication has been abandoned in accordance with this section, signed by an officer or other duly authorized representative, shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing prior to the effective date of the domestication. The statement shall be effective upon filing and the domestication shall be deemed abandoned and shall not become effective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the domestication of a foreign business corporation in the District is abandoned in accordance with the laws of the foreign jurisdiction after articles of domestication have been filed with the Mayor, a statement that the domestication has been abandoned, signed by an officer or other duly authorized representative, shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing. The statement shall be effective upon filing and the domestication shall be deemed abandoned and shall not become effective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
