<level type="section">
  <num>29-307.03</num>
  <heading>Articles of domestication.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After the domestication of a foreign business corporation has been authorized as required by the laws of the foreign jurisdiction, articles of domestication must be signed by any officer or other duly authorized representative. The articles shall set forth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the corporation immediately before the filing of the articles of domestication and, if that name is unavailable for use in the District or the corporation desires to change its name in connection with the domestication, a name that satisfies the requirements of § 29-103.02(a);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The jurisdiction of incorporation of the corporation immediately before the filing of the articles of domestication and the date the corporation was incorporated in that jurisdiction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement that the domestication of the corporation in the District was duly authorized as required by the laws of the jurisdiction in which the corporation was incorporated immediately before its domestication in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The articles of domestication shall contain:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>All of the provisions that § 29-302.02(a) requires to be set forth in articles of incorporation and any other desired provisions that § 29- 302.02(b) permits to be included in articles of incorporation; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have attached articles of incorporation.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, provisions that would not be required to be included in restated articles of incorporation may be omitted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The articles of domestication shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing and take effect at the effective time provided in § 29-102.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the foreign corporation is authorized to do business in the District under subchapter V of Chapter 1 of this title, its certificate of registration shall be canceled automatically on the effective date of its domestication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
