<level type="section">
  <num>50-2421.05</num>
  <heading>Removal of abandoned, dangerous, and unlawfully parked vehicles from private property.</heading>
  <text>The District government or any towing company at the direction of the Department shall remove a motor vehicle parked, left, or stored, on private property in violation of § 50-2421.03(2) or (3), as follows:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A vehicle parked, left, or stored without the consent of the property owner shall be removed immediately after a notice of infraction is issued and conspicuously placed on the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A dangerous vehicle shall be removed, with or without the consent of the property owner, immediately after a notice of infraction is issued and conspicuously placed on the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An abandoned vehicle shall be removed, with or without the consent of the property owner, 45 days after a warning notice has been mailed by first class mail to the last known address of the property owner, as indicated on the records of the Office of Tax and Revenue. For the purposes of this subsection, notice may run concurrently with the period of time required to establish that the vehicle is abandoned, as defined in § 50-2421.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The warning notice shall, at a minimum, indicate the make and model of the vehicle, the date that the vehicle was observed on the property, and the date that the District is authorized to remove, impound, or dispose of the vehicle if the vehicle remains unenclosed on the property.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The warning notice shall be mailed after the first sighting of a vehicle that meets the physical characteristics of an abandoned vehicle. A notice of infraction shall be conspicuously placed on the vehicle prior to its removal. The notice shall also include a telephone number, and website if any, that will inform the owner how to contact the Department to certify that the vehicle is not abandoned.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-35, § 5, 50 DCR 6579.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-2402.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 5 of Removal and Disposition of Abandoned and Other Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-171, October 6, 2003, 50 DCR 9163).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-35</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-35, see notes following § 50-2421.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
