<level type="section">
  <num>50-329.03</num>
  <heading>Complaints.</heading>
  <text>The Commission shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Allow the public to file complaints electronically on its website and through a hotline. This hotline shall be available 24 hours a day, 365 days a year, and be listed on the main page of the Commission's website and in every taxicab;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Within 72 hours of receiving a complaint, confirm in writing to the complainant that the complaint has been received;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Respond, in writing, to the taxicab operator against whom the complaint was filed, with a detailed description of the complaint against him or her, including the time, date, location, circumstances of the alleged incident, and the potential penalties, as well as provide clear instructions of the procedures used to adjudicate the complaint, the rights of the recipient to contest the complaint, and the documents, evidence, or materials necessary for proper adjudication of the complaint;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Provide training in the rules and regulations governing taxicab operators to all personnel responsible for reviewing complaints;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Provide information on its website about the appeals process for complaints;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Conduct annual performance and compliance audits of the complaints received by the Commission, how those complaints were handled, and how those complaints were used to improve the provision of taxicab service in the District; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Employ hearing examiners or hearing officers to hear and adjudicate complaints or other matters before the Commission or refer the matters to the Office of Administrative Hearings, pursuant to Chapter 18A of Title 2 [§ 2-1831.01 et seq.].</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(D.C. Law 6-97, § 20m, as added Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(s), 59 DCR 9431; Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 2(k), 60 DCR 1717.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-307.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-184 added this section.</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-270 rewrote (1), which read "Allow the public to file complaints electronically on its website."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-184, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-184, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-270, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-270, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-184</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-270</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the "Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-184 provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 5 of D.C. Law 19-270 provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 7007 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 19-184, § 7.</text>
      <text>Section 7017 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 19-270, § 5.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
