<level type="section">
  <num>50-329.02</num>
  <heading>Dispatch services.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All taxicab companies, taxicab associations, or taxicab fleets with 100 or more licensed taxicabs shall install radio or digital dispatch equipment in each taxicab. This equipment shall link to a central dispatch service within each company. Each licensed taxicab operator affiliated or contracted with a taxicab company, association, or fleet with more than 100 licensed taxicabs shall be available via dispatch at all times while accepting fares and may not turn off the dispatch equipment while in service. Once a taxicab operator chooses to accept a dispatch request, that operator must accept the fare, regardless of the fare's location within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A digital dispatch service shall be exempt from regulation by the Commission, other than rules and regulations that are necessary for the safety of customers and drivers or consumer protection. Any rules and regulations shall protect personal privacy rights of customers and drivers, shall not result in the disclosure of confidential business information, and shall allow providers to limit the geographic location of trip data to individual census tracts; provided, that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the digital dispatch service connects a customer to a taxicab, the fare shall be calculated in accordance with the taxicab fare structure established by the Commission through an approved taxicab meter system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the digital dispatch service connects a customer to a public vehicle-for-hire other than a taxicab, before booking the vehicle, the dispatch service shall disclose to the customer the fare calculation method, which shall be in compliance with the method required for that class of vehicle, the applicable rates being charged, and the option for an estimated fare;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The public vehicles-for-hire using a digital dispatch service shall be licensed and shall provide service in a manner that complies with all laws, rules, and regulations applicable to public vehicles-for-hire in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service and the operators it employs, contracts with, or affiliates with shall comply with all reciprocal agreements between governmental bodies in the Washington Metropolitan Area governing public vehicle-for-hire service, including section 828 of Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (31 DCMR § 828), as long as the Commission is actively accepting and processing applications for the licensure of public vehicle-for-hire operators and vehicles. The condition that the Commission is actively accepting and processing applications shall not apply if it issues rules establishing limits on the number of vehicles and licenses issued pursuant to § 47-2829(j), which requires the Committee both to conclude that limits are in the public interest and do not unduly and significantly harm the public vehicle-for-hire industry in the District and to submit the rules to the Council for approval;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Upon completion of the trip, the customer shall receive a paper or electronic receipt that lists the origination and destination of the trip, the total distance and time of the trip, and a breakdown of the total fare paid, including fees and gratuity, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service shall provide customers with the ability to indicate an interest in receiving service from a wheelchair accessible vehicle for the purposes of determining market need and for a request for this service once these vehicles become available in this class;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service shall not transmit any destination information about a customer, except for the jurisdiction of the customer's destination, to an operator of a public vehicle-for-hire until the customer has booked the trip;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service shall not allow a public vehicle-for-hire operator it employs, contracts, or affiliates with to discriminate against customers in any way or to otherwise refuse to provide service to or from an area of the District; provided, that a digital dispatch service may rate a customer as long as the customer's rating may be viewed by the customer, the digital dispatch service includes a non-discrimination policy in its contract terms with public vehicle-for-hire drivers, and the digital dispatch service provides a customer with the ability to report allegations of discrimination in public vehicle-for-hire service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service provides service throughout the entire District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The digital dispatch service shall submit proof to the Commission annually that it is licensed to do business in the District, maintains a registered agent in the District, and maintains a website, which shall contain information on its method of fare calculation, the rates and fees charged, and provides a customer service telephone number or email address.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall provide contact information, including hyperlinks, if available, for each of the available public vehicle-for-hire dispatch services within the District. The Commission shall list this information or a link to this information on the front page of the Commission's website and shall include the company name and any other appropriate, information, including a hyperlink to the website or phone number listing of each company.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "digital dispatch service" means a business that provides a service that connects a passenger to a public vehicle-for-hire through advanced reservation, including by computer, mobile phone application, text, email, or web-based reservations, or by other means as the Commission may define by rule.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(D.C. Law 6-97, § 20l, as added Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(s), 59 DCR 9431; Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 2(j), 60 DCR 1717.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-329.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-184 added this section.</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-270 rewrote (b); and added (c) and (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-184, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-184, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-270, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 19-270, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-184</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-270</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the "Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-184 provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 5 of D.C. Law 19-270 provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 7007 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 19-184, § 7.</text>
      <text>Section 7017 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 19-270, § 5.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
