<level type="section">
  <num>47-895.33</num>
  <heading>Notices; collection; penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Energy Efficiency Loan Agreement shall require the property owner to consent to the levy of the Special Assessment on the lots, following which consent, all actions by any owner of the lot to challenge the levy of the Special Assessment shall be forever barred. The property owner that enters into an Energy Efficiency Loan Agreement and each subsequent owner of the lot shall provide notice to the buyer of the lot of the levy of the Special Assessment; provided, that the notice shall not apply to lots sold under Chapter 13A [of this title]. Failure to receive disclosure of the Special Assessment by a subsequent owner shall not relieve the subsequent owner of the obligation to pay the Special Assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Special Assessments shall be collected in the same manner and at the same time as real property taxes are collected; provided, that the Special Assessments may be collected at a different time and in a different manner as determined by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an unpaid Special Assessment shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as a delinquent real property tax under this chapter. A lien for an unpaid Special Assessment, including penalty and interest, shall attach to the real property in the same manner as, and with a priority immediately junior to, a lien for delinquent real property tax under Chapter 13A [of this title] and senior to all other liens. Real property sold at a tax sale for the failure to pay real property taxes shall remain subject to the obligation to pay Special Assessments in subsequent years as provided in this subchapter. The unpaid Special Assessment shall be collected pursuant to section 47-1336.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an interest in or use of a lot is subject to the Special Assessment because it is subject to taxation under § 47-1005.01, an unpaid Special Assessment on such an interest or use shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as a delinquent tax imposed under § 47-1005.01, and the unpaid Special Assessment shall be collected in the same manner and under the same conditions and subject to the same penalty as for an unpaid tax imposed under § 47-1005.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-183, § 401(b), 57 DCR 3406; Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 103(b), 60 DCR 1300.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-262 substituted "pursuant to § 47-1336" for "in the same manner and under the same conditions and subject to the same penalties as for unpaid real property taxes" in the last sentence of (c)(1).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-183</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-183, see notes following § 47-895.31.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-262</heading>
      <text>See note to § 47-895.31.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
