<level type="section">
  <num>38-827.02</num>
  <heading>Composition and organization of the Commission.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall be composed of 13 members who are experts in health, wellness, or nutrition; parents; teachers; or students. The Mayor shall appoint 10 members, no more than 5 of whom shall represent District agencies. The Chairman of the Council shall appoint one member. The chair of the Council committee with oversight of education shall appoint one member. The Chair of the Public Charter School Board shall appoint one member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Members shall serve 3-year terms on the Commission, except that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Of the Mayor's first 10 persons appointed, 4 shall be appointed to serve 3- year terms, 3 shall be appointed to serve 2-year terms, and 3 shall be appointed to serve one-year terms; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Students shall serve for one year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate one member of the Commission to serve as its Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A member shall serve for no more than 2 consecutive, full terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Unless excused by the Chairperson, any member who fails to attend 3 consecutive meetings shall be deemed to be removed from the Commission, creating a vacancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation; provided, that each member may be reimbursed for actual expenses pursuant to ยง 1- 611.08.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, ยง 702, 57 DCR 4779.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-209, see notes following ยง 38-821.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
