<level type="section">
  <num>31-1603</num>
  <heading>Prohibited actions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In determining whether to issue, cancel, or renew insurance coverage, an insurer may not use age, marital status, geographic area of residence, occupation, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or any similar factor or combination of factors for the purpose of seeking to predict whether any individual may in the future develop AIDS or ARC.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In determining rates, premiums, dues, assessments, benefits covered, or expenses reimbursable, or in any other aspect of insurance marketing or coverage, an insurer may not use age, marital status, geographic area of residence, occupation, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, or any similar factor or combination of factors for the purpose of seeking to predict whether any individual may in the future develop AIDS or ARC.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No health or disability insurance policy or contract shall contain any exclusion, reduction, other limitation of coverage, deductibles, or coinsurance provisions related to the care and treatment of AIDS, ARC, HIV infection, or any illness or disease arising from these medical conditions, unless the provisions apply generally to all benefits under the policy or contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No life insurance policy or contract shall contain any exclusion, reduction, or other limitation of benefits related to AIDS, ARC, HIV infection, or any disease arising from these medical conditions, as a cause of death.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 7, 1986, D.C. Law 6-132, § 4, 33 DCR 3615; Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-208, § 2(b), 36 DCR 471; June 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-177, § 15(b), 55 DCR 3696.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 35-223.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-177, in subsec. (b), substituted "sexual orientation, gender identity or expression" for "sexual orientation".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-132</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-132, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-208</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-208, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1610.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-177</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-177, see notes following § 31-1601.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
