<level type="section">
  <num>29-809.08</num>
  <heading>Filings required for domestication; effective date.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After a plan of domestication is approved, a domesticating company shall deliver to the Mayor for filing articles of domestication, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement, as the case may be, that the company has been domesticated from or into another jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of the domesticating company and the jurisdiction of its governing statute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name of the domesticated company and the jurisdiction of its governing statute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The date the domestication is effective under the governing statute of the domesticated company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the domesticating company was a limited liability company, a statement that the domestication was approved as required by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>If the domesticating company was a foreign limited liability company, a statement that the domestication was approved as required by the governing statute of the other jurisdiction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>If the domesticated company was a foreign limited liability company not authorized to do business in the District, the street and mailing addresses of an office that the Mayor may use for the purposes of § 29-809.09(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A domestication shall be effective:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When the certificate of organization takes effect, if the domesticated company is a limited liability company; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>According to the governing statute of the domesticated company, if the domesticated organization is a foreign limited liability company.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-809.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1012 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
