<level type="section">
  <num>44-106.02</num>
  <heading>Resident agreements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A written contract must be provided to the resident prior to admission and signed by the resident or surrogate, if necessary, and a representative of the ALR. The nonfinancial portions of the contract shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The ALR's organizational affiliations (including parent or subsidiary organizations, religious or charitable affiliation, and management company);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The specific nature of any special care that it holds itself out to provide, such as specialty in Alzheimer's disease or Parkinson's disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An identification of services to be included and excluded, part of which is the ISP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A list of resident rights including grievance procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Unit assignment and procedures if changes occur;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Admission and discharge policies which include clear and specific criteria for admission, transfer, and discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A description of responsibility for provision or coordination of healthcare, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An arrangement for notification in case of the resident's death; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A disposition of the resident's property upon discharge, transfer, or death of the resident.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-127, ยง 602, 47 DCR 2647.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 44-106.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-127</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-127, see notes following ยง 44-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
