<level type="section">
  <num>29-708.03</num>
  <heading>Winding up.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited partnership shall continue after dissolution only for the purpose of winding up its activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In winding up its activities, the limited partnership:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>May amend its certificate of limited partnership to state that the limited partnership is dissolved, preserve the limited partnership business or property as a going concern for a reasonable time, prosecute and defend actions and proceedings, whether civil, criminal, or administrative, transfer the limited partnership's property, settle disputes by mediation or arbitration, file a statement of termination as provided in § 29-702.03, and perform other necessary acts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall discharge the limited partnership's liabilities, settle and close the limited partnership's activities, and marshal and distribute the assets of the partnership.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a dissolved limited partnership does not have a general partner, a person to wind up the dissolved limited partnership's activities may be appointed by the consent of limited partners owning a majority of the rights to receive distributions as limited partners at the time the consent is to be effective. A person appointed under this subsection shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have the powers of a general partner under § 29-708.04; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Promptly amend the certificate of limited partnership to state:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>That the limited partnership does not have a general partner;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name of the person that has been appointed to wind up the limited partnership; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The street and mailing address of the person.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>On the application of any partner, the Superior Court may order judicial supervision of the winding up, including the appointment of a person to wind up the dissolved limited partnership's activities, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A limited partnership does not have a general partner and within a reasonable time following the dissolution no person has been appointed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The applicant establishes other good cause.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 803 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
