<level type="section">
  <num>7-531.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 6-2241</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>For the purposes of this unit, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"District" means the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Eligible person" means an individual who is 60 years of age or older or is mentally or physically ill, infirm, or has a disability.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Service credit" means the unit of exchange upon which the volunteer service credit program operates.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Sponsor" means a nonprofit organization or a consortium of nonprofit organizations that receives and dispenses service credits on behalf of eligible persons and is designated by the Mayor to perform the administrative tasks necessary to implement this unit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Targeted service" means a task for which service credits may be earned when performed by a volunteer for an eligible person.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Volunteer" means an individual who earns service credits by:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Providing targeted services to an eligible person not related to him or her by blood, marriage, guardianship, or adoption;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Providing services under a demonstration project;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Participating in pre-service or in-service training under the volunteer service credit program or a demonstration project; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Performing administrative tasks in direct support of the volunteer service credit program or a demonstration project.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 13, 1986, D.C. Law 6-143, ยง 2, 33 DCR 4372; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, ยง 23, 53 DCR 6198.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 6-2241.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-305, in par. (2), substituted "infirm, or has a disability" for "disabled, or infirm".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 6-143, the "Volunteer Service Credit Program Act of 1986," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-282, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 10, 1986 and June 24, 1986, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 8, 1986, it was assigned Act No. 6-185 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>Law 16-305, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Act of 2006", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-664, which was referred to Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 20, 2006, and July 11, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-437 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-305 became effective on April 24, 2007.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to Law 6-143, see Mayor's Order 87-140, June 16, 1987.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
