<level type="section">
  <num>4-517.01</num>
  <heading>Crime victims assistance.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 3-437.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The victims assistance grants agency shall have the authority to use the funds transferred pursuant to § 4-515 to award grants and contracts to private nonprofit organizations and to transfer funds to government entities which provide assistance to crime victims.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-243, § 18a, as added Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 202(e), 47 DCR 6308; Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1192(f), 51 DCR 8441.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-205 repealed subsec. (b) which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) The District of Columbia Auditor shall perform a biennial audit of the use of the funds under this section. The audit shall include the number of:</text>
        <text>"(1) Grants, contracts and transfers in each fiscal year and the respective amounts awarded or transferred;</text>
        <text>"(2) Crime victims assisted through each grant, contract or transfer and the kinds of assistance rendered; and</text>
        <text>"(3) Personnel positions and amount of personnel funding and other administrative costs involved in carrying out this section."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 202(e) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000, 47 DCR 6574).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(f) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004, 51 DCR 8236).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(f) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR 11725).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 15-205, see notes following § 4-204.61.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
