<level type="section">
  <num>22-3010.01</num>
  <heading>Misdemeanor sexual abuse of a child or minor.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whoever, being 18 years of age or older and more than 4 years older than a child, or being 18 years of age or older and being in a significant relationship with a minor, engages in sexually suggestive conduct with that child or minor shall be imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or fined in an amount not to exceed $1,000, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "sexually suggestive conduct" means engaging in any of the following acts in a way which is intended to cause or reasonably causes the sexual arousal or sexual gratification of any person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Touching a child or minor inside his or her clothing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Touching a child or minor inside or outside his or her clothing close to the genitalia, anus, breast, or buttocks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Placing one's tongue in the mouth of the child or minor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Touching one's own genitalia or that of a third person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-257, § 209a, as added Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-306, § 216(e), 53 DCR 8610.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 216(e) of Omnibus Public Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-445, July 19, 2006, 53 DCR 6443).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 216(e) of Omnibus Public Safety Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-490, October 18, 2006, 53 DCR 8686).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 216(e) of Omnibus Public Safety Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-10, January 16, 2007, 54 DCR 1479).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 216(e) of Omnibus Public Safety Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-25, April 19, 2007, 54 DCR 4036).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 511(a) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011, 58 DCR 640).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 511(a) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011, 58 DCR 3701).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-306, see notes following § 22-404.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
