<level type="section">
  <num>28-5101</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Art dealer" means a person engaged in the business of selling works of fine art other than a person exclusively engaged in the business of selling goods at public auction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Artist" means the creator of a work of fine art.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"On consignment" means delivered to an art dealer for the purpose of sale or exhibition to the public by the art dealer other than at a public auction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Work of fine art" means an original art work which is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A visual rendition, including a painting, drawing, sculpture, mosaic, or photograph;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A work of calligraphy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A work of graphic art, including an etching, lithograph, offset print, or silk screen;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A craft work in materials, including clay, textile, fiber, wood, metal, plastic, or glass; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A work in mixed media, including a collage or a work consisting of any combination of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of this paragraph.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-310, ยง 2, 57 DCR 12392.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-310</heading>
      <text>Law 18-310, the "Artist Protection Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-451, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 9, 2010, and November 23, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 9, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-631 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-310 became effective on March 12, 2011.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
