<level type="section">
  <num>11-1568.01</num>
  <heading>Opportunity to revoke a previous survivor annuity election.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 11-1568.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any individual who, before the date of the enactment of this Act, made an election under section 11-1566 of title 11 of the District of Columbia Official Code, to come within the purview of the survivor annuity provisions of subchapter III of chapter 15 of such title may revoke that election. Such a revocation shall constitute a complete withdrawal from the survivor annuity program provided for in such subchapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in writing to the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A revocation under paragraph (1) shall be effective on the day it is received by the official referred to in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>On the effective date of a revocation under paragraph (1), any right to survivor benefits (to which the revocation relates) for the survivors of the individual who makes the revocation shall terminate, and all amounts credited to the account of such individual under section 11-1570(c) of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Official Code, together with interest computed as provided in subparagraph (B), shall be returned to that individual in a lump-sum payment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of subparagraph (A), interest shall be computed in accordance with section 11-1561(10)(C) of title 11 of the District of Columbia Official Code.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any individual who makes a revocation under paragraph (1) and who thereafter becomes eligible to make an election under section 11-1556 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Official Code may make such election only if such individual redeposits, to the credit of the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund referred to in section 11-1561(4) of such title, the full amount of the lump-sum payment made to such individual under paragraph (4), together with interest.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of subparagraph (A), interest shall be computed at 3 percent per annum, compounded on December 31 of each year from the date of the lump-sum payment referred to in such subparagraph until the date on which the amount referred to in such subparagraph is redeposited under such subparagraph.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 6, 1986, 100 Stat. 514, Pub. L. 99-335, § 601(c); Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 759, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11253(a)(3); Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2423, Pub. L. 105-274, § 2(e)(6); Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-538, Pub. L. 105-277, § 804(e)(6).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 11-1568.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>"The date of the enactment of this Act," referred to in paragraph (1)(A), is June 6, 1986.</text>
        <text>The reference in paragraph (4)(A) to § 11-1556 probably should be to § 11-1566.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Section 23(b) of D.C. Law 15-354 provides that the section designation of § 11-1568.1 of the District of Columbia Official Code is redesignated as § 11- 1568.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
