<level type="section">
  <num>36-303.02</num>
  <heading>Disclosures to prospective retail dealers.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 10-222</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Prior to entering into any marketing agreement with any prospective retail dealer, a distributor shall disclose the information set forth in this section to such prospective retail dealer in writing. Prior to transferring any marketing agreement or interest therein to any prospective transferee, a retail dealer shall disclose the information set forth in this section to such prospective transferee in writing:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and last known address of the previous retail dealer or dealers for the immediately prior 3-year period or for the entire period during which the distributor has either sold or distributed motor fuels or petroleum products to or through such retail service station location or owned, leased, or otherwise controlled such location, whichever period is shorter, and the grounds or reasons for the termination of, cancellation of, or failure to renew each marketing agreement with such previous retail dealer or dealers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The existence of any present commitments, negotiations, or plans for the future sale, demolition, or other disposition of such location.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 19, 1977, D.C. Law 1-123, § 4-202, 24 DCR 2371.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 10-222.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 10-222.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-123, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 36-301.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
