<level type="section">
  <num>29-408.22</num>
  <heading>Bylaw amendments requiring member approval.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, the board of directors or designated body of a membership corporation that has one or more members at the time shall not adopt or amend a bylaw under:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 29-404.10 providing that some of the members have different rights or obligations than other members with respect to voting, dissolution, transfer of memberships or other matters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Section 29-404.13 levying dues, assessments, or fees on some or all of the members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Section 29-404.21 relating to the termination or suspension of members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Section 29-404.22 authorizing the purchase of memberships;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Section 29-406.08(a):</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Requiring cause to remove a director; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Specifying what constitutes cause to remove a director;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Section 29-406.08(e) relating to the removal of a director who is designated in a manner other than election or appointment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Section 29-406.12.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The board of directors or designated body of a membership corporation shall not amend the articles of incorporation or bylaws to vary the application of subsection (a) of this section to the corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a nonprofit corporation has more than one class of members, the members of a class shall be entitled to vote as a separate voting group on an amendment to the bylaws that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is described in subsection (a) of this subsection if the amendment would affect the members of that class differently than the members of another class; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has any of the effects described in ยง 29-408.04.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a class of members will be divided into 2 or more classes by an amendment to the bylaws, the amendment shall be approved by a majority of the members of each class that will be created.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 29-408.20.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
