<level type="section">
  <num>2-354.08</num>
  <heading>Special pilot procurements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CPO may, with prior public notice and in accordance with rules issued pursuant to this chapter, award a contract without competitive sealed bidding or competitive sealed proposals if it is determined that an unusual or unique situation exists that makes the application of all requirements of competitive sealed bidding or competitive sealed proposals not in the public interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A special pilot procurement under this section shall be made with as much competition as is practicable under the circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A special pilot procurement under this section shall require a determination and findings setting forth the reasons warranting the special procurement and for the selection of the particular contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall post the notice of award and the determination and findings on the Internet within 7 days after the execution and approval of a special pilot procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An unusual or unique situation justifying a special pilot procurement under this section shall include a contract made to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Satisfy a new and unique District requirement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtain a new technology.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, ยง 408, 58 DCR 1185.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 2-354.01 and ยง 2-356.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-371</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-371, see notes under ยง 2-351.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
