<level type="section">
  <num>23-1110</num>
  <heading>Designation of official to take bail or collateral when court is not in session; issuance of citations.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The judges of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall have the authority to appoint some official of the Metropolitan Police Department to act as a clerk of the court with authority to take bail or collateral from persons charged with offenses triable in the Superior Court at all times when the court is not open and its clerks accessible. The official so appointed shall have the same authority at those times with reference to taking bonds or collateral as the clerk of the Municipal Court had on March 3, 1933; shall receive no compensation for these services other than his regular salary; shall be subject to the orders and rules of the Superior Court in discharge of his duties, and may be removed as the clerk at any time by the judges of the court. The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have power to authorize the official appointed by the Superior Court to take bond of persons arrested upon writs and process from that court in criminal cases between 4 o'clock postmeridian and 9 o'clock antemeridian and upon Sundays and holidays, and shall have power at any time to revoke the authority granted by it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An officer or member of the Metropolitan Police Department who arrests without a warrant a person for committing a misdemeanor may, instead of taking him into custody, issue a citation requiring the person to appear before an official of the Metropolitan Police Department designated under subsection (a) of this section to act as a clerk of the Superior Court.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whenever a person is arrested without a warrant for committing a misdemeanor and is booked and processed pursuant to law, an official of the Metropolitan Police Department designated under subsection (a) of this section to act as a clerk of the Superior Court may issue a citation to him for an appearance in court or at some other designated place, and release him from custody.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No citation may be issued under paragraph (1) or (2) unless the person authorized to issue the citation has reason to believe that the arrested person will not cause injury to persons or damage to property and that he will make an appearance in answer to the citation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whoever willfully fails to appear as required in a citation, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both. Prosecution under this paragraph shall be by the prosecuting officer responsible for prosecuting the offense for which the citation is issued.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 638, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 210(a); Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 101(a), 41 DCR 2608; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 283(e), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 25-781, § 25-785, and § 25-1002.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 23-1110.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 23-1110.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01]" for "not more than the maximum provided for the misdemeanor for which such citation was issued" in (b)(4).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(a) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994, 41 DCR 4286).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-151</heading>
      <text>See note to § 23-1108.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Capitol Police Citation Release: For designation of a member of the Capitol Police to have responsibility for citation release, and to take bail, collateral, or bond in the same manner as an official of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia under this section, see § 108 of Pub. L. 104-186, 110 Stat. 1719.</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
