<level type="section">
  <num>38-2652</num>
  <heading>Functions of the Board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the State Superintendent of Education on educational matters, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>State standards;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>State policies, including those governing special, academic, vocational, charter, and other schools;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>State objectives; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>State regulations proposed by the Mayor or the State Superintendent of Education;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>Oversee the Office of Ombudsman for Public Education in accordance with Chapter 3A of this title [§ 38-351 et seq.], and the Office of the Student Advocate in accordance with Chapter 3B of this title [§ 38-371 et seq.].</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Approve state academic standards, following a recommendation by the State Superintendent of Education, ensuring that the standards recommended by the State Superintendent of Education:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Specify what children are expected to know and be able to do;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Contain coherent and rigorous content;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Encourage the teaching of advanced skills; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Are updated on a regular basis;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Approve high school graduation requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Approve standards for high school equivalence credentials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Approve a state definition of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Adequate yearly progress" that will be applied consistently to all local education agencies;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>And standards for "highly qualified teachers," pursuant to the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001, approved January 8, 2002 (115 Stat. 1425; 20 U.S.C. § 6301 et seq.) ("NCLB Act"); and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>"Proficiency" that ensures an accurate measure of student achievement;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Approve standards for accreditation and certification of teacher preparation programs of colleges and universities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Approve the state accountability plan for the District of Columbia developed by the chief state school officer, pursuant to the NCLB Act, ensuring that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The plan includes a single statewide accountability system that will ensure all local education agencies make adequate yearly progress; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The statewide accountability system included in the plan is based on academic standards, academic assessments, a standardized system of accountability across all local education agencies, and a system of sanctions and rewards that will be used to hold local education agencies accountable for student achievement;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Approve state policies for parental involvement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Approve state policies for supplemental education service providers operating in the District to ensure that providers have a demonstrated record of effectiveness and offer services that promote challenging academic achievement standards and that improve student achievement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Approve the rules for residency verification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Approve the list of charter school accreditation organizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Approve the categories and format of the annual report card, pursuant to the NCLB Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Approve the list of private placement accreditation organizations, pursuant to Chapter 29 of this title [§ 38-2901 et seq.];</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Approve state rules for enforcing school attendance requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Approve state standards for home schooling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall conduct monthly meetings to receive citizen input with respect to issues properly before it, which may be conducted at a location in a ward.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall consider matters for policy approval upon submission of a request for policy action by the State Superintendent of Education within a review period requested by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Board shall, by order, specify its organizational structure, staff, operations, reimbursement of expenses policy, and other matters affecting the Board's functions.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Board shall appoint staff members, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board, to perform administrative functions and any other functions necessary to execute the mission of the Board.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2013, the Board shall prepare and submit to the Mayor, for inclusion in the annual budget prepared and submitted to the Council pursuant to part D of subchapter IV of Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 204.41 et seq.], annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the operation of the Board for the year. All the estimates shall be forwarded by the Mayor to the Council for, in addition to the Mayor's recommendations, action by the Council pursuant to §§ 1-204.46 and 1-206.03(c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Board shall be reflected in the budget and financial system as an agency-level entity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All assets, staff, and unexpended appropriations of the Office of the State Superintendent of Education or of any other agency that are associated with the Board shall be transferred to the Board by April 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "state" means District-wide and similar to functions, policies, and rules performed by states on a state-wide basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 403, 54 DCR 4102; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4032, 57 DCR 181; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-284, § 4, 60 DCR 2312; Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-76, § 301, 61 DCR 39.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 38-2601 and § 38-2602.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-111 rewrote subsec. (d), which had read as follows: "(d) The Mayor shall, by order, specify the Board's organizational structure, staff, budget, operations, reimbursement of expenses policy, and other matters affecting the Board's functions."</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-284 rewrote (d).</text>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-76 added (a)(1A).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the State Board of Education Personnel Authority Amendment Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-46, March 27, 2013, 60 DCR 5453, 20 DCSTAT 545).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-9</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-9, see notes following § 38-2651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 38-191.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-284</heading>
      <text>Law 19-284, the "State Board of Education Personnel Authority Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-774. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012 and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 29, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-651 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-284 became effective on April 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-76</heading>
      <text>Law 20-76, the "Parent and Student Empowerment Amendment Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-314. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 2013 and December 3, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 16, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-242 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-76 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Mayor's orders</heading>
      <text>Establishment of the State Board of Education's By laws, see Mayor's Order 2007-214, October 3, 2007 (55 DCR 139).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
