<level type="section">
  <num>38-2652</num>
  <heading>Functions of the Board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the State Superintendent of Education on educational matters, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>State standards;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>State policies, including those governing special, academic, vocational, charter, and other schools;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>State objectives; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>State regulations proposed by the Mayor or the State Superintendent of Education;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Approve state academic standards, following a recommendation by the State Superintendent of Education, ensuring that the standards recommended by the State Superintendent of Education:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Specify what children are expected to know and be able to do;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Contain coherent and rigorous content;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Encourage the teaching of advanced skills; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Are updated on a regular basis;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Approve high school graduation requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Approve standards for high school equivalence credentials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Approve a state definition of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Adequate yearly progress" that will be applied consistently to all local education agencies;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>And standards for "highly qualified teachers," pursuant to the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001, approved January 8, 2002 (115 Stat. 1425; 20 U.S.C. § 6301 <text i="True">et seq.</text>) ("NCLB Act"); and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>"Proficiency" that ensures an accurate measure of student achievement;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Approve standards for accreditation and certification of teacher preparation programs of colleges and universities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Approve the state accountability plan for the District of Columbia developed by the chief state school officer, pursuant to the NCLB Act, ensuring that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The plan includes a single statewide accountability system that will ensure all local education agencies make adequate yearly progress; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The statewide accountability system included in the plan is based on academic standards, academic assessments, a standardized system of accountability across all local education agencies, and a system of sanctions and rewards that will be used to hold local education agencies accountable for student achievement;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Approve state policies for parental involvement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Approve state policies for supplemental education service providers operating in the District to ensure that providers have a demonstrated record of effectiveness and offer services that promote challenging academic achievement standards and that improve student achievement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Approve the rules for residency verification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Approve the list of charter school accreditation organizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Approve the categories and format of the annual report card, pursuant to NCLB Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Approve the list of private placement accreditation organizations, pursuant to Chapter 29 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Approve state rules for enforcing school attendance requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Approve state standards for home schooling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board shall conduct monthly meetings to receive citizen input with respect to issues properly before it, which may be conducted at a location in a ward.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall consider matters for policy approval upon submission of a request for policy action by the State Superintendent of Education within a review period requested by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall, by order, specify the Board's organizational structure, staff, budget, operations, reimbursement of expenses policy, and other matters affecting the Board's functions; provided, that the Board shall be allocated 3 full-time equivalent staff members to perform administrative functions from within the Office of the State Superintendent of Education. These individuals shall be selected by the Board from a list of at least 3 qualified individuals per position produced by the State Superintendent. The individuals selected and serving shall not be removed except with the approval of both the Board and the State Superintendent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "state" means District-wide and similar to functions, policies, and rules performed by states on a state-wide basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 403, 54 DCR 4102; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4032, 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-111 rewrote subsec. (d), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(d) The Mayor shall, by order, specify the Board's organizational structure, staff, budget, operations, reimbursement of expenses policy, and other matters affecting the Board's functions."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-9, see notes following § 38-2651.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 38-191.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Establishment of the State Board of Education's By laws, see Mayor's Order 2007-214, October 3, 2007 (55 DCR 139).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
