<level type="section">
  <num>47-2826</num>
  <heading>Special events.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Owners, managers, or promoters of carnivals or fairs, by whatsoever name called, conducted for profit or gain, and not held in any building or structure licensed under this chapter, shall pay a license fee of $158 per day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may adjust the license fee set in subsection (a) of this section to cover the costs to the District of providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety. All funds received but not expended in a fiscal year shall revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 626, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 26; July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 554, ch. 366; Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 104(q), 23 DCR 2461; Mar. 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-224, § 2(a), 41 DCR 8055; Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-234, § 2(a), 42 DCR 28; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 105, 44 DCR 1730; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(23), 46 DCR 3142; Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(hh)(4)(M), 50 DCR 6913; Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9034, 58 DCR 6226.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other offices, application of certain sections to boards, commissions and committees, see § 1-321.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-325.81.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2826.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 47-2326.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-38, in subsec. (c), substituted "an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic" for "a Class A Entertainment endorsement to a master business license under the master".</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-21, in subsec. (b), inserted "All funds received but not expended in a fiscal year shall revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 1201(a) of Budget Spending Reduction Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Law 10-253, March 23, 1995, law notification 42 DCR 1652).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 103 of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Law 11-226, April 9, 1997, law notification 46 DCR 2584).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Budget Spending Reduction Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-339, November 22, 1994, 41 DCR 7702) and § 2(a) of the Budget Spending Reduction Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-13, February 28, 1995, 42 DCR 1162).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 107 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996, 43 DCR 4181), and see § 103 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996, 43 DCR 6151).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 103 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997, 44 DCR 1590).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(hh)(4)(M) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003, 50 DCR 6896).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-82</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-82, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2808.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-234</heading>
      <text>Law 10-234, the "Budget Spending Reduction Amendment Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-763, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-377 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-234 became effective on March 21, 1995.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-198</heading>
      <text>Law 11-198, the "Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-741, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 19, 1996, and July 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 26, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-360 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-198 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-261</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-38</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-38, see notes following § 47-2404</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-21</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-21, see notes under § 47-305.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 2(b) of D.C. Law 10-361 provided that the Mayor shall establish by rule a schedule of license fees for special events held on public space to cover the costs to the District providing police, fire, and other public services that are necessary to protect public health and safety.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
