<level type="section">
  <num>47-2814</num>
  <heading>Gasoline, kerosene, oils, fireworks, and explosives.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-2814</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Owners or managers of establishments where gasoline or oils of like grade are sold shall pay a license fee of $17 per annum for each pump used in dispensing said gasoline or oils.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Owners or managers of establishments where kerosene, oils, or gasoline of like grade are stored underground shall pay a license fee of $80 per annum, and where such like grade kerosene, oils, or gasoline are stored in above-ground tanks the license fee shall be $94 per annum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Owners or managers of establishments where kerosene or like grade is kept for sale shall pay a license fee of $19 per annum, and where oil or grease of like grade is kept for sale, the license fee shall be $30 per annum, and where coal is kept for sale, the license fee shall be $94 per annum, and where kerosene, gasoline, or oil is sold through a metering device, the license fee shall be $64 per annum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Owners or managers of establishments where fireworks are stored or are kept for sale at wholesale or at both wholesale and retail shall pay a license fee of $760. Owners or managers of establishments where fireworks are kept for sale at retail shall pay a license fee of $100.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Owners or managers of establishments where explosives of any kind, including ammunition but excluding fireworks, are stored or are kept for sale at wholesale or at both wholesale and retail shall pay a license fee of $760. Owners or managers of establishments where explosives of any kind, including ammunition but excluding fireworks, are kept for sale at retail shall pay a license fee of $47.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under this section without the approval of the Fire Marshal of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 624, ch. 1352, § 7, par. 14; July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 552, ch. 366; Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title I, § 104(g), 23 DCR 2461; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(pp)(11), 46 DCR 3142; Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(hh)(4)(D), 50 DCR 6913.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2814.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 47-2314.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-38, in subsec. (g), substituted "an Environmental Materials endorsement to a basic business license under the basic" for "a Class A Environmental Materials endorsement to a master business license under the master".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(hh)(4)(D) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003, 50 DCR 6896).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-82, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2808.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2801.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-38, see notes following § 47-2404.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
