<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section>47-2843</section>
  <heading>Undertakers' licenses; qualifications; examination; license without examination; authority of Mayor and Council; appropriations; definitions.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 22, 1984, D.C. Law 5-84, § 22(a), 31 DCR 1815.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Funeral directors, licensure, qualifications, applications and examinations, see § 3-405.</text>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other officers, licensing and registration fees, Mayor's power to fix, see § 1-301.74.</text>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other offices, application of certain sections to boards, commissions and committees, see § 1-321.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2843.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 5-84</heading>
      <text>Law 5-84, the "D.C. Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 5-7 which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 28, 1984 and March 13, 1984, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 29, 1984, it was assigned Act No. 5-120 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Repeal of regulations: Section 22(b) of D.C. Law 5-84 provided that the rules and regulations governing the licensing of undertakers and apprentice undertakers within the District of Columbia, promulgated March 23, 1954 (c.o. 54-644; 17 DCMR Chapter 23), are repealed.</text>
      <text>Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers abolished: Section 22(c) of D.C. Law 5-84 provided that the Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers, established pursuant to paragraph (2) of subsection (d) of § 47-2843, is abolished on the date that the final member of the Board of Funeral Directors established under § 3-403 takes office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
