<level type="section">
  <num>26-1401.08</num>
  <heading>Parity of powers of universal bank.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may authorize a universal bank to exercise a power that may be exercised by any other state bank, state or federally chartered savings bank, state or federally chartered savings and loan association, or federally charted national bank.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A universal bank shall file with the Commissioner a written request to exercise a power under subsection (a) of this section. Within 60 days after receiving a request under this subsection, the Commissioner shall approve the request if the Commissioner determines that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The power requested by the universal bank may be exercised by a state bank, state or federally chartered savings bank, a state or federally chartered savings and loan association, or a federally charted national bank; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The universal bank will exercise the power requested in a safe and sound manner.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department and the universal bank may agree to extend the 60-day period under paragraph (1) of this subsection for an additional 60 days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A universal bank shall exercise a power authorized under this section only through a subsidiary of the universal bank, with the appropriate safeguards to limit the risk exposure of the universal bank and to protect the banking customers of the universal bank.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, ยง 208, 48 DCR 3244.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-308, see notes following ยง 26-1401.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
