<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-405</num>
  <heading>Excused performance.</heading>
  <text>Subject to § 28:2A-404 on substituted performance, the following rules apply:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Delay in delivery or nondelivery in whole or in part by a lessor or a supplier who complies with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section is not a default under the lease contract if performance as agreed has been made impracticable by the occurrence of a contingency the nonoccurrence of which was a basic assumption on which the lease contract was made or by compliance in good faith with any applicable foreign or domestic governmental regulation or order, whether or not the regulation or order later proves to be invalid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>If the causes mentioned in paragraph (1) of this section affect only part of the lessor's or the supplier's capacity to perform, he or she shall allocate production and deliveries among his or her customers but at his or her option may include regular customers, not then under contract for sale or lease as well as his or her own requirements for further manufacture. He or she may so allocate in any manner that is fair and reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The lessor seasonably shall notify the lessee and in the case of a finance lease the supplier seasonably shall notify the lessor and the lessee, if known, that there will be delay or nondelivery and, if allocation is required under paragraph (2) of this section, of the estimated quota thus made available for the lessee.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(qq), 44 DCR 1271.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-406.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2A-405.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-128</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:2A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-255</heading>
      <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Uniform Statutory Source:</heading>
      <text>Section 2-615.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes:</heading>
      <text>Revised to reflect leasing practices and terminology.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>"Agreed". Section 1-201(3).</text>
      <text>"Contract". Section 1-201(11).</text>
      <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201(14).</text>
      <text>"Finance lease". Section 2A-103(1)(g).</text>
      <text>"Good faith". Sections 1-201(19) and 2-103(1)(b).</text>
      <text>"Knows". Section 1-201(25).</text>
      <text>"Lease". Section 2A-103(1)(j).</text>
      <text>"Lease contract". Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
      <text>"Lessee". Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
      <text>"Lessor". Section 2A-103(1)(p).</text>
      <text>"Notifies". Section 1-201(26).</text>
      <text>"Sale". Section 2-106(1).</text>
      <text>"Seasonably". Section 1-204(3).</text>
      <text>"Supplier". Section 2A-103(1)(x).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
