<level type="section">
  <num>2-1533.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Commission on Juvenile Justice Reform.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Juvenile Justice Commission ("Commission").</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall be empaneled within 30 days of September 24, 2010.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall be comprised of 12 members, who shall serve without public compensation and who shall be appointed as follows:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Four members to be appointed by the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia, in consultation with the Chairs of the related committees of the Council, one of whom shall be a representative of the public;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Four members to be appointed by the Mayor, one of whom shall be a representative of the public; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Four members to be appointed by the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, one of whom shall be a representative of the public.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Commission shall be selected by the members of the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for appointment as a Commissioner, other than as a member of the public, a person shall have individual expertise in a relevant discipline and familiarity with the laws, standards, and services related to youth safety and juvenile justice reform.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for appointment as a Commissioner as a representative of the public, a person shall not be required to have special expertise of any kind.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Office of the City Administrator shall provide administrative and staff support for the Commission and seek private financial support.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, ยง 5142, 57 DCR 6242.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 5142 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6542).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-223</heading>
      <text>Law 18-223, the "Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-731, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 26, 2010, and June 15, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 2, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-462 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-223 became effective on September 24, 2010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 5141 of D.C. Law 18-223 provided that subtitle O of title V of the act may be cited as the "Commission on Juvenile Justice Reform Establishment Act of 2010".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
