<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.25</num>
  <heading>Board and advisory committees.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless this chapter, the articles of incorporation, or the bylaws provide otherwise, a board of directors may create one or more committees of the board that consist of one or more directors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless this chapter otherwise provides, the creation of a committee and appointment of directors to it shall be approved by the greater of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A majority of all the directors in office when the action is taken; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of directors required by the articles of incorporation or bylaws to take action under § 29-406.24.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Sections 29-406.20 through 29-406.24 shall apply both to committees of the board and to their members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To the extent specified by the board of directors or in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, each committee may exercise the powers of the board of directors under § 29-406.01 except as limited by subsection (e) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A committee shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Authorize distributions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the case of a membership corporation, approve or propose to members action that this chapter requires be approved by members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fill vacancies on the board of directors or, subject to subsection (g) of this section, on any of its committees; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Adopt, amend, or repeal bylaws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The creation of, delegation of authority to, or action by a committee shall not alone constitute compliance by a director with the standards of conduct described in § 29-406.30.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The board of directors may appoint one or more directors as alternate members of any committee to replace any absent or disqualified member during the member's absence or disqualification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may create or authorize the creation of one or more advisory committees whose members need not be directors. An advisory committee shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a committee of the board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Exercise any of the powers of the board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-401.50.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
