<level type="section">
  <num>7-3008</num>
  <heading>Benefits.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>APRA shall formulate guidelines that give priority for enrollment in the Program to any eligible minor, pregnant woman, or the parent, guardian, or other person who has legal custody of a minor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A client with no dependent children shall receive a maximum of up to $20,000 per year, subject to the availability of funds in the Fund. A client with a dependent child shall receive a maximum of up to $40,000 per year, subject to the availability of funds in the Fund and the discretion of the Director of the Department of Health.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Health is authorized to increase the maximum amounts set forth in this subsection to adjust for inflation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By waiver, approved by the Administrator of APRA, expenditures in excess of the maximum amounts stated in subsection (b) of this section may be authorized where good cause is shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to create an entitlement to substance abuse treatment during any fiscal year if no funds remain available to the District government under a District or federal appropriation that has been enacted for the specific purpose of providing substance abuse treatment services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-146, ยง 9, 47 DCR 4350; Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, ยง 5031, 55 DCR 7598.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-219 rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) A client with no dependent children shall receive a maximum of up to $10,000 per year, subject to the availability of funds in the Fund. A client with a dependent child or children shall receive a maximum of up to $25,000 per year, subject to the availability of funds in the Fund."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-146, see notes following ยง 7-3001.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-219, see notes following ยง 7-651.17.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title: Section 5030 of D.C. Law 17-219 provided that subtitle M of title V of the act may be cited as the "Choice in Drug Treatment Maximum Benefit Amendment Act of 2008".</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
