<level type="section">
  <num>7-3014</num>
  <heading>Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established a Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission ("Commission") with the purpose of advising on the implementation of the Program and recommending improvements to its infrastructure to the Council and the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall consider approaches to reduce barriers to meaningful choice in drug treatment by working closely with APRA:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To establish clear access to services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To provide for linkages among providers and other support services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>To assure that services are culturally competent and sensitive;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>To assure that the delivery of services adjusts to changing needs and emerging issues; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>To provide any other assistance that may be required.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall submit its recommendations to the Council and the Mayor in the form of a report, with specific steps for implementing its recommendations, within one year of May 18, 2004, and every 6 months thereafter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall be composed of 13 members as follows:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One representative from APRA, to be appointed by the Mayor for an initial term of 4 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One representative from APRA who specializes in youth treatment and one representative from the Department of Mental Health, to be appointed by the Mayor for initial terms of 3 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One representative from APRA and one representative from the Department of Human Services, Family Services Administration, to be appointed by the Mayor for initial terms of 2 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>One treatment provider who treats youths, one representative from the housing sector who assists homeless persons who have substance abuse problems to obtain housing, and one representative from the medical profession, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 4 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Two treatment providers, one of whom must specialize in the treatment of Latinos with substance abuse issues, and one representative from the employment sector, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 3 years; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>One treatment provider and one client representative, to be appointed by the Council for initial terms of 2 years.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All appointments, following the initial appointments made pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be for terms of 3 years.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All initial appointments made pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made within 180 days of May 18, 2004 .</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A vacancy shall be filled in the same way the initial appointment was made.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The initial Chairperson shall be appointed by the Council from among the members of the Commission. Subsequent chairpersons shall be appointed by the members of the Commission from among the members of the Commission.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Each member shall serve without compensation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chairperson, or the Chairperson's designee, shall convene all meetings of the Commission. Seven members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have the authority to create and operate under its own rules of procedure, consistent with this chapter and Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All recommendations and reports prepared and submitted by the Commission shall be a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have the authority to request directly from each department, agency, or instrumentality of the District government, and each department, agency, or instrumentality is hereby authorized to furnish directly to the Commission upon its request, any information deemed necessary by the Commission to carry out its functions under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Commission is authorized to use space and supplies owned or rented by the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Funding for the Commission's operations shall be subject to annual appropriations, private sector assistance, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-146, ยง 15, 47 DCR 4350; May 18, 2004, D.C. Law 15-155, ยง 2, 51 DCR 3389.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-155 rewrote the section which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"ยง 7-3014. Drug Treatment Choice Advisory Commission.</text>
        <text>"(a)(1) There is established a Drug Treatment Choice Advisory Commission ('Commission') with the purpose of advising the Council and the Mayor on the implementation of the Program and recommending improvements to its infrastructure.</text>
        <text>"(2) The Commission shall consider approaches to reduce barriers to meaningful choice in drug treatment by working closely with APRA:</text>
        <text>"(A) To establish clear access to services;</text>
        <text>"(B) To provide for linkages among providers and other support services;</text>
        <text>"(C) To assure that services are culturally competent and sensitive;</text>
        <text>"(D) To assure that the delivery of services adjusts to changing needs and emerging issues; and</text>
        <text>"(E) To provide any other assistance to APRA that may be required.</text>
        <text>"(3) The Commission shall submit its recommendations to the Council and the Mayor in the form of a report, with specific steps for implementing its recommendations, within 180 days after July 18, 2000, and every six months thereafter.</text>
        <text>"(b)(1) The Commission shall be composed of 11 members as follows:</text>
        <text>"(A) Three representatives appointed by the Mayor; and</text>
        <text>"(B) Eight members appointed by the Council for a term of 3 years, including 2 members representing treatment providers, 2 members representing clients, and 1 member each from the housing sector, the employment sector, human services groups, and the medical profession.</text>
        <text>"(2) The Council appointments shall be made within 60 days of July 18, 2000. A vacancy shall be filled in the same way the initial appointment was made.</text>
        <text>"(3) The Chairperson of the Commission shall be appointed by the Council from among the members of the Commission. This paragraph shall expire one year after the date of the initial appointment.</text>
        <text>"(4) Each member shall serve without compensation.</text>
        <text>"(c) The Chairperson, or designee, shall convene all meetings of the Commission. Six members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.</text>
        <text>"(d) The Commission shall have the authority to create and operate under its own rules of procedure, consistent with this chapter and subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
        <text>"(e) All recommendations and reports prepared and submitted by the Commission shall be a matter of public record.</text>
        <text>"(f) The Commission shall have the authority to request directly from each department, agency, or instrumentality of the District government and each department, agency, or instrumentality is hereby authorized to furnish directly to the Commission upon its request, any information deemed necessary by the Commission to carry out its functions under this chapter.</text>
        <text>"(g) The Commission is authorized to use space and supplies owned or rented by the District government.</text>
        <text>"(h) Funding for the Commission's operations shall be provided by annual appropriations and private sector assistance."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-146, see notes following ยง 7-3001.</text>
        <text>Law 15-155, the "Choice in Drug Treatment Advisory Commission Amendment Act of 2004", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-606, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 3, 2004, and March 2, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 18, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-390 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-155 became effective on May 18, 2004.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
