<level type="section">
  <num>8-111.02</num>
  <heading>Asbestos worker license.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-991.2</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To obtain a license as an asbestos worker, a person shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Industrial Trades that the applicant has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Successfully completed a course of instruction on asbestos abatement that has been approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provided such additional evidence as the Board or the federal government has determined is necessary for the occupation of asbestos workers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Complied with other standards required for licensure by the Non-Health Related Professions and Occupations Licensure Act of 1998.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An asbestos worker license shall expire 2 years from the date of issuance. A license may be renewed for additional 2-year periods if the asbestos worker submits a renewal application with the renewal fee to the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 1, 1990, D.C. Law 8-116, § 3, 37 DCR 1641; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1240, 46 DCR 3142.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-991.2.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 8-116, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-111.01.</text>
        <text>Law 12-261, the "Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-845, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 31, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-615 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-261 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>"The Non-Health Related Professions and Occupations Licensure Act of 1998," referenced in (a)(3), is title I of D.C. Law 12-261.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
