<level type="section">
  <num>50-2651</num>
  <heading>Curb loading zone management program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish a curb loading zone management program ("program"). The purpose of the program is to increase availability and efficiency of curb loading zones and reduce double parking by loading vehicles. The Mayor shall submit rules for this program to the Council pursuant to ยง 50-2652. The program rules may include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establishing loading zone meter fees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Determining minimum curb loading zone space requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Providing for enhanced enforcement, which may include the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Increased fines for violations;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Dedicated enforcement personnel;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Improved signage; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Automated enforcement;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Determining eligibility for use of curb loading zones;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Providing for electronic payment cards; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Establishing requirements for monitoring loading zone performance and for adjusting meter rates, loading zone space requirements, and enforcement to improve performance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall consult with business organizations, residents, and other appropriate stakeholders in developing the curb loading zone management program.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-66, ยง 2, 56 DCR 6608.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-66</heading>
      <text>Law 18-66, the "Commercial Curbside Loading Zone Implementation Amendment Act of 2009", as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-153, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Transportation. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 14, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 28, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-162 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-66 became effective on October 22, 2009.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
