<level type="section">
  <num>16-4602.01</num>
  <heading>Initial child-custody jurisdiction.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § 16-4602.04, a court of the District has jurisdiction to make an initial child-custody determination only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District is the home state of the child on the date of the commencement of the proceeding, or was the home state of the child within 6 months before the commencement of the proceeding and the child is absent from the District, but a parent or person acting as a parent continues to live in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A court of another state does not have jurisdiction under paragraph (1) of this subsection, or a court of the home state of the child has declined to exercise jurisdiction on the ground that the District is the more appropriate forum under §§ 16-4602.07 or 16-4602.08, and:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The child and the child's parents, or the child and at least one parent or a person acting as a parent, have a significant connection with the District other than mere physical presence; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Substantial evidence is available in the District concerning the child's care, protection, training, and personal relationships;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All courts having jurisdiction under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection have declined to exercise jurisdiction on the ground that a court of the District is the more appropriate forum to determine the custody of the child under §§ 16-4602.07 or 16-4602.08; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>No court of any other state would have jurisdiction under the criteria specified in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section is the exclusive jurisdictional basis for making a child-custody determination by a court of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Physical presence of, or personal jurisdiction over, a party or a child is not necessary or sufficient to make a child-custody determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-293, § 2(d), 48 DCR 2214.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 16-4602.02, § 16-4602.03, § 16-4602.04, § 16-4602.08, and § 16-4604.10.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-293</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 13-293, see notes following § 16-4601.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 201 of the Uniform Child Custody Jurisdiction and Enforcement Act (1997 Act).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
