<level type="section">
  <num>4-202.02</num>
  <heading>Administrative duties of Mayor.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 3-202.2</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In accordance with rules issued by the Mayor and approved by the Council, pursuant to § 4-202.05, the Mayor shall administer this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide for maximum cooperation with other agencies rendering services to maintain and strengthen family life and to help applicants for public assistance and recipients to attain self-support or self-care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cooperate in all necessary respects with agencies of the United States government in the administration of this chapter, and accept any funds, goods, or services payable to the District for public assistance and for administering public assistance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Enter into reciprocal agreements with any state relative to the provision of public assistance to residents and nonresidents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 202, 29 DCR 1060; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(c), 46 DCR 905.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 3-202.2.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-230, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 4143).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998, 45 DCR 4270), § 2(c) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998, 45 DCR 5682), § 2(c) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998, 46 DCR 521), and § 2(c) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999, 46 DCR 2492).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-101, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-241, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>District of Columbia Coordinating Committee on Early Intervention Services established: See Mayor's Order 88-183, August 3, 1988.</text>
        <text>Mayor's Committee on Persons With Disabilities established: See Mayor's Order 88-245, November 16, 1988.</text>
        <text>Amendment of Mayor's Order 88-245, dated 11-16-88, Establishment - Mayor's Committee on Persons with Disabilities and Reappointments and Appointments, see Mayor's Order 2002-79, May 3, 2002 (49 DCR 4149).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
