<level type="section">
  <num>38-2021.25</num>
  <heading>Internal Revenue Code limits.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Benefits and contributions under the provisions of this part shall not be computed with reference to any compensation that exceeds that maximum dollar amount permitted by section 401(a)(17) [26 U.S.C. § 401] of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as adjusted for increases in the cost-of-living.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall apply as of October 1, 2002, and shall apply only with respect to an individual who first becomes covered by this part after October 1, 2002.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Benefits shall not be payable under this part to the extent that they exceed the limitations imposed by section 415 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as adjusted for increases in the cost-of-living.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 799, § 25, as added Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 3702, 49 DCR 6968; Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 71, 51 DCR 881.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-105 validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(m) of the Retirement of Public-School Teachers Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-584, January 1, 2013, 60 DCR 134).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-190</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-190, see notes following § 38-1208.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-105</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-105, see notes following § 38-302.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>Section 401(a)(17) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is classified to 26 U.S.C. § 401(a)(17).</text>
      <text>Section 415 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (b), is classified as 26 U.S.C. § 415.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 3703 of D.C. Law 14-190 provided: "This subtitle subtitle A of title XXXVII, §§ 3701 to 3705, of D.C. Law 14-190 is adopted in good faith to comply with the requirements of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001, approved June 7, 2001 (115 Stat. 38; scattered sections of Title 26 of the U.S. Code) ('EGTRRA') and shall be construed in accordance with EGTRRA and guidance issued thereunder."</text>
      <text>Section 3704 of D.C. Law 14-190 provided: "This subtitle subtitle A of title XXXVII, §§ 3701 to 3705, of D.C. Law 14-190 shall apply as of January 1, 2002."</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
