<level type="section">
  <num>26-1334</num>
  <heading>Powers of probate court.</heading>
  <text>The court having probate jurisdiction, or any judge thereof, shall have power to make orders respecting such company whenever it shall have been appointed trustee, guardian, receiver, personal representative, special administrator, committee of the estate of a person with mental illness or an intellectual disability or any other fiduciary, and require the said company to render all accounts which might lawfully be made or required by any court or any judge thereof if such trustee, guardian, receiver, personal representative, special administrator, committee of the estate of a person with mental illness or an intellectual disability or fiduciary were a natural person. And said court, or any judge thereof, at any time, on application of any person interested, may appoint some suitable person to examine into the affairs and standing of such companies, who shall make a full report thereof to the court, and said court, or any judge thereof, may at any time, in its discretion, require of said company a bond with sureties or other security for the faithful performance of its obligations, and such sureties or other security shall be liable to the same extent and in the same manner as if given or pledged by a natural person.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1309, ch. 854, § 746; June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804; June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(a), (b); May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127; July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 576, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 158(c)(4); June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, § 207(h), 27 DCR 2155; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 39(c), 53 DCR 6198; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 23(d), 59 DCR 5567.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 26-434.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 26-334.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-305 substituted "person with mental illness or mental retardation" for "lunatic, idiot," and "lunatic or idiot,".</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-169 substituted "an intellectual disability" for "mental retardation" both times it appears.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-72</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 26-1309.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-305</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-305, see notes following § 26-1309.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
