<level type="section">
  <num>26-1333</num>
  <heading>Security required for performance of fiduciary duties; liability thereon.</heading>
  <text>No bond or other collateral security, except as hereinafter stated, shall be required from any trust company incorporated under this chapter for and in respect to any trust, nor when appointed trustee, guardian, receiver, personal representative, special administrator, committee of the estate of a person with a mental illness or an intellectual disability, or other fiduciary appointment; but the capital stock subscribed for or taken, and all property owned by said company and the amount for which said stockholders shall be liable in excess of their stock, shall be taken and considered as the security required by law for the faithful performance of its duties, and shall be absolutely liable in case of any default whatever; and in case of the insolvency or dissolution of said company, the debts due from the said company as trustee, guardian, receiver, personal representative, special administrator, or committee of the estate of a person with mental illness or an intellectual disability or any other fiduciary appointment shall have a preference.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1309, ch. 854, § 745; June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72,§ 207(g), 27 DCR 2155; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 39(b), 53 DCR 6198; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 23(c), 59 DCR 5567.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 26-433.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 26-333.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-305 substituted "person with mental illness or mental retardation" for "lunatic or idiot" and "lunatics, idiots".</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-169 substituted "an intellectual disability" for "mental retardation" twice.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-72</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 26-1309.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-305</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-305, see notes following § 26-1309.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
