<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-301</num>
  <heading>Persons who take priority over unperfected security interests; right of "lien creditor".</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section, an unperfected security interest is subordinate to the rights of</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Persons entitled to priority under section 28:9-312;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A person who becomes a lien creditor before the security interest is perfected;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In the case of goods, instruments, documents, and chattel paper, a person who is not a secured party and who is a transferee in bulk or other buyer not in ordinary course of business, or is a buyer of farm products in ordinary course of business to the extent that he gives value and receives delivery of the collateral without knowledge of the security interest and before it is perfected;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In the case of accounts, general intangibles, and investment property, a person who is not a secured party and who is a transferee to the extent that he gives value without knowledge of the security interest and before it is perfected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>If the secured party files with respect to a purchase money security interest before or within ten days after the debtor receives possession of the collateral, he takes priority over the rights of a transferee in bulk or of a lien creditor which arise between the time the security interest attaches and the time of filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A "lien creditor" means a creditor who has acquired a lien on the property involved by attachment, levy or the like and includes an assignee for benefit of creditors from the time of assignment, and a trustee in bankruptcy from the date of the filing of the petition or a receiver in equity from the time of appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A person who becomes a lien creditor while a security interest is perfected takes subject to the security interest only to the extent that it secures advances made before he becomes a lien creditor or within forty-five days thereafter or made without knowledge of the lien or pursuant to a commitment entered into without knowledge of the lien.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 754, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 19, 29 DCR 309; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 3(k), 44 DCR 1087; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 26(c), 46 DCR 2118.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:9-301.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:9-301.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:9-102.</text>
        <text>Law 11-240, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Revision Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-576, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-500 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-240 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-264, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:9-115.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
