<level type="section">
  <num>38-1208.04</num>
  <heading>Requirements of short-term plan.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The short-term VEST plan shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A mission statement defining the goals and purposes of VEST;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of existing vocational education and adult apprenticeship courses offered by DCPS and UDC and in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A list of the services and programs to be provided by VEST;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A list of performance standards by which the success of VEST shall be measured;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The identification of all local, federal, private, and other resources, such as personnel, available to support VEST services and programs, including those found within the Department of Employment Services, the Apprenticeship Council, UDC, DCPS, the District of Columbia Workforce Investment Board, and other District of Columbia government agencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Use of identified resources to support VEST;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Suggestions for the establishment of Individual Training Accounts for DCPS graduates of vocational educational programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A strategy for recruiting individuals into the vocational education programs and adult apprenticeship programs offered by VEST;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A plan for the placement of graduates of UDC apprenticeship training programs and vocational education programs, including resources dedicated for the plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Specific recommendations for legislative action by the Council to assist VEST; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Other provisions deemed appropriate by the Advisory Board and consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The short-term VEST plan shall be presented to the Council within 120 calendar days following October 1, 2002, for a 30-day period of review excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within the 30-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 1974, Pub.L. 93-471, title VIII, ยง 804, as added Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, ยง 2202, 49 DCR 6968.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-190, see notes following ยง 38-1208.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
