<level type="section">
  <num>4-1001</num>
  <heading>Burial assistance program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Emergency assistance up to a maximum of $800 is available for burial and cremation services if the liquid assets of the deceased person at the time of death do not exceed $800.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Burial assistance shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to create an entitlement to burial assistance for any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall implement this subchapter within 30 days of the effective date of this subchapter [April 12, 2000], and shall make quarterly reports to the Council Committee on Human Services on the assistance granted under this program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall apply as of April 20, 1999.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 1802; Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 166, 32 DCR 764.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of §§ 1801 and 1802 of the Service Improvement and Fiscal Year 2000 Budget Support Act of 1999, see § 2 of Burial Assistance Program Reestablishment Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Law 13-76, April 5, 2000, law notification 47 DCR 2633).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 2 of the Burial Assistance Program Reestablishment Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-180, November 2, 1999, 46 DCR 9740).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Burial Assistance Program Reestablishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-263, February 9, 2000, 47 DCR 1195).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-91</heading>
      <text>Law 13-91, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1999," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-435, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 2, 1999, and December 7, 1999, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1999, it was assigned Act No. 13-234 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-91 became effective on April 12, 2000.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Act 13-180, the "Burial Assistance Program Re-Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 1999", see Mayor's Order 2000-13, January 21, 2000 (47 DCR 1025).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
