<level type="section">
  <num>47-2884.16</num>
  <heading>Penalties for violation of part; loan declared void; pledge returned.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any individual or any member, officer, director, agent, or employee of any firm, voluntary association, joint-stock company, incorporated society, or corporation who shall violate or participate in the violation of any of the provisions of this part shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or by imprisonment for not more than 90 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any contract of loan in the making or collection of which any act shall have been done which constitutes a violation of any of the provisions of this part shall be void and the lender shall have no right to collect or receive any principal, interest, or charges whatsoever on account thereof. Any person pledging any goods, article, or other thing as security for a loan which is void shall be entitled to the return of such goods, article, or thing without being required to pay any principal, interest, or other charge on account of such void loan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this part, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this part, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of this part shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 6, 1956, 70 Stat. 1042, ch. 970, § 16; Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 439, 32 DCR 4450; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 286(v), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 2-1916.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 2-2016.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-171 enacted this subchapter into law.</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01]" for "of not more than $300" in (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 286(v) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-42</heading>
      <text>Law 6-42, the "Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-187, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 25, 1985, and July 9, 1985, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 16, 1985, it was assigned Act No. 6-60 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>See note to § 47-2881.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>See note to § 47-2808.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
