<level type="section">
  <num>4-261.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Categorical eligibility" means the automatic eligibility for the food stamps program as determined by the enrollment in a separate TANF funded program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Food stamp program" means the federally funded Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"LIHEAP" means the Low Income Home Energy Assistance program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Maximum standard utility allowance" means the maximum level of accepted utility-based income deductions used in determining benefits under the food stamp program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"TANF" means the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, ยง 5081, 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 5081 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 5081 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>Law 18-111, the "Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-203, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 12, 2009, and September 22, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 18, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-255 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-111 became effective on March 3, 2010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 5080 of D.C. Law 18-111 provided that subtitle I of title V of the act may be cited as the "Food Stamp Expansion Act of 2009".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
