<level type="section">
  <num>8-2005</num>
  <heading>Care and use of horses in horse-drawn carriage trade.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An owner, operator, or custodian of a horse engaged in the horse-drawn carriage trade shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not use, work, drive, ride, or require labor from a horse for more than 8 hours in any 24-hour period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide for adequate rest periods for a horse during the 8 hours of use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide the horse with food and drinking water from a clean container of sufficient size and in good condition during the regular intervals during the 8 hours of use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Drape the body of the horse from forelegs to hind legs with a warm covering during times of cold or inclement weather;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Park the horse in an area of shade whenever practicable during rest periods;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Not overdrive or overload a horse as evidenced by physical stress, strain, or exhaustion of the horse; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Not beat or prod a horse to maintain a fast gait in any way that will cause pain or injury to the horse.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An owner, operator, or custodian of a horse engaged in the horse-drawn carriage trade shall not use a horse to draw a carriage unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The horse is in good health in accordance with standards established by the Mayor by rule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The horse weighs at least 1,100 pounds; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The hooves of the horse are properly shod and trimmed utilizing rubber compound shoes on the front 2 hooves and either rubber or open steel borium cork tip shoes on the 2 rear hooves.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 7, 1991, D.C. Law 8-224, § 6, 38 DCR 207; Feb. 5, 1994, D.C. Law 10-68, § 16(b), 40 DCR 6311.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 8-2003.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-1035.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 8-224</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 8-224, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-2001.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-68</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-68, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-2003.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
