<level type="section">
  <num>28:1-201</num>
  <heading>General definitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:1-201</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Subject to additional definitions contained in the subsequent articles of this subtitle which are applicable to specific articles or parts thereof, and unless the context otherwise requires, in this subtitle:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Action" in the sense of a judicial proceeding includes recoupment, counterclaim, set-off, suit in equity and any other proceedings in which rights are determined.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Aggrieved party" means a party entitled to resort to a remedy.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Agreement" means the bargain of the parties in fact as found in their language or by implication from other circumstances including course of dealing or usage of trade or course of performance as provided in this subtitle (sections 28:1-205 and 28:2-208). Whether an agreement has legal consequences is determined by the provisions of this subtitle, if applicable; otherwise by the law of contracts (section 28:1-103). (Compare "Contract".)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Bank" means any person engaged in the business of banking.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Bearer" means the person in possession of an instrument, document of title, or certificated security payable to bearer or indorsed in blank.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Bill of lading" means a document evidencing the receipt of goods for shipment issued by a person engaged in the business of transporting or forwarding goods, and includes an airbill. "Airbill" means a document serving for air transportation as a bill of lading does for marine or rail transportation, and includes an air consignment note or air waybill.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Branch" includes a separately incorporated foreign branch of a bank.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Burden of establishing" a fact means the burden of persuading the triers of fact that the existence of the fact is more probable than its non-existence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Buyer in ordinary course of business" means a person that buys goods in good faith, without knowledge that the sale violates the rights of another person in the goods, and in the ordinary course from a person, other than a pawnbroker, in the business of selling goods of that kind. A person buys goods in the ordinary course if the sale to the person comports with the usual or customary practices in the kind of business in which the seller is engaged or with the seller's own usual or customary practices. A person that sells oil, gas, or other minerals at the wellhead or minehead is a person in the business of selling goods of that kind. A buyer in ordinary course of business may buy for cash, by exchange of other property, or on secured or unsecured credit, and may acquire goods or documents of title under a preexisting contract for sale. Only a buyer that takes possession of the goods or has a right to recover the goods from the seller under Article 2 may be a buyer in ordinary course of business. A person that acquires goods in a transfer in bulk or as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a money debt is not a buyer in ordinary course of business.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Conspicuous": A term or clause is conspicuous when it is so written that a reasonable person against whom it is to operate ought to have noticed it. A printed heading in capitals (as: Non-Negotiable Bill of Lading) is conspicuous. Language in the body of a form is "conspicuous" if it is in larger or other contrasting type or color. But in a telegram any stated term is "conspicuous". Whether a term or clause is "conspicuous" or not is for decision by the court.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Contract" means the total legal obligation which results from the parties' agreement as affected by this subtitle and any other applicable rules of law. (Compare "Agreement".)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Creditor" includes a general creditor, a secured creditor, a lien creditor and any representative of creditors, including an assignee for the benefit of creditors, a trustee in bankruptcy, a receiver in equity and an executor or administrator of an insolvent debtor's or assignor's estate.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Defendant" includes a person in the position of defendant in a cross-action or counterclaim.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Delivery" with respect to instruments, documents of title, chattel paper, or certificated securities means voluntary transfer of possession.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14a)</num>
      <text>"District" means the District of Columbia; and "state" includes the District.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Document of title" includes bill of lading, dock warrant, dock receipt, warehouse receipt or order for the delivery of goods, and also any other document which in the regular course of business or financing is treated as adequately evidencing that the person in possession of it is entitled to receive, hold and dispose of the document and the goods it covers. To be a document of title a document must purport to be issued by or addressed to a bailee and purport to cover goods in the bailee's possession which are either identified or are fungible portions of an identified mass.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"Fault" means wrongful act, omission or breach.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>"Fungible" with respect to goods or securities means goods or securities of which any unit is, by nature or usage of trade, the equivalent of any other like unit. Goods which are not fungible shall be deemed fungible for the purposes of this subtitle to the extent that under a particular agreement or document unlike units are treated as equivalents.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>"Genuine" means free of forgery or counterfeiting.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>"Good faith" means honesty in fact in the conduct or transaction concerned.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>"Holder", with respect to a negotiable instrument, means the person in possession if the instrument is payable to bearer or, in the case of an instrument payable to an identified person, if the identified person is in possession. The term "holder", with respect to a document of title, means the person in possession if the goods are deliverable to bearer or to the order of the person in possession.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>To "honor" is to pay or to accept and pay, or where a credit so engages to purchase or discount a draft complying with the terms of the credit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>"Insolvency proceedings" includes any assignment for the benefit of creditors or other proceedings intended to liquidate or rehabilitate the estate of the person involved.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>A person is "insolvent" who either has ceased to pay his debts in the ordinary course of business or cannot pay his debts as they become due or is insolvent within the meaning of the federal bankruptcy law.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(24)</num>
      <text>"Money" means a medium of exchange authorized or adopted by a domestic or foreign government and includes a monetary unit of account established by an intergovernmental organization or by agreement between 2 or more nations.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(25)</num>
      <text>A person has "notice" of a fact when:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>he has actual knowledge of it; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>he has received a notice or notification of it; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>from all the facts and circumstances known to him at the time in question he has reason to know that it exists.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <text>A person "knows" or has "knowledge" of a fact when he has actual knowledge of it. "Discover" or "learn" or a word or phrase of similar import refers to knowledge rather than to reason to know. The time and circumstances under which a notice or notification may cease to be effective are not determined by this subtitle.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(26)</num>
      <text>A person "notifies" or "gives" a notice or notification to another by taking such steps as may be reasonably required to inform the other in ordinary course whether or not such other actually comes to know of it. A person "receives" a notice or notification when:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>it comes to his attention; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>it is duly delivered at the place of business through which the contract was made or at any other place held out by him as the place for receipt of such communications.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(27)</num>
      <text>Notice, knowledge or a notice or notification received by an organization is effective for a particular transaction from the time when it is brought to the attention of the individual conducting that transaction, and in any event from the time when it would have been brought to his attention if the organization had exercised due diligence. An organization exercises due diligence if it maintains reasonable routines for communicating significant information to the person conducting the transaction and there is reasonable compliance with the routines. Due diligence does not require an individual acting for the organization to communicate information unless the communication is part of his regular duties or unless he has reason to know of the transaction and that the transaction would be materially affected by the information.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(28)</num>
      <text>"Organization" includes a corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, estate, trust, partnership or association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(29)</num>
      <text>"Party", as distinct from "third party", means a person who has engaged in a transaction or made an agreement within this subtitle.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(30)</num>
      <text>"Person" includes an individual or an organization (see section 28:1- 102).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(31)</num>
      <text>"Presumption" or "presumed" means that the trier of fact must find the existence of the fact presumed unless and until evidence is introduced which would support a finding of its nonexistence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(32)</num>
      <text>"Purchase" includes taking by sale, discount, negotiation, mortgage, pledge, lien, security interest, issue or re-issue, gift or any other voluntary transaction creating an interest in property.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(33)</num>
      <text>"Purchaser" means a person who takes by purchase.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(34)</num>
      <text>"Remedy" means any remedial right to which an aggrieved party is entitled with or without resort to tribunal.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(35)</num>
      <text>"Representative" includes an agent, an officer of a corporation or association, and a trustee, executor or administrator of an estate, or any other person empowered to act for another.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(36)</num>
      <text>"Rights" includes remedies.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(37)</num>
      <text>"Security interest" means an interest in personal property or fixtures which secures payment or performance of an obligation. The term also includes any interest of a consignor and a buyer of accounts, chattel paper, a payment intangible, or a promissory note in a transaction that is subject to Article 9. The special property interest of a buyer of goods on identification of those goods to a contract for sale under § 28:2-401 is not a "security interest", but a buyer may also acquire a "security interest" by complying with Article 9. Except as otherwise provided in § 28:2-505, the right of a seller or lessor of goods under Article 2 or 2A to retain or acquire possession of the goods is not a "security interest", but a seller or lessor may also acquire a security interest by complying with Article 9. The retention or reservation of title by a seller of goods notwithstanding shipment or delivery to the buyer (§ 28:2- 401) is limited in effect to a reservation of a "security interest".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(38)</num>
      <text>"Send" in connection with any writing or notice means to deposit in the mail or deliver for transmission by any other usual means of communication with postage or cost of transmission provided for and properly addressed and in the case of an instrument to an address specified thereon or otherwise agreed, or if there be none to any address reasonable under the circumstances. The receipt of any writing or notice within the time at which it would have arrived if properly sent has the effect of a proper sending.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(39)</num>
      <text>"Signed" includes any symbol executed or adopted by a party with present intention to authenticate a writing.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(40)</num>
      <text>"Surety" includes guarantor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(41)</num>
      <text>"Telegram" includes a message transmitted by radio, teletype, cable, any mechanical method of transmission, or the like.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(42)</num>
      <text>"Term" means that portion of an agreement which relates to a particular matter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(43)</num>
      <text>"Unauthorized signature" means one made without actual, implied, or apparent authority and includes a forgery.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(44)</num>
      <text>"Value". Except as otherwise provided with respect to negotiable instruments and bank collections (sections 28:3-303, 28:4-210 and 28:4-211) a person gives "value" for rights if he acquires them:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>in return for a binding commitment to extend credit or for the extension of immediately available credit whether or not drawn upon and whether or not a charge-back is provided for in the event of difficulties in collection; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a pre-existing claim; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>by accepting delivery pursuant to a pre-existing contract for purchase; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>generally, in return for any consideration sufficient to support a simple contract.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(45)</num>
      <text>"Warehouse receipt" means a receipt issued by a person engaged in the business of storing goods for hire.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(46)</num>
      <text>"Written" or "writing" includes printing, typewriting or any other intentional reduction to tangible form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 632, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 679, Pub. L. 88-509, § 4; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 3, 29 DCR 309; July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(c)(2), 39 DCR 3830; Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 2, 39 DCR 9165; Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(b)(1), 42 DCR 467; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(jj), 44 DCR 1271; Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(b)(2), 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision, Changes and New Matter:</heading>
        <text>1. "Action". See similar definitions in Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law; Section 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act. The definition has been rephrased and enlarged.</text>
        <text>2. "Aggrieved party". New.</text>
        <text>3. "Agreement". New. As used in this Act the word is intended to include full recognition of usage of trade, course of dealing, course of performance and the surrounding circumstances as effective parts thereof, and of any agreement permitted under the provisions of this Act to displace a stated rule of law.</text>
        <text>4. "Bank". See Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law.</text>
        <text>5. "Bearer". From Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law. The prior definition has been broadened.</text>
        <text>6. "Bill of Lading". See similar definitions in Section 1, Uniform Bills of Lading Act. The definition has been enlarged to include freight forwarders' bills and bills issued by contract carriers as well as those issued by common carriers. The definition of airbill is new.</text>
        <text>7. "Branch". New.</text>
        <text>8. "Burden of establishing a fact". New.</text>
        <text>9. "Buyer in ordinary course of business". From Section 1, Uniform Trusts Receipts Act. The definition has been expanded to make clear the type of person protected. Its major significance lies in Section 2-403 and in the Article on Secured Transactions (Article 9).</text>
        <text>The first sentence of paragraph (9) makes clear that a buyer from a pawnbroker cannot be a buyer in ordinary course of business. The second sentence tracks Section 6-102(1)(m). It explains what it means to buy "in the ordinary course." The penultimate sentence prevents a buyer that does not have the right to possession as against the seller from being a buyer in ordinary course of business. Concerning when a buyer obtains possessory rights, see Sections 2-502 and 2-716. However, the penultimate sentence is not intended to affect a buyer's status as a buyer is ordinary course of business in cases (such as a "drop shipment") involving delivery by the seller to a person buying from the buyer or a donee from the buyer. The requirement relates to whether as against the seller the buyer or one taking through the buyer has possessory rights.</text>
        <text>10. "Conspicuous". New. This is intended to indicate some of the methods of making a term attention-calling. But the test is whether attention can reasonably be expected to be called to it.</text>
        <text>11. "Contract". New. But see Sections 3 and 71, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
        <text>12. "Creditor". New.</text>
        <text>13. "Defendant". From Section 76, Uniform Sales Act. Rephrased.</text>
        <text>14. "Delivery". Section 76, Uniform Sales Act, Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law, Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act and Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
        <text>15. "Document of title". From Section 76, Uniform Sales Act, but rephrased to eliminate certain ambiguities. Thus, by making it explicit that the obligation or designation of a third party as "bailee" is essential to a document of title, this definition clearly rejects any such result as obtained in Hixson v. Ward, 254 Ill.App. 505 (1929), which treated a conditional sales contract as a document of title. Also the definition is left open so that new types of documents may be included. It is unforeseeable what documents may one day serve the essential purpose now filled by warehouse receipts and bills of lading. Truck transport has already opened up problems which do not fit the patterns of practice resting upon the assumption that a draft can move through banking channels faster than the goods themselves can reach their destination. There lie ahead air transport and such probabilities as teletype transmission of what may some day be regarded commercially as "Documents of Title". The definition is stated in terms of the function of the documents with the intention that any document which gains commercial recognition as accomplishing the desired result shall be included within its scope. Fungible goods are adequately identified within the language of the definition by identification of the mass of which they are a part.</text>
        <text>Dock warrants were within the Sales Act definition of document of title apparently for the purpose of recognizing a valid tender by means of such paper. In current commercial practice a dock warrant or receipt is a kind of interim certificate issued by steamship companies upon delivery of the goods at the dock, entitling a designated person to have issued to him at the company's office a bill of lading. The receipt itself is invariably nonnegotiable in form although it may indicate that a negotiable bill is to be forthcoming. Such a document is not within the general compass of the definition, although trade usage may in some cases entitle such paper to be treated as a document of title. If the dock receipt actually represents a storage obligation undertaken by the shipping company, then it is a warehouse receipt within this Section regardless of the name given to the instrument.</text>
        <text>The goods must be "described", but the description may be by marks or labels and may be qualified in such a way as to disclaim personal knowledge of the issuer regarding contents or condition. However, baggage and parcel checks and similar "tokens" of storage which identify stored goods only as those received in exchange for the token are not covered by this Article.</text>
        <text>The definition is broad enough to include an airway bill.</text>
        <text>16. "Fault". From Section 76, Uniform Sales Act.</text>
        <text>17. "Fungible". See Sections 5, 6 and 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act. Fungibility of goods "by agreement" has been added for clarity and accuracy. Amendment approved by the Permanent Editorial Board for Uniform Commercial Code November 4, 1995.</text>
        <text>18. "Genuine". New.</text>
        <text>19. "Good faith". See Section 76(2), Uniform Sales Act; Section 58(2), Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 53(2), Uniform Bills of Lading Act; Section 22(2), Uniform Stock Transfer Act. "Good faith", whenever it is used in the Code, means at least what is here stated. In certain Articles, by specific provision, additional requirements are made applicable. See, e.g., Secs. 2-103(1)(b), 7-404. To illustrate, in the Article on Sales, Section 2-103, good faith is expressly defined as including in the case of a merchant observance of reasonable commercial standards of fair dealing in the trade, so that throughout that Article wherever a merchant appears in the case an inquiry into his observance of such standards is necessary to determine his good faith.</text>
        <text>20. "Holder". See similar definitions in Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law; Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
        <text>21. "Honor". New.</text>
        <text>22. "Insolvency proceedings". New.</text>
        <text>23. "Insolvent". Section 76(3), Uniform Sales Act. The three tests of insolvency--"ceased to pay his debts in the ordinary course of business," "cannot pay his debts as they become due," and "insolvent within the meaning of the federal bankruptcy law"--are expressly set up as alternative tests and must be approached from a commercial standpoint.</text>
        <text>24. "Money". Section 6(5), Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law. The test adopted is that of sanction of government, whether by authorization before issue or adoption afterward, which recognizes the circulating medium as a part of the official currency of that government. The narrow view that money is limited to legal tender is rejected.</text>
        <text>25. "Notice". New. Compare N.I.L. Sec. 56. Under the definition a person has notice when he has received a notification of the fact in question. But by the last sentence the act leaves open the time and circumstances under which notice or notification may cease to be effective. Therefore such cases as Graham v. White-Phillips Co., 296 U.S. 27, 56 S.Ct. 21, 80 L.Ed. 20 (1935), are not overruled.</text>
        <text>26. "Notifies". New. This is the word used when the essential fact is the proper dispatch of the notice, not its receipt. Compare "Send". When the essential fact is the other party's receipt of the notice, that is stated. The second sentence states when a notification is received.</text>
        <text>27. New. This makes clear that reason to know, knowledge, or a notification, although "received" for instance by a clerk in Department A of an organization, is effective for a transaction conducted in Department B only from the time when it was or should have been communicated to the individual conducting that transaction.</text>
        <text>28. "Organization". This is the definition of every type of entity or association, excluding an individual, acting as such. Definitions of "person" were included in Section 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law; Section 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act; Section 22, Uniform Stock Transfer Act; Section 1, Uniform Trust Receipts Act. The definition of "organization" given here includes a number of entities or associations not specifically mentioned in prior definition of "person", namely, government, governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, trust and estate.</text>
        <text>29. "Party". New. Mention of a party includes, of course, a person acting through an agent. However, where an agent comes into opposition or contrast to his principal, particular account is taken of that situation.</text>
        <text>30. "Person". See Comment to definition of "Organization". The reference to Section 1-102 is to subsection (5) of that section.</text>
        <text>31. "Presumption". New.</text>
        <text>32. "Purchase". Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act; Section 22, Uniform Stock Transfer Act; Section 1, Uniform Trust Receipts Act. Rephrased. With the addition of taking "by ... security interest," the revised definition makes explicit what formerly was implicit.</text>
        <text>33. "Purchaser". Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act; Section 22, Uniform Stock Transfer Act; Section 1, Uniform Trust Receipts Act. Rephrased.</text>
        <text>34. "Remedy". New. The purpose is to make it clear that both remedy and rights (as defined) include those remedial rights of "self help" which are among the most important bodies of rights under this Act, remedial rights being those to which an aggrieved party can resort on his own motion.</text>
        <text>35. "Representative". New.</text>
        <text>36. "Rights". New. See Comment to "Remedy".</text>
        <text>37. "Security Interest". See Section 1, Uniform Trust Receipts Act. The definition of "security interest" was revised in connection with the promulgation of Article 2A and also to take account of the expanded scope of Article 9 as revised in the 1998 Official Text. It includes the interest of a consignor and the interest of a buyer of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes. See Section 9-109. It also makes clear that, with certain exceptions, in rem rights of sellers and lessors under Articles 2 and 2A are not "security interests." Among the rights that are not security interests are the right to withhold delivery under Section 2- 702(1), 2-703(a), or 2A-525, the right to stop delivery under Section 2- 705 or 2A-526, and the right to reclaim under Section 2-507(2) or 2- 702(2).</text>
        <text>One of the reasons it was decided to codify the law with respect to leases was to resolve an issue that has created considerable confusion in the courts: what is a lease? The confusion exists, in part, due to the last two sentences of the definition of security interest in the 1978 Official Text of the Act. Section 1-201(37). The confusion is compounded by the rather considerable change in the federal, state and local tax laws and accounting rules as they relate to leases of goods. The answer is important because the definition of lease determines not only the rights and remedies of the parties to the lease but also those of third parties. If a transaction creates a lease and not a security interest, the lessee's interest in the goods is limited to its leasehold estate; the residual interest in the goods belongs to the lessor. This has significant implications to the lessee's creditors. "On common law theory, the lessor, since he has not parted with title, is entitled to full protection against the lessee's creditors and trustee in bankruptcy ...." 1 G. Gilmore, Security Interests in Personal Property § 3.6, at 76 (1965).</text>
        <text>Under pre-Act chattel security law there was generally no requirement that the lessor file the lease, a financing statement, or the like, to enforce the lease agreement against the lessee or any third party; the Article on Secured Transactions (Article 9) did not change the common law in that respect. Coogan, Leasing and the Uniform Commercial Code, in Equipment Leasing-- Leveraged Leasing 681, 700 n.25, 729 n.80 (2d ed.1980). The Article on Leases (Article 2A) has not changed the law in that respect, except for leases of fixtures. Section 2A-309. An examination of the common law will not provide an adequate answer to the question of what is a lease. The definition of security interest in Section 1-201(37) of the 1978 Official Text of the Act provides that the Article on Secured Transactions (Article 9) governs security interests disguised as leases, i.e., leases intended as security; however, the definition is vague and outmoded.</text>
        <text>Lease is defined in Article 2A as a transfer of the right to possession and use of goods for a term, in return for consideration. Section 2A-103(1)(j). The definition continues by stating that the retention or creation of a security interest is not a lease. Thus, the task of sharpening the line between true leases and security interests disguised as leases continues to be a function of this section.</text>
        <text>The first paragraph of this definition is a revised version of the first five sentences of the 1978 Official Text of Section 1-201(37). The changes are modest in that they make a style change in the fourth sentence and delete the reference to lease in the fifth sentence. The balance of this definition is new, although it preserves elements of the last two sentences of the prior definition. The focus of the changes was to draw a sharper line between leases and security interests disguised as leases to create greater certainty in commercial transactions.</text>
        <text>Prior to this amendment, Section 1-201(37) provided that whether a lease was intended as security (i.e., a security interest disguised as a lease) was to be determined from the facts of each case; however, (a) the inclusion of an option to purchase did not itself make the lease one intended for security, and (b) an agreement that upon compliance with the terms of the lease the lessee would become, or had the option to become, the owner of the property for no additional consideration, or for a nominal consideration, did make the lease one intended for security.</text>
        <text>Reference to the intent of the parties to create a lease or security interest has led to unfortunate results. In discovering intent, the courts have relied upon factors that were thought to be more consistent with sales or loans than leases. Most of these criteria, however, are as applicable to true leases as to security interests. Examples include the typical net lease provisions, a purported lessor's lack of storage facilities or its character as a financing party rather than a dealer in goods. Accordingly, amended Section 1-201(37) deletes all reference to the parties' intent.</text>
        <text>The second paragraph of the new definition is taken from Section 1(2) of the Uniform Conditional Sales Act (act withdrawn 1943), modified to reflect current leasing practice. Thus, reference to the case law prior to this Act will provide a useful source of precedent. Gilmore, Security Law, Formalism and Article 9, 47 Neb.L.Rev. 659, 671 (1968). Whether a transaction creates a lease or a security interest continues to be determined by the facts of each case. The second paragraph further provides that a transaction creates a security interest if the lessee has an obligation to continue paying consideration for the term of the lease, if the obligation is not terminable by the lessee (thus correcting early statutory gloss, e.g., In re Royer's Bakery, Inc., 1 U.C.C. Rep.Serv. (Callaghan) 342 (Bankr.E.D.Pa.1963)) and if one of four additional tests is met. The first of these four tests, subparagraph (a), is that the original lease term is equal to or greater than the remaining economic life of the goods. The second of these tests, subparagraph (b), is that the lessee is either bound to renew the lease for the remaining economic life of the goods or to become the owner of the goods. In re Gehrke Enters., 1 Bankr. 647, 651-52 (Bankr.W.D.Wis.1979). The third of these tests, subparagraph (c), is whether the lessee has an option to renew the lease for the remaining economic life of the goods for no additional consideration or for nominal additional consideration, which is defined later in this section. In re Celeryvale Transp., 44 Bankr. 1007, 1014-15 (Bankr.E.D.Tenn.1984). The fourth of these tests, subparagraph (d), is whether the lessee has an option to become the owner of the goods for no additional consideration or for nominal additional consideration. All of these tests focus on economics, not the intent of the parties. In re Berge, 32 Bankr. 370, 371-73 (Bankr.W.D.Wis.1983).</text>
        <text>The focus on economics is reinforced by the next paragraph, which is new. It states that a transaction does not create a security interest merely because the transaction has certain characteristics listed therein. Subparagraph (a) has no statutory derivative; it states that a full payout lease does not per se create a security interest. Rushton v. Shea, 419 F.Supp. 1349, 1365 (D.Del.1976). Subparagraph (b) provides the same regarding the provisions of the typical net lease. Compare All-States Leasing Co. v. Ochs, 42 Or.App. 319, 600 P.2d 899 (Ct.App.1979) with In re Tillery, 571 F.2d 1361 (5th Cir.1978). Subparagraph (c) restates and expands the provisions of former Section 1-201(37) to make clear that the option can be to buy or renew. Subparagraphs (d) and (e) treat fixed price options and provide that fair market value must be determined at the time the transaction is entered into. Compare Arnold Mach. Co. v. Balls, 624 P.2d 678 (Utah 1981) with Aoki v. Shepherd Mach. Co., 665 F.2d 941 (9th Cir.1982).</text>
        <text>The relationship of the second paragraph of this subsection to the third paragraph of this subsection deserves to be explored. The fixed price purchase option provides a useful example. A fixed price purchase option in a lease does not of itself create a security interest. This is particularly true if the fixed price is equal to or greater than the reasonably predictable fair market value of the goods at the time the option is to be performed. A security interest is created only if the option price is nominal and the conditions stated in the introduction to the second paragraph of this subsection are met. There is a set of purchase options whose fixed price is less than fair market value but greater than nominal that must be determined on the facts of each case to ascertain whether the transaction in which the option is included creates a lease or a security interest.</text>
        <text>It was possible to provide for various other permutations and combinations with respect to options to purchase and renew. For example, this section could have stated a rule to govern the facts of In re Marhoefer Packing Co., 674 F.2d 1139 (7th Cir.1982). This was not done because it would unnecessarily complicate the definition. Further development of this rule is left to the courts.</text>
        <text>The fourth paragraph provides definitions and rules of construction.</text>
        <text>38. "Send". New. Compare "notifies".</text>
        <text>39. "Signed". New. The inclusion of authentication in the definition of "signed" is to make clear that as the term is used in this Act a complete signature is not necessary. Authentication may be printed, stamped or written; it may be by initials or by thumbprint. It may be on any part of the document and in appropriate cases may be found in a billhead or letterhead. No catalog of possible authentications can be complete and the court must use common sense and commercial experience in passing upon these matters. The question always is whether the symbol was executed or adopted by the party with present intention to authenticate the writing.</text>
        <text>40. "Surety". New.</text>
        <text>41. "Telegram". New.</text>
        <text>42. "Term". New.</text>
        <text>43. Under the former version of § 1-201(43), it was not clear whether a reference to an "unauthorized signature" in Articles 3 and 4 applied to indorsements. The words "or indorsement" are deleted so that references to "unauthorized signature" in § 3-406 and elsewhere will unambiguously refer to any signature.</text>
        <text>44. "Value". See Sections 25, 26, 27, 191, Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law; Section 76, Uniform Sales Act; Section 53, Uniform Bills of Lading Act; Section 58, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 22(1), Uniform Stock Transfer Act; Section 1, Uniform Trust Receipts Act. All the Uniform Acts in the commercial law field (except the Uniform Conditional Sales Act) have carried definitions of "value". All those definitions provided that value was any consideration sufficient to support a simple contract, including the taking of property in satisfaction of or as security for a pre-existing claim. Subsections (a), (b) and (d) in substance continue the definitions of "value" in the earlier acts. Subsection (c) makes explicit that "value" is also given in a third situation: where a buyer by taking delivery under a pre-existing contract converts a contingent into a fixed obligation.</text>
        <text>This definition is not applicable to Articles 3 and 4, but the express inclusion of immediately available credit as value follows the separate definitions in those Articles. See Sections 4-208, 4-209, 3-303. A bank or other financing agency which in good faith makes advances against property held as collateral becomes a bona fide purchaser of that property even though provision may be made for charge-back in case of trouble. Checking credit is "immediately available" within the meaning of this section if the bank would be subject to an action for slander of credit in case checks drawn against the credit were dishonored, and when a charge-back is not discretionary with the bank, but may only be made when difficulties in collection arise in connection with the specific transaction involved.</text>
        <text>45. "Warehouse receipt". See Section 76(1), Uniform Sales Act; Section 1, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act. Receipts issued by a field warehouse are included, provided the warehouseman and the depositor of the goods are different persons.</text>
        <text>46. "Written" or "writing". This is a broadening of the definition contained in Section 191 of the Uniform Negotiable Instruments Law.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:1-201.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:1-201.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-201, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:1-105.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:1-105.</text>
        <text>Law 9-196, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-20, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-321 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-196 became effective on March 16, 1993.</text>
        <text>Law 10-249, the "Uniform Commercial Code--Negotiable Instruments Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-240, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 1994, and December 6, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 18, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 10-396 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10- 249 became effective on March 23, 1995.</text>
        <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:1-105.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
