<level type="section">
  <num>4-1371.04</num>
  <heading>Composition of the Child Fatality Review Committee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall appoint a minimum of one representative from appropriate programs providing services to children within the following public agencies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Department of Human Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Department of Health;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Office of the Chief Medical Examiner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Child and Family Services Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Metropolitan Police Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>D.C. Public Schools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Department of Housing and Community Development; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Office of the Corporation Counsel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall appoint, or request the designation of, members from federal, judicial, and private agencies and the general public who are knowledgeable in child development, maternal and child health, child abuse and neglect, prevention, intervention, treatment or research, with due consideration given to representation of ethnic or racial minorities and to geographic areas of the District of Columbia. The appointments shall include representatives from the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Office of the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia hospitals where children are born or treated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>College or university schools of social work; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Mayor's Committee on Child Abuse and Neglect.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council, shall appoint 8 community representatives, none of whom shall be employees of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Governmental appointees shall serve at the will of the Mayor, or of the federal or judicial body designating their availability for appointment. Community representatives shall serve for 3-year terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Vacancies in membership shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall select co-chairs according to rules set forth by the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall establish quorum and other procedural requirements as it considers necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4604, 48 DCR 6981; Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 36, 51 DCR 881; Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 85(c), 52 DCR 2638.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-1371.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-105, in subsec. (f), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-354, in subsec. (f), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Temporary Act of 2001 (D.C. Law 14-20, September 6, 2001, law notification 48 DCR 9090).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-40, April 25, 2001, 48 DCR 5917).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-82, July 9, 2001, 48 DCR 6355).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-28</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-28, see notes following § 4-344.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-105</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-105, see notes following § 4-204.08.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-354</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-354, see notes following § 4-204.55.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
