<level type="section">
  <num>4-1303.33</num>
  <heading>Civil action to compel disclosure.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who has submitted a request to the disclosing official to release findings and information under § 4-1303.32, and whose request has been denied in whole or in part, may bring a civil action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia ("Superior Court") to compel the disclosing official to release the findings and information as requested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A suit filed under this section shall be set for hearing by the Superior Court at the earliest practicable time and shall be given all possible expedited treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In any suit filed under this section, the Superior Court may order the production of any findings or information improperly withheld from the person seeking disclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The burden is on the disclosing official to sustain his or her action. The court shall determine the matter de novo, and may examine the contents of the requested findings and information in camera to determine whether the findings and information, or any part thereof, shall be withheld under § 4- 1303.32(a)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a person seeking the right to inspect or to receive a copy of findings and information prevails in whole or in part in a civil action filed under this section, he or she may be awarded reasonable attorney fees and other costs of litigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title IIIA, § 333, as added Feb. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-69, § 2(b), 48 DCR 11072.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see section 2(b) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-6, February 13, 2001, 48 DCR 2479).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-191, November 29, 2001, 48 DCR 11233).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of Public Disclosure of Findings and Information in Cases of Child Fatality or Near Fatality Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-286, February 25, 2002, 49 DCR 2317).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-69, see notes following § 4-1303.06.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
