<level type="section">
  <num>34-2410.03</num>
  <heading>Maintenance of private fire hydrants.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority shall have a right of access to inspect, maintain, repair, or replace any private fire hydrant, including the connected water distribution system, in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the identified owner of a private fire hydrant fails to effect the maintenance, repair, or replacement as required in the notice provided pursuant to ยง 34-2410.04(c), the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority may effect such maintenance, repair, or replacement of the private fire hydrant and the connected water distribution system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority shall bill the owner of the private fire hydrant for the cost of the maintenance, repair, or replacement. If the owner fails to pay for the repair, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority shall have the authority to obtain and enforce a lien against the owner of the private fire hydrant in accordance with procedures established by ยง 34-2407.02.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority shall keep and maintain records of all inspections, maintenance, repair, and replacement of a private fire hydrant and shall make the records available to the owner of the private fire hydrant upon request. The records shall be kept and maintained for not less than 10 years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-337, ยง 4, 58 DCR 609.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-337, see notes under ยง 34-2410.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
