<level type="section">
  <num>22-2752</num>
  <heading>Engaging in an unlawful protest targeting a residence.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>It is unlawful for a person, as part of a group of 3 or more persons, to target a residence for purposes of a demonstration:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Between 10:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m.;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>While wearing a mask; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Without having provided the Metropolitan Police Department notification of the location and approximate time of the demonstration.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The notification required by paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection shall be provided in writing to the operational unit designated for such purpose by the Chief of Police not less than 2 hours before the demonstration begins. The Metropolitan Police Department shall post on its website the e-mail and facsimile number by which the operational unit may be notified 24 hours a day, and the address to which notification may be hand delivered, as an alternative, during business hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who violates this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01 or imprisoned for not more than 90 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 26, 2011, D.C. Law 18-374, § 3, 58 DCR 715; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 231, 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 23-581.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" for "not more than $500" in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 231 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-374</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-374, see notes under § 22-2751.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
