<level type="section">
  <num>29-1012.06</num>
  <heading>Winding up.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited cooperative association shall continue after dissolution only for purposes of winding up its activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In winding up a limited cooperative association's activities, the board of directors shall cause the association to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Discharge its liabilities, settle and close its activities, and marshal and distribute its assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Preserve the association or its property as a going concern for no more than a reasonable time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Prosecute and defend actions and proceedings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Transfer association property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Perform other necessary acts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After dissolution and upon application of a limited cooperative association, a member, or a holder of financial rights, the Superior Court may order judicial supervision of the winding up of the association, including the appointment of a person to wind up the association's activities, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After a reasonable time, the association has not wound up its activities; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The applicant establishes other good cause.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a person is appointed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section to wind up the activities of a limited cooperative association, the association shall promptly deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment to the articles of organization to reflect the appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 1206 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act . See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
