<level type="section">
  <num>8-1807</num>
  <heading>Adoption.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not release a dog for adoption unless the person adopting the dog obtains a license as provided in § 8-1804.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not release a female animal over the age of 6 months for adoption unless:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The animal has been spayed; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person adopting the animal has paid the expense of spaying.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not release a female animal under the age of 6 months for adoption unless the person adopting the animal has paid the expense of spaying the animal. The person adopting the animal shall have it spayed before it becomes 6 months of age.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not release a male animal over the age of 10 months for adoption unless:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The animal has been neutered; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person adopting the animal has paid the expense of neutering.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not release a male animal under the age of 10 months for adoption unless the person adopting the animal has paid the expense of neutering the animal. The person adopting the animal shall have it neutered before it becomes 10 months of age.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall refund any money collected for the purpose of spaying or neutering an animal upon proof that the animal has been spayed or neutered by a private veterinarian.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 18, 1979, D.C. Law 3-30, § 8, 26 DCR 765; Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-97, § 2(c), 27 DCR 3523.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-1007.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 6-2407.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-30</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-30, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-97</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-97, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1802.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of authority under Law 3-30, see Mayor's Order 83-206, August 2, 1983.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
