<level type="section">
  <num>29-306.55</num>
  <heading>Determination and authorization of indemnification.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A corporation shall not indemnify a director under ยง 29-306.51 unless authorized for a specific proceeding after a determination has been made that indemnification is permissible because the director has met the relevant standard of conduct set forth in ยง 29-306.51.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The determination under subsection (a) of this section shall be made:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If there are 2 or more qualified directors, by the board of directors by a majority vote of all the qualified directors, a majority of whom shall for such purpose constitute a quorum, or by a majority of the members of a committee of 2 or more qualified directors appointed by such a vote;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By special legal counsel:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Selected in the manner prescribed in paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If there are fewer than 2 qualified directors, selected by the board of directors, in which selection directors who are not qualified directors may participate; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By the shareholders, but shares owned by or voted under the control of a director who at the time is not a qualified director shall not be voted on the determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Authorization of indemnification shall be made in the same manner as the determination that indemnification is permissible; provided, that if there are fewer than 2 qualified directors, or if the determination is made by special legal counsel, authorization of indemnification shall be made by those entitled to select special legal counsel under subsection (b)(2)(B) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
