<level type="section">
  <num>4-752.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of Interagency Council on Homelessness.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established in the District the Interagency Council on Homelessness for the purpose of facilitating interagency, cabinet-level leadership in planning, policymaking, program development, provider monitoring, and budgeting for the Continuum of Care of homeless services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Interagency Council is composed of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The City Administrator, who shall serve as chairperson of the Interagency Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The administrative head of each of the following entities or divisions thereof:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Department of Human Services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Department of Mental Health;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Child and Family Services Agency;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Department of Housing and Community Development;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Department of Health;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>District of Columbia Housing Authority;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Department of Corrections;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Department of Employment Services;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Office of the State Superintendent of Education;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Department of General Services; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Metropolitan Police Department;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A representative of any private entity designated to approve or allocate any grants or contracts, on behalf of the Mayor, for services within the Continuum of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A representative from a minimum of 4 and a maximum of 10 organizations that are providing services within the Continuum of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 2 and a maximum of 5 homeless or formerly homeless individuals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 2 and a maximum of 5 advocates for the District of Columbia's homeless population;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee, and the Chairman of the committee of the Council having purview over homeless services, or his or her designee, both of whom shall be non-voting members; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The administrative head of the Office of Shelter Monitoring, who shall be a non-voting member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All non-government members of the Interagency Council described in subsections (b)(4)-(6) of this section shall be nominated for appointment by the Mayor and approved by the Council. The Mayor shall transmit to the Council, within 90 days of October 22, 2005, nominations of each non-government member of the Interagency Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove a nomination by resolution within the 60-day review period, the nomination shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 4, 52 DCR 8113; Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-262, § 405, 54 DCR 794; Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-296, § 2(d), 54 DCR 1097; Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 5004(a), 55 DCR 7598; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 33(a), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-262, in subsec. (b)(2)(J), substituted "Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency" for "District of Columbia Emergency Management Agency".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-296, in subsec. (b), added par. (8).</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-219, in subsec. (b)(2)(I), substituted "Office of the State Superintendent of Education" for "District of Columbia Public Schools".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171, in subsec. (b)(2)(K), substituted "Department of General Services" for "Office of Property Management".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-35, see notes following § 4-751.01.</text>
        <text>Law 16-262, the "Homeland Security, Risk Reduction, and Preparedness Amendment Act of 2006", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-242, which was referred to Committee on Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 5, 2006, and December 19, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-618 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-262 became effective on March 14, 2007.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-296, see notes following § 4-751.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-219, see notes following § 4-126.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-171, see notes under § 4-205.19m.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title: Section 5003 of D.C. Law 17-219 provided that subtitle B of title V of the act may be cited as the "Housing First and Homeless Services Reform Amendment Act of 2008".</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
