<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.251</num>
  <heading>Schools Technology Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Schools Technology Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of appropriated amounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Fund shall be used to improve technology at District of Columbia Public Schools and District of Columbia Public Charter Schools.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For fiscal year 2014, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall distribute the amounts in the fund to local education agencies ("LEAs") on a per-pupil basis, based on the Fall 2012 audited enrollment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In fiscal year 2015 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall distribute any amounts in the fund to LEAs on a per-pupil basis, based on the audited enrollment for the preceding school year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 10005, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 10005 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 10005 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-325.221.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 10001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Title X of the act may be cited as the "Revised Revenue Estimate Adjustment Allocation Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
