<level type="section">
  <num>50-1703</num>
  <heading>Requirements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The operator of a motor vehicle may not transport any child of less than 3 years of age unless the child is properly restrained in a child restraint seat.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The operator of a motor vehicle shall not transport any child under 16 years of age unless the child is properly restrained in an approved child safety restraint system or restrained in a seat belt. Children under 8 years of age shall be properly seated in an installed infant, convertible (toddler) or booster child safety seat, according to the manufacturer's instructions. A booster seat shall only be used with both a lap and shoulder belt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A parent or legal guardian may transport his or her own child without restraint herein if that person is transporting a number of his or her own children of less than 16 years of age which exceeds the number of passenger positions equipped with safety belts in the motor vehicle. However, an unrestrained child may not be transported in the front seat of a motor vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Automobile rental companies shall be required to inform each customer of the provisions of this chapter and provide educational materials to the customer. The educational materials shall be provided by the Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-194, § 4, 30 DCR 49; Mar. 7, 1992, D.C. Law 9-57, § 2(b), 38 DCR 7283; Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-212, § 2(a), 49 DCR 8137.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 50-1706.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 40-1203.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 14-212 rewrote subsec. (b) and added subsec. (d). Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: "(b) The operator of a motor vehicle may not transport any child between 3 years of age and 16 years of age unless the child is properly restrained in an approved child restraint seat or safety belt."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-194</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-194, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 40-1201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-57</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-57, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50-1701.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-212</heading>
      <text>Law 14-212, the "Child Restraint Amendment Act of 2002", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-214, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 2002, and July 2, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 26, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-458 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-212 became effective on October 19, 2002.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
