<level type="section">
  <num>28:8-404</num>
  <heading>Wrongful registration.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § 28:8-406, an issuer is liable for wrongful registration of transfer if the issuer has registered a transfer of a security to a person not entitled to it, and the transfer was registered:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to an ineffective indorsement or instruction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After a demand that the issuer not register transfer became effective under § 28:8-403(a) and the issuer did not comply with § 28:8-403(b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>After the issuer had been served with an injunction, restraining order, or other legal process enjoining it from registering the transfer, issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the issuer had a reasonable opportunity to act on the injunction, restraining order, or other legal process; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By an issuer acting in collusion with the wrongdoer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An issuer that is liable for wrongful registration of transfer under subsection (a) of this section on demand shall provide the person entitled to the security with a like certificated or uncertificated security, and any payments or distributions that the person did not receive as a result of the wrongful registration. If an overissue would result, the issuer's liability to provide the person with a like security is governed by § 28:8-210.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (a) of this section or in a law relating to the collection of taxes, an issuer is not liable to an owner or other person suffering loss as a result of the registration of a transfer of a security if registration was made pursuant to an effective indorsement or instruction.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 739, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165; renumbered and amended, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:8-406.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:8-404.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:8-404.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-196</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-196, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:8-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-240</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-240, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:8-401.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
