<level type="section">
  <num>28:8-402</num>
  <heading>Assurance that indorsement or instruction is effective.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An issuer may require the following assurance that each necessary indorsement or each instruction is genuine and authorized:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In all cases, a guaranty of the signature of the person making an indorsement or originating an instruction including, in the case of an instruction, reasonable assurance of identity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by an agent, appropriate assurance of actual authority to sign;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a fiduciary pursuant to § 28:8-107(a)(4) or (a)(5), appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If there is more than one fiduciary, reasonable assurance that all who are required to sign have done so; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a person not covered by another provision of this subsection, assurance appropriate to the case corresponding as nearly as may be to the provisions of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An issuer may elect to require reasonable assurance beyond that specified in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Guaranty of the signature" means a guaranty signed by or on behalf of a person reasonably believed by the issuer to be responsible. An issuer may adopt standards with respect to responsibility if they are not manifestly unreasonable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of a fiduciary appointed or qualified by a court, a certificate issued by or under the direction or supervision of the court or an officer thereof and dated within 60 days before the date of presentation for transfer; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In any other case, a copy of a document showing the appointment or a certificate issued by or on behalf of a person reasonably believed by an issuer to be responsible or, in the absence of that document or certificate, other evidence the issuer reasonably considers appropriate.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 742, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 4, 39 DCR 9165; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:8-401.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:8-402.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:8-402.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-196</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-196, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:8-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-240</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-240, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:8-401.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
