<level type="section">
  <num>38-2561.16</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The SEA shall report to the Council annually, on or before the 1st day of the school year, for each nonpublic special education school or program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and location of each nonpublic special education school or program issued or denied a Certificate of Approval by the SEA, including the status of each;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of children assigned to each school or program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any enforcement action that has been taken with respect to the license, Certificate of Approval, or charter of the school or program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any action the school or program has taken, or is taking, with respect to an enforcement action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All incident reports, including any report of abuse, neglect, or use of aversive intervention regarding any student placed by the SEA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any investigation taken by the school or program as a result of an incident, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The time it took to complete the investigation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whether the parents or guardian of the student and the SEA have been informed of the report; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The progress and outcomes of the investigation, including any action taken by the facility; provided, that the information shall not be reported in a manner that violates any applicable provision of federal, state, or local law relating to the privacy of student information.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report shall be made available to the public on the SEA and DCPS Internet sites.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-269, ยง 116, as added Mar. 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-304, ยง 2(e), 55 DCR 12806.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-304</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-304, see notes following ยง 38-2561.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
