<level type="section">
  <num>47-4001</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-4001</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"District" means the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Children at risk" means persons under 18 years of age who have had direct or indirect contact with drugs.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Drug prevention" means a program designed to promote positive self-worth and stress the importance of the avoidance of drug and alcohol consumption.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Fund" means the Public Fund established in § 47-4002, which is responsible for investment and distribution of the funds generated by the tax check-off.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Tax check-off" means the drug prevention and children at risk tax check-off system established in § 47-1812.11b.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-246, § 2, 38 DCR 371; Nov. 20, 1993, D.C. Law 10-56, § 10, 40 DCR 7222; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-236, § 2(d), 46 DCR 660.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-4001.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 8-246, the "District of Columbia Drug Prevention and Children at Risk Check-Off Amendment Act of 1990," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-561, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1990, and December 18, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-330 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>Law 10-56, the "Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Children's Trust Fund Act of 1993," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-114, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 13, 1993 and September 21, 1993, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 1, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 10-109 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-56 became effective on November 20, 1993.</text>
        <text>Law 12-236, the "Drug Prevention and Children at Risk Tax Check-Off, Tax Initiative Delay, and Attorney License Fee Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-706, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-561 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-236 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
