<level type="section">
  <num>22-4007</num>
  <heading>Registration functions of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall have the authority to adopt and implement procedures and requirements for the registration of sex offenders under this chapter. The procedures and requirements may include, but need not be limited to, requirements that a responsible officer or official shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Inform the sex offender of the duty to register and the penalties for failure to register;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtain the information required for registration, which may include such information as the sex offender's name, all aliases used, date of birth, sex, race, height, weight, eye color, identifying marks and characteristics, driver's license number, social security number, PDID, DCDC, FBI and NCIC numbers, home address or expected place of residence, and any current or expected place of employment or school attendance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Obtain a photograph and set of fingerprints of the sex offender;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Obtain a detailed description of the offense on the basis of which the sex offender is required to register, the victim impact statement, the date of conviction or other disposition related to the offense, and any sentence imposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Obtain the sex offender's criminal record and a detailed description of any relevant offense;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Inform the sex offender of the duty to report any change of address, and of any duty to update other registration information, and the procedures for reporting such changes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Inform the sex offender that if the sex offender moves to another state, or works or attends school in another state, then the sex offender also must report this information, and must register in any such state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Require the sex offender to read and sign a form stating that the duties of the sex offender under this chapter have been explained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Inform a person that if the person disagrees with the determination that he or she is required to register or to register for life under this chapter, he or she must follow the procedures set forth in ยง 22-4004.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall have the authority to direct that a sex offender meet with a responsible officer or official at a reasonable time for the purpose of complying with any requirement adopted by the Agency under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall have the authority to ensure that the sex offender registry is updated regularly and that outdated information is promptly removed from publicly available information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 11, 2000, D.C. Law 13-137, ยง 8, 47 DCR 797.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-137, see notes following ยง 22-4001.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
