<level type="section">
  <num>47-2718</num>
  <heading>Public space permits.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall amend from time to time the schedule of fees to be charged by the District of Columbia for the issuance of public space permits for underground excavations, constructing manholes, and connecting sewers, conduits and mains. The Mayor shall amend the schedule by rule to provide for fees in amounts as in his judgment will defray the approximate costs of issuing permits and of performing inspections as may be necessary in connection therewith.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Until the schedule of fees is amended by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, the schedule of fees to be charged by the District of Columbia for the issuance of public space permits for underground excavations, constructing manholes, and connecting sewers, conduits and mains is as follows:</text>
    <level type="form">
      <text/>
      <text class="centered"> Public Space Permit Fee Schedule</text>
      <text class="centered"> UNDERGROUND EXCAVATIONS =te</text>
      <text class="centered"> MANHOLES</text>
      <text> (Except transformer), and valves. For 1 house connection and 1 associated necessary manhole when no other work is included in permit. For constructing a single manhole or gas valve without laying conduit or main. For rebuilding a manhole, including any change in the size, shape, depth, or location of conduit made necessary by the work on the manhole. If a manhole is reduced in size, the conduit may be extended to a new wall, or altered slightly in location or depth to conform to the new manhole location without 
additional charge .....................................................42.00.</text>
      <text class="centered"> SEWER CONNECTIONS</text>
      <text> 
 All sewer connections except those to trunk sewers, when part of 
another job ...........................................................24.00. 
 

 Sewer connections to trunk sewers, when part of another job ....69.00. 
 
 All sewer connections except those to trunk sewers, when not included 
with other work .......................................................39.00. 
 

 Sewer connections to trunk sewers, when not included with other work ...................................................................... 85.00.</text>
      <text class="centered"> CONDUIT OR MAIN</text>
      <text> 

 Conduit and manholes, or main and valves .......................85.00.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, title VI, § 601, 23 DCR 2461; June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 202(b), 30 DCR 2632; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other officers, licensing and registration fees, Mayor's power to fix, see § 1-301.74.</text>
      <text>Mayor, Council and other officers, Mayor's power to increase or decrease fees authorized in § 1-301.74, see § 1-301.75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-301.74, § 47-4607, and § 47-4620.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2718.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 47-2216.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>Section 503 of D.C. Law 13-172 provided: "The amendments made by section 502 of this title to the public rights-of-way rental fees do not preclude the Mayor from further amending these same fees as authorized in section 604 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996 provided that the amended rates, when taken together with the other user fees, charges, and penalties collected pursuant to that section and D.C. Code § 47-2718 do not adversely impact the positive fiscal impact identified in section 506 of this title."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) authorization of fee changes, see § 503 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000, 47 DCR 6574).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 503 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000, 47 DCR 8740).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-82</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-82, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2702.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 5-14</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-14, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2712.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to An Act Making Appropriations to Provide for the Expenses of the Government of D.C. for the FY Ending June 30, 1920 and for Other Purposes; and to the License Fees and Charges Act of 1976, see Mayor's Order 99-158, October 13, 1999 (46 DCR 8841).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 1102 of D.C. Law 5-14 provided that the Mayor shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
