<level type="section">
  <num>16-4208</num>
  <heading>Mediator's disclosure of conflicts of interest; background.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before accepting a mediation, an individual who is requested to serve as a mediator shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make an inquiry that is reasonable under the circumstances to determine whether there are any known facts that a reasonable individual would consider likely to affect the impartiality of the mediator, including a financial or personal interest in the outcome of the mediation and an existing or past relationship with a mediation party or foreseeable participant in the mediation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disclose any such known fact to the mediation parties as soon as is practical before accepting a mediation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a mediator learns any fact described in subsection (a)(1) of this section after accepting a mediation, the mediator shall disclose it as soon as is practicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>At the request of a mediation party, an individual who is requested to serve as a mediator shall disclose the mediator's qualifications to mediate a dispute.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that violates subsection (a), (b), or (g) of this section is precluded by the violation from asserting a privilege under ยง 16-4203.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsections (a), (b), (c), and (g) of this section do not apply to an individual acting as a judge or administrative law judge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This chapter does not require that a mediator have a special qualification by background or profession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A mediator must be impartial, unless after disclosure of the facts required in subsections (a) and (b) of this section to be disclosed, the parties agree otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-87, ยง 2(b), 53 DCR 1075.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-87, see notes following ยง 16-4201.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 9 of the Uniform Mediation Act. See 7A, Pt. II, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
