<level type="section">
  <num>9-203.08</num>
  <heading>Submission of highway plan.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 1 year of May 10, 1988, the Mayor shall submit a report to the Council on the highway plan for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An updated list of each street that has been acquired but has not been improved and does not function as a public right-of-way for vehicles, including the location of the street, the date and method of approval of the street on the highway plan if applicable, and the date and method of acquisition of the street by the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An updated list of each street on the highway plan that has not been acquired by the District, including the location of the street and the date and method of approval of the street on the highway plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A list of each unimproved acquired street and of each unacquired street on the highway plan determined by the Mayor to be no longer necessary for present or future street purposes, accompanied by proposed legislation and supporting documents to close these unimproved acquired streets and to remove these unacquired streets from the highway plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, ยง 308, as added May 10, 1988, D.C. Law 7-106, ยง 2(a), 35 DCR 2170.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 7-448.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-106</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-106, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 9-203.06.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Law 7-106, "New Street or Alley Amendment Act of 1988", see Mayor's Order 88-162, July 11, 1988.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
