<level type="section">
  <num>32-1606</num>
  <heading>Performance based accountability.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Service providers shall be paid only for achieving positive outcomes for participants, such as job placement, job retention and earnings in accordance with the Core Indicators of Performance as described in section 136(b)(2)(A) of the Federal Act, except partial payment to a service provider is permissible when a participant meets the Core Indicator of attaining a recognized credential, pending further payment when the participant enters unsubsidized employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish a performance report with quantifiable benchmarks to assess the full range of programs providing education and training services, including WIA, TANF, Welfare to Work, and Vocational Rehabilitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Council shall evaluate the workforce investment system by using the following factors as relevant for individual programs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount and source of funding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Program entrance and successful completion rates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Employment and wage information for 6 months and one year after completion of the training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The relationship of training to employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Achievement of industry skill standard certification, where it exists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Return on public investment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Employment-related barriers of customers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any other indicators of performance required under the Federal Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-150, ยง 7, 47 DCR 4644; Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, ยง 129(d), 56 DCR 1117.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-353 validated a previously made technical correction by substituting "Council" for "Board".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-150, see notes following ยง 32-1601.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-353, see notes following ยง 32-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
