<level type="section">
  <num>32-1605</num>
  <heading>Labor market analysis.</heading>
  <text>The Council shall conduct a labor market analysis. The analysis shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Identify industries or occupations that have or expect growth, the loss of skilled workers or that have a demand for a subset of workers;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Create a profile and analyze the characteristics of the District's unemployed and underemployed residents, including educational attainment, barriers to employment, geographic concentrations, self-sufficiency needs and access to needed support services;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Identify the entry-level education and skills requirements for the industries or occupations that have or expect a need for workers;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Analyze the entry-level wages and benefits in identified industries or occupations;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Develop a profile of the education, training and support services already in place to prepare workers for the identified industries or occupations;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Identify the mismatch between job seekers and identified industries or occupations where wages and benefits match the needs of the unemployed, in terms of education and training resources; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Identify opportunities for collaboration with institutions of higher education community-based organizations and economic development and welfare agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-150, ยง 6, 47 DCR 4644; Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, ยง 129(c), 56 DCR 1117.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-353 validated a previously made technical correction by substituting "Council" for "Board".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-150</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-150, see notes following ยง 32-1601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-353</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-353, see notes following ยง 32-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
