<level type="section">
  <num>38-822.03</num>
  <heading>Additional requirements for public school meals.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools shall offer free breakfast to all students.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If more than 40% of the students at a school qualify for free or reduced-price meals:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A public elementary school, public charter elementary school, and participating private elementary school shall offer breakfast in the classroom each day;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A public middle and high school, public charter middle and high school, and participating private middle and high school shall offer alternative serving models, such as breakfast in the classroom or grab-and-go carts, in one or more locations with high student traffic, other than the cafeteria, each day to increase breakfast participation; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The requirements of this paragraph shall not apply to a public school or a public charter school in which the school's current breakfast participation rate, without breakfast-in-the-classroom, exceeds 75% of its average daily attendance.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not charge students for meals if the students qualify for reduced-price meals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide meals that meet the dietary needs of children with diagnosed medical conditions as required by a physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Solicit input from students, faculty, and parents, through taste tests, comment boxes, surveys, a student nutrition advisory council, or other means, regarding nutritious meals that appeal to students;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Promote healthy eating to students, faculty, staff, and parents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide at least 30 minutes for students to eat lunch and sufficient time during the lunch period for every student to pass through the food service line; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Participate in federal nutritional and commodity foods programs whenever possible.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools shall make cold, filtered water available free to students, through water fountains or other means, when meals are served to students in public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 203, 57 DCR 4779; Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(e), 58 DCR 6841; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(c), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-37 rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c); in the lead-in language of subsec. (b), substituted "Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools" for "Public schools and public charter schools"; in subsec. (b)(5), inserted "and sufficient time during the lunch period for every student to pass through the food service line,". Prior to amendment, subsecs. (a) and (c) read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a)(1) Public schools and public charter schools shall offer free breakfast to all students.</text>
        <text>"(2) If more than 40% of the students at a school qualify for free or reduced-price meals:</text>
        <text>"(A) A public elementary school and a public charter elementary school shall offer breakfast in the classroom each day; and</text>
        <text>"(B) A public middle and high school and a public charter middle and high school shall offer alternative serving models, such as breakfast in the classroom or grab-and-go carts, each day to increase breakfast participation."</text>
        <text>"(c) Public schools and public charter schools are encouraged to make cold, filtered water available free to students, through water fountains or other means, when meals are served to students in public schools and public charter schools."</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-168, in subsec. (c), substituted "shall" for "are encouraged to".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011, 58 DCR 6814).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(c) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012, 59 DCR 7764).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(c) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-209, see notes following § 38-821.01.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-37, see notes under § 38-821.01.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-168, see notes under § 38-751.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
