<level type="section">
  <num>38-822.04</num>
  <heading>Central kitchen.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools shall establish a central facility in the District to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Prepare, process, grow, and store healthy and nutritious foods for schools and nonprofit organizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Support nutrition education programs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide job-training programs for students and District residents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools shall provide reasonable access to charter schools that wish to use the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department of General Services shall assist the District of Columbia Public Schools in selecting real property for the facility and the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization shall convert the real property into the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>On or before December 31 of each year until the project is completed, the District of Columbia Public Schools, in consultation with the Department of General Services, shall issue a report to the Mayor, the Council, and the Healthy Schools and Youth Commission documenting progress on the development of the central kitchen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 204, 57 DCR 4779; Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(f), 58 DCR 6841; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(d), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-37 added subsec. (d).</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-168, in subsec. (c), substituted "The Department of General Services" for "The Department of Real Estate Services".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(f) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011, 58 DCR 6814).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(d) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012, 59 DCR 7764).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(d) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-209, see notes following § 38-821.01.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-37, see notes under § 38-821.01.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-168, see notes under § 38-751.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
