<level type="section">
  <num>9-202.06</num>
  <heading>Duties of applicant; Mayor to make available signs and prescribe format for written notice.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 7-426</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At least 15 days and no more than 60 days prior to the date of any public hearing to consider an application to close all or part of a street or alley, the applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Give written notice of the date, time, and location of the public hearing to all of the owners of all the property on both sides of the block(s) of the street which abuts the block(s) of that street to be closed or which abuts that entire alley; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Post a sign which indicates the date, time, and location of the public hearing at each end of the block(s) of that street to be closed, or at each entrance from a street to any alley in the square.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At least 15 days and no more than 6 months prior to final consideration by the Council of a proposed resolution to close all or part of a street or alley which has not been the subject of a public hearing, the applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Give written notice of the Council's intent to consider the proposed resolution to all of the owners of all the property on both sides of the block(s) of the street or which abuts that alley; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Post a sign which indicates the Council's intent to consider the proposed resolution at each end of the block(s) of that street to be closed, or at each entrance from a street to any alley in the square.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The applicant shall certify to the Council that the notice required in subsection (a) or (b) of this section has been given. A post office receipt of proof of mailing of the notice to the property owner's last known address and a photograph of each posted sign shall be sufficient proof that the required notice was given.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall make available the signs and shall prescribe by rule a format for the written notice to be given pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 206, 30 DCR 148; Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 30, 35 DCR 147; Sept. 21, 1988, D.C. Law 7-144, § 3(b), 35 DCR 5405; Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 504(b), 45 DCR 1172; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 20, 46 DCR 2118.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 7-426.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-201, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 9-201.01.</text>
        <text>Law 7-104, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1987," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-346, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1987, and December 8, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-144, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 9-202.02.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-86, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 9-202.01.</text>
        <text>Law 12-264, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-804, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 7, 1999, it was assigned Act No. 12-626 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-264 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
