<level type="section">
  <num>47-365</num>
  <heading>Reprogrammings of appropriated funds.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Funds appropriated pursuant to an appropriations act that remain available for obligation or expenditure, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded in an appropriations act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure for an agency through a reprogramming of funds which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Creates new programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Eliminates a program, project, or responsibility center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establishes or changes allocations specifically denied, limited, or increased by Congress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Increases funds or personnel by any means for any program, project, or responsibility center for which funds have been denied or restricted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Reestablishes through reprogramming any program or project previously deferred through reprogramming;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Augments existing programs, projects, or responsibility centers through a reprogramming of funds in excess of $3 million or 10%, whichever is less; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Increases by 20% or more personnel assigned to a specific program, project or responsibility center.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Such funds shall be available for obligation or expenditure for an agency through a reprogramming of funds as described in subsection (a) of this section; provided, that the appropriations committees of both the Senate and House of Representatives are notified in writing 30 days in advance of any reprogramming as set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 4502, 47 DCR 6308; June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-310, § 11(a), 50 DCR 1092; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 122(d), 58 DCR 1008.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-310, in the section name line, deleted "Fiscal Year 2001 and beyond" following "funds"; redesignated the existing text as subsection (a); in the newly designated subsec. (a), deleted "in fiscal year 2001, or any subsequent fiscal year" following "expenditure"; made a nonsubstantive change, and deleted "provided that the appropriations committees of both the Senate and House of Representatives are notified in writing 30 days in advance of any reprogramming as set forth in this section" from the end of par. (7); and added subsec. (b).</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-370 , in par. (6), substituted "$3 million" for "$1,000,000".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 4502 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000, 47 DCR 6574).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4502 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000, 47 DCR 8740).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 122(d) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011, 58 DCR 662).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 13-172, the "Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Act of 2000," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-679, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2000, and June 6, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 26, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-175 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-172 became effective on October 19, 2000.</text>
        <text>Law 14-310, the "Criminal Code and Miscellaneous Technical Amendments Act of 2002", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-954, which was referred to the Committee on Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2002, and December 17, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 22, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 14-622 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-310 became effective on June 12, 2003.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-370, see notes under § 47-143.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
