<level type="section">
  <num>4-402.01</num>
  <heading>Funding for day care provided by D.C. Public Schools.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In Fiscal Year 2004, the Department may transfer no more than $6 million to the D.C. Public Schools for the purpose of funding an after-school day care program pursuant to a memorandum of understanding. The memorandum of understanding shall include the following program requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Participation in the program shall be based on TANF eligibility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Verification of family income shall be required before a child may be enrolled in the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Priority shall be given to children of families actively participating in TANF;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Additional slots shall be allocated on the sliding scale set forth in ยง 4-405(b); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Records documenting the costs of the program shall be maintained and provided to the Department on an annual basis, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Verifiable data establishing the number of children enrolled by the program;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Documentation that each enrolled child met the eligibility requirements for the program; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Reports documenting, for each month of operation, the funds expended in relation to service delivery.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, ยง 3a, as added Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, ยง 2702, 50 DCR 5668.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 15-39, see notes following ยง 4-204.11.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title of title XXVII of Law 15-39: Section 2701 of D.C. Law 15-39 provided that title XXVII of the act may be cited as the Day Care in Schools Eligibility Requirement Amendment Act of 2003.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
