<level type="section">
  <num>1-531.02</num>
  <heading>Budget for Office of Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining.</heading>
  <text>Beginning with the proposed budget for Fiscal Year 2004, the Mayor shall provide in the budget funding for the Office of Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining ("OLRCB") represented as a separate line or responsibility center. The Mayor shall include in the budget request submitted to the Council historical spending information for the OLRCB so that an accurate, complete comparison can be made of the fiscal costs for the OLRCB.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 3803, 49 DCR 6968.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Administration, "employee" defined, see § 2-223.01.</text>
      <text>D.C. Housing Authority, executive director, duties, see § 6-255.</text>
      <text>Department of Corrections, employees, mandatory drug and alcohol testing, grounds for termination, see §§ 24-211.23 and 24-211.24.</text>
      <text>Department of public health, director, see § 7-153.</text>
      <text>Education Licensure Commission, personnel, appointment and compensation, see § 38-1305.</text>
      <text>Election campaigns, conflict of interest, disclosure, see § 1-1106.02.</text>
      <text>Equal opportunity employment, veterans' preference, see § 1-607.03.</text>
      <text>Health occupation boards, compensation of staff set by Mayor, see § 3-1204.07.</text>
      <text>Licensure, non-health related occupations and professions, compensation of boards' support personnel, see § 47-2853.10.</text>
      <text>Management supervisory service, composition, see § 1-609.52.</text>
      <text>Merit system, educational employees, coverage, see § 1-602.03.</text>
      <text>Merit system, effective date provisions, see § 1-636.02.</text>
      <text>Merit system, equal employment opportunity, physically handicapped and developmentally disabled persons, see § 1-607.02.</text>
      <text>Merit system, personnel system, transition, rights and benefits, see § 1-602.04.</text>
      <text>Office of Police Complaints, executive director, duties, application of this chapter, see § 5-1106.</text>
      <text>Public libraries, board of trustees, selection and appointment of professional librarian, see § 39-105.</text>
      <text>Public Parking Authority, Board of Directors, compensation, see § 50-2504.</text>
      <text>Sports and Entertainment Commission, employees not District employees, exempted from coverage, see § 3-1417.</text>
      <text>University of the District of Columbia, Board of Trustees, powers and duties, selecting CEO and staff, approving academic and legal counsel appointments, see § 38-1202.06.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-190</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-190, see notes following § 1-531.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
