<level type="section">
  <num>31-1349</num>
  <heading>Liquidation of property of foreign or alien insurers found in the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 35-2849</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If no domiciliary receiver has been appointed, the Commissioner may apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by verified petition for an order directing him or her to liquidate the assets, found in the District, of a foreign insurer or an alien insurer not domiciled in the District, on any of the following grounds:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any of the grounds in § 31-1310 or § 31-1315; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any of the grounds specified in § 31-1348(a)(2) through (4).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When an order is sought under subsection (a) of this section, the court shall cause the insurer to be given notice and time to respond reasonable under the circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If it appears to the court that the best interests of creditors, policyholders, and the public so require, the court may issue an order to liquidate in whatever terms it shall deem appropriate. The filing or recording of the order with the Clerk of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or the recorder of deeds of the District of Columbia shall impart the same notice as a deed, bill of sale, or other evidence of title duly filed or recorded with that recorder of deeds would have imparted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a domiciliary liquidator is appointed in a reciprocal state while a liquidation is proceeding under this section, the liquidator under this section shall thereafter act as ancillary receiver under § 31-1351. If a domiciliary liquidator is appointed in a nonreciprocal state while a liquidation is proceeding under this section, the liquidator under this section may petition the court for permission to act as ancillary receiver under § 31-1351.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On the same grounds as are specified in subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner may petition any appropriate federal district court to be appointed receiver to liquidate that portion of the insurer's assets and business over which the court will exercise jurisdiction, or any lesser part thereof that the Commissioner deems desirable for the protection of the policyholders and creditors in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The court may order the Commissioner, when he or she has liquidated the assets of a foreign or alien insurer under this section, to pay claims of residents of the District against the insurer under rules concerning liquidation of insurers under this chapter as are otherwise compatible with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 15, 1993, D.C. Law 10-35, § 50, 40 DCR 5773; Feb. 27, 1996, D.C. Law 11-90, § 2, 42 DCR 7155; May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(z)(2), 44 DCR 1730.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 35-2849.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Law 11-36, September 8, 1995, law notification 42 DCR 5305).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Insurance Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-48, May 15, 1995, 42 DCR 2544) and § 2 of the Insurance Omnibus Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-97, July 19, 1995, 42 DCR 3844).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-35, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1301.</text>
        <text>Law 11-90, the "Insurance Omnibus Amendment Act of 1995," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-182, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1995, and December 5, 1995, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 18, 1995, it was assigned Act No. 11-173 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-90 became effective on February 27, 1996.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-268, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
