<level type="section">
  <num>47-1806.09f</num>
  <heading>Tax on residents and nonresidents --Credits --Lower income, long-term homeowner credit --Applicability date; Mayoral certification.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Sections 47-1806.09 through 47-1806.09f shall apply for the income tax years beginning after December 31, 2002.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An eligible resident shall apply for the tax credit under § 47-1806.09a using an application form to be developed by the Office of Tax and Revenue. For tax year 2003, this form shall be developed by the Chief Financial Officer by April 1, 2004.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 401(b), 49 DCR 1468; Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1172(g), 51 DCR 8441.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-205 rewrote subsec. (b) which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) The Mayor shall certify to the Office of Tax and Revenue and to each owner of each property that the owner is an eligible resident, that the property is an eligible residence qualified for the tax credit allowed under § 47-1806.09a, and the dollar amount of the improvements to the property qualifying for the credit. The certification shall specify the record owner; address; full legal description; and the dollar amount of the qualified improvements under this section. The certification shall be delivered to both the qualified property owner and Office of Tax and Revenue on or before the first day the tax year in which the credit is first claimed. In addition, the certification shall be attached to the owner's District of Columbia income tax return to claim the credit."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Low-Income, Long-Term Homeowner's Protection Clarification Temporary Act of 2004 (D.C. Law 15- 161, May 18, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 5701).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Lower Income, Long-Term Homeowner Credit Administration Temporary Act of 2004 (D.C. Law 15-179, September 8, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 9221).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Low-income, Long-Term Homeowner's Protection Clarification Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15- 380, February 27, 2004, 51 DCR 2649).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Lower Income, Long-term Homeowner Credit Administration Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-421, May 10, 2004, 51 DCR 5174).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(g) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004, 51 DCR 8236).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1172(g) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR 11725).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-114, see notes following § 47-857.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-205, see notes following § 47-903.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
