<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section-start>44-1601</section-start>
  <section-end>44-1609</section-end>
  <section-range-type>range</section-range-type>
  <heading>Definitions; expenditure of net appreciation of assets of endowment funds - appropriations authorized; expenditure of net appreciation of assets of endowment funds - restrictions by gift instruments; rule of construction; Investments authorized for institutional funds; delegation of investment authority; standard of care for administration of certain powers; release of restrictions on funds; severability; construction of chapter.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 6, 1977, D.C. Law 1-103, §§ 2-10, 23 DCR 8733; Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 68, 52 DCR 2638; Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 48(e), 53 DCR 6794; Jan. 23, 2008, D.C. Law 17-69, § 11, 54 DCR 11650.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 32-401 to 409.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 32-1201 to 32-1209.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-103</heading>
      <text>Law 1-103 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-139, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 15, 1976, and October 12, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 9, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-172 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-354</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-354, see notes following § 44-212.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-191</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-191, see notes following § 44-151.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-69</heading>
      <text>Law 17-69, the "Uniform Prudent Management of Institutional Fund Act of 2007", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-145 which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 23, 2007, and November 6, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-181 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-69 became effective on January 23, 2008.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Prudent investor rule: Section 2(b) of D.C. Law 12-187 provided that "the prudent investor rule is a default rule that may be expanded, restricted, eliminated, or otherwise altered by provisions of the trust. A trustee is not liable to a beneficiary to the extent that the trustee acted in reasonable reliance on provisions of the trust."</text>
      <text>Uniform Law: These sections were based upon §§ 1-9 of the Uniform Management of Institutional Funds Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
