<level type="section">
  <num>36-302.21</num>
  <heading>Security requirements for retail service stations.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The operator of a retail service station shall install video surveillance equipment to monitor all pumps at the retail service station within 6 months after October 22, 2009. The Metropolitan Police Department shall review the surveillance video in the event of a crime committed at the station.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The operator of a retail service station shall display a warning sign at each pump and at the attendant's duty station that warns:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Always remove the keys from a vehicle;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Lock all doors when exiting a vehicle; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Premises under surveillance.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The measurements for each sign shall exceed 8 inches by 8 inches.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The text for each sign shall be in boldface and shall exceed a 36-point font.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The text and background for each sign shall be in contrasting colors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 19, 1977 D.C. Law 1-123, ยง 3-121, as added Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-65, ยง 2, 56 DCR 6606; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 27, 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171 made a technical amendment to D.C. Law 18-65, ยง 2, that did not change the text of the section.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 18-65, the "Enhanced Security at Gas Stations Amendment Act of 2009", as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-95, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 14, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 28, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-161 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-65 became effective on October 22, 2009.</text>
        <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 20, 2012, and April 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
