<level type="section">
  <num>2-1322</num>
  <heading>Composition.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-2322</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The Commission shall consist of 15 public (voting) members appointed by the Mayor. There shall also be the following ex-officio nonvoting members: The Directors of the Department of Human Services, Department of Housing and Community Development, Department of Recreation, Department of Transportation, Department of Manpower, the librarian of the District of Columbia Public Library, the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department, and the Director of the Department of Licenses, Investigation and Inspections.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 29, 1976, D.C. Law 1-86, title IV, § 402, 23 DCR 2543; June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-285, § 4(j), 46 DCR 1355.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2322.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-1922.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(j) of the Confirmation Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-25, March 15, 1999, 46 DCR 2971).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4(j) of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999, 46 DCR 5330).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-86, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-2301.</text>
        <text>Law 12-285, the "Confirmation Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-261, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 5, 1999, it was assigned Act No. 12-622 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-285 became effective on June 12, 1999.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>Pursuant to Mayor's Order 2000-20, the agency formerly known as the "Department of Recreation and Parks" shall be known as the "Department of Parks and Recreation."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
        <text>The functions of the Department of Transportation were transferred to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</text>
        <text>The functions of the Department of Licenses, Investigations, and Inspections were transferred to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983, effective March 31, 1983.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
