<level type="section">
  <num>22-3132</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Any device" means electronic, mechanical, digital or any other equipment, including: a camera, spycam, computer, spyware, microphone, audio or video recorder, global positioning system, electronic monitoring system, listening device, night-vision goggles, binoculars, telescope, or spyglass.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Any means" includes the use of a telephone, mail, delivery service, e-mail, website, or other method of communication or any device.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Communicating" means using oral or written language, photographs, pictures, signs, symbols, gestures, or other acts or objects that are intended to convey a message.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Emotional distress" means significant mental suffering or distress that may, but does not necessarily, require medical or other professional treatment or counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Financial injury" means the monetary costs, debts, or obligations incurred as a result of the stalking by the specific individual, member of the specific individual's household, a person whose safety is threatened by the stalking, or a person who is financially responsible for the specific individual and includes:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The costs of replacing or repairing any property that was taken or damaged;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The costs of clearing the specific individual's name or his or her credit, criminal, or any other official record;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Medical bills;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Relocation expenses;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Lost employment or wages; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Attorney's fees.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Personal identifying information" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 22-3227.01(3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Specific individual" or "individual" means the victim or alleged victim of stalking.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"To engage in a course of conduct" means directly or indirectly, or through one or more third persons, in person or by any means, on 2 or more occasions, to:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Follow, monitor, place under surveillance, threaten, or communicate to or about another individual;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Interfere with, damage, take, or unlawfully enter an individual's real or personal property or threaten or attempt to do so; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Use another individual's personal identifying information.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 502, 56 DCR 7413.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 502 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009, 56 DCR 6903).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 502 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009, 56 DCR 8668).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-88, see notes following § 22-3131.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
