<level type="section">
  <num>29-312.05</num>
  <heading>Effect of dissolution.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved corporation continues its corporate existence but shall not carry on any business except that appropriate to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Collecting its assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disposing of its properties that will not be distributed in kind to its shareholders;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Discharging or making provision for discharging its liabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Distributing its remaining property among its shareholders according to their interests; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Dissolution of a corporation shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transfer title to the corporation's property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Prevent transfer of its shares or securities, although the authorization to dissolve may provide for closing the corporation's share transfer records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Subject its directors or officers to standards of conduct different from those prescribed in subchapter VI of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Change:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Quorum or voting requirements for its board of directors or shareholders;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Provisions for selection, resignation, or removal of its directors or officers, or both;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provisions for amending its bylaws;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Prevent commencement of a proceeding by or against the corporation in its corporate name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Abate or suspend a proceeding pending by or against the corporation on the effective date of dissolution; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Terminate the authority of the registered agent of the corporation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
