<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-206</num>
  <heading>Termination of storage at warehouseman's option.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-206</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A warehouseman may on notifying the person on whose account the goods are held and any other person known to claim an interest in the goods require payment of any charges and removal of the goods from the warehouse at the termination of the period of storage fixed by the document, or, if no period is fixed, within a stated period not less than thirty days after the notification. If the goods are not removed before the date specified in the notification, the warehouseman may sell them in accordance with the provisions of the section on enforcement of a warehouseman's lien (section 28:7-210).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>If a warehouseman in good faith believes that the goods are about to deteriorate or decline in value to less than the amount of his lien within the time prescribed in subsection (1) for notification, advertisement and sale, the warehouseman may specify in the notification any reasonable shorter time for removal of the goods and in case the goods are not removed, may sell them at public sale held not less than one week after a single advertisement or posting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>If as a result of a quality or condition of the goods of which the warehouseman had no notice at the time of deposit the goods are a hazard to other property or to the warehouse or to persons, the warehouseman may sell the goods at public or private sale without advertisement on reasonable notification to all persons known to claim an interest in the goods. If the warehouseman after a reasonable effort is unable to sell the goods he may dispose of them in any lawful manner and shall incur no liability by reason of such disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The warehouseman must deliver the goods to any person entitled to them under this article upon due demand made at any time prior to sale or other disposition under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The warehouseman may satisfy his lien from the proceeds of any sale or disposition under this section but must hold the balance for delivery on the demand of any person to whom he would have been bound to deliver the goods.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 721, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Section 34, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Rewritten and expanded to define the warehouseman's right to terminate the storage not only where the goods are perishable or hazardous as in Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act, Section 34, but also for any other reason including decline in value of the goods imperilling the warehouseman's security for charges.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>1. Most warehousing is for an indefinite term, the bailor being entitled to delivery on reasonable demand. It is necessary to define the warehouseman's power to terminate the bailment, since it would be commercially intolerable to allow warehousemen to order removal of the goods on short notice. The thirty day period provided where the document does not carry its own period of termination corresponds to commercial practice of computing rates on a monthly basis. The right to terminate under subsection (1) includes a right to require payment of "any charges", but does not depend on the existence of unpaid charges.</text>
        <text>2. In permitting expeditions disposition of perishable and hazardous goods Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act, Section 34, made no distinction between cases where the warehouseman knowingly undertook to store such goods and cases where the goods were discovered to be of that character subsequent to storage. The former situation presents no such emergency as justifies the summary power of removal and sale. Subsections (2) and (3) distinguish between the two situations.</text>
        <text>3. Protection of his lien is the only interest which the warehouseman has to justify summary sale of perishable goods which are not hazardous. This same interest must be recognized when the stored goods, although not perishable, decline in market value to a point which threatens the warehouseman's security.</text>
        <text>4. The right to order removal of stored goods is subject to provisions of the public warehousing laws of some states forbidding warehousemen from discriminating among customers. Nor does the section relieve the warehouseman of any obligation under the state laws to secure the approval of a public official before disposing of deteriorating goods. Such <text i="True">regulatory</text> statutes and the regulations under them remain in force and operative. Sections 7-103, 10-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Sections 7-103, 7-403, 10-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross Reference:</heading>
        <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Document". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Good faith". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Notice". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Notification". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Reasonable time". Section 1-204.</text>
        <text>"Value". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouseman". Section 7-102.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-206.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-206.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
