<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-202</num>
  <heading>Form of warehouse receipt; essential terms; optional terms.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-202</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A warehouse receipt need not be in any particular form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Unless a warehouse receipt embodies within its written or printed terms each of the following, the warehouseman is liable for damages caused by the omission to a person injured thereby:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The location of the warehouse where the goods are stored;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of issue of the receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The consecutive number of the receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement whether the goods received will be delivered to the bearer, to a specified person, or to a specified person or his order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The rate of storage and handling charges, except that where goods are stored under a field warehousing arrangement a statement of that fact is sufficient on a non-negotiable receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of the goods or of the packages containing them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The signature of the warehouseman, which may be made by his authorized agent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If the receipt is issued for goods of which the warehouseman is owner, either solely or jointly or in common with others, the fact of such ownership; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A statement of the amount of advances made and of liabilities incurred for which the warehouseman claims a lien or security interest (section 28:7- 209). If the precise amount of such advances made or of such liabilities incurred is, at the time of the issue of the receipt, unknown to the warehouseman or to his agent who issues it, a statement of the fact that advances have been made or liabilities incurred and the purpose thereof is sufficient.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A warehouseman may insert in his receipt any other terms which are not contrary to the provisions of this subtitle and do not impair his obligation of delivery (section 28:7-403) or his duty of care (section 28:7-204). Any contrary provisions shall be ineffective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 719, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Section 2, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Exemption for field warehouse receipts added in subsection (2)(e).</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes:</heading>
        <text>To make clear that the formal requirements of the Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act are continued but not to displace particular legislation requiring other or different specifications of form. See Sections 7-103 and 10-103. This section does not require that a receipt be issued but states formal requirements for those which are issued.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Sections 7-103 and 10-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Bearer". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Security interest". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Term". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouse receipt". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouseman". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Written". Section 1-201.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-202.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-202.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
