<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-209</num>
  <heading>Lien of warehouseman.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:7-209</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A warehouseman has a lien against the bailor on the goods covered by a warehouse receipt or on the proceeds thereof in his possession for charges for storage or transportation (including demurrage and terminal charges), insurance, labor, or charges present or future in relation to the goods, and for expenses necessary for preservation of the goods or reasonably incurred in their sale pursuant to law. If the person on whose account the goods are held is liable for like charges or expenses in relation to other goods whenever deposited and it is stated in the receipt that a lien is claimed for charges and expenses in relation to other goods, the warehouseman also has a lien against him for such charges and expenses whether or not the other goods have been delivered by the warehouseman. But against a person to whom a negotiable warehouse receipt is duly negotiated a warehouseman's lien is limited to charges in an amount or at a rate specified on the receipt or if no charges are so specified then to a reasonable charge for storage of the goods covered by the receipt subsequent to the date of the receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The warehouseman may also reserve a security interest against the bailor for a maximum amount specified on the receipt for charges other than those specified in subsection (1), such as for money advanced and interest. Such a security interest is governed by the article on secured transactions (Article 9).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A warehouseman's lien for charges and expenses under subsection (1) or a security interest under subsection (2) is also effective against any person who so entrusted the bailor with possession of the goods that a pledge of them by him to a good faith purchaser for value would have been valid but is not effective against a person as to whom the document confers no right in the goods covered by it under section 28:7-503.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A warehouseman's lien on household goods for charges and expenses in relation to the goods under subsection (1) is also effective against all persons if the depositor was the legal possessor of the goods at the time of deposit. "Household goods" means furniture, furnishings and personal effects used by the depositor in a dwelling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A warehouseman loses his lien on any goods which he voluntarily delivers or which he unjustifiably refuses to deliver.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 722, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 8, 29 DCR 309.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Sections 27 through 32, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Rewritten.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>1. Subsection (1) defines the warehouseman's statutory lien. A specific lien attaches automatically, without express notation on the receipt, to goods stored under a non-negotiable receipt. That lien is limited to the usual charges arising out of a storage transaction; by notation on the receipt it can be made a general lien extending to like charges in relation to other goods. The same rules apply where the receipt is negotiable, except that as against a holder by due negotiation the lien is limited to the amount or rate specified on the receipt, or, if none is specified, to a reasonable charge for storage of the specific goods after the date of the receipt.</text>
        <text>2. Subsection (2) provides for a security interest based upon agreement. Such a security interest arises out of relations between the parties other than bailment for storage or transportation, as where the bailee assumes the role of financer or performs a manufacturing operation, extending credit in reliance upon the goods covered by the receipt. Such a security interest is not a statutory lien. Compare Sections 9-102(2) and 9-310. It is governed in all respects by Article 9, except that subsection (2) requires that the receipt specify a maximum amount and limits the security interest to the amount specified.</text>
        <text>3. Subsections (1) and (2) validate the lien and security interest "against the bailor." As against third parties, subsection (3)(a) continues the rule under the prior uniform statutory provision that to validate the lien the owner must have entrusted the goods to the depositor, and that the circumstances must be such that a pledge by the depositor to a good faith purchaser for value would have been valid. Thus the owner's interest will not be subjected to a lien or security interest arising out of a deposit of his goods by a thief. The warehouseman may be protected because of the actual, implied or apparent authority of the depositor, because of a Factor's Act, or because of other circumstances which would protect a bona fide pledgee, unless those circumstances are denied effect under Section 7-503. Where the third party is the holder of a security interest, the rights of the warehouseman depend on the priority given to a hypothetical bona fide pledgee by Article 9, particularly Section 9-312. Thus the special priority granted to statutory liens by Section 9-310 does not apply to liens under subsection (1) of this section, since subsection (3) "expressly provides otherwise" within the meaning of Section 9-310. As to household goods, however, subsection (3)(b) makes the warehouseman's lien "for charges and expenses in relation to the goods" effective against all persons if the depositor was the legal possessor. The purpose of the exception is to permit the warehouseman to accept household goods for storage in sole reliance on the value of the goods themselves, especially in situations of family emergency. [This paragraph was amended in 1966].</text>
        <text>4. It is unnecessary to state here, as in Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act 31, that a bailee with a valid lien need not deliver until the lien is satisfied. Section 7-403 provides that a person demanding delivery under a document must be prepared to satisfy the bailee's lien.</text>
        <text>5. Where goods have been stored under a non-negotiable warehouse receipt and are sold by the person to whom the receipt has been issued, frequently the goods are not withdrawn by the new owner. The obligations of the seller of the goods in this situation are set forth in Section 2-503(4) on tender of delivery and include procurement of an acknowledgment by the bailee of the buyer's right to possession of the goods. If a new receipt is requested, such an acknowledgment can be withheld until storage charges have been paid or provided for. The statutory lien for charges on the goods sold, granted by the first sentence of subsection (1), continues valid unless the bailee gives it up. But once a new receipt is issued to the buyer, the buyer becomes "the person on whose account the goods are held" under the second sentence of subsection (1); unless he undertakes liability for charges in relation to other goods stored by the seller, there is no general lien against the buyer for such charges. Of course, the bailee may preserve the general lien in such a case either by an arrangement by which the buyer "is liable for" such charges, or by reserving a security interest under subsection (2).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Point 2: Sections 9-102(2) and 9-310.</text>
        <text>Point 3: Sections 7-503, 9-310 and 9-312.</text>
        <text>Point 4: Section 7-403.</text>
        <text>Point 5: Section 2-503.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Deliver". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Document". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Money". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Purchaser". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Right". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Security interest". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Value". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouse receipt". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouseman". Section 7-102.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-209.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-209.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 4-85, the "Uniform Commercial Code Amendments Act of 1981," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-89, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1981, and December 8, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 18, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-139 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
