<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-207</num>
  <heading>Goods must be kept separate; fungible goods.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-207</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Unless the warehouse receipt otherwise provides, a warehouseman must keep separate the goods covered by each receipt so as to permit at all times identification and delivery of those goods except that different lots of fungible goods may be commingled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Fungible goods so commingled are owned in common by the persons entitled thereto and the warehouseman is severally liable to each owner for that owner's share. Where because of overissue a mass of fungible goods is insufficient to meet all the receipts which the warehouseman has issued against it, the persons entitled include all holders to whom overissued receipts have been duly negotiated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 721, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Sections 22, 23 and 24, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Consolidated and revised; holders of overissued receipts permitted to share in mass of fungible goods.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>No change of substance is made other than the explicit statement that holders to whom overissued receipts have been duly negotiated shall share in a mass of fungible goods. Where individual ownership interests are merged into claims on a common fund, as is necessarily the case with fungible goods, there is no policy reason for discriminating between successive purchasers of similar claims.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Duly negotiate". Section 7-501.</text>
        <text>"Fungible" goods. Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Holder". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouse receipt". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Warehouseman". Section 7-102.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-207.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-207.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
