<level type="section">
  <num>50-1401.03</num>
  <heading>Federally-accepted driver's license - Identification card option.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may offer a resident the option of applying for a driver's license or a special identification card that will be accepted by the federal government for any official purpose, subject to the applicable federal requirements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An applicant for an identification card who served on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States and was discharged under conditions other than dishonorable may submit to the Department of Motor Vehicles, along with any other documentation required by this chapter, a DD Form 214, a WD AGO form, or a DD256 form certifying the applicant's veteran status. Upon receipt of this documentation, the Department of Motor Vehicles shall display the word "veteran" in capital letters on the applicant's identification card.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to take actions as specified in the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Tsunami Relief, 2005, approved May 11, 2005 (Pub. L. No. 109-13; 119 Stat. 231) [see note under 49 U.S.C. § 30301], and the regulations authorized pursuant to that act so that a driver's license or special identification card issued to a person choosing an option described in subsection (a) of this section shall be accepted by the federal government for any official purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 443, § 8a, as added Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-279, § 202(e), 54 DCR 903; Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-52, § 2(b), 60 DCR 15157.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-52 added (a)(2).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-279</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-279, see notes following § 50-312.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-52</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-1401.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-52: Section 3 of D.C. Law 20-52 provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
