<level type="section">
  <num>32-416</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 36-1016</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The requirements of this chapter shall not apply to:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any employer who directly hires and compensates employees for the exclusive purpose of furnishing part-time or temporary help to others and does not in any way offer or attempt to place the employees in permanent jobs with any other employer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person conducting a business which, for a fee, prepares resumes for individuals but does not provide, offer, or imply the offer of any other service related to employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Bona fide educational, religious, charitable, fraternal, and benevolent organizations in which no fee, commission, or other charge is made for services rendered other than ordinary membership dues or tuition fees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Bona fide labor organizations securing or attempting to secure employment for their members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Bona fide employees' organizations securing or attempting to secure employment for their members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Professional counselors whose advice and counsel to individuals concerning employment is incidental to the primary counseling services provided; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any agency or instrumentality of the United States government or the District government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 13, 1985, D.C. Law 5-136, ยง 18, 31 DCR 5727.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 36-1016.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-136, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 32-401.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
