<level type="section">
  <num>2-361.03</num>
  <heading>Supply schedule, purchase card, and training funds.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CPO may charge and collect a fee, in an amount to be determined by rule, on all sales, purchase orders, delivery orders, task orders, and purchase card transactions made under contracts awarded to contractors under the DCSS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CPO may charge a fee for training conducted by the procurement training institute established pursuant to § 2-352.06.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to the terms of any memoranda of understanding with the Chief Financial Officer regarding adherence to the applicable requirements of federal grants, loans, or other extensions of credit to the District, the Chief Procurement Officer shall collect any rebates issued to the District by the purchase card issuers under the Purchase Card Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All funds received pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 1103, 58 DCR 1185; Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9024, 58 DCR 6226; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 15(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-352.06 and § 2-354.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-21 rewrote subsec. (d).</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 rewrote the section heading, which formerly read: "District of Columbia Supply Schedule, Purchase Card, and Training Fund."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-371</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-371, see notes under § 2-351.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-21</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-21, see notes under § 2-351.15.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
