<level type="section">
  <num>2-361.01</num>
  <heading>Green procurement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except for emergency procurements, before entering into any contract in excess of $ 100,000, the District shall issue an environmental certification to demonstrate, to the maximum extent practicable, the purchase of an EPPS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An environmental certification shall not be required for procurements that conform to an applicable Default Environmental Preference Standard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The requirement shall be satisfied if a District solicitation included a requirement that a contractor provide an EPPS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within one year after December 24, 2013, and annually thereafter, OCP shall prepare and submit to the Council a report detailing the progress of this policy, including the following elements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Total contracting amount, and percentage of contracting amount, spent on EPPS;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Successes and challenges to implementing the policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Changes to policies or standards.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 1101, 58 DCR 1185.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>As to applicability of §§ 2-352.06, 2-358.03, and 2-361.01, see § 2-362.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 18-371, § 1203, see § 7015 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) repeal of D.C. Law 18-371, § 1203, see § 7015 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-371</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-371, see notes under § 2-351.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 1203 of D.C. Law 18-371 provided that this section shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <text>Section 7015 of D.C. Law 20-61 repealed D.C. Law 18-371, § 1203.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the "Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
