<level type="section">
  <num>7-1131.18</num>
  <heading>Behavioral health resource guide.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By March 30, 2013, the Department shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Create a behavioral health resource guide for parents and legal guardians that includes information on:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Common signs and symptoms of behavioral health issues facing youth;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The roles and responsibilities of District government agencies in promoting and protecting the behavioral health of youth;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>How a parent or legal guardian can obtain a behavioral health screening or assessment for a youth; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Governmental and non-governmental resources for youth behavioral health programs and services in the District, including contact information; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Create a behavioral health resource guide for a youth that includes:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Age-appropriate information on common behavioral health issues facing youth;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A description of the impact behavioral health issues can have on a youth's development; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Governmental and non-governmental resources for youth behavioral health programs and services in the District, including contact information.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall make the behavioral health resources guides available to the public both in print and on its website. The Department shall also make the guides available to other District agencies and organizations for distribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall update the behavioral health resource guides as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 115c, as added June 7, 2012, D.C. Law 19-141, § 402(b), 59 DCR 3083.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-1303.03e.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 601 of D.C. Law 19-141, see § 7004 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012, 59 DCR 7764).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 601 of D.C. Law 19-141, see § 7004 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-141</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-141, see notes under § 7-1131.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 601 of D.C. Law 19-141 provided: "Sec. 601. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan."</text>
      <text>Section 601 of D.C. Law 19-141 originally provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Section 601 of D.C. Law 19-141, as amended by D.C. Law 19-168, § 7004, provided that the applicability of only §§ 302(b)(1), 304, and 502(a) are contingent upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
