<level type="section">
  <num>7-1131.10</num>
  <heading>Partnership Council.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director shall appoint and convene a Partnership Council, consisting of between 15 and 25 people, to advise the Director, upon his or her request, with respect to departmental matters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The membership of the Partnership Council shall represent the range of interests and perspectives held by adults and children, youth, and their families, as well as the various geographic areas of the District, and shall include at least one person from each ward of the District and 2 representatives from labor unions for departmental workers. At least 51% of the members of the Partnership Council shall be consumers of mental health services or their family members. No members of the Partnership Council shall receive remuneration for their service.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 110, 48 DCR 7674.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 7-1131.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 10 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Law 14-51, October 30, 2001, law notification 48 DCR 10807).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 10 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001, 48 DCR 4390).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 10 of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001, 48 DCR 7123).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 110 of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001, 48 DCR 9947).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-56</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-56, see notes following § 7-1131.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
