<level type="section">
  <num>32-1306</num>
  <heading>Enforcement, records and subpoenas.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 36-106</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall enforce and administer the provisions of this chapter and may hold hearings and otherwise investigate any violations of this chapter and institute actions for penalties provided hereunder. Any and all prosecutions of violations of this chapter shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia and by the Corporation Counsel or his assistants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall have power to administer oaths and examine witnesses under oath, issue subpoenas, compel the attendance of witnesses, and the production of papers, books, accounts, records, payrolls, documents, and testimony and to take depositions and affidavits in any proceedings before him.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In case of failure of any person to comply with any subpoena lawfully issued, or on the refusal of any witness to testify to any matter regarding which he may be lawfully interrogated, it shall be the duty of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or any judge thereof, on application by the Mayor, to compel obedience by attachment proceedings for contempt, as in the case of disobedience of the requirements of a subpoena issued from such Court or a refusal to testify therein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 977, ch. 924, § 6; July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1; July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 36-106.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 36-606.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Change in Government</heading>
        <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
