<level type="section">
  <num>29-402.05</num>
  <heading>Organization of corporation.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After incorporation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If initial directors or members of a designated body are named in the articles of incorporation, those persons shall hold an organizational meeting, as appropriate, at the call of a majority of them, to complete the organization of the nonprofit corporation by electing directors, when the organization of the corporation is to be completed by a designated body, appointing officers, adopting bylaws, and carrying on any other business brought before the meeting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If initial directors or members of a designated body are not named in the articles, the incorporator or incorporators shall hold an organizational meeting at the call of a majority of the incorporators to elect:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Directors and complete the organization of the nonprofit corporation; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A board of directors who shall complete the organization of the corporation.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Action required or permitted by this chapter to be taken by incorporators at an organizational meeting may be taken without a meeting if the action taken is evidenced by one or more consents in the form of a record describing the action taken and signed by each incorporator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An organizational meeting may be held in or outside of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
