<level type="section">
  <num>29-402.02</num>
  <heading>Articles of incorporation.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation shall set forth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A name for the nonprofit corporation that satisfies the requirements of § 29-103.01;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The information required by § 29-104.04;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That the corporation is incorporated as a nonprofit corporation under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name and street address of each incorporator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Whether the corporation will have members.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation may set forth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The names of the individuals who are to serve as the initial directors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provisions creating one or more designated bodies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The names of the initial members of a designated body;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The names of the initial members, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provisions not inconsistent with law regarding:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The purpose or purposes for which the nonprofit corporation is organized;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Managing the business and regulating the affairs of the corporation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Defining, limiting, and regulating the powers of the corporation, its board of directors, any designated body, and the members, if any;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The characteristics, qualifications, rights, limitations, and obligations attaching to each or any class of members; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The distribution of assets on dissolution;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any provision that this chapter requires or permits to be set forth in the articles or bylaws;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A provision permitting or making obligatory indemnification of a director for liability, as defined in § 29-406.50, to any person for any action taken, or any failure to take any action, as a director, except liability for:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Receipt of a financial benefit to which the director is not entitled;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An intentional infliction of harm;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A violation of § 29-406.33; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An intentional violation of criminal law; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Provisions required if the corporation is to be exempt from taxation under federal, state, or local law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The liability of a director of a nonprofit corporation that is not a charitable corporation may be eliminated or limited by a provision of the articles of incorporation that a director is not liable to the corporation or its members for money damages for any action taken, or any failure to take any action, as a director, except liability for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of a financial benefit received by the director to which the director is not entitled;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An intentional infliction of harm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A violation of § 29-406.33; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An intentional violation of criminal law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation need not set forth any of the corporate powers enumerated in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Provisions of the articles of incorporation may be made dependent upon facts objectively ascertainable outside the articles of incorporation in accordance with § 29-401.04.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
