<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-103</num>
  <heading>Perfection of security interests in multiple state transactions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Documents, instruments, letters of credit and ordinary goods.</text>--</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This subsection applies to documents and instruments, rights to proceeds of written letters of credit, and goods other than those covered by a certificate of title described in subsection (2) of this section, mobile goods described in subsection (3) of this section, and minerals described in subsection (5) of this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of a security interest in collateral are governed by the law of the jurisdiction where the collateral is when the last event occurs on which is based the assertion that the security interest is perfected or unperfected.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the parties to a transaction creating a purchase money security interest in goods in one jurisdiction understand at the time that the security interest attaches that the goods will be kept in another jurisdiction, then the law of the other jurisdiction governs the perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of the security interest from the time it attaches until thirty days after the debtor receives possession of the goods and thereafter if the goods are taken to the other jurisdiction before the end of the thirty day period.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When collateral is brought into and kept in the District while subject to a security interest perfected under the law of the jurisdiction from which the collateral was removed, the security interest remains perfected, but if action is required by part 3 of this article to perfect the security interest,</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>if the action is not taken before the expiration of the period of perfection in the other jurisdiction or the end of four months after the collateral is brought into the District, whichever period first expires, the security interest becomes unperfected at the end of that period and is thereafter deemed to have been unperfected as against a person who became a purchaser after removal;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>if the action is taken before the expiration of the period specified in subparagraph (i), the security interest continues perfected thereafter;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>for the purpose of priority over a buyer of consumer goods (section 28:9-307 (2)), the period of the effectiveness of a filing in the jurisdiction from which the collateral is removed is governed by the rules with respect to perfection in subparagraphs (i) and (ii).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Certificate of title.</text> -- (a) This subsection applies to goods covered by a certificate of title issued under a statute of the District or of another jurisdiction under the law of which indication of a security interest on the certificate is required as a condition of perfection.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of the security interest are governed by the law (including the conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction issuing the certificate until four months after the goods are removed from that jurisdiction and thereafter until the goods are registered in another jurisdiction, but in any event not beyond surrender of the certificate. After the expiration of that period, the goods are not covered by the certificate of title within the meaning of this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Except with respect to the rights of a buyer described in the next paragraph, a security interest, perfected in another jurisdiction otherwise than by notation on a certificate of title, in goods brought into the District and thereafter covered by a certificate of title issued by the District is subject to the rules stated in paragraph (d) of subsection (1).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If goods are brought into the District while a security interest therein is perfected in any manner under the law of the jurisdiction from which the goods are removed and a certificate of title is issued by the District and the certificate does not show that the goods are subject to the security interest or that they may be subject to security interests not shown on the certificate, the security interest is subordinate to the rights of a buyer of the goods who is not in the business of selling goods of that kind to the extent that he gives value and receives delivery of the goods after issuance of the certificate and without knowledge of the security interest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Accounts, general intangibles and mobile goods.</text> -- (a) This subsection applies to accounts (other than an account described in subsection (5) on minerals) and general intangibles (other than uncertificated securities) and to goods which are mobile and which are of a type normally used in more than one jurisdiction, such as motor vehicles, trailers, rolling stock, airplanes, shipping containers, road building and construction machinery and commercial harvesting machinery and the like, if the goods are equipment or are inventory leased or held for lease by the debtor to others, and are not covered by a certificate of title described in subsection (2).</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The law (including the conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction in which the debtor is located governs the perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of the security interest.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If, however, the debtor is located in a jurisdiction which is not a part of the United States, and which does not provide for perfection of the security interest by filing or recording in that jurisdiction, the law of the jurisdiction in the United States in which the debtor has its major executive office in the United States governs the perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of the security interest through filing. In the alternative, if the debtor is located in a jurisdiction which is not a part of the United States or Canada and the collateral is accounts or general intangibles for money due or to become due, the security interest may be perfected by notification to the account debtor. As used in this paragraph, "United States" includes its territories and possessions and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A debtor shall be deemed located at his place of business if he has one, at his chief executive office if he has more than one place of business, otherwise at his residence. If, however, the debtor is a foreign air carrier under the Federal Aviation Act of 1958, as amended, it shall be deemed located at the designated office of the agent upon whom service of process may be made on behalf of the foreign air carrier.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A security interest perfected under the law of the jurisdiction of the location of the debtor is perfected until the expiration of four months after a change of the debtor's location to another jurisdiction, or until perfection would have ceased by the law of the first jurisdiction, whichever period first expires. Unless perfected in the new jurisdiction before the end of that period, it becomes unperfected thereafter and is deemed to have been unperfected as against a person who became a purchaser after the change.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Chattel paper.</text> -- The rules stated for goods in subsection (1) apply to a possessory security interest in chattel paper. The rules stated for accounts in subsection (3) apply to a non-possessory security interest in chattel paper, but the security interest may not be perfected by notification to the account debtor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Minerals.</text> -- Perfection and the effect of perfection or non-perfection of a security interest which is created by a debtor who has an interest in minerals or the like (including oil and gas) before extraction and which attaches thereto as extracted, or which attaches to an account resulting from the sale thereof at the wellhead or minehead are governed by the law (including the conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction wherein the wellhead or minehead is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Choice of law.</text> -- The law (including conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction of organization of the issuer governs the perfection and effect of perfection or nonperfection of a security interest in uncertificated securities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Investment property.</text> --</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This subsection applies to investment property.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (f) of this section, during the time that a security certificate is located in a jurisdiction, perfection of a security interest, the effect of perfection or non-perfection, and the priority of a security interest in the certificated security represented thereby are governed by the local law of that jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (f) of this subsection, perfection of a security interest, the effect of perfection or non-perfection, and the priority of a security interest in an uncertificated security are governed by the local law of the issuer's jurisdiction as specified in § 28:8-110(d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (f) of this subsection, perfection of a security interest, the effect of perfection or non-perfection, and the priority of a security interest in a security entitlement or securities account are governed by the local law of the securities intermediary's jurisdiction as specified in § 28:8-110(e).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (f) of this subsection, perfection of a security interest, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in a commodity contract or commodity account are governed by the local law of the commodity intermediary's jurisdiction. The following rules determine a "commodity intermediary's jurisdiction" for purposes of this paragraph:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>If an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer specifies that it is governed by the law of a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary's jurisdiction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>If an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer does not specify the governing law as provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, but expressly specifies that the commodity account is maintained at an office in a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary's jurisdiction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>If an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer does not specify a jurisdiction as provided in subparagraphs (i) and (ii) of this paragraph, the commodity intermediary's jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which is located the office identified in an account statement as the office serving the commodity customer's account.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>If an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer does not specify a jurisdiction as provided in subparagraphs (i) or (ii) of this paragraph and an account statement does not identify an office serving the commodity customer's account as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the commodity intermediary's jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which is located the chief executive office of the commodity intermediary.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Perfection of a security interest by filing, automatic perfection of a security interest in investment property granted by a broker or securities intermediary, and automatic perfection of a security interest in a commodity contract or commodity account granted by a commodity intermediary are governed by the local law of the jurisdiction in which the debtor is located.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 747, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 11, 29 DCR 309; Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 5(a), 39 DCR 9165; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 3(d), 44 DCR 923; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 3(f), 44 DCR 1087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:9-103.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:9-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:9-102.</text>
        <text>Law 9-196, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-20, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-321 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-196 became effective on March 16, 1993.</text>
        <text>Law 11-238, the "Uniform Commercial Code--Letters of Credit Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-574, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-498 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-238 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
        <text>Law 11-240, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Revision Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-576, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-500 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-240 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
