<level type="section">
  <num>3-343.02</num>
  <heading>Unauthorized entry onto stadium playing field prohibited.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless expressly authorized by the Washington Convention and Sports Authority or its duly authorized agent, no person shall at any time enter onto any portion of the playing field within the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless expressly authorized by the Washington Convention and Sports Authority, the lessee or operator of the Baseball Stadium, or their duly authorized agents, no person shall at any time enter onto any portion of the playing field within the Baseball Stadium.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "playing field" means the area encompassed by the seating facilities within the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium or the Baseball Stadium, as such seating facilities may be arranged from time to time.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 3, 1977, D.C. Law 2-37, § 4b, as added July 20, 1996, D.C. Law 11-145, § 3, 43 DCR 2842; June 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-169, § 2(d), 55 DCR 5183; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2082(h)(2), 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 2-343.2.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-169 rewrote the section which had read as follows: "Unless expressly authorized by the District of Columbia Sports Commission or its duly authorized agent, no person shall at any time enter onto any portion of the playing field within the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium. For the purposes of this section, the 'playing field' is that area encompassed by the seating facilities within the Stadium as such seating facilities may be arranged from time to time."</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-111, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted "Washington Convention and Sports Authority" for "District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>See note to § 2-343.01.</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of Ballpark Public Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-316, March 19, 2008, 55 DCR 3412).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(h)(2) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(h)(2) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-145</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-145, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 3-343.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-169</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-169, see notes following § 3-342.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 3-343.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
