<level type="section">
  <num>32-1541</num>
  <heading>Administration fund.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 36-341</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established in the Treasury of the District of Columbia a fund to provide for the payment of all expenses to administer the provisions of this chapter. The fund shall be administered by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall determine, for fiscal years commencing on or after October 1, 1999, the cost of administration of this chapter for each fiscal year and shall prorate and assess the costs of administration as provided in subsections (d) and (f) of this section. The cost of administration shall include any expenses that have been incurred, will be incurred, or that will accrue during the fiscal year.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall determine, in each fiscal year commencing on or after September 30 of the fiscal year in which the Workers' Compensation Amendment Act of 1998 becomes effective, prior to the commencement of the fiscal year, the cost of administration of this chapter. The cost of administration shall include any expenses to be incurred or that will accrue during the fiscal year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The provisions of § 32-1540(b) and (e) shall apply to the fund established pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall determine, at the end of each fiscal year, the cost of the administration of this chapter. The cost of administration shall include any expenses to be incurred or which will accrue during the fiscal year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The total amount of costs to administer this chapter, shall be pro rated among the carriers and self-insurers authorized to insure pursuant to § 32- 1534. The assessment base shall be the total amount of compensation and medical payments that carriers and self-insurers have paid pursuant to this chapter during the preceding fiscal year; provided, however, beginning with the fiscal year commencing on or after October 1, 1999, the Mayor shall have the authority to assess each carrier or self-insured a minimum annual amount of $1,000.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The assessment for each carrier and self-insurer for the preceding fiscal year shall be redetermined, subsequent to each fiscal year, based upon the actual total amount of compensation and medical payments paid and the administrative costs incurred that year. Adjustments for differences between the beginning year assessment and the year end actual determination, if any, shall be made to the next ensuing assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e-1)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor fails to properly determine or redetermine the costs of administering this chapter or fails to properly determine or redetermine the assessment rate or assessments under this section, the assessment rates and assessments shall remain valid and no cause of action shall lie for the Mayor's failure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall assess each carrier and self-insurer for its pro rata share of the total amount of costs to administer this chapter in the fiscal year pursuant to this section, and shall give written notice by certified or registered mail to each carrier or self-insurer of the assessment against it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assessments shall be paid within the time prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a period not to exceed 12 months following April 16, 1999, the Mayor may permit payment of the assessment of each carrier or self-insured in quarterly installment payments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>If a deficit is projected to occur in the administration of the fund created pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, prior to the end of the fiscal year, the Mayor is authorized to implement an emergency assessment in an amount deemed necessary to avoid the deficit. Self-insurers and carriers, on behalf of their policyholders, shall remit the emergency assessment within 30 calendar days of receipt of the assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to promulgate rules deemed necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including provisions for making and preserving appropriate records, paying of assessments, inspecting these records, and the submission by carriers and self-insurers of reports prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>If a carrier or self-insurer fails to pay the assessment referred to in subsection (f) or (h) of this section, or to make and preserve records in the form and manner required by the Mayor, to file a report in the form and manner required by the Mayor, or to allow the Mayor to inspect records required by rules issued pursuant to this section, the Mayor may suspend or revoke the authorization of a carrier to insure for workers' compensation or a self-insurer to act as a self-insurer pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The administration fund shall be audited annually by the Department of Employment Services. The Director of the Department of Employment Services shall file an audited financial report with the Council by March 1st detailing the financial status of the fund as of the end of the preceding fiscal year, including the fund's operation, cash flow, and changes in capital and surplus, using standard accounting principles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-77, § 42, 27 DCR 2503; Apr. 16, 1999, D.C. Law 12-229, § 2(k), 46 DCR 891; Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1102(d), 51 DCR 8441; Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2193, 57 DCR 6242.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 36-341.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-205 added subsec. (k).</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-223 added subsec. (e-1).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(d) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004, 51 DCR 8236).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1102(d) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR 11725).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2193 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6542).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-77, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 32-1501.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-229, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 32-1501.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-205, see notes following § 32-1521.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-223, see notes following § 32-241.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>The effective date of the Workers' Compensation Amendment Act of 1998, referred to in (a)(3), is April 16, 1999.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Section 2193(b) 0f D.C. Law 18-223 provides:</text>
        <text>"(b) This section shall apply as of July 1, 1980."</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
