<level type="section">
  <num>44-653</num>
  <heading>Hospital provider fee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to § 44-654, the District may charge a fee at a uniform rate on the gross patient revenue of each hospital beginning May 1, 2013. The District may charge the fee retroactively to May 1, 2013, upon the effective date of this chapter. The uniform rate shall be applied to each hospital's gross patient revenue as derived from each hospital's filed Medicare cost report ending between July 1, 2009, and June 30, 2010. The hospital provider fee is applied at a uniform rate necessary to generate the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the non-federal share of the total available spending room under the Medicaid upper payment limit for private hospitals applicable to District fiscal years ("DFY") 2013 and 2014 consistent with the federal approval of the authorizing Medicaid State Plan amendment; plus</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the lesser of the non-federal share of the total available spending room under the Medicaid upper payment limit for District operated hospitals applicable to DFY 2013 and 2014 consistent with the federal approval of the authorizing Medicaid State Plan amendment or United Medical Center's Medicaid disproportionate share hospital limit as adjusted by the District in accordance with the federally approved Medicaid State Plan; plus</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the Department's administrative expenses as described in § 44-652(c)(2).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A psychiatric hospital provider that is an agency or a unit of the District government is exempt from the fee imposed under this chapter, unless the exemption is adjudged to be unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, in which case a psychiatric hospital provider that is an agency or a unit of the District government shall pay the fee imposed by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5074, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 44-654, § 44-656, and § 44-657.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5074 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5074 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 44-651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
