<level type="section">
  <num>44-651</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Department" means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Gross patient revenue" means the amount calculated in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles for hospitals that is reported as the sum of Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Lines 1, 2, 2.01, 15, 17 and 18 and Worksheet G-2; Column 2; Lines 17, 18, 18.5 and 18.51 of the Medicare Cost Report (2552-96), excluding long-term care inpatient ancillary revenues.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Hospital" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 44-501(a)(1), but excludes any hospital operated by the federal government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Hospital system" means any group of hospitals licensed separately but operated, owned, or maintained by a common entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Medicaid" means the medical assistance programs authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.), and by § 1-307.02, and administered by the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5072, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
