<level type="section">
  <num>44-657</num>
  <heading>Multi-hospital systems, closure, merger, and new hospitals.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a hospital system conducts, operates, or maintains more than one hospital licensed by the Department of Health, the provider shall pay the fee for each hospital separately.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, in the case of a person who ceases to conduct, operate, or maintain a hospital for which the person is subject to the fee under this chapter as a hospital provider, the fee for the DFY in which the cessation occurs shall be adjusted by multiplying the fee computed under § 44-653 by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days in the year during which the provider conducts, operates, or maintains the hospital and the denominator of which is 365. Immediately upon ceasing to conduct, operate, or maintain a hospital, the person shall pay the fee for the year as so adjusted (to the extent not previously paid).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, a provider who conducts, operates, or maintains a hospital, upon notice by the Department, shall pay the fee computed under § 44-653 and subsection (a) of this section in installments on the due dates stated in the notice and on the regular installment due dates for the DFY occurring after the due dates of the initial notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5078, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5078 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5078 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 44-651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
