<level type="section">
  <num>44-655</num>
  <heading>Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For visits and services beginning May 1, 2013, quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to each private hospital. Each payment will be equal to the hospital's DFY 2011 outpatient Medicaid payments divided by the total private hospital DFY 2011 outpatient Medicaid payments multiplied by one quarter of the total outpatient private hospital access payment pool minus $250,000. The total outpatient private hospital access payment pool is equal to the total available spending room under the private hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2013 and 2014, respectively.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The remaining $250,000 shall be distributed as an adjustment to the quarterly access payments for all private children's hospitals with less than 150 beds and distributed based on the hospital's DFY 2011 outpatient Medicaid payments relative to the total qualifying hospitals' DFY 2011 outpatient Medicaid payments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any private hospital that is also a Disproportionate Share Hospital ("DSH") will receive no more than the available room under their District-adjusted, hospital-specific DSH limit. Any Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments that would otherwise exceed a private disproportionate share hospital's adjusted DSH limit shall be distributed to the remaining private hospitals consistent with each private hospital's relative share of DFY 2011 Medicaid payments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For visits and services beginning May 1, 2013, outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to the United Medical Center. Each payment will be equal to one quarter of the total outpatient public hospital access payment pool. The total outpatient public hospital access payment pool is equal to the lesser of the total available spending room under the District-operated hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2013 and 2014, respectively, and the United Medical Center District-adjusted Medicaid DSH limit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made within 15 business days of the end of each DFY quarter for the Medicaid visits and services rendered during that quarter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No payments shall be made under this section until such time that the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services approves the Medicaid State Plan amendment authorizing the Medicaid payments described in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Medicaid payment methodologies authorized under this chapter shall not be altered in any way unless such alteration is necessary to gain federal approval from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5076, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 44-652, § 44-654, and § 44-656.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5076 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5076 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 44-651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
