<level type="section">
  <num>44-652</num>
  <heading>Hospital Provider Fee Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Effective May 1, 2013, there is established as a special fund the Hospital Provider Fee Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department and used in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of revenue from the following sources:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All moneys collected or received by the Department from the hospital provider fee imposed by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All federal matching funds received by the Department as a result of expenditures made by the Department that are attributable to moneys deposited in the Fund;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Interest and penalties collected under this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Interest earned by the Fund.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Fund may only be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For making Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments to hospitals as required under § 44-655;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For payment of administrative expenses incurred by the Department or its agent in performing the activities authorized by this chapter at an amount not to exceed the prorated amount of $150,000 annually; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For making refunds to hospital providers pursuant to § 44-654.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization by Congress, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall not be used to replace any moneys appropriated to the Medicaid program.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5073, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 44-653.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5073 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5073 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 44-651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
