<level type="section">
  <num>44-654</num>
  <heading>Applicability of fees.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed by § 44-653 shall not be due and payable until such time that the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services approves the Medicaid State Plan amendment authorizing the Medicaid payments described in § 44-655.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed by § 44-653 shall cease to be imposed, and any moneys remaining in the Fund shall be refunded to hospital providers in proportion to the amounts paid by them, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department makes changes in its rules that reduce the hospital inpatient or outpatient Medicaid payment rates, including adjustment payment rates, in effect on October 1, 2012; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The payments to hospitals required under § 44-655 are modified in any way other than to secure federal approval of such payments as described in § 44-655 or are not eligible for federal matching funds under Title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed by § 44-653 shall not take effect or shall cease to be imposed if the fee is determined to be an impermissible tax under Title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Should the fee imposed by § 44-653 not take effect or cease to be imposed, moneys in the Fund derived from the imposed fee shall be disbursed in accordance with § 44-655 to the extent federal matching is available. If federal matching is not available due to a determination by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services that the provider fee is impermissible, any remaining moneys shall be refunded to hospital providers in proportion to the amounts paid by them.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5075, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 44-652 and § 44-653.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5075 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5075 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 44-651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle H of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Medicaid Hospital Outpatient Supplemental Payment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
