<level type="section">
  <num>22-2501</num>
  <heading>Possession of implements of crime; penalty.</heading>
  <text>No person shall have in his or her possession in the District any instrument, tool, or implement for picking locks or pockets, with the intent to use such instrument, tool, or implement to commit a crime. Whoever violates this section shall be imprisoned for not more than 180 days and may be fined not more than and, in addition, may be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, unless the violation occurs after he or she has been convicted in the District of a violation of this section or of a felony, either in the District or another jurisdiction, in which case he or she shall be imprisoned for not less than one year nor more than 5 years and, in addition, may be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 97, ch. 159, § 209(a); Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 604(a)(2), 28 DCR 3081; Nov. 17, 1981, D.C. Law 4-52, § 3(g), 28 DCR 4348; May 21, 1994, D.C. Law 10-119, § 9(c), 41 DCR 1639; Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 110(b), 41 DCR 2608; June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-275, § 11, 44 DCR 1408; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, §§ 202(b), 305, 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>District defined, see § 1-201.03.</text>
      <text>Minimum sentences, convictions under this section, see § 24-403.</text>
      <text>Sentencing, supervised release, and good time credit for felonies under this section committed on or after August 5, 2000, see § 24-403.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 24-403 and § 24-403.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 22-3601.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 22-3601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" for "not more than $1,000"; and added "and, in addition, may be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" at the end of the last sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 110(b) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994, 41 DCR 4286).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 202(b) and 305 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-29</heading>
      <text>Law 4-29, the "District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-123, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 5, 1981, and May 19, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 9, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 4-51 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-52</heading>
      <text>Law 4-52, the "Minors Health Consent Regulation, District of Columbia Sexual Assault Reform Act of 1981, District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, Traffic Act Amendments Act of 1981, District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act, District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act, and Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979 Amendment of 1981" was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-270, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 28, 1981 and September 15, 1981 respectively. Signed by the Mayor on September 25, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 4-89 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-119</heading>
      <text>Law 10-119, the "Anti-Gender Discriminatory Language Criminal Offenses Amendment Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-332, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 1, 1994, and March 1, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 17, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-209 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-119 became effective on May 21, 1994.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-151</heading>
      <text>Law 10-151, the "Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Amendment Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-98, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 29, 1994, and April 12, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 4, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-238 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-151 became effective on August 20, 1994.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-275</heading>
      <text>Law 11-275, the "Second Criminal Code Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-909, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-520 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-275 became effective on June 3, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
