<level type="section">
  <num>1-609.54</num>
  <heading>Employment-at-will.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An appointment to a position in the Management Supervisory Service shall be an at-will appointment. Management Supervisory Service employees shall be given a 15-day notice prior to termination. Upon termination, a person with Career or Educational Service status, or with Excepted Service status due to appointment as an attorney pursuant to § 1-609.09, may retreat, at the discretion of the personnel authority, within 3 months of the effective date of the termination, to a vacant position within the agency to which he or she was promoted for which he or she is qualified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An individual appointed to the Management Supervisory Service pursuant to this section may be paid severance pay upon separation for non-disciplinary reasons according to the length of the individual's employment with the District government as follows:</text>
    <level type="form">
      <text/>
      <text>
 
 Length of Employment <span style="font-weight: bold; ">Maximum Severance 
 </span>
 Up to 6 months 2 weeks of the employee's basic pay 
 
 6 months to 1 year 4 weeks of the employee's basic pay 
 
 1 to 3 years 8 weeks of the employee's basic pay 
 
 More than 3 years 10 weeks of the employee's basic pay.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 954, as added June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(k), 45 DCR 2464; Mar. 14, 2012, D.C. Law 19-115, § 2(f), 59 DCR 461.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-610.54.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-115 repealed subsec. (b), which formerly read:</text>
      <text>"(b) Employees appointed to the Management Supervisory Service shall be given severance pay in accordance with subchapter XI of this chapter upon separation for non-disciplinary reasons."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-124</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-124, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-603.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-115</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-115, see notes under § 1-608.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of § 101(k) of D.C. Law 12-124: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-609.51.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
