<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-525</num>
  <heading>Lessor's right to possession of goods.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a lessor discovers the lessee to be insolvent, the lessor may refuse to deliver the goods.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After a default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in § 28:2A-523(a) or § 28:2A-523(c)(1) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, the lessor has the right to take possession of the goods. If the lease contract so provides, the lessor may require the lessee to assemble the goods and make them available to the lessor at a place to be designated by the lessor which is reasonably convenient to both parties. Without removal, the lessor may render unusable any goods employed in trade or business, and may dispose of goods on the lessee's premises (§ 28:2A-527).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The lessor may proceed under subsection (b) of this section without judicial process if it can be done without breach of the peace or the lessor may proceed by action.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830; Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 26, 43 DCR 530.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-504, § 28:2A-523, and § 28:2A-527.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2A-525.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-128</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:2A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-110</heading>
      <text>Law 11-110, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-485, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 5, 1995, and January 4, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-199 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-110 became effective on April 18, 1996.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
