<level type="section">
  <num>22-3232</num>
  <heading>Receiving stolen property.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 22-3832</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person commits the offense of receiving stolen property if that person buys, receives, possesses, or obtains control of stolen property, knowing or having reason to believe that the property was stolen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall not be a defense to a prosecution under this section, alone or in conjunction with § 22-1803, that the property was not in fact stolen, if the accused engages in conduct which would constitute the crime if the attendant circumstances were as the accused believed them to be.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any person convicted of receiving stolen property shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than 7 years, or both, if the value of the stolen property is $1,000 or more.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person convicted of receiving stolen property shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, if the stolen property has some value.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "stolen property" includes property that is not in fact stolen if the person who buys, receives, possesses, or obtains control of the property had reason to believe that the property was stolen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 132, 29 DCR 3976; Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 113(f), 41 DCR 2608; June 3, 2011, D.C. Law 18-377, § 12(e), 58 DCR 1174; Apr. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-120, § 101(c), 58 DCR 11235.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 22-3832.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-377, in subsec. (c)(1), substituted "$1,000" for "$250"; and, in subsec. (c)(2), substituted "if the stolen property has some value" for "if the value of the stolen property is less than $250".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-120, in subsec. (a), substituted "stolen" for "stolen, with intent to deprive another of the right to the property or a benefit of the property"; in subsec. (b), substituted "under this section, alone or in conjunction with § 22-1803," for "for an attempt to commit the offense described in this section"; and added subsec. (d).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 113(f) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994, 41 DCR 4286).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 512(e) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011, 58 DCR 640).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 512(e) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011, 58 DCR 3701).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 101(c) of Receiving Stolen Property and Public Safety Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-261, December 21, 2011, 58 DCR 11232).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 101(c) of Receiving Stolen Property and Public Safety Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-326, March 19, 2012, 59 DCR 2384).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-164, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 22-3201.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-151, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 22-3212.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-377, see notes under § 22-303.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-120, see notes under § 22-2701.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
