<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section>50-2633</section>
  <heading>Parking meters.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(April 4, 1938, 52 Stat. 192, ch. 62, § 11; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370,§ 628, 58 DCR 1008; Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6082, 58 DCR 6226; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6003, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>National Capital Region Transportation, revenues allocated to the Metrorail/Metrobus Account, see § 9-1111.15.</text>
      <text>Regulation of parking, allocation of collected revenues, see § 50-2607.</text>
      <text>Regulation of parking, parking meters, see § 50-2603.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 9-1111.15.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 40-724.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 40-616.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-370 substituted 'and all fees collected shall be dedicated annually to paying the District's annual operating subsidies to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority' for 'and all fees collected shall be paid to the Collector of Taxes for deposit in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the revenues of said District'.</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-21, in subsec. (b), substituted 'Authority, except for fees collected in performance parking pilot zones, pursuant to Chapter 25A of this title, and dedicated in § 50-2534' for 'Authority'.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 628 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011, 58 DCR 662).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-370</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-370, see notes under § 50-921.10.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-21</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-21, see notes under § 50-231.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: The Office of the Collector of Taxes was abolished and the functions thereof transferred to the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1952. All functions of the Office of the Collector of Taxes including the functions of all officers, employees and subordinate agencies were transferred to the Director, Department of General Administration by Reorganization Order No. 3, dated August 28, 1952. Reorganization Order No. 20, dated November 10, 1952, transferred the functions of the Collector of Taxes to the Finance Office. The same Order provided for the Office of the Collector of Taxes headed by a Collector in the Finance Office, and abolished the previously existing Office of the Collector of Taxes. Reorganization Order No. 20 was superseded and replaced by Organization Order No. 121, dated December 12, 1957, which provided that the Finance Office (consisting of the Office of the Finance Officer, Property Tax Division, Revenue Division, Treasury Division, Accounting Division, and Data Processing Division) would continue under the direction and control of the Director of General Administration, and that the Treasury Division would perform the function of collecting revenues of the District of Columbia and depositing the same with the Treasurer of the United States. Organization Order No. 121 was revoked by Organization Order No. 3, dated December 13, 1967, Part IVC of which prescribed the functions of the Finance Office within a newly established Department of General Administration. The executive functions of the Board of Commissioners were transferred to the Commissioner of the District of Columbia by § 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967. Functions of the Finance Office as stated in Part IVC of Organization Order No. 3 were transferred to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue by Commissioner's Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969.</text>
      <text>Section 629 of D.C. Law 18-370 provided: "Sec. 629. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of October 1, 2011; except, that sections 622 and 623(a)(2) shall apply as of the effective date of this act."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 6081 of D.C. Law 19-21 provided that subtitle I of title VI of the act may be cited as the "Performance Parking Pilot Zone Amendment Act of 2011".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(301, 302, 303) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
