<level type="section">
  <num>4-251.04</num>
  <heading>Subsidies.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All subsidies established under this chapter shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as creating an entitlement to a subsidy for any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to § 4-251.06, the Mayor shall establish by rule the amount of a subsidy a grandparent is eligible to receive under this chapter; provided, that the subsidy shall be at least 66%, but no more than 105%, of the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent Level 1 guardianship established under section 29-6103.3 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The amount of a subsidy a grandparent is eligible to receive under this chapter shall be offset by any amount a grandparent receives as TANF or Supplemental Security Income for the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-69, § 104, 53 DCR 54; Sept. 20, 2007, D.C. Law 17-21, § 3(b), 54 DCR 6835; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 502, 58 DCR 1008.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-21, in subsec. (b), substituted "within 5% (no less than 95% and no more than 105%) of the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent Level 1 guardianship" for "no less than the regular daily rate of the subsidy for a long-term permanent guardianship"; and, in subsec. (c), substituted "receives as TANF or Supplemental Security Income" for "receives from TANF".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-370, in subsec. (b), substituted "that the subsidy shall be at least 66%, but no more than 105%" for "that the subsidy shall be within 5% (no less than 95% and no more than 105%)".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 104 of Grandparent Caregivers Pilot Program Establishment Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-278, February 22, 2006, 53 DCR 1459).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of Safe and Stable Homes for Children and Youth Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-69, July 9, 2007, 54 DCR 6826).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011, 58 DCR 662).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-69, see notes following § 4-251.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-21, see notes following § 4-251.03.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-370, see notes under § 4-202.05.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title: Section 501 of D.C. Law 18-370 provided that subtitle A of title V of the act may be cited as "Grandparent Caregivers Program and Long-Term Permanent Guardianship Subsidies Amendment Act of 2010".</text>
        <text>Section 503 of D.C. Law 18-370 provides:</text>
        <text>"Sec. 503. Applicability. </text>
        <text>"This subtitle shall apply as of January 1, 2011."</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
