<level type="section">
  <num>50-2351</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Autonomous vehicle" means a vehicle capable of navigating District roadways and interpreting traffic-control devices without a driver actively operating any of the vehicle's control systems. The term "autonomous vehicle" excludes a motor vehicle enabled with active safety systems or driver- assistance systems, including systems to provide electronic blind-spot assistance, crash avoidance, emergency braking, parking assistance, adaptive cruise control, lane-keep assistance, lane-departure warning, or traffic-jam and queuing assistance, unless the system alone or in combination with other systems enables the vehicle on which the technology is installed to drive without active control or monitoring by a human operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Driver" means a human operator of a motor vehicle with a valid driver's license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Public roadway" means a street, road, or public thoroughfare that allows motor vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Traffic control device" means a traffic signal, traffic sign, electronic traffic sign, pavement marking, or other sign, device, or apparatus designed and installed to direct moving traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-278, ยง 2, 60 DCR 2119.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-278</heading>
      <text>Law 19-278, the "Autonomous Vehicle Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-931. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012 and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-643 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-278 became effective on April 23, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
