<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-105</num>
  <heading>Control of electronic chattel paper.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A secured party has control of electronic chattel paper if a system employed for evidencing the transfer of interests in the chattel paper reliably establishes the secured party as the person to which the chattel paper was assigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A system satisfies subsection (a) of this section if the record or records comprising the chattel paper are created, stored, and assigned in such a manner that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A single authoritative copy of the record or records exists which is unique, identifiable, and, except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection, unalterable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The authoritative copy identifies the secured party as the assignee of the record or records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The authoritative copy is communicated to and maintained by the secured party or its designated custodian;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Copies or amendments that add or change an identified assignee of the authoritative copy can be made only with the consent of the secured party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Each copy of the authoritative copy and any copy of a copy is readily identifiable as a copy that is not the authoritative copy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any amendment of the authoritative copy is readily identifiable as authorized or unauthorized.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(c), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-203, § 28:9-207, § 28:9-208, § 28:9-314, § 28:9-330, § 28:9-601, § 40-102, § 50-601, and § 50-1201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-302 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-302: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-302 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
