<level type="toc">
  <prefix>Part</prefix>
  <num>A</num>
  <heading>Reorganization Plan No. 1.</heading>
  <level>
    <text>
      <text b="True">(Effective November 1, 1989)</text>
    </text>
    <text>
      <text b="True">DEPARTMENT OF HUMAN RIGHTS AND MINORITY BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT</text>
    </text>
    <text>I. ESTABLISHMENT</text>
    <text>There is hereby established, in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, under the supervision of a Director, a Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development.</text>
    <text>II. PURPOSE</text>
    <text>The purpose of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development is to ensure an end to illegal discriminatory practices in employment, housing and commercial space, public accommodations, educational institutions and District Government and private sector contracting. The Department will promote equal opportunity and equal access in all aspects of life in the District of Columbia, as authorized by the laws of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>III. FUNCTIONS</text>
    <text>The following functions are hereby transferred to the Director of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development:</text>
    <level>
      <text>A. All of the functions of the staff director and additional staff of the Minority Business Opportunity Commission, appointed pursuant to Section 5(e) of the Minority Contracting Act of 1976, D.C. Law 1-95, D.C. Code, section 2- 215.04(e) (1987).</text>
      <text>B. All of the functions assigned to the Office of Human Rights by the following statutes and Mayor's Orders and all Mayor's Orders and rules issued pursuant thereto:</text>
      <level>
        <level>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Affirmative Action in District Government Employment Act, D.C. Law 1-63, D.C. Code, sec. 1-521.01 et seq.;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Human Rights Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, as amended, D.C. Code, sec. 2-1401.01 et seq.;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Mayor's Order 79-89 ("Sexual Harassment");</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Section 42 of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, D.C. Law 4- 142, D.C. Code, sec. 34-1241;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Mayor's Order 83-243 ("Access of the Handicapped to Government Programs");</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Mayor's Order 85-85 ("Compliance with Equal Opportunity Obligations in Contracts");</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
    <text>IV. TRANSFER</text>
    <text>All positions, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations and other funds available or to be made available relating to the duties and functions assigned in this plan are transferred to the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development. The Director of the existing Office of Human Rights and Executive Director of the Minority Business Opportunity Commission shall be the Director of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development upon the effective date of this plan and shall serve without the necessity of a new Council confirmation process.</text>
    <text>V. ORGANIZATION</text>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development shall organize the personnel and property transferred in this plan into such organizational units as the Director deems appropriate.</text>
    <text>VI. ABOLISHMENT</text>
    <text>The following agencies and Offices of the District of Columbia government are hereby abolished:</text>
    <level>
      <text>The Office of Human Rights; and</text>
      <text>The offices of staff director and additional staff of the Minority Business Opportunity Commission.</text>
    </level>
    <text>VII. EFFECTIVE DATE</text>
    <text>This Reorganization Plan shall take effect on a date to be designated by executive order of the Mayor within 30 days after the expiration of Council review provided in sec. 422(12) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, D.C. Code, sec. 242(12) (1986).</text>
    <level>
      <type>annotations</type>
      <level>
        <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
        <level>
          <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
          <text>For establishment of Department of Human Rights and Minority Business Development, see Mayor's Order 89-247, November 1, 1989.</text>
          <text>DC CODE D. I, T. 1, Ch. 15, Subch. X, Pt. A, 1989 Plan 1</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
