<level type="section">
  <num>26-1120.01</num>
  <heading>Confidential information.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To assist in the performance of the Commissioner's duties under this chapter, the Commissioner may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Share documents, materials, or other information, including confidential and privileged documents, materials, or information subject to this chapter, with other local, state, federal, and international regulatory agencies, with the Conference of State Bank Supervisors, SRR, NMLSR, their affiliates, or subsidiaries, or with state, federal, and international law enforcement authorities; provided, that the recipient agrees to maintain the confidentiality and privileged status of the document, material, or other information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Receive documents, materials, or information, including confidential and privileged documents, materials, or other information, from the Conference of State Bank Supervisors, SRR, NMLSR, their affiliates, or subsidiaries, or from regulatory and law enforcement officials of foreign or other domestic jurisdictions, and shall maintain as confidential or privileged any document, material, or information received with notice or the understanding that it is confidential or privileged under the laws of the jurisdiction that is the source of the document, material, or information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Enter into agreements with the entities set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection governing sharing and use of information consistent with this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Authorize a national criminal background check and submission of fingerprints and other identifying information, submitted through the NMLSR, and other information with, and receive criminal history record information from, the NMLSR, the Metropolitan Police Department, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the purposes of facilitating determinations regarding eligibility for licensure under this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Contract with a third party, including the SRR, the Conference of State Bank Supervisors, or its affiliates or subsidiaries, to perform any functions, including the collection of licensing and processing fees, collection of contact information and other identifying information, fingerprints, written consent to a criminal background check, personal history and experience, and conduct of examinations related to mortgage loan originator, loan officer, mortgage lender, or mortgage broker activities, that the Commissioner may consider appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-155, § 21a, as added July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-38, § 2(o), 56 DCR 4290.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 26-1120.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-38</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-38, see notes following § 26-1101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of D.C. Law 18-38 provided: "Sec. 3. Applicability. Except for section 2(c)(1), (g), (j), and (o), this act shall not apply until the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking has promulgated rules implementing this act."</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
