<level type="section">
  <num>26-1105</num>
  <heading>Acquisition of control; application.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, no person shall acquire directly or indirectly 25% or more of the voting shares of a corporation or 25% of the ownership of any other entity licensed to conduct business under this chapter unless such person first:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Files an application with the Superintendent [Commissioner] in such form as the Superintendent [Commissioner] may prescribe from time to time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Delivers such other information to the Superintendent [Commissioner] as the Superintendent [Commissioner] may require concerning the financial responsibility, background, experience, and activities of the applicant, its directors, officers, principals, and members, and of any proposed new directors, officers, principals, or members of the licensee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pays such application fee as the Superintendent [Commissioner] may prescribe.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon the filing and investigation of an application, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall permit the applicant to acquire the interest in the licensee if it finds that the applicant, its members if applicable, its directors, officers, and principals and any proposed new directors, members, officers, and principals have the financial responsibility, character, reputation, experience and general fitness to warrant the belief that the business will be operated efficiently and fairly, in the public interest, and in accordance with the law. The Superintendent [Commissioner] shall grant or deny the application within 60 days after the date a completed application accompanied by the required fee is filed unless the period is extended by order of the Superintendent [Commissioner] reciting the reasons for the extension. If the application is denied, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall notify the applicant of the denial and the reasons for the denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The acquisition of an interest in a licensee directly or indirectly, including an acquisition by merger or consolidation by or with a person licensed by this chapter or a person exempt from this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The acquisition of an interest in a licensee directly or indirectly, including an acquisition by merger or consolidation by or with a person affiliated through common ownership with the licensee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The acquisition of an interest in a licensee by a person by bequest, descent, survivorship, or operation of law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The person acquiring an interest in a licensee in a transaction which is exempt from filing an application pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall send written notice to the Superintendent [Commissioner] of such acquisition within 10 days after the closing of such acquisition.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-155, § 6, 43 DCR 4213.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 26-1005.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-155</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-155, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 26-1101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Fees credited to the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions Enterprise Fund: Section 1804(4) of D.C. Law 12-60 provided that all fees received pursuant to § 26-1005(a)(3) shall be credited to the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions Enterprise Fund.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
