<level type="section">
  <num>31-5322</num>
  <heading>Valuation standards for certificates.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 35-1252</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Standards of valuation for certificates issued prior to one year after April 29, 1998 shall be those provided by the laws applicable immediately prior to April 29, 1998.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The minimum standards of valuation for certificates issued on or after one year from April 29, 1998 shall be based on the following tables:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For certificates of life insurance, the Commissioner's 1941 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table, the Commissioner's 1941 Standard Industrial Table, the Commissioner's 1958 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table, the Commissioner's 1980 Standard Mortality Table, or any more recent table made applicable to life insurers in the District; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For annuity and pure endowment certificates, for total and permanent disability benefits, for accidental death benefits, and for noncancelable accident and health benefits, such tables as are authorized for use by life insurers in the District.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The valuation methods and standards (including interest assumptions) set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in accordance with the laws of the District applicable to life insurers issuing policies containing like benefits.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may, in his or her discretion, accept other standards for valuation if the Commissioner finds that the reserves produced thereby will not be less in the aggregate than reserves computed in accordance with the minimum valuation standard herein prescribed. The Commissioner may, in his or her discretion, vary the standards of mortality applicable to all benefit contracts on substandard lives or other extra hazardous lives by any society authorized to do business in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any society, with the consent of the Commissioner of the state of domicile of the society and under such conditions, if any, which the Commissioner may impose, may establish and maintain reserves on its certificates in excess of the reserves required thereunder, but the contractual rights of any benefit member shall not be affected thereby.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, ยง 1223, 45 DCR 1172.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 35-1252.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-86, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 31-5301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
