<level type="section">
  <num>8-1102</num>
  <heading>Comprehensive plan for multi-material recycling system.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 1 year from July 25, 1987, the Mayor of the District of Columbia ("Mayor") shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia ("Council") a comprehensive plan for a District of Columbia ("District") multi-material recycling system for the purpose of recovering energy and other resources from discarded materials and solid waste and for distributing reusable organic compounds for public use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before submitting the comprehensive plan to the Council, the Mayor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Hold a public hearing to receive public comments on the proposed comprehensive plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Consult with the Council, the Litter and Solid Waste Reduction Commission established pursuant to § 3-1001, the Hazardous Materials Study Commission established pursuant to § 8-1201 [repealed], and other interested parties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The comprehensive plan submitted to the Council by the Mayor shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A technical and economic description of the level of performance and results that can be attained from an effective multi-material recycling program and solid waste resource recovery facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Detailed methods for the collection, transportation, separation, and reduction of discarded materials, household hazardous waste, and solid waste;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Guidelines for the implementation of an office waste paper recycling program for District government office buildings, District-based educational facilities, and private corporations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the alternative management of garbage disposal and resource recovery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Information regarding an adequate location, design, and construction site for a facility associated with the conversion of solid waste to energy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Information regarding regional, geographic, demographic, and environmental factors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Information regarding public health and safety considerations and applicable federal regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Guidelines for the distribution of reusable organic compounds, such as mulch, at convenient distribution centers throughout the District for use by its residents for gardening, landscaping, and other similar purposes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A description of a public information campaign and community outreach program to be targeted to District residents and visitors regarding the importance of the District's multi-material recycling system and the public's role in this system.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 25, 1987, D.C. Law 7-19, § 3, 34 DCR 3810.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-3202.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-19</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-19, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>"Section 8-1201," referred to in (b)(2), was repealed by § 7 of D.C. Law 7-190, effective March 16, 1989.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
