<level type="section">
  <num>42-3226</num>
  <heading>Lease held by an infant or person with a mental disability - Costs of renewal chargeable to estate of infant or person with a disability or deemed charge upon leasehold.</heading>
  <text>All and every sum and sums of money and other consideration, paid or advanced by any such guardian, trustee, committee or other person, for or on account of the renewal of any such lease or leases, and all reasonable charges incident thereto, shall be paid out of the estate or effects of the infant or person with a mental illness for whose benefit the said lease or leases shall be renewed, or shall be a charge and incumbrance upon the leasehold premises, together with interest for the same, as the said court shall direct and determine.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(29 Geo. 2, ch. 31, § 2, 1756; Kilty's Rep. 253; Alex. Br. Stat. 789; Comp. Stat. D.C., 335, § 71; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 64(e), 53 DCR 6198; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 26(b), 59 DCR 5567.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 45-1426.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 45-928.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-305 rewrote the section heading, which formerly read: "Lease held by infant or mentally handicapped - Costs of renewal chargeable to estate of infant or handicapped or deemed charge upon leasehold."</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-169 substituted "person with a mental illness" for "lunatic."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-305</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-305, see notes following § 42-820.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
