<level type="section">
  <num>28-4032</num>
  <heading>Implied warranty; responsibility for repair; return or replacement; certain actions deemed void.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or express warranty furnished by the manufacturer, the manufacturer shall be deemed to have warranted that for a period of one year from date of 1st delivery to the consumer the assistive technology device, when used as intended, will be free from any nonconformity. Any nonconformity shall be repaired, including parts and labor, by the manufacturer or its agent without cost to the consumer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If, after a reasonable attempt to repair, the nonconformity is not repaired, the assistive device dealer, assistive device lessor, or manufacturer shall, within 30 days after a consumer's request:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Refund to the consumer all collateral costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Accept return of the nonconforming assistive technology device and replace the nonconforming assistive technology device with one of comparable value, function, and usefulness; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Refund the full purchase price to the consumer.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A manufacturer or dealer exclusion or limitation of the implied warranties or consumer remedies prescribed by this section shall be void.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A purported waiver of rights to legal action by a consumer within an assistive technology device purchase agreement or assistive technology device lease agreement shall be void.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2010, D.C. Law 18-241, ยง 3, 57 DCR 7550; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 83(d), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171 enacted into law Chapter 40A of Title 28.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-241, see notes under ยง 28-4031.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-171, see notes under ยง 28-3814.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
