<level type="section">
  <num>38-2601.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"CTE grant program" is the supplemental career and technical education grant program established by § 38-2611 that provides grants to DCPS and public charter schools to support and enhance their career and technical education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>"DCPS" means the District of Columbia Public Schools established by § 38-171.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>"Districtwide assessments" has the same meaning as provided in § 38-1800.02(13).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Field test" means a test used during the test-development process to assess the quality and appropriateness of test items, administration procedures, scoring, and reporting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>"Formula" shall have the meaning as provided in § 38-2901(8).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2B)</num>
    <text>"Fund" means the CTE Grant Program Fund established by § 38-2612.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Local education agency" or "LEA" means an educational institution at the local level that exists primarily to operate a publicly funded school or schools in the District of Columbia, including the District of Columbia Public Schools and a District of Columbia public charter school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"OSSE" means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education established by § 38-2601.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Practice test" means any test or other evaluation that has as its primary purpose the simulation of a Districtwide assessment or other test or evaluation as administered by an LEA rather than for assessing student proficiency levels or informing instruction and remediation needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"State Superintendent" means the head of OSSE appointed by the Mayor pursuant to § 38-2601.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 2b, as added Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-84, § 102(b), 61 DCR 178; Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-87, § 2(a), 61 DCR 309.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-84 added this section.</text>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-87 redesignated (1) as (1B); and added (1), (1A), (2A) and (2B).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-84</heading>
      <text>See note to § 38-2601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-87</heading>
      <text>Law 20-87, the "Fair Student Funding and School-Based Budgeting Amendment Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-309. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2013, and December 17, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 2, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-257 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-87 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
