<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-505</num>
  <heading>Indorser not guarantor for other parties.</heading>
  <text>The indorsement of a tangible document of title issued by a bailee does not make the indorser liable for any default by the bailee or previous indorsers.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 730, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-505.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-505.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:7-501.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</heading>
      <text>Section 37, Uniform Sales Act; Section 45, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act; Section 36, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes:</heading>
      <text>No substantial change.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>The indorsement of a document of title is generally understood to be directed towards perfecting the transferee's rights rather than towards assuming additional obligations. The language of the present section, however, does not preclude the one case in which an indorsement given for value guarantees future action, namely, that in which the bailee has not yet become liable upon the document at the time of the indorsement. Under such circumstances the indorser, of course, engages that appropriate honor of the document by the bailee will occur. See Section 7-502(1)(d) as to negotiable delivery orders. However, even in such a case, once the bailee attorns to the transferee, the indorser's obligation has been fulfilled and the policy of this section excludes any continuing obligation on the part of the indorser for the bailee's ultimate actual performance.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross Reference:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>Section 7-502.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>"Bailee". Section 7-102.</text>
      <text>"Document of title". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Party". Section 1-201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</heading>
      <text>Former Section 7-505.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes:</heading>
      <text>Limited to tangible documents of title.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Purposes:</heading>
      <text>This section is limited to tangible documents of title as the concept of indorsement is irrelevant to electronic documents of title. Electronic documents of title will be transferred by delivery of control. Section 7-106. The indorsement of a tangible document of title is generally understood to be directed towards perfecting the transferee's rights rather than towards assuming additional obligations. The language of the present section, however, does not preclude the one case in which an indorsement given for value guarantees future action, namely, that in which the bailee has not yet become liable upon the document at the time of the indorsement. Under such circumstances the indorser, of course, engages that appropriate honor of the document by the bailee will occur. See Section 7-502(a)(4) as to negotiable delivery orders. However, even in such a case, once the bailee attorns to the transferee, the indorser's obligation has been fulfilled and the policy of this section excludes any continuing obligation on the part of the indorser for the bailee's ultimate actual performance.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross Reference:</heading>
      <text>Sections 7-106 and 7-502.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text>"Bailee". Section 7-102.</text>
      <text>"Document of title". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Party". Section 1-201.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
