<level type="section">
  <num>34-1102</num>
  <heading>Use of equipment of other companies; application to Commission to require such use in event of disagreement.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 43-502</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Every utility doing business in the District of Columbia having tracks, conduits, subways, poles, wires, switchboards, exchanges, works, or other equipment shall, for a reasonable compensation, permit the use of the same by any other public utility whenever public convenience and necessity require such use, and such use will not result in irreparable injury to the owners or other users of such equipment; nor in any substantial detriment to the service to be rendered by such owners or other users. In case of failure to agree upon such use, or the conditions or compensation for such use, any public utility or any person, firm, copartnership, association, or corporation interested may apply to the Commission, and if after investigation the Commission shall ascertain that public convenience and necessity require such use and that it would not result in irreparable injury to the owners or other user of such equipment nor in any substantial detriment to the service to be rendered by such owners or other users of such equipment, it shall by order direct that such use be permitted and prescribe the conditions and compensation for such joint use. Such use so ordered shall be permitted and such conditions and compensation so prescribed shall be the lawful conditions and compensation to be observed, followed, and paid, subject to recourse to the courts upon the complaint of any interested party, as hereinafter provided, which provisions, so far as applicable, shall apply to any action arising on such complaint so made. Any such order of the Commission may be from time to time revised by the Commission upon application of any interested party or upon its own motion after hearing and notice by order in writing.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 977, ch. 150, ยง 8, par. 3.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 43-502.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 43-302.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
