<level type="section">
  <num>31-1401</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 35-3601</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Company" means any person engaging in or proposing or attempting to engage in any transaction or kind of insurance or surety business and any person or group of persons who may otherwise be subject to the insurance laws of the District of Columbia, including fraternal benefit associations and excluding the District of Columbia Life and Health Guaranty Association and the District of Columbia Property and Liability Insurance Guaranty Association.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"District" means the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Examiner" means any individual or firm having been authorized by the Mayor to conduct an examination under this chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Person" means any individual, aggregation of individuals, trust, association, partnership, or corporation, or any affiliate thereof.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-49, § 2, 40 DCR 6110; May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(ff)(1), 44 DCR 1730; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 39, 45 DCR 745; June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(j), 51 DCR 2817.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 35-3601.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-166, in par. (2A), substituted "Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking" for "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(j) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004, 51 DCR 2653).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 10-49, the "Law on Examinations Act of 1993," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-131, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 29, 1993, and July 13, 1993, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 4, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 10-94 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-49 became effective on October 21, 1993.</text>
        <text>Law 11-268, the "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation Establishment Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11- 415, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 30, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-524 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-268 became effective on May 21, 1997.</text>
        <text>Law 12-81, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-408, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1997, and December 4, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-246 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-81 became effective on March 24, 1998.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-166, see notes following § 31-1004.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Law 10-49, the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, see Mayor's Order 94-54, March 7, 1994 (41 DCR 1433).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Mayor authorized to issue rules: Section 10 of D.C. Law 10-49 provided that the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 15 of Title 1 [subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, 2001 Ed.], issue rules to implement the provisions of this chapter.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
