<level type="section">
  <num>31-1405</num>
  <heading>Conflict of interest.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No examiner may be appointed by the Mayor if the examiner, either directly or indirectly, has a conflict of interest or is affiliated with the management of or owns a pecuniary interest in any person subject to examination under this chapter. This section shall not be construed to automatically preclude an examiner from being:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A policyholder or claimant under an insurance policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A grantor of a mortgage or similar instrument on the examiner's residence to a regulated entity if done under customary terms and in the ordinary course of business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An investment owner in shares of regulated diversified investment companies; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A settlor or beneficiary of a blind trust into which any otherwise impermissible holdings have been placed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the requirements of this section, the Mayor may retain from time to time, on an individual basis, qualified actuaries, certified public accountants, or other similar individuals who are independently practicing their professions, even though these persons may from time to time be similarly employed or retained by persons subject to examination under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-49, ยง 6, 40 DCR 6110.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 35-3605.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-49</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-49, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 31-1401.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
