<level type="section">
  <num>31-1406</num>
  <heading>Cost of examinations.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 35-3606</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>All expenses of the examinations shall be paid by the company examined, and the company shall timely pay the Mayor the actual expense of such an examination upon receipt of itemized bills provided by the Mayor. For purposes of expenses assessed and paid under this section, the provisions of Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 shall not apply.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-49, § 7, 40 DCR 6110; Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-236, § 4, 49 DCR 10483.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 35-3606.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-236 added the last sentence.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation Procurement Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-159, June 25, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 6495).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation Procurement Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-314, March 26, 2002, 49 DCR 3451).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation Procurement Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-9, January 27, 2003, 50 DCR 1478).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-49, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1401.</text>
        <text>Law 14-236, the "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation Procurement Amendment Act of 2002", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-571, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 2, 2002, and October 1, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-515 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-236 became effective on March 25, 2003.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
