<level type="section">
  <num>22-3306</num>
  <heading>Defacing books, manuscripts, publications, or works of art.</heading>
  <text>Any person who shall wrongfully deface, injure, or mutilate, tear, or destroy any book, pamphlet, or manuscript, or any portion thereof belonging to the Library of Congress, or to any public library in the District of Columbia, whether the property of the United States or of the District of Columbia or of any individual or corporation in said District, or who shall wrongfully deface, injure, mutilate, tear, or destroy any book, pamphlet, document, manuscript, public record, print, engraving, medal, newspaper, or work of art, the property of the United States or of the District of Columbia, shall be held guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall, when the offense is not otherwise punishable by some statute of the United States, be punished by a fine of not less than $10 and not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, and by imprisonment for not less than 1 month nor more than 180 days, or both, for every such offense.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1327, ch. 854, § 849; June 30, 1902, 32 Stat. 535, ch. 1329; Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 601(d), 29 DCR 3976; Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 14(b), 32 DCR 3590; Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151,§ 105(n), 41 DCR 2608; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 201(l), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 22-3106.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 22-3106.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "and not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" for "nor more than $1,000".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 105(n) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994, 41 DCR 4286).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-164</heading>
      <text>Law 4-164, the "District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982." was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-133, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first and second readings on June 22, 1982, July 6, 1982, and July 20, 1982, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 4, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-238 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-19</heading>
      <text>Law 6-19, the "District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-139, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 14, 1985 and May 28, 1985, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 10, 1985, it was assigned Act No. 6-34 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-151</heading>
      <text>Law 10-151, the "Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Amendment Act of 1994," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 10-98, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 29, 1994, and April 12, 1994, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 4, 1994, it was assigned Act No. 10-238 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 10-151 became effective on August 20, 1994.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>See note to § 22-3301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
