<level type="section">
  <num>34-1251.02</num>
  <heading>Findings and purposes.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The rates, services, and operation of cable services and systems in the District affect the public interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Further development of cable television may result in greater benefits for District residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Cable television and cable technology play an essential role in the District's basic infrastructure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Cable systems occupy and extensively use scarce and valuable public rights-of-way in a manner reserved primarily for those who provide essential service to the public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Cable systems have the capacity to provide, in addition to entertainment and information services to District residents, a variety of broadband interactive communications services to individuals, the District government, and other institutions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>It is, and should be, the policy of the District of Columbia to provide fair regulation of cable service providers in the public interest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purposes of this subchapter are:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To ensure that any authority granted to provide cable service is exercised in the public interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To establish the procedures for granting, renewing, transferring, and revoking authority to provide cable services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To establish baseline standards for the operation of cable service providers in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To establish a framework for the ongoing regulation of cable service providers and for the promulgation of rules and regulations governing the provision of cable service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To encourage the optimum development of the economic, educational, and community service potentials of cable services and cable systems;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>To promote just and reasonable rates and charges for cable services without discrimination, undue preferences or advantages, or unfair or destructive competitive practices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>To promote harmonious relationships between cable operators and their customers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>To create and maintain an economic and regulatory environment that promotes competition in the cable television industry in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>To attract the deployment and maintenance of advanced cable services in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, ยง 102, as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, ยง 2(b), 49 DCR 7334.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-193</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-193, see notes following ยง 34-1251.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
