<level type="section">
  <num>28:4A-106</num>
  <heading>Time payment order is received.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The time of receipt of a payment order or communication cancelling or amending a payment order is determined by the rules applicable to receipt of a notice stated in § 28:1-202. A receiving bank may fix a cut-off time or times on a funds-transfer business day for the receipt and processing of payment orders and communications cancelling or amending payment orders. Different cut-off times may apply to payment orders, cancellations, or amendments, or to different categories of payment orders, cancellations, or amendments. A cut-off time may apply to senders generally or different cut-off times may apply to different senders or categories of payment orders. If a payment order or communication cancelling or amending a payment order is received after the close of a funds-transfer business day or after the appropriate cut-off time on a funds-transfer business day, the receiving bank may treat the payment order or communication as received at the opening of the next funds-transfer business day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If this article refers to an execution date or payment date or states a day on which a receiving bank is required to take action, and the date or day does not fall on a funds-transfer business day, the next day that is a funds-transfer business day is treated as the date or day stated, unless the contrary is stated in this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 30, 1992, D.C. Law 9-95, § 2(c), 39 DCR 1595; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 7(b), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:4A-106.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 substituted "§ 28:1-202" for "§ 28:1-201(27)" in the first sentence of (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-95</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-95, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:4A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:4A-105.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
