<level type="section">
  <num>28:4A-105</num>
  <heading>Other definitions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this article:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Authorized account" means a deposit account of a customer in a bank designated by the customer as a source of payment of payment orders issued by the customer to the bank. If a customer does not so designate an account, any account of the customer is an authorized account if payment of a payment order from that account is not inconsistent with a restriction on the use of that account.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Bank" means a person engaged in the business of banking and includes a savings bank, savings and loan association, credit union, and trust company. A branch or separate office of a bank is a separate bank for purposes of this article.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Customer" means a person, including a bank, having an account with a bank or from whom a bank has agreed to receive payment orders.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Funds-transfer business day" of a receiving bank means the part of a day during which the receiving bank is open for the receipt, processing, and transmittal of payment orders and cancellations and amendments of payment orders.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Funds-transfer system" means a wire transfer network, automated clearing house, or other communication system of a clearing house or other association of banks through which a payment order by a bank may be transmitted to the bank to which the order is addressed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Prove" with respect to a fact means to meet the burden of establishing the fact under § 28:1-201(b)(8).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Other definitions applying to this article and the sections in which they appear are:</text>
    <level type="form">
      <text/>
      <text>


 "Acceptance". § 28:4A-209 


 "Beneficiary". § 28:4A-103 


 "Beneficiary's bank". § 28:4A-103 


 "Executed". § 28:4A-301 


 "Execution date". § 28:4A-301 


 "Funds transfer". § 28:4A-104 


 "Funds-transfer system rule". § 28:4A-501 


 "Intermediary bank". § 28:4A-104 


 "Originator". § 28:4A-104 


 "Originator's bank". § 28:4A-104 


 "Payment by beneficiary's bank to beneficiary". § 28:4A-405 


 "Payment by originator to beneficiary". § 28:4A-406 


 "Payment by sender to receiving bank". § 28:4A-403 


 "Payment date". § 28:4A-401 


 "Payment order". § 28:4A-103 


 "Receiving bank". § 28:4A-103 


 "Security procedure". § 28:4A-201 


 "Sender". § 28:4A-103 
 
 (c) The following definitions in Article 4 apply to this article: 


 "Clearing house". § 28:4-104 


 "Item". § 28:4-104 


 "Suspends payments". § 28:4-104 
 
 (d) In addition Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 30, 1992, D.C. Law 9-95, § 2(c), 39 DCR 1595; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 7(a), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:4A-105.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 repealed (a)(6), which read: "'Good faith' means honesty in fact and the observance of reasonable commercial standards of fair dealing"; and substituted "under § 28:1-201(b)(8)" for "(§ 28:1-201(8))" in (a)(7).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-95</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-95, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:4A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
