<level type="section">
  <num>38-753.03</num>
  <heading>Pilot incentive program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established a pilot incentive program to encourage highly effective teachers to teach in high-need schools for the start of the 2013-2014 school year.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The incentives shall include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A one-time bonus of $10,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Homebuyer and other housing assistance, including:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Access to subsidized rental housing units;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Forgivable loans for a down payment of up to 10% of the median home price in the District; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Access to low-interest mortgage loans;</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An amount of up to $5,000 to be expended on tuition assistance, which may include reimbursement for specific courses that lead to certification in high-demand subject areas, such as math and science, and loan-repayment assistance for existing education loans; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An amount of up to $3,000 to be used as income tax credits.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The incentives shall not exceed the maximum allowable amounts over the 3- year period of the pilot program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The pilot program shall consist of 4 high-need schools. At least one of the schools shall be a tier one or tier 2 public charter school.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At least 3, but not more than 5, teachers shall be selected for each school of the 4 schools in the pilot program.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall establish a plan to implement the pilot program. The plan shall be submitted to the Council for review within 90 days of June 19, 2012. The plan shall include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A process for teachers to apply to the program;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A process for selecting qualified applicants, which shall include a requirement that a teacher commit to serving a minimum of 3 years at a high-need school; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Guidelines for selecting high-need schools, which shall include schools that have:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A proficiency in both reading and math of 40% or below; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>At least 75% or more of students who qualify for free or reduced-price lunch; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Guidelines for selecting highly effective teachers.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For DCPS, highly effective teachers shall be selected according to IMPACT standards. For public charter schools, the Mayor shall work with each public charter school to develop the criteria for selecting highly effective teachers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 19, 2012, D.C. Law 19-142, ยง 303, 59 DCR 3642.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 19-142, see notes under ยง 38-751.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
