<level type="section">
  <num>1-610.57</num>
  <heading>Performance incentives</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-611.57</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The Mayor may authorize performance incentives for exceptional service for subordinate agency heads not to exceed 10% of the rate of basic pay in any year. Exceptional service incentives may be paid only if:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The agency head is bound by a performance contract, available to the public upon request, that clearly identifies measurable goals and outcomes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The agency head has exceeded contractual expectations in the year for which the incentive is paid.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1057, as added June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(m), 45 DCR 2464; Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 2802, 49 DCR 6968.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-611.57.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-190 rewrote the section which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"The Mayor may authorize performance incentives for exceptional service for subordinate agency heads not to exceed 10% of the rate of basic pay in any year. Exceptional service incentives may be paid only when the agency head is bound by a performance contract that clearly identifies measurable goals and outcomes and the agency head has exceeded contractual expectations in the year for which the incentive is paid."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2702 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8026).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-124, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-603.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 14-190, see notes following § 1-301.131.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Applicability of § 101(m) of D.C. Law 12-124: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-610.51.</text>
        <text>Short title of title XXVIII of Law 14-190: Section 2801 of D.C. Law 14-190 provided that title XXVIII of the act may be cited as the Executive Compensation and Fiscal Responsibility Amendment Act of 2002.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
