<level type="section">
  <num>9-204.13</num>
  <heading>Authority of the Committee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall act in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Council to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Develop criteria to be used to review, evaluate, approve, or deny applications for placement of commemorative works on public space in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Review each application for placement of a commemorative work on public space in the District, by considering: the appropriateness of the location, subject matter, and design of the commemorative work, including the aesthetic, environmental, traffic and parking, and financial impacts of the proposal upon the surrounding community and the District; and the sufficiency of the sponsor to fund the construction and maintenance of the commemorative work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Refer each application for a commemorative work on public space in the District for review and comments by affected advisory neighborhood commissions, by affected District agencies and public utilities, and by the National Capital Memorial Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Recommend to the Mayor and the Council a disposition of each application for placement of a commemorative work on public space in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The recommendations of the Committee shall not be inconsistent with:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital (10 DCMR);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Home Rule Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia (11 DCMR); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Public Space and Safety Regulations of the District of Columbia (24 DCMR).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, ยง 413, as added Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-275, ยง 2(d), 48 DCR 1660.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see ยง 2(d) of the Commemorative Works on Public Space Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-564, January 31, 2001, 48 DCR 1627).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-275, see notes following ยง 9-204.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
