<level type="section">
  <num>9-204.11</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>"Commemorative work" means any statue, monument, sculpture, streetscape or landscape feature, including a garden or memorial grove, or other structure, which is located on public space and which is designed to perpetuate in a permanent manner the memory of an individual, group, event, or other significant element of international, national, or local culture or history.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>"Commemorative work" does not mean any statue, monument, sculpture, streetscape or landscape feature, including a garden or memorial grove, or other structure, which is (i) located within the interior of a structure that is not itself a commemorative work; (ii) a structure that is used primarily for other purposes; or (iii) intended to be displayed for only a limited period of time that does not exceed one year.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>"Commemorative work" does not mean the naming of an existing public space, a plaque, or a wayside or wayfinding sign or commemorative feature incorporated within ordinary walkway paving.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>"Public space" means any public street, alley, circle, bridge, building, park, other public place or property owned by or under the administrative control or jurisdiction of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>"Public space" does not include property that is both owned by the Federal government and under the administrative control or jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the General Services Administration, the Department of Defense, or other federal agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Sponsor" means a Federal or District agency, or an individual, group, or organization that is described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, and which is authorized by the Mayor and Council to establish a commemorative work on public space in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, ยง 411, as added Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-275, ยง 2(d), 48 DCR 1660.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see ยง 2(d) of the Commemorative Works on Public Space Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-564, January 31, 2001, 48 DCR 1627).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-275</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-275, see notes following ยง 9-204.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
