<level type="section">
  <num>28:6-102</num>
  <heading>Definitions and index of definitions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this article, unless the context otherwise requires, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Assets" means the inventory that is the subject of a bulk sale and any tangible and intangible personal property used or held for use primarily in, or arising from, the seller's business and sold in connection with that inventory, but the term does not include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Fixtures (§ 28:9-102(a)(41)) other than readily removable factory and office machines;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The lessee's interest in a lease of real property; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Property to the extent it is generally exempt from creditor process under nonbankruptcy law.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Auctioneer" means a person whom the seller engages to direct, conduct, control, or be responsible for a sale by auction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Bulk sale" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of a sale by auction or a sale or series of sales conducted by a liquidator on the seller's behalf, a sale or series of sales not in the ordinary course of the seller's business of more than half of the seller's inventory, as measured by value on the date of the bulk-sale agreement, if on that date the auctioneer or liquidator has notice, or after reasonable inquiry would have had notice, that the seller will not continue to operate the same or a similar kind of business after the sale or series of sales; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In all other cases, a sale not in the ordinary course of the seller's business of more than half the seller's inventory, as measured by value on the date of the bulk-sale agreement, if on that date the buyer has notice, or after reasonable inquiry would have had notice, that the seller will not continue to operate the same or a similar kind of business after the sale.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Claim" means a right to payment from the seller, whether or not the right is reduced to judgment, liquidated, fixed, matured, disputed, secured, legal, or equitable. The term includes costs of collection and attorney's fees only to the extent that the laws of the District permit the holder of the claim to recover them in an action against the obligor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Claimant" means a person holding a claim incurred in the seller's business other than:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An unsecured and unmatured claim for employment compensation and benefits, including commissions and vacation, severance, and sick-leave pay;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A claim for injury to an individual or to property, or for breach of warranty, unless:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A right of action for the claim has accrued;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The claim has been asserted against the seller; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The seller knows the identity of the person asserting the claim and the basis upon which the person has asserted it; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A claim for taxes owing to a governmental unit, if:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A statute governing the enforcement of the claim permits or requires notice of the bulk sale to be given to the governmental unit in a manner other than by compliance with the requirements of this article; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Notice is given in accordance with the statute.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Creditor" means a claimant or other person holding a claim.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Date of the bulk sale" means:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>If the sale is by auction or is conducted by a liquidator on the seller's behalf, the date on which more than 10% of the net proceeds is paid to or for the benefit of the seller; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In all other cases, the later of the date on which:</text>
          <level>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>More than 10% of the net contract price is paid to or for the benefit of the seller; or</text>
          </level>
          <level>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>More than 10% of the assets, as measured by value, are transferred to the buyer.</text>
          </level>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For purposes of this subsection:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Delivery of a negotiable instrument (§ 28:3-104(a)) to or for the benefit of the seller in exchange for assets constitutes payment of the contract price pro tanto;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>To the extent that the contract price is deposited in an escrow, the contract price is paid to or for the benefit of the seller when the seller acquires the unconditional right to receive the deposit or when the deposit is delivered to the seller or for the benefit of the seller, whichever is earlier; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>An asset is transferred when a person holding an unsecured claim can no longer obtain through judicial proceedings rights to the asset that are superior to those of the buyer arising as a result of the bulk sale. A person holding an unsecured claim can obtain those superior rights to a tangible asset at least until the buyer has an unconditional right, under the bulk-sale agreement, to possess the asset, and a person holding an unsecured claim can obtain those superior rights to an intangible asset at least until the buyer has an unconditional right, under the bulk-sale agreement, to use the asset.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Date of the bulk-sale agreement" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of a sale by auction or conducted by a liquidator, the date on which the seller engages the auctioneer or liquidator; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In all other cases, the date on which a bulk-sale agreement becomes enforceable between the buyer and the seller.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Debt" means liability on a claim.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Liquidator" means a person who is regularly engaged in the business of disposing of assets for businesses contemplating liquidation or dissolution.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Mayor" means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Net contract price" means the new consideration the buyer is obligated to pay for the assets less:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The amount of any proceeds of the sale of an asset, to the extent the proceeds are applied in partial or total satisfaction of a debt secured by the asset; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of any debt to the extent it is secured by a security interest or lien that is enforceable against the asset before and after it has been sold to a buyer. If a debt is secured by an asset and other property of the seller, the amount of the debt secured by a security interest or lien that is enforceable against the asset is determined by multiplying the debt by a fraction, the numerator of which is the value of the new consideration for the asset on the date of the bulk sale and the denominator of which is the value of all property securing the debt on the date of the bulk sale.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Net proceeds" means the new consideration received for assets sold at a sale by auction or a sale conducted by a liquidator on the seller's behalf less:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Commissions and reasonable expenses of the sale;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of any proceeds of the sale of an asset, to the extent the proceeds are applied in partial or total satisfaction of a debt secured by the asset; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The amount of any debt to the extent it is secured by a security interest or lien that is enforceable against the asset before and after it has been sold to a buyer. If a debt is secured by an asset and other property of the seller, the amount of the debt secured by a security interest or lien that is enforceable against the asset is determined by multiplying the debt by a fraction, the numerator of which is the value of the new consideration for the asset on the date of the bulk sale and the denominator of which is the value of all property securing the debt on the date of the bulk sale.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>A sale is "in the ordinary course of the seller's business" if the sale comports with usual or customary practices in the kind of business in which the seller is engaged or with the seller's own usual or customary practices.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"United States" includes its territories and possessions and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"Value" means fair market value.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>"Verified" means signed and sworn to or affirmed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following definitions in other Articles apply to this article:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Buyer." § 28:2-103(1)(a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Equipment." § 28:9-102(a)(33).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Inventory." § 28:9-102(a)(48).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Sale." § 28:2-106(1).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Seller." § 28:2-103(1)(d).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition, Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 714, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Feb. 7, 1980, D.C. Law 3-49, § 2, 26 DCR 2731; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-239, § 2, 44 DCR 936; Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(g)(1), 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:6-104.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:6-102.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:6-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-201, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 3-49</heading>
      <text>Law 3-49, the "Uniform Commercial Code - Bulk Transfers Amendment Act of 1979," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-104, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 6, 1979 and November 20, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 12, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-135 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-239</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-239, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:6-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>Law 13-201, the "Uniform Commercial Code Secured Transactions Revision Act of 2000," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-370, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 6, 2000, and July 11, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 11, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-434 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-201 became effective on October 26, 2000.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
