<level type="section">
  <num>29-701.09</num>
  <heading>Partnership agreement; effect on third parties and relationship to records effective on behalf of limited partnership.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A partnership agreement may specify that its amendment requires the approval of a person that is not a party to the agreement or the satisfaction of a condition. An amendment is ineffective if its adoption does not include the required approval or satisfy the specified condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The obligations of a limited partnership and its partners to a person in the person's capacity as a transferee or person dissociated as a partner are governed by the partnership agreement. Subject only to a court order issued under § 29-707.03(b)(2) to effectuate a charging order, an amendment to the partnership agreement made after a person becomes a transferee or is dissociated as a partner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is effective with regard to any debt, obligation, or other liability of the limited partnership or its partners to the person in the person's capacity as a transferee or person dissociated as a partner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is not effective to the extent the amendment imposes a new debt, obligation, or other liability on the transferee or person dissociated as a partner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a record delivered by a limited partnership to the Mayor for filing becomes effective and contains a provision that would be ineffective under § 29-701.07(b) or (c)(2) if contained in the partnership agreement, the provision is ineffective in the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, if a record delivered by a limited partnership to the Mayor for filing becomes effective and conflicts with a provision of the partnership agreement:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The agreement prevails as to partners, persons dissociated as partners, and transferees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The record prevails as to other persons to the extent they reasonably rely on the record.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(2)(G), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-701.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 2(g)(2)(F) of D.C. Law 19-210 redesignated former § 20-701.09 as § 29-701.11.</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
