<level type="section">
  <num>29-1014.03</num>
  <heading>Notice and action on disposition of assets.</heading>
  <text>For a limited cooperative association to dispose of assets under ยง 29- 1014.02:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A majority of the board of directors, or a greater percentage if required by the organic rules, shall approve the proposed disposition; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The board of directors shall call a members meeting to consider the proposed disposition, hold the meeting not later than 90 days after approval of the proposed disposition by the board, and mail or otherwise transmit or deliver in a record to each member:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The terms of the proposed disposition;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A recommendation that the members approve the disposition or, if the board determines that because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances, it should not make a favorable recommendation, the basis for that determination;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A statement of any condition of the board's submission of the proposed disposition to the members; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Notice of the meeting at which the proposed disposition will be considered, which shall be given in the same manner as notice of a special meeting of members.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 1503 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act . See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
