<level type="section">
  <num>47-2853.122</num>
  <heading>Eligibility requirements.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 47-2853.122</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant to be an apprentice plumber shall be registered by the Mayor, without examination, upon providing such information as may be required by the Board of Industrial Trades and payment of appropriate fees. An apprentice plumber shall work only under the direct personal supervision and control of a licensed master plumber/gasfitter or master gasfitter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a journeyman plumber or journeyman gasfitter shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Industrial Trades that the applicant has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Worked as an apprentice plumber or gasfitter for at least 8,000 hours over at least 4 years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Graduated from an accredited college or university with a degree in mechanical engineering, and has at least 2 years of practical experience as a plumber or gasfitter as verified by a licensed master plumber or licensed master gasfitter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has comparable experience or a combination of education and experience that the Board deems equivalent to the above; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Such additional evidence as the Board determines is necessary for the particular specialty license sought by the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a master plumber/gasfitter or master gasfitter shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant has a valid license as a journeyman plumber or gasfitter, or has met the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, and has worked as a journeyman plumber or journeyman gasfitter for at least 4 years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, ยง 1002, 46 DCR 3142.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 47-2853.122.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 47-2801.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
