<level type="section">
  <num>28:1-101</num>
  <heading>Short titles.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This subtitle may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code".</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This article may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code - General Provisions".</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 631, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 2, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 34-2202.09 and § 42-2704.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:1-101.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:1-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 39(a) of D.C. Law 15-354 provided that Title 28 is designated Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code.</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-300 amended this article in its entirety, substituting present §§ 28:1-101 through 28:1-310 for former §§ 28:1-101 through 28:1-208. Although similar in many respects to former Article 1, the statute sections in the revised Article are sufficiently different that a detailed explanation of the changes was impracticable; however, where possible, the historical citations from the former sections have been transferred to the new, similar sections. Where appropriate, annotations to former sections have also been retained under corresponding sections in the amended article.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Source:</heading>
      <text>Former Section 1-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes from former law:</heading>
      <text>Subsection (b) is new. It is added in order to make the structure of Article 1 parallel with that of the other articles of the Uniform Commercial Code.</text>
      <text>1. Each other article of the Uniform Commercial Code (except Articles 10 and 11) may also be cited by its own short title. See Sections 2-101, 2A-101, 3-101, 4-101, 4A-101, 5-101, 6-101, 7-101, 8-101, and 9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
