<level type="section">
  <num>2-1831.06</num>
  <heading>Commission on Selection and Tenure of Administrative Law Judges of the Office of Administrative Hearings.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Commission on Selection and Tenure of Administrative Law Judges of the Office of Administrative Hearings. The Commission's mission shall be to ensure the recruitment and retention of a well-qualified, efficient, and effective corps of Administrative Law Judges in the Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have final authority to appoint, reappoint, discipline, and remove Administrative Law Judges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No Administrative Law Judge shall be appointed to an initial term without the affirmative vote of a majority of the voting members of the Commission; provided, that the Commission shall appoint to an initial term as an Administrative Law Judge any hearing examiner employed by an agency to which this chapter becomes applicable if that person timely seeks the appointment and is eligible for the appointment pursuant to § 2-1831.08(e).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Commission members shall have protection from liability as provided in § 2-415(b-1).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-76, § 9, 48 DCR 11442; Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-217, § 3(b), 51 DCR 9126.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-415.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-217 added (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Commission on Selection and Tenure of Administrative Law Judges Non-Liability Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Law 15-169, June 19, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 7334).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Commission on Selection and Tenure of Administrative Law Judges Non-Liability Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-389, March 18, 2004, 51 DCR 3387).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Commission on Selection and Tenure of Administrative Law Judges Non-Liability Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-444, June 23, 2004, 51 DCR 6556).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-76</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-76, see notes following § 2-1831.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-217</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-217, see notes following § 2-1831.03.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
