<level type="section">
  <num>38-353</num>
  <heading>Duties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Ombudsman shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide outreach to residents and parents, and to further this purpose, have the cooperation of all individuals within the public school system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Encourage communication between residents and the Mayor regarding all levels of public education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Serve as a vehicle for citizens to communicate their complaints and concerns regarding public education through a single office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Respond to complaints and concerns in a timely fashion with accurate and helpful information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Receive complaints and concerns from parents, students, teachers, and other District residents concerning public education, including personnel actions, policies, and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Determine the validity of any complaint quickly and professionally;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Examine and address valid complaints and concerns;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Generate options for a response, and offer a recommendation among the options;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Make a referral to the pertinent school official, when appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Identify systemic concerns raised by citizens, or otherwise received, related to public education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Maintain a database that tracks complaints and concerns received according to various categories, including school level and location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Deputy Mayor for Public Education and the Chairman of the Council, on a monthly basis, an analysis of the preceding month, including complaint and resolution data;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Recommend policy changes, staff training, and strategies to improve the delivery of public education services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Systemically track complaints and concerns, and periodically analyze the data and report to the Deputy Mayor for Education patterns of complaints and concerns that suggest a need for a policy change, staff training, or the implementation of strategic action to address an issue; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days of the end of each school year, submit to the Deputy Mayor for Education a report analyzing the work of the previous year, including an analysis of the types, and number, of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Inquiries;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Complaints and concerns resolved informally;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Complaints and concerns examined;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Examinations pending;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Recommendations made; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Recommendations that were followed, to the extent that it can be determined.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 604, 54 DCR 4102.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 38-191.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-9</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-9, see notes following § 38-351.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 3(b) of D.C. Law 19-284 rewrote (12); in the introductory language of (15), substituted "45 days" for "90 days"; and substituted "Deputy Mayor for Education, the Council, the State Board of Education a report, which shall be posted on their websites," for "Deputy Mayor for Education a report".</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-284: Section 5 of D.C. Law 19-284 provided that section 3 of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
