<level type="section">
  <num>1-608.54</num>
  <heading>Appointment of attorneys.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-609.54</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Attorneys employed by the Office of the Attorney General shall be hired by the Attorney General. Attorneys, including Senior Executive Attorneys, employed by the Office of the Attorney General who perform work primarily for any other subordinate agency, whether located at that agency or not, shall be hired by the Attorney General after consultation with the head of the other subordinate agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Attorneys employed by an independent agency shall be hired by the head of the agency or the Senior Executive Attorney designee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Legal Service attorneys may be hired noncompetitively.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 854, as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-260, § 2(j), 46 DCR 1318; Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 110(c), 47 DCR 520; Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 3012(d), 52 DCR 7503.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-609.54.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-91, in subsec. (b), added "or the Senior Executive Attorney designee"; and added subsec. (c).</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-33 rewrote subsec. (a), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) Attorneys employed by the Office of the Corporation Counsel, wherever located in the District government, shall be hired by the Corporation Counsel. Attorneys, including Senior Executive Attorneys, employed by any other subordinate agency shall be hired by the head of the agency with the approval of the Corporation Counsel."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of subchapter, see note to § 1-608.51.</text>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-203, December 8, 1999, 46 DCR 10456).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-293, March 7, 2000, 47 DCR 2063).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3012(d) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-260, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-604.04.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-91, see notes following § 1-602.03.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following § 1-617.17.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
