<level type="section">
  <num>1-608.55</num>
  <heading>Supervision of attorneys.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Attorneys employed by the Office of the Attorney General, wherever located in the District government, including Senior Executive attorneys, shall act under the direction, supervision, and control of the Attorney General.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the authority vested in the Attorney General by subsection (a) of this section, the Attorney General may delegate the direction, supervision and control of attorneys who perform work primarily for any other subordinate agency, whether located at the agency or not, to the head of that agency as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After consulting with the agency head, delegate in writing the direction, supervision and control of all or some of the attorneys who perform work primarily for the agency, including Senior Executive Attorneys. This delegation may be withdrawn at any time, in writing, after consulting with the agency head.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The delegation and its withdrawal, if any, pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall cite the reasons for the delegation or withdrawal of delegation using the following criteria:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Agency size;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Agency workload;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Necessity or lack of necessity for agency in-house counsel to engage in high level policy-making;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Agency head or agency General Counsel or the equivalent, expressed preferences;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Necessity or lack of necessity for Attorney General supervision;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Practicality or impracticality of Attorney General supervision;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Existence of a conflict of interest if the Attorney General supervises agency counsel; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Any other relevant factor as identified by the Attorney General.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Attorneys employed by independent agencies shall act under the direction, supervision, and control of the respective agency heads.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After consulting with the affected subordinate agency head, assign an attorney employed by the Office of the Attorney General who previously performed work primarily for the Office of the Attorney General to perform work primarily for the affected subordinate agency, whether located at the agency or not, in the Attorney General's discretion; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After consulting with the affected sending and receiving subordinate agency heads, assign an attorney employed by the Office of the Attorney General who previously performed work primarily for the sending agency, including the Office of the Attorney General, to perform work primarily for the receiving agency, whether located at the receiving agency or not in the Attorney General's discretion, unless the Attorney General has delegated the direction, supervision, and control of the attorney pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 855, as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-260, § 2(j), 46 DCR 1318; Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 3012(e), 52 DCR 7503.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-608.53, § 1-608.56, § 7-771.06, and § 7-1131.08.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-609.55.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-33, rewrote subsec. (a), (b) and (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of subchapter, see note to § 1-608.51.</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3012(e) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-260</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-260, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-604.04.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-33</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following § 1-617.17.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
