<level type="section">
  <num>999-2</num>
  <heading>Domestic Violence Hotline.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office shall establish the Domestic Violence Hotline to provide assistance for victims and potential victims of domestic violence beginning October 1, 2014.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Hotline shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be operated by a domestic violence program funded and supported by the Office;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Provide a direct toll-free number that accepts calls and text messages;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Be directly available to callers, without an intermediary agency;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Be available on a 24-hour basis;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Provide live assistance by domestic violence counselors; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Offer anonymity and confidentiality to enable a victim or a friend or family member of a victim to seek support without giving his or her legal name.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The requirements of paragraph (1)(F) of this subsection shall not be construed to limit or supersede any mandatory reporting requirements under District law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Office shall develop and implement an outreach campaign to educate District residents about the Hotline.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3033, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-551.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3033 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 3033 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 4-551.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 3031 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle D of Title III of the act may be cited as the "Domestic Violence Hotline Establishment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
