<level type="section">
  <num>2-1431.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this unit, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"ADA" means the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 <text i="True">et seq.</text>).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"ADA Compliance Program" means the program established by § 2-1431.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Agency" means all agencies and instrumentalities of the District government.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Disability" means, with respect to an individual:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more of the major life activities of such individual;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A record of such an impairment; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Being regarded as having such an impairment.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Human Rights Act" means Unit A of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Mayor's Committee on Persons with Disabilities" means the Mayor's Committee on Persons with Disabilities, established by Mayor's Order 88-245 (November 16, 1998), and amended by Mayor's Order 2002-79 (April 15, 2002).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Office" means the Office of Disability Rights established by § 2- 1431.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Office of Human Rights" means the Office of Human Rights established by § 2-1411.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Olmstead Compliance Plan" means a comprehensive working plan, developed in collaboration with individuals with disabilities and with District agencies serving individuals with disabilities, which shall include annual legislative, regulatory, and budgetary recommendations for the District to serve qualified individuals with disabilities in accordance with <text i="True">Olmstead v. L.C.</text>, 527 U.S. 581, and in the most integrated setting as provided in 28 C.F.R. Part 35, App. A.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Rehabilitation Act" means the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, approved September 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 355; 29 U.S.C. § 701 <text i="True">et seq.</text>).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-239, § 2, 54 DCR 404.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 16-239, the "Disability Rights Protection Act of 2006", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-866, which was referred to Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-595 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-239 became effective on March 8, 2007.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Re-Establishment of the District of Columbia Commission on Persons with Disabilities, see Mayor's Order 2009-165, September 25, 2009 (56 DCR 8093).</text>
        <text>Section 7083 of D.C. Law 17-219 repealed Section 10 of D.C. Law 16-239.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
