<level type="section">
  <num>2-1431.03</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office of Disability Rights.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Office of Disability Rights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purpose of the Office is to advance the civil rights of people with disabilities by coordinating the District's ADA Compliance Program and by ensuring and overseeing District-wide compliance with the ADA and related disability-rights laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Mayor with ยง 1-523.01(a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director shall serve as the Chief Administrative Officer, and may organize personnel, re-delegate authority, develop programs, and take any other action consistent with appropriations and other applicable law. Annual compensation for the Director shall be fixed in accordance with subchapter X-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the position of Director is vacant or about to be vacant, the Mayor may receive input on the selection of the Director from the Mayor's Committee on Persons with Disabilities and shall endeavor to hire a qualified individual with a disability.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition to a Director, the Office shall at a minimum have the following full-time staff:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In fiscal year 2007, 3 full-time staff to include a Deputy Director, a communications specialist, and an administrative assistant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In fiscal year 2008 and thereafter, the Director may, pursuant to subsection (c) of this section and subject to appropriations, increase the number of staff members and organize the Office as the Director may determine is necessary and appropriate to carry out the Office's mission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Director shall endeavor to hire qualified individuals with disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-239, ยง 4, 54 DCR 404.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-239, see notes following ยง 2-1431.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
