<level type="section">
  <num>47-1264</num>
  <heading>Interest and penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a nursing facility fails to pay the full amount of an assessment by the date required by this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to § 47-1267, the unpaid balance shall accrue interest at the rate of 1.5% per month or any fraction thereof, which shall be added to the unpaid balance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A nursing facility that fails to file a report required under this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to § 47-1267, shall pay an administrative penalty equal to 5% of the monthly assessment for each month, or any fraction thereof, that the failure to file continues. The total administrative penalty shall not exceed 25% of the nursing facility's annual assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A nursing facility that knowingly provides false information in a report required by this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to § 47-1267, shall be subject to a penalty equal to the tax owed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall have a lien upon the real and personal property located in the District of Columbia of the nursing facility for any assessments, interest, or administrative penalties that are due under this chapter, or rules issued pursuant to § 47-1267. The District of Columbia shall have the priority of a secured creditor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any action brought to enforce the provisions of subsection (c) of this section shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 5202(c), 51 DCR 8441; Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 1242(b), 52 DCR 7503.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-1262 and § 47-1266.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-33, in subsec. (a), deleted the second sentence, which had read as follows: "The Chief Financial Officer may arrange a payment plan for the amount of the assessment and interest in arrears."; and, in subsec. (c), substituted "equal to the tax owed." for "of not more than $1,000".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004, 51 DCR 8236).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5202(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR 11725).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1242(b) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-205</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-205, see notes following § 47-1261.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-33</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following § 47-308.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
