<level type="section">
  <num>5-431</num>
  <heading>Fire and Emergency Medical Services training for non-District of Columbia personnel.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may provide training to non-District of Columbia government agencies, organizations, and individuals through the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department ("Department"), including hazardous materials training, firefighting training, emergency medical technician training, fire extinguisher safety training, and cardiopulmonary resuscitation training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may impose fees to cover the costs of any training provided under subsection (a) of this section. The fees shall be established in accordance with Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, ยง 702, 50 DCR 5668.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 702 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003, 50 DCR 5613).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 702 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003, 50 DCR 8360).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 15-39, see notes following ยง 5-101.04.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of Authority Pursuant to Title VII of the Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003, effective September 22, 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149; 50 DCR 8389), see Mayor's Order 2004-7, January 14, 2004 (51 DCR 873).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title of title VII of Law 15-39: Section 701 of D.C. Law 15-39 provided that title VII of the act may be cited as the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Training Act of 2003.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
