<level type="section">
  <num>7-210.01</num>
  <heading>New certificates of birth for change of gender designation.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall establish a new certificate of birth that reflects the new gender designation and, if applicable, the new name of an individual born in the District upon receipt of the following documents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A written request, signed under penalty of law, for a new certificate of birth with a gender designation that differs from the gender designated on the original certificate of birth, from the individual or, if the individual is a minor, the individual's:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Parent;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Guardian; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Legal representative;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement, signed under the penalty of law, by a licensed healthcare provider who has treated or evaluated the individual, stating that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The individual has undergone surgical, hormonal, or other treatment appropriate for the individual for the purpose of gender transition, based on contemporary medical standards; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The individual has an intersex condition, and that in the healthcare provider's professional opinion, the individual's gender designation should be changed; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If a change of name listed on the certificate is also being requested, an original or certified copy of an order of a court of competent jurisdiction granting a change of name.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall establish, upon request, a new certificate of birth reflecting the new gender designation, new name, or name as previously amended, in these additional circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When an individual holds an amended certificate of birth issued before November 5, 2013, that reflects a previous name change and seeks a change of gender designation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When an individual, who is requesting a change of name, holds a certificate of birth previously issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section that reflects a change in gender; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>When an individual holds an amended certificate of birth issued before November 5, 2013, that reflects a previous change in gender designation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A new certificate of birth, issued in accordance with subsection (a) or (b) of this section, shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be substituted for the original certificate of birth; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Not be marked "amended" or on its face show that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A change in gender has been made;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A change in name has been made; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Both.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The original certificate of birth, along with any documents submitted pursuant to this section, shall be sealed and made available only upon the demand of the individual to whom the new certificate of birth was issued or an order of the Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 8, 1981, D.C. Law 4-34, ยง 11a, as added Nov. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 20-37, ยง 2(c), 60 DCR 12145.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 16-2503.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-37 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-37</heading>
      <text>See note to ยง 7-205.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
