<level type="section">
  <num>26-551.20</num>
  <heading>Judicial review.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days after service of a temporary cease and desist order, a financial institution or other party named in the temporary cease and desist order may apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an injunction to set aside, limit, or suspend the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A final order or a final cease and desist order issued under this chapter shall be reviewable by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. The review of the final order or the final cease and desist order shall be confined to the record of the hearing conducted under § 26-551.13 and to a determination of whether the Commissioner's order was arbitrary or capricious.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to any temporary cease and desist order, final order. or final cease and desist order issued by the Commissioner pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section, any final order of the Commissioner or final action of the Department shall be subject to review by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, unless the final order or final agency action is appealable to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals pursuant to § 2-510.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 120, 48 DCR 3244; Nov. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 20-40, § 3, 60 DCR 12304.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-40 added subsection (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-308</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-308, see notes following § 26-551.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-40</heading>
      <text>Law 20-40, the "Saving D.C. Homes from Foreclosure Clarification and Title Insurance Clarification Amendment Act of 2013", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-268. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 26, 2013 and July 10, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 20, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-156 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-40 became effective on Nov. 5, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-40: Section 8 of D.C. Law 20-40 provided that §§ 2 and 3 of the act shall apply as of November 7, 2011.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
