<level type="section">
  <num>1-350.09</num>
  <heading>Offset of delinquent debt against District employee pay and against contractual obligations to District contractors.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Central Collection Unit may collect delinquent debt from District employees by deducting delinquent debt from the biweekly pay of District employees, in an amount not to exceed 10% of an employee's gross biweekly pay, until the delinquent debt is fully satisfied.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a District employee's wages are subject to a preexisting attachment or attachments, the Central Collection Unit shall not exercise its authority under paragraph (1) of this subsection until the preexisting attachments have been satisfied, in order of priority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Central Collection Unit may collect delinquent debt from District contractors by deducting the delinquent debt from any amounts owed to a District contractor pursuant to a contractual obligation between the District and the contractor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Contractual obligation" includes an obligation arising from a contract or a grant agreement described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph that is entered into after September 20, 2012.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"District contractor" includes any person who receives payments from the District pursuant to a contract or a grant agreement that requires the grantee to perform services in consideration for the payment of the grant amount.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Central Collection Unit may collect delinquent debts by offsetting District tax refunds and District lottery winnings against delinquent debts owed to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, ยง 1050, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 19-168, see notes under ยง 1-350.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
