<level type="section">
  <num>1-350.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Central Collection Unit" means the Central Collection Unit established within the Office of Finance and Treasury of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to implement this subchapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Delinquent debt" means any financial obligation owed by a person to a District agency that remains unpaid more than 90 days after it was due; provided, that the term shall not include tax debts or child-support debts.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Delinquent Debt Fund" or "Fund" means the Delinquent Debt Fund established by ยง 1-350.04.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"District agency" means any District office, department, or agency, including independent agencies, but not including the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Person" means any natural person, trust, corporation, limited liability corporation, partnership, limited liability partnership, or any other business organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, ยง 1042, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title: Section 1041 of D.C. Law 19-168 provided that subtitle E of title I of the act may be cited as "Delinquent Debt Recovery Act of 2012."</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
