<level type="section">
  <num>1-350.04</num>
  <heading>Delinquent Debt Fund.</heading>
  <text>There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a special nonlapsing fund known as the Delinquent Debt Fund ("Fund"). Funds allocated to the Central Collection Unit through the District's annual Budget and Financial Plan, all delinquent debts collected by the Central Collection Unit, except those amounts collected by the Central Collection Unit described in § 1-350.02(a-1) and (a-2), and all fees authorized by § 1-350.03 shall be deposited into the Fund; provided, that any funds deposited in the Fund before the then-current fiscal year, including any interest earned on such funds before the then-current fiscal year, the money remaining in the Fund after the payment of all costs and expenses accrued before the then-current fiscal year, less 10% of such remainder, which shall be retained as a reserve operating balance, shall be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia. All funds deposited in the Fund shall be administered and used by the Central Collection Unit, subject to appropriation by Congress, to conduct the authorized activities of the Central Collection Unit.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1045, 59 DCR 8025; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7032(c), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-350.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 added "except those amounts collected by the Central Collection Unit described in § 1-350.02(a-1) and (a-2)" in the second sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 7032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-350.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-350.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 7031 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle C of Title VII of the act may be cited as the "Delinquent Debt Recovery Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
