<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-324</num>
  <heading>Priority of purchase-money security interests.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a perfected purchase-money security interest in goods other than inventory or livestock has priority over a conflicting security interest in the same goods, and, except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-327, a perfected security interest in its identifiable proceeds also has priority, if the purchase-money security interest is perfected when the debtor receives possession of the collateral or within 20 days thereafter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) and except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a perfected purchase-money security interest in inventory has priority over a conflicting security interest in the same inventory, has priority over a conflicting security interest in chattel paper or an instrument constituting proceeds of the inventory and in proceeds of the chattel paper, if so provided in § 28:9-330, and, except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-327, also has priority in identifiable cash proceeds of the inventory to the extent the identifiable cash proceeds are received on or before the delivery of the inventory to a buyer, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The purchase-money security interest is perfected when the debtor receives possession of the inventory;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The purchase-money secured party sends an authenticated notification to the holder of the conflicting security interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The holder of the conflicting security interest receives the notification within 5 years before the debtor receives possession of the inventory; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The notification states that the person sending the notification has or expects to acquire a purchase-money security interest in inventory of the debtor and describes the inventory.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subsections (b)(2) through (4) of this section apply only if the holder of the conflicting security interest had filed a financing statement covering the same types of inventory:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the purchase-money security interest is perfected by filing, before the date of the filing; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the purchase-money security interest is temporarily perfected without filing or possession under § 28:9-312(f), before the beginning of the 20-day period thereunder.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (e) and except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a perfected purchase-money security interest in livestock that are farm products has priority over a conflicting security interest in the same livestock, and, except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-327, a perfected security interest in their identifiable proceeds and identifiable products in their unmanufactured states also has priority, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The purchase-money security interest is perfected when the debtor receives possession of the livestock;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The purchase-money secured party sends an authenticated notification to the holder of the conflicting security interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The holder of the conflicting security interest receives the notification within 6 months before the debtor receives possession of the livestock; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The notification states that the person sending the notification has or expects to acquire a purchase-money security interest in livestock of the debtor and describes the livestock.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsections (d)(2) through (4) of this section apply only if the holder of the conflicting security interest had filed a financing statement covering the same types of livestock:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the purchase-money security interest is perfected by filing, before the date of the filing; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the purchase-money security interest is temporarily perfected without filing or possession under § 28:9-312(f), before the beginning of the 20-day period thereunder.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a perfected purchase-money security interest in software has priority over a conflicting security interest in the same collateral, and, except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-327, a perfected security interest in its identifiable proceeds also has priority, to the extent that the purchase-money security interest in the goods in which the software was acquired for use has priority in the goods and proceeds of the goods under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If more than one security interest qualifies for priority in the same collateral under subsection (a), (b), (d), or (f) of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A security interest securing an obligation incurred as all or part of the price of the collateral has priority over a security interest securing an obligation incurred for value given to enable the debtor to acquire rights in or the use of collateral; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In all other cases, § 28:9-322(a) applies to the qualifying security interests.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-325.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
