<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-322</num>
  <heading>Priorities among conflicting security interests in and agricultural liens on same collateral.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, priority among conflicting security interests and agricultural liens in the same collateral is determined according to the following rules:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conflicting perfected security interests and agricultural liens rank according to priority in time of filing or perfection. Priority dates from the earlier of the time a filing covering the collateral is first made or the security interest or agricultural lien is first perfected, if there is no period thereafter when there is neither filing nor perfection.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A perfected security interest or agricultural lien has priority over a conflicting unperfected security interest or agricultural lien.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The first security interest or agricultural lien to attach or become effective has priority if conflicting security interests and agricultural liens are unperfected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes subsection (a)(1):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The time of filing or perfection as to a security interest in collateral is also the time of filing or perfection as to a security interest in proceeds; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The time of filing or perfection as to a security interest in collateral supported by a supporting obligation is also the time of filing or perfection as to a security interest in the supporting obligation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (f), a security interest in collateral which qualifies for priority over a conflicting security interest under § 28:9-327, 28:9-328, 28:9-329, 28:9-330, or 28:9-331 also has priority over a conflicting security interest in:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any supporting obligation for the collateral; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Proceeds of the collateral if:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The security interest in proceeds is perfected;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The proceeds are cash proceeds or of the same type as the collateral; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the case of proceeds that are proceeds of proceeds, all intervening proceeds are cash proceeds, proceeds of the same type as the collateral, or an account relating to the collateral.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (e) and except as otherwise provided in subsection (f), if a security interest in chattel paper, deposit accounts, negotiable documents, instruments, investment property, or letter-of-credit rights is perfected by a method other than filing, conflicting perfected security interests in proceeds of the collateral rank according to priority in time of filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsection (d) applies only if the proceeds of the collateral are not cash proceeds, chattel paper, negotiable documents, instruments, investment property, or letter-of-credit rights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Subsections (a) through (e) are subject to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subsection (g) and the other provisions of this part;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>§ 28:4-210 with respect to a security interest of a collecting bank;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>§ 28:5-118 with respect to a security interest of an issuer or nominated person; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>§ 28:9-110 with respect to a security interest arising under Article 2 or 2A.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A perfected agricultural lien on collateral has priority over a conflicting security interest in or agricultural lien on the same collateral if the statute creating the agricultural lien so provides.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-109, § 28:9-317, § 28:9-323, § 28:9-324, § 28:9-325, § 28:9-328, § 28:9-330, and § 28:9-709.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
