<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-334</num>
  <heading>Priority of security interests in fixtures and crops.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A security interest under this article may be created in goods that are fixtures or may continue in goods that become fixtures. A security interest does not exist under this article in ordinary building materials incorporated into an improvement on land.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This article does not prevent creation of an encumbrance upon fixtures under real property law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In cases not governed by subsections (d) through (h), a security interest in fixtures is subordinate to a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the related real property other than the debtor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (h), a perfected security interest in fixtures has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if the debtor has an interest of record in or is in possession of the real property and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The security interest is a purchase-money security interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The interest of the encumbrancer or owner arises before the goods become fixtures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The security interest is perfected by a fixture filing before the goods become fixtures or within 20 days thereafter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A perfected security interest in fixtures has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The debtor has an interest of record in the real property or is in possession of the real property and the security interest:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is perfected by a fixture filing before the interest of the encumbrancer or owner is of record; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has priority over any conflicting interest of a predecessor in title of the encumbrancer or owner;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Before the goods become fixtures, the security interest is perfected by any method permitted by this article and the fixtures are readily removable:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Factory or office machines;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Equipment that is not primarily used or leased for use in the operation of the real property; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Replacements of domestic appliances that are consumer goods;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The conflicting interest is a lien on the real property obtained by legal or equitable proceedings after the security interest was perfected by any method permitted by this article; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The security interest is:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Created in a manufactured home in a manufactured-home transaction; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Perfected pursuant to a statute described in ยง 28:9-311(a)(2).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A security interest in fixtures, whether or not perfected, has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The encumbrancer or owner has, in an authenticated record, consented to the security interest or disclaimed an interest in the goods as fixtures; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The debtor has a right to remove the goods as against the encumbrancer or owner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The priority of the security interest under subsection (f)(2) continues for a reasonable time if the debtor's right to remove the goods as against the encumbrancer or owner terminates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A mortgage is a construction mortgage to the extent that it secures an obligation incurred for the construction of an improvement on land, including the acquisition cost of the land, if a recorded record of the mortgage so indicates. Except as otherwise provided in subsections (e) and (f), a security interest in fixtures is subordinate to a construction mortgage if a record of the mortgage is recorded before the goods become fixtures and the goods become fixtures before the completion of the construction. A mortgage has this priority to the same extent as a construction mortgage to the extent that it is given to refinance a construction mortgage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A perfected security interest in crops growing on real property has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if the debtor has an interest of record in or is in possession of the real property.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, ยง 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:9-109.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following ยง 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
