<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-323</num>
  <heading>Future advances.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), for purposes of determining the priority of a perfected security interest under § 28:9-322(a)(1), perfection of the security interest dates from the time an advance is made to the extent that the security interest secures an advance that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is made while the security interest is perfected only:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Under § 28:9-309 when it attaches; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Temporarily under § 28:9-312(e), (f), or (g); and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is not made pursuant to a commitment entered into before or while the security interest is perfected by a method other than under § 28:9-309 or 28:9-312(e), (f), or (g).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), a security interest is subordinate to the rights of a person that becomes a lien creditor to the extent that the security interest secures an advance made more than 45 days after the person becomes a lien creditor unless the advance is made:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), a security interest is subordinate to the rights of a person that becomes a lien creditor while the security interest is perfected only to the extent that it secures advances made more than 45 days after the person becomes a lien creditor unless the advance is made:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Without knowledge of the lien; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Pursuant to a commitment entered into without knowledge of the lien.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply to a security interest held by a secured party that is a buyer of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes or a consignor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a buyer of goods other than a buyer in ordinary course of business takes free of a security interest to the extent that it secures advances made after the earlier of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The time the secured party acquires knowledge of the buyer's purchase; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Forty-five days after the purchase.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Subsection (d) does not apply if the advance is made pursuant to a commitment entered into without knowledge of the buyer's purchase and before the expiration of the 45-day period.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a lessee of goods, other than a lessee in ordinary course of business, takes the leasehold interest free of a security interest to the extent that it secures advances made after the earlier of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The time the secured party acquires knowledge of the lease; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Forty-five days after the lease contract becomes enforceable.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Subsection (f) does not apply if the advance is made pursuant to a commitment entered into without knowledge of the lease and before the expiration of the 45-day period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-307 and § 28:9-328.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
