<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-317</num>
  <heading>Interests that take priority over or take free of unperfected security interest or agricultural lien.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A security interest or agricultural lien is subordinate to the rights of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person entitled to priority under § 28:9-322; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a person that becomes a lien creditor before the earlier of the time:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The security interest or agricultural lien is perfected; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One of the conditions specified in § 28:9-203(b)(3) is met and a financing statement covering the collateral is filed.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a buyer, other than a secured party, of tangible chattel paper, tangible documents, goods, instruments, or a certificated security takes free of a security interest or agricultural lien if the buyer gives value and receives delivery of the collateral without knowledge of the security interest or agricultural lien and before it is perfected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a lessee of goods takes free of a security interest or agricultural lien if the lessee gives value and receives delivery of the collateral without knowledge of the security interest or agricultural lien and before it is perfected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A licensee of a general intangible or a buyer, other than a secured party, of collateral other than tangible chattel paper, tangible documents, goods, instruments, or a certificated security takes free of a security interest if the licensee or buyer gives value without knowledge of the security interest and before it is perfected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in §§ 28:9-320 and 28:9-321, if a person files a financing statement with respect to a purchase-money security interest before or within 20 days after the debtor receives delivery of the collateral, the security interest takes priority over the rights of a buyer, lessee, or lien creditor which arise between the time the security interest attaches and the time of filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(l), 60 DCR 2634; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(g), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-307.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 substituted "tangible documents" for "documents" in (b); and inserted "electronic documents" in (d).</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-302 substituted "certificated security" for "security certificate" in (b); and substituted "collateral other than tangible chattel paper, tangible documents, goods, instruments, or a certificated security" for "accounts, electronic chattel paper, electronic documents, general intangibles, or investment property other than a certificated security" in (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-302: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-302 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
