<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-320</num>
  <heading>Buyer of goods.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a buyer in ordinary course of business, other than a person buying farm products from a person engaged in farming operations, takes free of a security interest created by the buyer's seller, even if the security interest is perfected and the buyer knows of its existence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a buyer of goods from a person who used or bought the goods for use primarily for personal, family, or household purposes takes free of a security interest, even if perfected, if the buyer buys:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Without knowledge of the security interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For value;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Primarily for the buyer's personal, family, or household purposes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Before the filing of a financing statement covering the goods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To the extent that it affects the priority of a security interest over a buyer of goods under subsection (b), the period of effectiveness of a filing made in the jurisdiction in which the seller is located is governed by § 28:9-316(a) and (b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A buyer in ordinary course of business buying oil, gas, or other minerals at the wellhead or minehead or after extraction takes free of an interest arising out of an encumbrance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsections (a) and (b) do not affect a security interest in goods in the possession of the secured party under § 28:9-313.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:7-209, § 28:7-503, and § 28:9-317.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
