<level type="section">
  <num>34-1256.05</num>
  <heading>Performance bond.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At all times during the term of a franchise, including the time for removal of facilities or management, the cable operator shall obtain and hold a performance bond running to the District with good and sufficient surety approved by the Office, in an amount to be determined by the Office or set forth in a franchise agreement, to ensure that the operation of the cable system continues uninterrupted in the event of a default by the cable operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The cable operator shall make all payments associated with the bond in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The cable operator shall file with the Office written evidence of payment of premiums and executed duplicate copies of the bond documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The bond shall be with a surety company authorized by the District's Superintendent of Insurance to transact business in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The bond shall require 60 calendar days written notice of any cancellation to both the Office and the cable operator. If the Office or the cable operator receives a cancellation notice, the cable operator shall obtain a new bond, meeting the requirements of this section, within 60 days after receipt of the notice by the Office or the cable operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Failure to comply with the provisions of this section, or with the performance bond provisions of the franchise agreement, shall constitute a material violation of a franchise.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, ยง 605, as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, ยง 2(b), 49 DCR 7334.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-193</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-193, see notes following ยง 34-1251.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
