<level type="section">
  <num>29-802.02</num>
  <heading>Amendment or restatement of certificate of organization.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A certificate of organization may be amended or restated at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To amend its certificate of organization, a limited liability company shall deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment stating:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date of filing of its certificate of organization; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The changes the amendment makes to the certificate as most recently amended or restated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To restate its certificate of organization, a limited liability company shall deliver to the Mayor for filing a restatement, designated as such in its heading, stating:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the heading or an introductory paragraph, the company's present name and the date of the filing of the company's initial certificate of organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the company's name has been changed at any time since the company's formation, each of the company's former names; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The changes the restatement makes to the certificate as most recently amended or restated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to §§ 29-801.09(c) and 29-802.05(c), an amendment to or restatement of a certificate of organization shall be effective when filed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a member of a member-managed limited liability company, or a manager of a manager-managed limited liability company, knows that any information in a filed certificate of organization was inaccurate when the certificate was filed or has become inaccurate owing to changed circumstances, the member or manager shall promptly:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cause the certificate to be amended; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If appropriate, deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of change under §§ 29-104.07 through 29-104.10 or a statement of correction under § 29-102.05.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A limited liability company may amend its certificate of organization to delete the information required by § 29-802.01(b)(2) at any time after it has filed its first biennial report under § 29-102.11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 202 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act). See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
