<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-301</num>
  <heading>Law governing perfection and priority of security interests.</heading>
  <text>Except as otherwise provided in §§ 28:9-303 through 28:9-306, the following rules determine the law governing perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in collateral:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, while a debtor is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in collateral.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>While collateral is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a possessory security interest in that collateral.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (4), while tangible negotiable documents, goods, instruments, money, or tangible chattel paper is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Perfection of a security interest in the goods by filing a fixture filing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Perfection of a security interest in timber to be cut; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The effect of perfection or nonperfection and the priority of a nonpossessory security interest in the collateral.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The local law of the jurisdiction in which the wellhead or minehead is located governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in as-extracted collateral.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(e), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:1-301 and § 28:9-316.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 inserted "tangible" preceding "negotiable documents" in (3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
