<level type="section">
  <num>2-1376</num>
  <heading>Transition provisions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall commence operations, and the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor's Order 95-119 shall be abolished, on April 17, 2008. The members of the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor's Order 95-119 shall hold over as members of the Commission until new members are appointed pursuant to § 2-1374.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All records and functions of the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor's Order 95-119 shall be transferred to the Commission on April 17, 2008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 307, 48 DCR 6981; Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 312(b), 56 DCR 1117.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-353 rewrote the section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) The Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor's Order 95-119, shall be abolished the later of the date of the:</text>
        <text>"(1) Confirmation of the 15th public member; or</text>
        <text>"(2) Convening of the 2001 Mayor's Town Hall Meeting with the Asian and Pacific Islander communities.</text>
        <text>"(b) All records, and functions of the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor's Order 95-119, shall be transferred to the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Community Development established pursuant to § 2-1374, upon the later of:</text>
        <text>"(1) The confirmation of the 15th public member; or</text>
        <text>"(2) The convening of the 2001 Mayor's Town Hall Meeting with the Asian and Pacific Islander communities."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 307 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001, 48 DCR 7861).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-28, see notes following § 2-1371.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-353, see notes following § 2-218.42.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
