<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-502</num>
  <heading>Buyer's right to goods on seller's repudiation, failure to deliver, or insolvency.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (2) and (3) and even though the goods have not been shipped, a buyer who has paid a part or all of the price of goods in which he has a special property under the provisions of § 28:2-501 may, on making and keeping good a tender of any unpaid portion of their price, recover them from the seller if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>in the case of goods bought for personal, family, or household purposes, the seller repudiates or fails to deliver as required by the contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>in all cases, the seller becomes insolvent within 10 days after receipt of the first installment on their price.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The buyer's right to recover the goods under subsection (1)(a) vests upon acquisition of a special property, even if the seller had not then repudiated or failed to deliver.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>If the identification creating his special property has been made by the buyer he acquires the right to recover the goods only if they conform to the contract for sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 655, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 201(c)(4), 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-402 and § 28:2-711.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-502.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:2-502.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-201, enacting a new Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code applicable July 1, 2001, made conforming amendments to this section applicable upon the same date.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:2-103.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
