<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-503</num>
  <heading>Manner of seller's tender of delivery.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Tender of delivery requires that the seller put and hold conforming goods at the buyer's disposition and give the buyer any notification reasonably necessary to enable him to take delivery. The manner, time and place for tender are determined by the agreement and this article, and in particular</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>tender must be at a reasonable hour, and if it is of goods they must be kept available for the period reasonably necessary to enable the buyer to take possession; but</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>unless otherwise agreed the buyer must furnish facilities reasonably suited to the receipt of the goods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Where the case is within the next section respecting shipment tender requires that the seller comply with its provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Where the seller is required to deliver at a particular destination tender requires that he comply with subsection (1) and also in any appropriate case tender documents as described in subsections (4) and (5) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Where goods are in the possession of a bailee and are to be delivered without being moved</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>tender requires that the seller either tender a negotiable document of title covering such goods or procure acknowledgment by the bailee of the buyer's right to possession of the goods; but</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>tender to the buyer of a non-negotiable document of title or of a record directing to the bailee to deliver is sufficient tender unless the buyer seasonably objects, and except as otherwise provided in Article 9 receipt by the bailee of notification of the buyer's rights fixes those rights as against the bailee and all third persons; but risk of loss of the goods and of any failure by the bailee to honor the non-negotiable document of title or to obey the direction remains on the seller until the buyer has had a reasonable time to present the document or direction, and a refusal by the bailee to honor the document or to obey the direction defeats the tender.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Where the contract requires the seller to deliver documents</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>he must tender all such documents in correct form except as provided in this article with respect to bills of lading in a set (subsection (2) of section 28:2-323); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>tender through customary banking channels is sufficient and dishonor of a draft accompanying or associated with the documents constitutes non-acceptance or rejection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 655, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 3(h), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-319 and § 28:2-509.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-503.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:2-503.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299, in (4)(b), substituted "record directing" for "written direction to" and inserted "except as otherwise provided in Article 9" following "seasonably objects, and"; and substituted "accompanying or associated with" for "accompanying" in (5)(b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
