<level type="section">
  <num>28-3102</num>
  <heading>Insolvency.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28-3102</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A debtor is insolvent if the sum of the debtor's debts is greater than all of the debtor's assets, at a fair valuation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A debtor who is generally not paying his or her debts as they become due is presumed to be insolvent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A partnership is insolvent under subsection (a) of this section if the sum of the partnership's debts is greater than the aggregate, at a fair valuation, of all of the partnership's assets, and the sum of the excess of the value of each general partner's nonpartnership assets over the partner's nonpartnership debts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Assets under this section do not include property that has been transferred, concealed, or removed with intent to hinder, delay, or defraud creditors or that has been transferred in a manner making the transfer voidable under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Debts under this section do not include an obligation to the extent it is secured by a valid lien on property of the debtor not included as an asset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-83, § 2, 42 DCR 6773.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28-3102.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-83, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-3101.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 2 of the Uniform Fraudulent Transfer Act. See Volume 7A, Part II Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
