<level type="section">
  <num>28-3107</num>
  <heading>Remedies of creditors.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28-3107</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In an action for relief against a transfer or obligation under this chapter, a creditor, subject to the limitations in section 28-3108, may obtain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Avoidance of the transfer or obligation to the extent necessary to satisfy the creditor's claim;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An attachment or other provisional remedy against the asset transferred or other property of the transferee in accordance with the procedure prescribed by sections 16-501 through 16-584;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Subject to applicable principles of equity and in accordance with applicable rules of civil procedure:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An injunction against further disposition by the debtor or a transferee, or both, of the asset transferred or of other property;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Appointment of a receiver to take charge of the asset transferred or of other property of the transferee; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other relief the circumstances may require.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a creditor has obtained a judgment on a claim against the debtor, the creditor, if the court so orders, may levy execution on the asset transferred or its proceeds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-83, § 2, 42 DCR 6773.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28-3107.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-83, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-3101.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 7 of the Uniform Fraudulent Transfer Act. See Volume 7A, Part II Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
