<level type="section">
  <num>29-801.03</num>
  <heading>Knowledge; notice.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person knows a fact when the person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has actual knowledge of it; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is deemed to know it under subsection (d)(1) of this section or law other than this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person has notice of a fact when the person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has reason to know the fact from all of the facts known to the person at the time in question; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is deemed to have notice of the fact under subsection (d)(2) of this section;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person notifies another of a fact by taking steps reasonably required to inform the other person in ordinary course, whether or not the other person knows the fact.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that is not a member shall be deemed to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Know of a limitation on authority to transfer real property as provided in § 29-803.02(g); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have notice of a limited liability company's:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Dissolution, 90 days after a statement of dissolution under § 29-807. 02(b)(2)(A) becomes effective;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Termination, 90 days after a statement of termination § 29- 807.02(b)(2)(F) becomes effective; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Merger or domestication, 90 days after articles of merger or domestication under subchapter IX of this chapter becomes effective.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 103 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act). See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
