<level type="section">
  <num>29-801.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Certificate of organization" means the certificate required by § 29- 802.01. The term "certificate of organization" shall include the certificate as amended or restated.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Contribution" means any benefit provided by a person to a limited liability company:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To become a member upon formation of the company and in accordance with an agreement between or among the persons that have agreed to become the initial members of the company;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To become a member after formation of the company and in accordance with an agreement between the person and the company; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the person's capacity as a member and in accordance with the operating agreement or an agreement between the member and the company.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Distribution", except as otherwise provided in § 29-804.05(g), means a transfer of money or other property from a limited liability company to another person on account of a transferable interest.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Effective", with respect to a record required or permitted to be delivered to the Mayor for filing under this chapter, means effective under § 29- 102.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Foreign limited liability company" means an unincorporated entity formed under the law of a jurisdiction other than the District and denominated by that law as a limited liability company.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Manager" means a person that under the operating agreement of a manager-managed limited liability company is responsible, alone or in concert with others, for performing the management functions stated in § 29-804.07(c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Manager-managed limited liability company" means a limited liability company that qualifies under § 29-804.07(a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Member" means a person that has become a member of a limited liability company under § 29-804.01 and has not dissociated under § 29-806.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Member-managed limited liability company" means a limited liability company that is not a manager-managed limited liability company.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Operating agreement" means the agreement, whether or not referred to as an operating agreement and whether oral, in a record, implied, or in any combination thereof, of all the members of a limited liability company, including a sole member, concerning the matters described in § 29-801.07. The term includes the agreement as amended or restated.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Organizer" means a person that acts under § 29-802.01 to form a limited liability company.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Transferee" means a person to which all or part of a transferable interest has been transferred, whether or not the transferor is a member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 102 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act). See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
