<level type="section">
  <num>37-110</num>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <text>In the event that a market vendor violates any law, regulation, sidewalk market rule or condition of the market vendor's sub-lease as specified in the contract, the market manager may issue a market violation notice ("MVN") to the market vendor suspending the market vendor's sub-lease until the violation has been cured or corrected. If 3 MVNs are issued to a market vendor during the contract year, the market vendor's sub-lease shall be cancelled. If the market manager decides not to renew a market vendor's sub-lease, the market manager shall give the market vendor written notice on or before January 31. MVNs, cancellation, and any decision not to renew a market vendor's sub-lease shall be effective immediately but may be appealed to the Department of General Services.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 16, 1999, D.C. Law 12-228, ยง 11, 46 DCR 1066; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 91(c), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 10-310.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 substituted "Department of General Services" for "Office of Property Management" in the last sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-228</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-228, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 37-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
