<level type="section">
  <num>37-102</num>
  <heading>Coordinated management.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of General Services shall supervise and provide coordinated management over all operations in the Eastern Market Square. On April 16, 1999, the District of Columbia shall notify any extant lessees and sub-assignees with an existing lease, contract, agreement or legally binding understanding with respect to any occupant or occupants of the Eastern Market building of the status of their lease or agreement, including the date of termination or expiration of their lease or sub-assignment or any other change to an agreement or legally binding understanding with the District of Columbia that is required by this chapter. The District of Columbia shall remain responsible for capital expenditures for Eastern Market and the Eastern Market Square.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CPMO may promulgate rules to implement this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 16, 1999, D.C. Law 12-228, ยง 3, 46 DCR 1066; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 91(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 10-302.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 substituted "Department of General Services" for "OPM" in the first sentence of (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-228</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-228, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 37-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
