<level type="section">
  <num>29-106.02</num>
  <heading>Procedure and effect.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor determines that one or more grounds exist under § 29-106. 01 for dissolving a domestic filing entity, the Mayor shall serve the entity pursuant to § 29-104.12 with notice in a record of the Mayor's determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a domestic filing entity, not later than 60 days after service of the notice is effected under § 29-104.12, does not correct each ground for dissolution or demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor that each ground determined by the Mayor does not exist, after the expiration of the 60-day period, the Mayor shall dissolve the entity administratively by signing a statement of dissolution that recites the grounds for dissolution and its effective date. The Mayor shall file the original of the statement and serve a copy on the entity pursuant to § 29-104.12 and publish a notice of the statement on an appropriate website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A domestic filing entity that is dissolved administratively continues its existence as an entity, but shall not carry on any business except as necessary to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs in the manner provided in its organic law or to apply for reinstatement under § 29-106.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The administrative dissolution of a domestic filing entity shall not terminate the authority of its registered agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
