<level type="section">
  <num>24-241.05</num>
  <heading>Suspension of work release privilege; violations of work release plan.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 24-465</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Corrections may suspend or revoke the work release privilege for any breach of discipline or infraction of institution regulations. The Court may revoke the work release privilege at any time, either upon its own motion or upon recommendation of the Director of the Department of Corrections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any prisoner who willfully fails to return at the time and to the place of confinement designated in his work release plan shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, such sentence of imprisonment to run consecutively with the remainder of previously imposed sentences. All prosecutions for violation of this subsection shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia upon information filed by the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia or any of his assistants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 10, 1966, 80 Stat. 1519, Pub. L. 89-803, § 6; July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a); June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-273, § 4(d), 43 DCR 6168.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 24-465.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 24-465.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(e) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-390, August 26, 1996, 43 DCR 4986), § 4(d) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-436, December 4, 1996, 43 DCR 6651), and see § 4(d) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-35, March 11, 1997, 44 DCR 1928).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-273, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 24-241.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
