<level type="section">
  <num>34-1254.05</num>
  <heading>Minimum contents of franchise agreement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The proposed franchise agreement shall contain the following provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall construct, operate, and maintain a state-of-the-art cable system.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The capacity of the cable system shall be at least 750 MHz, with both downstream and upstream capacity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The cable system shall be capable of providing Internet access services.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall pay a franchise fee of at least 5% of gross revenues.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall contribute at least 1% of gross revenues to the operations of the Public Access Corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall provide at least 8 PEG channels on the analog portion of the cable system and at least 10 PEG channels on the digital portion of the cable system.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall provide at least 1% of gross revenues each year as continuing capital support for the public, educational, and government access channels.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall enter into an agreement regarding contracting with, and procuring from, local, small, and disadvantaged business enterprises.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall enter into a First Source agreement.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall provide significant financial resources or capacity or equipment to an institutional network.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The construction schedule required by § 34-1257.03.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The term of a franchise agreement shall not exceed 15 years in the case of an initial franchise and shall not exceed 10 years in the case of a renewed franchise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The proposed franchise agreement shall include procedures for amending the franchise agreement, including the District's right to amend the franchise agreement in order to take advantage of advancements in technology.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The proposed franchise agreement shall also cover matters regarding system construction, operation, and maintenance; indemnity, insurance and bonding requirements; reports and records; default and remedies; notices; and all terms and conditions related to the provision of cable service the Office deems necessary or appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, § 405, as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, § 2(b), 49 DCR 7334.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 34-1251.04, § 34-1254.06, § 34-1254.07, and § 34-1254.08.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-193</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-193, see notes following § 34-1251.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
