<level type="section">
  <num>8-1772.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Air conditioner" means an appliance, system, or mechanism designed to remove heat and humidity from ambient air for thermal comfort.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Chain of stores" means 2 or more stores located within the District that are engaged in the same general field of business under the same business name or that operate under common ownership or management or pursuant to a franchise agreement with the same franchisor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Commercial property" means income-producing property as identified under zoning classifications that would allow for uses such as office buildings, retail stores, and service facilities pursuant to Chapter 7 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (11 DCMR § 700 et seq.); provided, that the term "commercial property" shall not include a small store, hotel, or restaurant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Person" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The owner or lessee of the portion of a commercial building or structure that is a retail or wholesale establishment that sells goods or provides services to consumers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The record owner or lessee of any other portion of a commercial building or structure.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Small store" means a retail or wholesale establishment that sells goods or provides services to consumers and occupies less than 4,000 square feet of retail or wholesale space, excluding storage space, and is not one of a chain of stores.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-252, § 201, 59 DCR 14932.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-252</heading>
      <text>19-252, the "Energy Innovation and Savings Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-749. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Nov. 1, 2012 and Nov. 15, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Dec. 7, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-562 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-252, became effective on March 19, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 301 of D.C. Law 19-252 provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act within 180 days of its effective date [March 19, 2013].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
