<level type="section">
  <num>8-651.04</num>
  <heading>Preservation of Special Trees; permits; penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person or nongovernmental entity, without a Special Tree removal permit issued by the Mayor, to Top, cut down, remove, girdle, break, or destroy any Special Tree.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue a Special Tree removal permit under this section where the applicant has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shown that the Special Tree in question is a Hazardous Tree;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shown that the Special Tree in question is of a species that has been identified, by regulation, as appropriate for removal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Paid into the Tree Fund an amount equal to $35 for each inch of the circumference of the Special Tree in question; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Averred in a signed Special Tree removal permit application that the applicant will plant, in compliance with the applicable regulations, a quantity of saplings whose aggregated circumference equals or exceeds the circumference of the Special Tree in question.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The showings required by subsection (b) of this section may be satisfied by a combination of payments and plantings pursuant to subsection (b)(3) and (b)(4) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A violation of subsection (a) of this section, or a failure to comply with the conditions contained in a Special Tree removal permit, shall constitute a violation subject to a fine of not less than $100 per each inch of the circumference of the Special Tree in question.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-309, ยง 104, 50 DCR 888.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-309, see notes following ยง 8-651.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
