<level type="section">
  <num>25-783</num>
  <heading>Production of valid identification document required; penalty.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A licensee shall refuse to sell, serve, or deliver an alcoholic beverage to any person who, upon request of the licensee, fails to produce a valid identification document.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee or his agent or employee shall take steps reasonably necessary to ascertain whether any person to whom the licensee sells, delivers, or serves an alcoholic beverage is of legal drinking age. Any person who supplies a valid identification document showing his or her age to be the legal drinking age shall be deemed to be of legal drinking age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon finding that a licensee has violated subsection (a) or (b) of this section in the preceding 2 years:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon the first violation, the Board shall fine the licensee not less than $1,000, and not more than $2,000, and suspend the licensee for 5 consecutive days. The 5-day suspension may be stayed by the Board for one year if all employees who serve alcoholic beverages in the licensed establishment complete an alcohol training program within 3 months.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon the second violation, the Board shall fine the licensee not less than $2,000, and not more than $4,000, and suspend the licensee for 10 consecutive days. The Board may stay up to 6 days of the 10-day suspension for one year if all employees who serve alcoholic beverages in the licensed establishment complete an alcohol training program within 3 months.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon the third violation, the Board shall fine the licensee not less than $4,000, and not more than $10,000, and suspend the licensee for 15 consecutive days, or revoke the license. The Board may stay up to 5 days of the 15-day suspension for one year if all employees who serve alcoholic beverages in the licensed establishment complete an alcohol training program within 3 months.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Upon the fourth violation, the Board may revoke the license.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Board may revoke the license of a licensed establishment that has 5 or more violations of this section within a 5-year period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section notwithstanding, no licensee shall discriminate on any basis prohibited by Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An affirmative defense to a violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be that the person was at the time of the violation 21 years of age or older.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 331, ch. 4, § 20; Aug. 27, 1935, 49 Stat. 901, ch. 756, § 10; June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 104, ch. 159, § 404(g); Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, § 12, 29 DCR 3617; Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-106, § 2, 31 DCR 3381; Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-178, § 2(a), 33 DCR 7654; Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 12, 34 DCR 907; Sept. 11, 1993, D.C. Law 10-12,§ 2(c), 40 DCR 4020; May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(i), 41 DCR 1658; May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(cc), 60 DCR 3410.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 25-783.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 25-121.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-310 added (e).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of (e), see § 2(cc) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1001).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(cc) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013, 60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-298</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 13-298, see notes following § 25-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-310</heading>
      <text>See note to § 25-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
