<level type="section">
  <num>45-102</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Code; preparation and publication; printing.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 49-102</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After publication by the Law Revision Counsel of the fifth annual cumulative supplement to the 1973 Edition of the District of Columbia Code, new editions of the District of Columbia Code (and annual cumulative supplements thereto) shall be prepared and published under the direction of the Council of the District of Columbia and shall set forth the general and permanent laws relating to or in force in the District of Columbia, whether enacted by the Congress or by the Council of the District of Columbia, except such laws as are of application in the District of Columbia by reason of being laws of the United States general and permanent in nature.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After completion of the printing of the fifth annual cumulative supplement to the 1973 Edition of the District of Columbia Code, the Public Printer shall, as the Council of the District of Columbia may request, either:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Furnish to the Council of the District of Columbia, on such terms as the Public Printer (in consultation with the Joint Committee on Printing) deems appropriate, the type used in preparing the 1973 Edition of the District of Columbia Code and the fifth annual cumulative supplement to such edition; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Make such arrangements with the Council of the District of Columbia as the Public Printer (in consultation with the Joint Committee on Printing) deems appropriate for the printing by the Government Printing Office of future editions of the District of Columbia Code, and annual cumulative supplements thereto, prepared under the direction of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 14, 1976, 90 Stat. 1170, Pub. L. 94-386, ยง 2.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 49-102.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 49-112.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
