<level type="section">
  <num>4-754.36</num>
  <heading>Termination.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A provider may terminate its delivery of services to a client only when:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The provider documents that it has considered suspending the client in accordance with § 4-754.35 or has made a reasonable effort, in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the termination, to transfer the client in accordance with § 4-754.34;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The client:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Possesses a weapon on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Possesses or sells illegal drugs on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Assaults or batters any person on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Endangers the client's own safety or the safety of others on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Intentionally or maliciously vandalizes, destroys, or steals the property of any person on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Fails to accept an offer of appropriate permanent housing or supportive housing that better serves the client's needs after having been offered 2 appropriate permanent or supportive housing opportunities; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Knowingly engages in repeated violations of a provider's Program Rules; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of a termination pursuant to paragraph (2)(F) or (G) of this subsection, the provider has made reasonable efforts to help the client overcome obstacles to obtaining permanent housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subsection (a)(2)(F) of this section, Rapid Re-Housing shall be considered an offer of supportive housing and an offer of 2 different units through a Rapid Re-Housing program shall be considered 2 offers of supportive housing. In determining whether an offer of permanent or supportive housing is appropriate, the results of a research- or evidence-based assessment tool used as part of the decision to make such an offer shall be given great weight.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 22, 52 DCR 8113; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5182(g), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-754.34 and § 4-754.35.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5182(g) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5182(g) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-35</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-35, see notes following § 4-751.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 4-751.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5181 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle Q of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Homeless Services Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
