<level type="section">
  <num>4-754.36</num>
  <heading>Termination of services.</heading>
  <text>A provider may terminate its delivery of services to a client only when:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The provider documents that it has considered suspending the client in accordance with ยง 4-754.35 or has made a reasonable effort, in light of the severity of the act or acts leading to the termination, to transfer the client in accordance with ยง 4-754.34;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The client:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Possesses a weapon on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Possesses or sells illegal drugs on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Assaults or batters any person on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Endangers the client's own safety or the safety of others on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Intentionally or maliciously vandalizes, destroys, or steals the property of any person on the provider's premises;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Fails to accept an offer of appropriate permanent housing or supportive housing that better serves the client's needs after having been offered 2 appropriate permanent or supportive housing opportunities; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Knowingly engages in repeated violations of a provider's Program Rules; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of terminations pursuant to subparagraphs (2)(F) and (2)(G) of this section, the provider has made reasonable efforts to help the client overcome obstacles to obtaining permanent housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, ยง 22, 52 DCR 8113.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-35, see notes following ยง 4-751.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
