<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-209</num>
  <heading>Modification, rescission and waiver.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>An agreement modifying a contract within this article needs no consideration to be binding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A signed agreement which excludes modification or rescission except by a signed writing cannot be otherwise modified or rescinded, but except as between merchants such a requirement on a form supplied by the merchant must be separately signed by the other party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The requirements of the statute of frauds section of this article (section 28:2-201) must be satisfied if the contract as modified is within its provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Although an attempt at modification or rescission does not satisfy the requirements of subsection (2) or (3), it can operate as a waiver.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>A party who has made a waiver affecting an executory portion of the contract may retract the waiver by reasonable notification received by the other party that strict performance will be required by any term waived, unless the retraction would be unjust in view of a material change of position in reliance on the waiver.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 644, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(kk), 44 DCR 1271; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 16(a), 45 DCR 745.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:1-303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-209.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:2-209.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-255</heading>
      <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-81</heading>
      <text>Law 12-81, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-408, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1997, and December 4, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-246 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-81 became effective on March 24, 1998.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
