<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-518</num>
  <heading>Claim concerning inaccurate or wrongfully filed record.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person may file in the filing office an information statement with respect to a record indexed there under the person's name if the person believes that the record is inaccurate or was wrongfully filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An information statement under subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the record to which it relates by the file number assigned to the initial financing statement to which the record relates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Indicate that it is an information statement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide the basis for the person's belief that the record is inaccurate and indicate the manner in which the person believes the record should be amended to cure any inaccuracy or provide the basis for the person's belief that the record was wrongfully filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person may file in the filing office an information statement with respect to a record filed there if the person is a secured party of record with respect to the financing statement to which the record relates and believes that the person that filed the record was not entitled to do so under § 28:9-509(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An information statement under subsection (c) of this section shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the record to which it relates by the file number assigned to the initial financing statement to which the record relates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Indicate that it is an information statement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide the basis for the person's belief that the person that filed the record was not entitled to do so under § 28:9-509(d).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The filing of an information statement does not affect the effectiveness of an initial financing statement or other filed record.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(p), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-516.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-302 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-302: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-302 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
