<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-509</num>
  <heading>Persons entitled to file a record.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person may file an initial financing statement, amendment that adds collateral covered by a financing statement, or amendment that adds a debtor to a financing statement only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The debtor authorizes the filing in an authenticated record or pursuant to subsection (b) or (c) of this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person holds an agricultural lien that has become effective at the time of filing and the financing statement covers only collateral in which the person holds an agricultural lien.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By authenticating or becoming bound as debtor by a security agreement, a debtor or new debtor authorizes the filing of an initial financing statement, and an amendment, covering:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The collateral described in the security agreement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Property that becomes collateral under § 28:9-315(a)(2), whether or not the security agreement expressly covers proceeds.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By acquiring collateral in which a security interest or agricultural lien continues under § 28:9-315(a)(1), a debtor authorizes the filing of an initial financing statement, and an amendment, covering the collateral and property that becomes collateral under § 28:9-315(a)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person may file an amendment other than an amendment that adds collateral covered by a financing statement or an amendment that adds a debtor to a financing statement only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The secured party of record authorizes the filing; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amendment is a termination statement for a financing statement as to which the secured party of record has failed to file or send a termination statement as required by § 28:9-513(a) or (c), the debtor authorizes the filing, and the termination statement indicates that the debtor authorized it to be filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If there is more than one secured party of record for a financing statement, each secured party of record may authorize the filing of an amendment under subsection (d).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-510, § 28:9-512, § 28:9-518, and § 28:9-625.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
