<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-507</num>
  <heading>Effect of certain events on effectiveness of financing statement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A filed financing statement remains effective with respect to collateral that is sold, exchanged, leased, licensed, or otherwise disposed of and in which a security interest or agricultural lien continues, even if the secured party knows of or consents to the disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section and § 28:9-508, a financing statement is not rendered ineffective if, after the financing statement is filed, the information provided in the financing statement becomes seriously misleading under § 28:9-506.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the name that a filed financing statement provides for a debtor becomes insufficient as the name of the debtor under § 28:9-503(a) so that the financing statement becomes seriously misleading under § 28:9-506:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The financing statement is effective to perfect a security interest in collateral acquired by the debtor before, or within 4 months after, the filed financing statement becomes seriously misleading; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The financing statement is not effective to perfect a security interest in collateral acquired by the debtor more than 4 months after the filed financing statement becomes seriously misleading, unless an amendment to the financing statement which renders the financing statement not seriously misleading is filed within 4 months after the financing statement became seriously misleading.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(m), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-508.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-302 rewrote (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-302: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-302 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
