<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-516</num>
  <heading>What constitutes filing; effectiveness of filing.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b), communication of a record to a filing office and tender of the filing fee or acceptance of the record by the filing office constitutes filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Filing does not occur with respect to a record that a filing office refuses to accept because:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The record is not communicated by a method or medium of communication authorized by the filing office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to or greater than the applicable filing fee is not tendered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The filing office is unable to index the record because:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of an initial financing statement, the record does not provide a name for the debtor;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of an amendment or information statement, the record:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Does not identify the initial financing statement as required by § 28:9-512 or 28:9-518, as applicable; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Identifies an initial financing statement whose effectiveness has lapsed under § 28:9-515;</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the case of an initial financing statement that provides the name of a debtor identified as an individual or an amendment that provides a name of a debtor identified as an individual which was not previously provided in the financing statement to which the record relates, the record does not identify the debtor's surname; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>In the case of a record filed or recorded in the filing office described in § 28:9-501(a)(1), the record does not provide a sufficient description of the real property to which it relates;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In the case of an initial financing statement or an amendment that adds a secured party of record, the record does not provide a name and mailing address for the secured party of record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>In the case of an initial financing statement or an amendment that provides a name of a debtor which was not previously provided in the financing statement to which the amendment relates, the record does not:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide a mailing address for the debtor; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Indicate whether the name provided as the name of the debtor is the name of an individual or an organization.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the financing statement indicates that the debtor is an organization, provide:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A type of organization for the debtor;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A jurisdiction of organization for the debtor; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>An organizational identification number for the debtor or indicate that the debtor has none;</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>In the case of an assignment reflected in an initial financing statement under § 28:9-514(a) or an amendment filed under § 28:9-514(b), the record does not provide a name and mailing address for the assignee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>In the case of a continuation statement, the record is not filed within the 6-month period prescribed by § 28:9-515(d).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of subsection (b):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A record does not provide information if the filing office is unable to read or decipher the information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A record that does not indicate that it is an amendment or identify an initial financing statement to which it relates, as required by § 28:9-512, 28:9-514, or 28:9-518, is an initial financing statement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A record that is communicated to the filing office with tender of the filing fee, but which the filing office refuses to accept for a reason other than one set forth in subsection (b), is effective as a filed record except as against a purchaser of the collateral which gives value in reasonable reliance upon the absence of the record from the files.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(o), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-109, § 28:9-338, § 28:9-520, and § 28:9-521.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-302 substituted "information" for "correction" in (b)(3)(B); substituted "surname" for "last name" in (b)(3)(C); added "or" at the end of (b)(5)(A); and rewrote (b)(5)(B), which read: "Indicate whether the debtor is an individual or an organization; or".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-302: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-302 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
