<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-512</num>
  <heading>Amendment of financing statement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to § 28:9-509, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or, subject to subsection (e), otherwise amend the information provided in, a financing statement by filing an amendment that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identifies, by its file number, the initial financing statement to which the amendment relates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the amendment relates to an initial financing statement filed or recorded in a filing office described in § 28:9-501(a)(1), provides the information specified in § 28:9-502(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-515, the filing of an amendment does not extend the period of effectiveness of the financing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A financing statement that is amended by an amendment that adds collateral is effective as to the added collateral only from the date of the filing of the amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A financing statement that is amended by an amendment that adds a debtor is effective as to the added debtor only from the date of the filing of the amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An amendment is ineffective to the extent it:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Purports to delete all debtors and fails to provide the name of a debtor to be covered by the financing statement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purports to delete all secured parties of record and fails to provide the name of a new secured party of record.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-109 and § 28:9-516.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
