<level type="section">
  <num>46-306.05</num>
  <heading>Notice of registration of order.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-346.5</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a support order or income-withholding order issued in another state is registered, the registering tribunal shall notify the nonregistering party. The notice must be accompanied by a copy of the registered order and the documents and relevant information accompanying the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notice must inform the nonregistering party:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That a registered order is enforceable as of the date of registration in the same manner as an order issued by a tribunal of the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That a hearing to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered order must be requested within 20 days after the notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That failure to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered order in a timely manner will result in confirmation of the order and enforcement of the order and the alleged arrearages and precludes further contest of that order with respect to any matter that could have been asserted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Of the amount of any alleged arrearages.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the registering party asserts that 2 or more orders are in effect, a notice must also:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the 2 or more orders and the order alleged by the registering person to be the controlling order and the consolidated arrears, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notify the nonregistering party of the right to a determination of which is the controlling order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>State that the procedures provided in subsection (b) of this section apply to the determination of which is the controlling order; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>State that failure to contest the validity or enforcement of the order alleged to be the controlling order in a timely manner may result in confirmation that the order is the controlling order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon registration of an income-withholding order for enforcement, the registering tribunal shall notify the obligor's employer or holder pursuant to Chapter 2 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 605, 42 DCR 6748; July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-131, § 2(j), 45 DCR 2924; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(f)(5), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-346.5.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137, in subsec. (b), substituted "A notice" for "The notice"; redesignated subsec. (c) as subsec. (d); and added subsec. (c).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Uniform Interstate Family Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-94, April 29, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 2785).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(j) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-225, December 23, 1997, 45 DCR 151).</text>
        <text>Emergency act amendments: For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(j) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-310, March 29, 1998, 45 DCR 1950.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following §46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-131, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 605 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
