<level type="section">
  <num>46-306.07</num>
  <heading>Contest of registration or enforcement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A party contesting the validity or enforcement of a registered order or seeking to vacate the registration has the burden of proving 1 or more of the following defenses:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The issuing tribunal lacked personal jurisdiction over the contesting party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The order was obtained by fraud;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The order has been vacated, suspended, or modified by a later order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The issuing tribunal has stayed the order pending appeal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>There is a defense under the law of the District to the remedy sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Full or partial payment has been made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The statute of limitation under § 46-306.04 precludes enforcement of some or all of the alleged arrearages; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The alleged controlling order is not the controlling order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a party presents evidence establishing a full or partial defense under subsection (a) of this section, a tribunal may stay enforcement of the registered order, continue the proceeding to permit production of additional relevant evidence, and issue other appropriate orders. An uncontested portion of the registered order may be enforced by all remedies available under the law of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the contesting party does not establish a defense under subsection (a) of this section to the validity or enforcement of the order, the registering tribunal shall issue an order confirming the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 607, 42 DCR 6748; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(f)(7), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 46-306.06.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 30-346.7.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-137, in par. (a)(6), substituted ";" for "; or"; in par. (a)(7), deleted "(choice of law)" following "§ 46-306.04", substituted "alleged arrearages" for "arrearages", and substituted "; or" for a period; and added par. (a)(8).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-81</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-137</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provided: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 607 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
