<level type="section">
  <num>3-101.01</num>
  <heading>Criminal code reform.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2007, the Commission shall also have as its purpose the preparation of comprehensive recommendations to the Council and the Mayor that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Revise the language of criminal statutes to be clear and consistent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In consultation with the Codification Counsel in the Office of the General Counsel for the Council of the District of Columbia, organize existing criminal statutes in a logical order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assess whether criminal penalties (including fines) for felonies are proportionate to the seriousness of the offense, and, as necessary, revise the penalties so they are proportionate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Propose a rational system for classifying misdemeanor criminal statutes, determine appropriate levels of penalties for such classes; and classify misdemeanor criminal statutes in the appropriate classes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Identify any crimes defined in common law that should be codified, and propose recommended language for codification, as appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Identify criminal statutes that have been held to be unconstitutional;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Propose such other amendments as the Commission believes are necessary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Enable the adoption of Title 22 as an enacted title of the District of Columbia Official Code.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than March 31, 2007, the Commission shall submit to the Council and the Mayor a work plan and schedule for carrying out the responsibilities authorized by this section. The work of the Commission under this section shall be completed no later than September 30, 2016.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall submit its recommendations for criminal code revisions in the form of reports. Each report shall be accompanied by draft legislation or other specific steps for implementing the recommendations for criminal code revisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 16, 1998, D.C. Law 12-167, § 2a, as added June 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-126, § 2(b), 53 DCR 4709; Oct. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-25, § 2(b), 54 DCR 8014; Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 202, 56 DCR 7413; Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 3032, 58 DCR 6226; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 3032(b), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-25, in subsec. (c), substituted "recommendations for criminal code revisions" for "recommendations".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-88, in subsec. (b), substituted "2012" for "2010".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-21, in subsec. (b), substituted "2014" for "2012". </text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-168, in subsec. (b), substituted "2016" for "2014".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of District of Columbia Sentencing and Criminal Code Revision Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-72, July 20, 2007, 54 DCR 7401).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009, 56 DCR 6903).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 202 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18- 227, October 21, 2009, 56 DCR 8668).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-126, see notes following § 3-101.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-25, see notes following § 3-101.</text>
        <text>Law 18-88, the "Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Amendment Act of 2009", as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-151, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The bill as adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 31, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 26, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-189 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-88 became effective on December 10, 2009.</text>
        <text>Law 19-21, the "Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Act of 2011", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-203, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 25, 2011, and June 14, 2011, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 22, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 19-98 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-21 became effective on September 14, 2011.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-168, see notes under § 3-101.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 4 of D.C. Law 16-126 provides: 'This act shall apply as of January 1, 2007."</text>
        <text>Short title: Section 3031 of D.C. Law 19-21 provided that subtitle D of title III of the act may be cited as "Criminal Code Reform Extension Amendment Act of 2011".</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
