<level type="section">
  <num>29-603.08</num>
  <heading>Liability of purported partner.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 41-153.8</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 33-103.08</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a person, by words or conduct, purports to be a partner, or consents to being represented by another as a partner, in a partnership or with one or more persons not partners, the purported partner shall be liable to a person to whom the representation is made, if that person, relying on the representation, enters into a transaction with the actual or purported partnership. If the representation, either by the purported partner or by a person with the purported partner's consent, is made in a public manner, the purported partner shall be liable to a person that relies upon the purported partnership even if the purported partner is not aware of being held out as a partner to the claimant. If partnership liability results, the purported partner shall be liable with respect to that liability as if the purported partner were a partner. If no partnership liability results, the purported partner shall be liable with respect to that liability jointly and severally with any other person consenting to the representation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a person is thus represented to be a partner in an existing partnership, or with one or more persons not partners, the purported partner shall be an agent of persons consenting to the representation to bind them to the same extent and in the same manner as if the purported partner were a partner, with respect to persons that enter into transactions in reliance upon the representation. If all of the partners of the existing partnership consent to the representation, a partnership act or obligation shall result. If fewer than all of the partners of the existing partnership consent to the representation, the person acting and the partners consenting to the representation shall be jointly and severally liable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person shall not be liable as a partner merely because the person is named by another in a statement of partnership authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person shall not continue to be liable as a partner merely because of a failure to file a statement of dissociation or to amend a statement of partnership authority to indicate the partner's dissociation from the partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, persons that are not partners as to each other shall not be liable as partners to other persons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 33-103.08.</text>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 41-153.8.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 308 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act). See Vol. 6, Part I , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
