<level type="section">
  <num>29-412.22</num>
  <heading>Receivership or custodianship.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court in a judicial proceeding brought to dissolve a nonprofit corporation may appoint one or more receivers to wind up and liquidate, or one or more custodians to manage, the affairs of the corporation. The court shall hold a hearing, after giving notice to all parties to the proceeding and any interested persons designated by the court, before appointing a receiver or custodian. The court appointing a receiver or custodian has exclusive jurisdiction over the corporation and all of its property wherever located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may require the receiver or custodian to post bond, with or without sureties, in an amount the court directs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall describe the powers and duties of the receiver or custodian in its appointing order, which may be amended. Among other powers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The receiver:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>May dispose of all or any part of the assets of the nonprofit corporation wherever located, at a public or private sale, if authorized by the court; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>May sue and defend in his or her own name as receiver of the corporation;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The custodian may exercise all of the powers of the corporation, through or in place of its board of directors and any designated body, to the extent necessary to manage the affairs of the corporation consistent with its mission and in the best interests of its members, if any, and creditors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>During a receivership, the Superior Court may redesignate the receiver a custodian, and during a custodianship may redesignate the custodian a receiver, if doing so is consistent with the mission of the nonprofit corporation and in the best interests of the corporation, its members, and creditors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court during the receivership or custodianship may order compensation paid and expense disbursements or reimbursements made to the receiver or custodian and counsel from the assets of the nonprofit corporation or proceeds from the sale of the assets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to a religious corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
