<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-806</num>
  <heading>When initial financing statement suffices to continue effectiveness of financing statement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The filing of an initial financing statement in the office specified in § 28:9-501 continues the effectiveness of a financing statement filed before the applicability date if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The filing of an initial financing statement in that office would be effective to perfect a security interest under Article 9 as amended by the 2012 Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The pre-effective-date financing statement was filed in an office in another state; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The initial financing statement satisfies subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The filing of an initial financing statement under subsection (a) of this section continues the effectiveness of the pre-effective-date financing statement:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the initial financing statement is filed before the applicability date, for the period provided in § 28:9-515 as it existed before the applicability date with respect to an initial financing statement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the initial financing statement is filed after the applicability date, for the period provided in § 28:9-515 as amended by the 2012 Act with respect to an initial financing statement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To be effective for purposes of subsection (a) of this section, an initial financing statement must:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Satisfy the requirements of Part 5 as amended by the 2012 Act for an initial financing statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify the pre-effective-date financing statement by indicating the office in which the financing statement was filed and providing the dates of filing and file numbers, if any, of the financing statement and of the most recent continuation statement filed with respect to the financing statement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Indicate that the pre-effective-date financing statement remains effective.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-302, § 2(s), 60 DCR 2688.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-805 and § 28:9-807.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-302</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-669: Section 4 of D.C. Law 19-669 provided that the act shall apply as of July 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
