<level type="section">
  <num>8-105.71</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Authority" means the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority established pursuant to § 34-2202.02(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Backwater valve" means a device installed in a building drain or branch of a building drain that prevents the backflow of water and sewage into the building's drainage system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"District of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund" or "Fund" means the District of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund established in § 8-105.73.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Personal property" means movable property not affixed to land, including goods, wares, merchandise, and household items and furnishings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Program" means the Flood Assistance Fund Program established in § 8-105.72.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Property owner" means the owner of residential property or nonresidential property located within the District of Columbia or the owner of personal property, as defined in this section, housed within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Sewer" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 34-2202.01(9).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"Sewer-line backup" means a wastewater backup into a building, which is caused by blockages, flow conditions, or malfunctions within the sewer system. The term "sewer-line backup" does not include wastewater backups resulting from flow conditions caused by overland flooding or blockages, flow conditions, or malfunctions of a private sewer lateral or internal building plumbing.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-293, § 2, 60 DCR 2613.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-293</heading>
      <text>Law 19-293, the "District Of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund Amendment Act of 2012", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-938. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Returned without signature from the Mayor on Feb. 4, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-661 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-293 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
