<level type="section">
  <num>8-105.73</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the District of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund ("Fund"), which shall be used solely for the purposes stated in subsection (b) of this section. The Fund shall be funded by a flood assistance fund fee, established by the Flood Assistance Fund Manager pursuant to § 8-105.72. All funds collected from the fee defined in paragraph (3) of this subsection shall be deposited into the Fund and shall be disbursed by the Flood Assistance Fund Manager.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 45 days of April 27, 2013, the Mayor shall transmit to the Council a proposed budget for the Fund.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Authority shall collect a flood assistance fund fee in an amount not to exceed $0.30 per Equivalent Residential Unit per month from each property in the District; provided, that the fee shall not apply to District-owned properties or ratepayers enrolled in the Authority's Customer Assistance Program.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on the funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation until September 30, 2014, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money in the Fund shall be used solely:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To reimburse District property owners and renters whose personal property or residential property sustained damage as a result of a sewer-line backup pursuant to § 8-105.72; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To allow the Authority to recover the actual administrative costs associated with collecting the fee on the District's behalf.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the damage to the residential property or the personal property must have been sustained during the time period established in § 8-105.72(b)(2)(C); and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The damage to the residential property or the personal property is not otherwise covered by an insurance policy.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If, at the beginning of a fiscal year, the fund balance of the Fund exceeds the projected annual cost of all programs pursuant to subsection (b) of this section in that fiscal year by at least $1 million, the Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall suspend payment and the collection of the fee defined in subsection (a)(3) of this section, until the excess is estimated by the Flood Assistance Fund Manager to be under $500,000.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If, upon the expiration of this subchapter, there is a balance in the Fund, the excess funds shall be refunded back to the Authority's customers who have paid the fee pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-293, § 4, 60 DCR 2613.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 8-105.71 and § 8-105.72.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-293</heading>
      <text>See note to § 8-105.71.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
