<level type="section">
  <num>8-105.72</num>
  <heading>Flood Assistance Fund Program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 45 days of April 27, 2013, the Mayor shall establish a Flood Assistance Fund Program to reimburse District property owners for damage to personal property and residential property caused directly and exclusively by sewer-line backups that occurred during the time period established in subsection (b)(2)(C) of this section. The Program shall manage the District of Columbia Flood Assistance Fund established in § 8-105.73. The Mayor shall designate a Flood Assistance Fund Manager to oversee the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Coordinate with the Authority to determine eligibility requirements for property owners seeking reimbursement through the Flood Assistance Fund;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Contract with a third party outside the District government to examine and evaluate the property damage for which a District property owner is seeking reimbursement;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Establish the qualifications of the third party to evaluate property damage caused by sewer-line backup;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Establish the criteria the third party shall use to evaluate the damage of a property;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Inform District property owners and renters of the establishment of the Fund within 45 days of April 27, 2013;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Create a process to receive and administer claims submitted by District property owners seeking reimbursement through the Fund;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Establish additional Program requirements as needed; provided, that a property owner's mitigation of the property owner's damage is considered as a requirement; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Coordinate with the Authority to establish a flood assistance fund fee; provided, that the fee shall not exceed $0.30 per Equivalent Residential Unit per month.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In determining whether a residential property owner shall be eligible for reimbursement through the Program, the Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall require the property owner to establish:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>That the property owner owns or rents residential property in the District of Columbia;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>That all damage to the residential property described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph or to personal property housed within the residential property described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, for which the property owner is seeking reimbursement, was caused directly and exclusively by a sewer-line backup;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>That the sewer-line backup occurred:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>After April 27, 2013; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Between June 1, 2012 and April 27, 2013; provided, that the property owner submitted a claim to the Authority seeking reimbursement for property damage related to a sewer-line backup and the claim has not been resolved by the Authority, or the property owner has documentation of property damage related to a sewer-line backup that occurred during this time period, which the Program considers sufficient to evaluate for the purposes of eligibility for reimbursement; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>That the property owner contacted the Program, in a manner prescribed by the Flood Assistance Fund Manager, or notified the Authority about a sewer- line backup within 48 hours of becoming aware of the damage to the property described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A property owner submitting a claim pursuant to paragraph (2)(C)(ii) of this subsection shall submit the claim no later than 6 months after April 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In determining whether a property owner shall be eligible for reimbursement through the Program, the Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall consider the evaluation of the third party established in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall establish eligibility requirements, which shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period review excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove by resolution the requirements within the 45-day period of review, the requirements shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>In executing the process to receive and administer claims submitted by District property owners, the Flood Assistance Fund Manager shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Make an eligibility determination within 30 days of receipt of a claim for reimbursement;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notify a property owner, in writing, of the owner's eligibility for reimbursement through the Fund within 7 days of the determination;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Manage the payment of individual claims reimbursed pursuant to this section; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Remit payment to a property owner within 45 days of issuing a determination that the property owner's claim has been deemed eligible for reimbursement.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Program shall submit a quarterly report to the Mayor and the Council which, at a minimum, shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of claims submitted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The geographic distribution of claims submitted and paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The type of damage compensated by claims paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The processing time for claims and disbursements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The total dollar amount of claims paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Flood Assistance Fund balance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Administrative costs of operating the program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An action to recover for property damage may not be maintained against the District of Columbia or the Authority by a property owner who submits a claim pursuant to this section and is reimbursed through the Fund for the claim.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to exclude from eligibility for the Program, a District property that is not in compliance with section P3008 of the 2006 International Residential Code or section 715 of the 2006 International Plumbing Code; provided, that upon receiving reimbursement through the Fund, a residential property owner shall install a backwater valve, pursuant to section P3008 of the 2006 International Residential Code and section 715 of the 2006 International Plumbing Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No new rights or entitlements are created by this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-293, § 3, 60 DCR 2613.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 8-105.71 and § 8-105.73.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-293</heading>
      <text>See note to § 8-105.71.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
