<level type="section">
  <num>29-607.03</num>
  <heading>Dissociated partner's liability to other persons.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 41-157.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 33-107.03</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A partner's dissociation shall not of itself discharge the partner's liability for a partnership obligation incurred before dissociation. A dissociated partner shall not be liable for a partnership obligation incurred after dissociation, except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A partner that dissociates without resulting in a dissolution and winding up of the partnership business shall be liable as a partner to the other party in a transaction entered into by the partnership, or a surviving partnership under subchapter IX of this chapter, within 2 years after the partner's dissociation, only if the partner is liable for the obligation under § 29- 603.06 and at the time of entering into the transaction the other party:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reasonably believed that the dissociated partner was then a partner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Did not have notice of the partner's dissociation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is not deemed to have had knowledge under § 29-603.03(e) or notice under § 29-607.04(c).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By agreement with the partnership creditor and the partners continuing the business, a dissociated partner may be released from liability for a partnership obligation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A dissociated partner shall be released from liability for a partnership obligation if a partnership creditor, with notice of the partner's dissociation but without the partner's consent, agrees to a material alteration in the nature or time of payment of a partnership obligation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 41-157.3.</text>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 33-107.03.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 703 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act). See Vol. 6, Part I , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
