<level type="section">
  <num>7-2004</num>
  <heading>Eligibility.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible for a loan or grant from the fund, the applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be a District resident who is current in the payment of all taxes and other obligations owed to the District, except that a corporation, association, or partnership must be organized and doing business in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Obtain, from sources other than the fund, money to finance no less than 25% of the cost of the project; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Mayor, for approval, a business plan, which shall include an estimated schedule for completion of the project, the estimated number of children to be served, and the designation of the proposed site in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each project financed by the fund shall comply with ยง 6-1401 et seq., and the Child Development Facilities Regulation, effective December 14, 1974 (Regulation No. 74-34; 21 DCR 1333).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The applicant shall obtain insurance as required by the Mayor and indemnify the District from any liability arising out of the operation of the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible for a grant from the fund, the applicant must be a non-profit organization.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-220, ยง 5, 36 DCR 550.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 6-3604.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-220</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-220, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 7-2001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
