<level type="section">
  <num>24-1302</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Office on Returning Citizen Affairs.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Office on Returning Citizen Affairs. The Office shall coordinate and monitor service delivery to returning citizens. The Office shall make recommendations to the Mayor to promote the general welfare, empowerment, and reintegration of returning citizens in the areas of employment and career development, health care, education, housing, and social services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office shall be headed by an Executive Director, who shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to § 1-523.01(a). The Director shall be a full-time employee, for whom annual compensation shall be fixed in accordance with subchapter X-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Serve as principal advisor to the Mayor on matters related to the reintegration of returning citizens into the general population;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Serve as an advocate for the returning citizens;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Respond to recommendations and policy statements from the Commission;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Identify areas for service improvement and policy development and implementation for presentation to the Mayor and the Commission by funding research, hosting symposia, and undertaking other projects;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Coordinate efforts of District government agencies targeted toward returning citizens;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Accept volunteer services and funding from public and private sources to supplement the budget in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the Office;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Apply for, receive, and expend any gift or grant to further the purposes of the Office;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>File an annual report on the operations of the Office with the Mayor and the Council; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Meet and coordinate with members of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, as set forth in § 22-4233(a), and their designates, to disseminate information and recommendations to and from the voting members of the Commission.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Office shall have staff as funded by appropriations and federal or private grants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-243, § 3, 54 DCR 605; Jan. 19, 2012, D.C. Law 19-80, § 2(a), 58 DCR 8908; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3062(b), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 24-1301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-80, in subsec. (b)(2), deleted "and" from the end of subpar. (G ), substituted "; and" for a period the end of par. (H), and added par. (I).</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 substituted "Office on Returning Citizens" for "Office on Ex-Offender Affairs" in the section heading and (a); and substituted "returning citizens" for "ex-offender" throughout the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3062(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3062(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-243</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-243, see notes following § 24-1301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-80</heading>
      <text>Law 19-80, the "Returning Citizens and Ex-Offender Services Reform Amendment Act of 2011", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-1, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Workforce Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 12, 2011, and September 20, 2011, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 11, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 19-170 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-80 became effective on January 19, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 24-1031.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 3061 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle G of Title III of the act may be cited as the "Returning Citizens Renaming Emergency Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
