<level type="section">
  <num>47-3906</num>
  <heading>Alternate method of reporting.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-3906</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A taxpayer subject to the provisions of § 47-3902 may be allowed an alternate method of reporting its monthly gross charges subject to the tax under this chapter upon showing to the satisfaction of the Mayor, within 90 days from the effective date of this act or 30 days from the first day a toll or wireless telecommunication company begins offering a new toll or wireless telecommunication service in the District, that it does not have the capability to identify the gross charges from the sale of District-based wireless telecommunication, or it is unable to identify the jurisdiction of origination or termination of a particular toll telecommunication service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The showing shall be made by a petition to the Mayor which shall include the factual basis for the inability of the taxpayer to identify the charges, with supporting documentation, and an alternate method of reporting the charges that the taxpayer believes is reasonable and equitable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may employ a reasonable and equitable alternate method for reporting the gross charges of the taxpayer based on information submitted pursuant to this chapter or based on any other information made available to the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 1989, D.C. Law 8-26, § 7, 36 DCR 4723; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; Apr. 30, 1998, D.C. Law 12-100, § 2(e), 45 DCR 1533.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-3906.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Toll Telecommunications Service Tax Temporary Act of 1989 (D.C. Law 8-4, May 23, 1989, law notification 36 DCR 4154).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 8-26, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-3901.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-100, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-3901.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
