<level type="section">
  <num>42-3502.15</num>
  <heading>Voluntary agreement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Seventy percent or more of the tenants of a housing accommodation may enter into a voluntary agreement with the housing provider:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To establish the rent charged;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To alter levels of related services and facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To provide for capital improvements and the elimination of deferred maintenance (ordinary repair).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The voluntary agreement must be filed with the Rent Administrator and shall include the signature of each tenant, the number of each tenant's rental unit or apartment, the specific amount of increased rent each tenant will pay, if applicable, and a statement that the agreement was entered into voluntarily without any form of coercion on the part of the housing provider. If approved by the Rent Administrator the agreement shall be binding on the housing provider and on all tenants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Where the agreement filed with the Rent Administrator is to have the rent charged for all rental units in the housing accommodation adjusted by a specified percentage, the Rent Administrator shall immediately certify approval of the increase.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 215, 32 DCR 3089; Aug. 5, 2006, D.C. Law 16-145, § 2(a), 53 DCR 4889.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 42-3502.08.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 45-2525.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-145, in par. (a)(1) and subsec. (c), substituted "rent charged" for "rent ceiling".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Rent Control Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-470, July 31, 2006, 53 DCR 6772).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-10</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-10, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 42-3501.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-145</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-145, see notes following § 42-3502.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Termination of law Termination of Law 6-10</heading>
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 42-3502.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
