<level type="section">
  <num>29-804.07</num>
  <heading>Management of limited liability company.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited liability company shall be a member-managed limited liability company unless the operating agreement:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Expressly provides that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The company is or will be "manager-managed";</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The company is or will be "managed by managers"; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Management of the company is or will be "vested in managers"; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Includes words of similar import.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In a member-managed limited liability company, the following rules shall apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The management and conduct of the company shall be vested in the members.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each member shall have equal rights in the management and conduct of the company's activities.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A difference arising among members as to a matter in the ordinary course of the activities of the company may be decided by a majority of the members.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An act outside the ordinary course of the activities of the company shall be undertaken only with the consent of all members.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The operating agreement shall be amended only with the consent of all members.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In a manager-managed limited liability company, the following rules apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter, any matter relating to the activities of the company shall be decided exclusively by the managers.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each manager shall have equal rights in the management and conduct of the activities of the company.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A difference arising among managers as to a matter in the ordinary course of the activities of the company may be decided by a majority of the managers.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The consent of all members shall be required to:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise dispose of all, or substantially all, of the company's property, with or without the good will, outside the ordinary course of the company's activities;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Approve a merger or domestication under subchapter IX of this chapter or transaction under Chapter 2 of this title;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Undertake any other act outside the ordinary course of the company's activities; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Amend the operating agreement.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A manager may be chosen at any time by the consent of a majority of the members and shall remain a manager until a successor has been chosen, unless the manager at an earlier time resigns, is removed, or dies, or, in the case of a manager that is not an individual, terminates. A manager may be removed at any time by the consent of a majority of the members without notice or cause.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A person need not be a member to be a manager, but the dissociation of a member that is also a manager shall remove the person as a manager. If a person that is both a manager and a member ceases to be a manager, that cessation shall not by itself dissociate the person as a member.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A person's ceasing to be a manager shall not discharge any debt, obligation, or other liability to the limited liability company or members which the person incurred while a manager.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An action requiring the consent of members under this chapter may be taken without a meeting, and a member may appoint a proxy or other agent to consent or otherwise act for the member by signing an appointing record, personally or by the member's agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The dissolution of a limited liability company shall not affect the applicability of this section. However, a person that wrongfully causes dissolution of the company loses the right to participate in management as a member and a manager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This chapter shall not entitle a member to remuneration for services performed for a member-managed limited liability company, except for reasonable compensation for services rendered in winding up the activities of the company.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 407 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act). See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
