<level type="section">
  <num>29-412.05</num>
  <heading>Effect of dissolution.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved nonprofit corporation continues its corporate existence but shall not carry on any activities except those appropriate to wind up and liquidate its affairs, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Collecting its assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Disposing of its properties that will not be distributed in kind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Discharging or making provision for discharging its liabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Distributing its remaining property as required by law and its articles of incorporation and bylaws, and otherwise as approved when the dissolution was approved or among the members per capita; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate its activities and affairs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Dissolution of a nonprofit corporation shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transfer title to the corporation's property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject its directors, members of a designated body, or officers to standards of conduct different from those prescribed in subchapter VI of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Change:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Quorum or voting requirements for its board of directors or members;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Provisions for selection, resignation, or removal of its directors or officers, or both;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provisions for amending its bylaws;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Prevent commencement of a proceeding by or against the corporation in its corporate name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Abate or suspend a proceeding pending by or against the corporation on the effective date of dissolution; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Terminate the authority of the registered agent of the corporation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Property held in trust or otherwise dedicated to a charitable purpose shall not be diverted from its purpose by the dissolution of a nonprofit corporation unless and until the corporation obtains an order of the Superior Court to the extent required by and pursuant to the law of the District on cy pres or otherwise dealing with the nondiversion of charitable assets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that is a member or otherwise affiliated with a charitable corporation shall not receive a direct or indirect financial benefit in connection with the dissolution of the corporation unless the person is a charitable corporation or an unincorporated entity that has a charitable purpose. This subsection shall not apply to the receipt of reasonable compensation for services rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 29-412.23.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
