<level type="section">
  <num>7-1531.07</num>
  <heading>Preclusive effect of anatomical gift, amendment, or revocation.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section and subject to subsection (f) of this section, in the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor, a person other than the donor is barred from making, amending, or revoking an anatomical gift of a donor's body or part if the donor made an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.04 or an amendment to an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7- 1531.05.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A donor's revocation of an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.05 is not a refusal and does not bar another person specified in § 7-1531.03 or § 7-1531.08 from making an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.04 or § 7-1531.09.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a person other than the donor makes an unrevoked anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.04 or an amendment to an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.05, another person may not make, amend, or revoke the gift of the donor's body or part under § 7-1531.09.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A revocation of an anatomical gift of a donor's body or part under § 7- 1531.05 by a person other than the donor does not bar another person from making an anatomical gift of the body or part under § 7-1531.04 or § 7- 1531.09.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under § 7-1531.03, an anatomical gift of a part is neither a refusal to give another part nor a limitation on the making of an anatomical gift of another part at a later time by the donor or another person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>In the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under § 7-1531.03, an anatomical gift of a part for one or more of the purposes set forth in § 7- 1531.03 is not a limitation on the making of an anatomical gift of the part for any of the other purposes by the donor or any other person under § 7-1531.04 or § 7-1531.09.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If a donor who is an unemancipated minor dies, a parent of the donor who is reasonably available may revoke or amend an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>If an unemancipated minor who signed a refusal dies, a parent of the minor who is reasonably available may revoke the minor's refusal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-145, § 8, 55 DCR 2532; Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 230(b), 56 DCR 1117.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-353 validated previously made technical corrections in subsecs. (b), (d), and (f).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-145, see notes following § 7-1531.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-353, see notes following § 7-161.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 8 of the Revised Uniform Anatomical Gift Act (2006). See Vol. 8A, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
