<level type="section">
  <num>6-1504</num>
  <heading>Tax incentives for businesses in economic development zones.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any incorporated or unincorporated business entity that has a place of business located within an economic development zone shall be qualified for tax incentives if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The qualification is recommended by the Mayor and approved by the Council, by resolution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The business entity has entered an employment agreement with the District of Columbia pursuant to § 2-219.01; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The business entity is subject to franchise taxes under either § 47-1807.01 et seq. or § 47-1808.01 et seq.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The resolution approving the qualification for tax incentives pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the qualified incorporated or unincorporated business entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify each franchise tax credit to be granted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Include an estimate of the annual dollar value of each franchise tax credit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of an incorporated or unincorporated business entity's eligibility for the tax credits provided under §§ 47-1807.04, 47-1807.05, and 47-1808.04, the Mayor shall certify any employee who is a resident of the District of Columbia who received an annual income equal to or less than 150% of the lower living standard income level, as that term is defined in 29 U.S.C. § 1503, in the 12 months immediately preceding the commencement of his employment by the qualified incorporated or unincorporated business and is not a qualified summer youth as defined in 26 U.S.C. § 51.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The following tax incentives shall be available to a qualified incorporated or unincorporated business:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Credits against the corporate franchise tax under §§ 47-1807.04, 47-1807.05, and 47-1807.06; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Credits against the unincorporated business franchise tax under § 47-1808.07.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 1988, D.C. Law 7-177, § 5, 35 DCR 6158; Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 4, 50 DCR 896.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Rent charged to licensed, nonprofit child development center, tax credit, see § 47-1807.06.</text>
      <text>Tax credit for insurance premiums, see § 47-1807.05.</text>
      <text>Tax credit to qualified businesses for wages to qualified employees, see § 47-1807.04.</text>
      <text>Unincorporated business, tax credit, see § 47-1808.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-1807.04, § 47-1807.05, § 47-1807.06, and § 47-1808.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 5-1404.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 14-282, in subsec. (d)(1), substituted "§§ 47-1807.04, 47-1807.05, and 47-1807.06" for "§§ 47-1807.04 and 47-1807.05"; and in subsec. (d)(2), substituted "§ 47-1808.07" for "§ 47-1808.04".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-191, Oct. 5, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 9549).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-228, March 25, 2003, law notification 50 DCR 2741).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-177</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-177, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 6-1501.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-282</heading>
      <text>Law 14-282, the "Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Act of 2002", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-537, which was referred to Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 2, 2002, and October 1, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 22, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 14-616 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-282 became effective on April 4, 2003.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>CEMI-Ridgecrest, Inc., Real Property Tax and Water and Sewer Changes Relief Qualification Approval Emergency Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-605, effective July 7, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the qualification of the Walter E. Washington Estates Project, in Square 6159, Lot No. 125, in the 800 block of Bellevue Street, S.E., which is located in the Alabama Avenue Development Zone, owned by CEMI-Ridgecrest, Inc., for forgiveness of water and sewer charges and forgiveness and reduction of real property taxes owed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
