<level type="section">
  <num>47-2883.05</num>
  <heading>Prosecutions to be conducted by Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 2-505</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Prosecutions for violations of this part, or of the regulations made pursuant thereto, shall be conducted in the name of the District by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia or any of his assistants. As used in this part, the term "Attorney General for the District of Columbia" means the attorney for the District, by whatever title such attorney may be known, designated by the Mayor to perform the functions prescribed for the Attorney General for the District of Columbia in this part. Adjudication of civil infractions shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 6, 1960, 74 Stat. 816, Pub. L. 86-715, § 5; Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 433(b), 32 DCR 4450; Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 74, 52 DCR 2638; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 2-505.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 2-2305.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-354 substituted "Attorney General for the District of Columbia" for "Corporation Counsel".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171 enacted into law Part A of subchapter IV of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-42, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-28803.04.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-354, see notes following § 47-340.03.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-171, see notes under § 47-2883.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Change in Government</heading>
        <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
