<level type="section">
  <num>28:4-404</num>
  <heading>Bank not obliged to pay check more than 6 months old.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:4-404</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>A bank is under no obligation to a customer having a checking account to pay a check, other than a certified check, which is presented more than 6 months after its date, but it may charge its customer's account for a payment made thereafter in good faith.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 706, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text>This section incorporates a type of statute that had been adopted in 26 jurisdictions before the Code. The time limit is set at six months because banking and commercial practice regards a check outstanding for longer than that period as stale, and a bank will normally not pay such a check without consulting the depositor. It is therefore not required to do so, but is given the option to pay because it may be in a position to know, as in the case of dividend checks, that the drawer wants payment made.</text>
      <text>Certified checks are excluded from the section because they are the primary obligation of the certifying bank (Sections 3-409 and 3-413). The obligation runs directly to the holder of the check. The customer's account was presumably charged when the check was certified.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:4-404.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:4-404.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-249, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:4-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
