<level type="section">
  <num>47-1270</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Fund" means the Stevie Sellows Quality Improvement Fund established by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Gross revenue" means the sum of revenue for provisions of services to consumers with developmental disabilities. For purposes of this chapter, gross revenues does not include charitable contributions or interest income.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Intermediate care facility for persons with intellectual or developmental disabilities" and "ICF-IDD" have the same meaning as under 42 U.S.C. 1396d(d), but do not include a facility operated by the federal government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Medicaid" means the medical assistance programs authorized by title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.), and by [§ 1-307.02], and administered by the Department of Health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Quality of care improvements" means improving the quality of care for consumers with developmental disabilities by efforts to reduce turnover and increase the qualifications of the employees, excluding managers, administrators, and contract employees, such as an increase in salaries or benefits, or an increase in training and educational opportunities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Resident" means a person receiving services in an ICF-IDD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Reimbursement methodology" means the prospective Medicaid payment rate system for intermediate care facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-68, § 2(b), 53 DCR 47; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 33(b)(3), 59 DCR 5567.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-1272.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by 19-169, rewrote (3); substituted "ICF-IDD" for "ICF-MR" in (6); and substituted "persons with intellectual disabilities" for "the mentally retarded" in (7).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-169</heading>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
      <text>Law 19-169, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-189. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 6, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 15, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-361 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-169 became effective on Sept. 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7067 of D.C. Law 17-219 repealed section 3 of D.C. Law 16-68.</text>
      <text>Section 33(b)(1) of D.C. Law 19-169 substituted "ICF-IDD Assessment" for "ICF-MR Assessment" in the chapter heading.</text>
      <text>Section 35 of D.C. Law 19-169 provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
