<level type="section">
  <num>8-406</num>
  <heading>Pesticide operators.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person shall act in the capacity of a pesticide operator, or advertise as or assume to act as a pesticide operator at any time unless he is licensed by the Mayor in accordance with this subchapter and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Application for a pesticide operator license shall be made in writing on a form prescribed by the Mayor. Each application shall contain information regarding the applicant's proposed operations, license classification or classifications applied for, and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The full name of the person applying for the license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The full name of each member of the firm or partnership, or the names of the principal officers of the association, corporation, or group, if the applicant is a person other than an individual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The business address of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A certificate of liability insurance as required by § 8-407;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Designation of those individuals who are certified and licensed in each category in which the business will engage; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Mayor may prescribe.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No licensed pesticide operator (as defined in § 8-401(bb)(1) and (bb)(3)) shall permit the use of any pesticide by any person who is not a licensed commercial or public applicator designated pursuant to § 8-406, or a registered employee of the pesticide operator acting under the direct supervision of the licensed applicator.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No licensed pesticide operator (as defined in § 8-401(bb)(2)) shall permit the use of any restricted use pesticide by any person who is not a licensed commercial or public applicator designated pursuant to § 8-406(b)(5), or a registered employee of the pesticide operator acting under the direct supervision of the licensed applicator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 18, 1978, D.C. Law 2-70, § 7, 24 DCR 6867.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-751.6.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 2-70</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-70, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-401.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
