<level type="section">
  <num>32-1008</num>
  <heading>Duties of employers; open records.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every employer subject to any provision of this subchapter or of any regulation or order issued under this subchapter shall make, keep, and preserve for a period of not less than 3 years a record of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name, address, and occupation of each employee;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A record of the date of birth of any employee under 19 years of age;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The rate of pay and the amount paid each pay period to each employee;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The hours worked each day and each workweek by each employee; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any other records or information as the Mayor shall prescribe by regulation as necessary or appropriate for the enforcement of the provisions of this subchapter or of the regulations issued under this subchapter.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any records shall be open and made available for inspection or transcription by the Mayor or the Mayor's authorized representative at any reasonable time. Every employer shall furnish the Mayor or to the Mayor's authorized representative on demand a sworn statement of records and information upon forms prescribed or approved by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every employer shall furnish to each employee at the time of payment of wages an itemized statement showing the date of the wage payment, gross wages paid, deductions from and additions to wages, net wages paid, hours worked during the pay period, and any other information as the Mayor may prescribe by regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, ยง 9, 40 DCR 761.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 32-1010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 36-220.7.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-248</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-248, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 32-1001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
