<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-105</num>
  <heading>Reissuance in alternative medium.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon request of a person entitled under an electronic document of title, the issuer of the electronic document may issue a tangible document of title as a substitute for the electronic document if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person entitled under the electronic document surrenders control of the document to the issuer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The tangible document when issued contains a statement that it is issued in substitution for the electronic document.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon issuance of a tangible document of title in substitution for an electronic document of title in accordance with subsection (a) of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The electronic document ceases to have any effect or validity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person that procured issuance of the tangible document warrants to all subsequent persons entitled under the tangible document that the warrantor was a person entitled under the electronic document when the warrantor surrendered control of the electronic document to the issuer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon request of a person entitled under a tangible document of title, the issuer of the tangible document may issue an electronic document of title as a substitute for the tangible document if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person entitled under the tangible document surrenders possession of the document to the issuer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The electronic document when issued contains a statement that it is issued in substitution for the tangible document.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon issuance of an electronic document of title in substitution for a tangible document of title in accordance with subsection (c) of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tangible document ceases to have any effect or validity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person that procured issuance of the electronic document warrants to all subsequent persons entitled under the electronic document that the warrantor was a person entitled under the tangible document when the warrantor surrendered possession of the tangible document to the issuer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:7-305 and § 28:7-402.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-105.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-105.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:7-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Former § 28:7-105, concerning construction against negative implication, was derived from Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 719, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1. The 2013 revision of this article deleted former § 28:7-105, a statute that provided that courts could apply a rule from Parts 2 and 3 by analogy to a situation not explicitly covered in the provisions on warehouse receipts or bills of lading when it was appropriate. Per the official commentary appearing under § 28:7-101: "this is, of course, an unexceptional proposition and need not be stated explicitly in the statute. Thus former Section 7-105 has been deleted. Whether applying a rule by analogy to a situation is appropriate depends upon the facts of each case."</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
