<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-102</num>
  <heading>Definitions and index of definitions.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this article, unless the context otherwise requires, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Bailee" means a person that by a warehouse receipt, bill of lading, or other document of title acknowledges possession of goods and contracts to deliver them.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Carrier" means a person that issues a bill of lading.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Consignee" means a person named in a bill of lading to which or to whose order the bill promises delivery.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Consignor" means a person named in a bill of lading as the person from which the goods have been received for shipment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Delivery order" means a record that contains an order to deliver goods directed to a warehouse, carrier, or other person that in the ordinary course of business issues warehouse receipts or bills of lading.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Good faith" means honesty in fact and the observance of reasonable commercial standards of fair dealing.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Goods" means all things that are treated as movable for the purposes of a contract for storage or transportation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Issuer" means a bailee that issues a document of title or, in the case of an unaccepted delivery order, the person that orders the possessor of goods to deliver. The term "issuer" includes a person for which an agent or employee purports to act in issuing a document if the agent or employee has real or apparent authority to issue documents, even if the issuer did not receive any goods, the goods were misdescribed, or in any other respect the agent or employee violated the issuer's instructions.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Person entitled under the document" means the holder, in the case of a negotiable document of title or the person to which delivery of the goods is to be made by the terms of or pursuant to instructions in a record under a nonnegotiable document of title.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Shipper" means a person that enters into a contract of transportation with a carrier.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Sign" means with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic sound, symbol, or process.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Warehouse" means a person engaged in the business of storing goods for hire.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Definitions in other articles applying to this article and the sections in which they appear include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Contract for sale", § 28:2-106.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Lessee in the ordinary course of business", § 28:2A-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Receipt" of goods, § 28:2-103.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition, Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 718, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(vv), 44 DCR 1271; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-103 and § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-102.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-255</heading>
      <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:7-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>The National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws has noted that if a state has enacted Revised Article 1, as the District of Columbia did in 2013, the definitions of "good faith" in subsection (a)(6) and "record" in (a)(10) need not be enacted in this section as they are contained in Article 1, Section 1-201.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
