<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-106</num>
  <heading>Control of electronic document of title.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person has control of an electronic document of title if a system employed for evidencing the transfer of interests in the electronic document reliably establishes that person as the person to which the electronic document was issued or transferred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A system satisfies subsection (a) of this section, and a person is deemed to have control of an electronic document of title, if the document is created, stored, and assigned in such a manner that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A single authoritative copy of the document exists which is unique, identifiable, and, except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection, unalterable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The authoritative copy identifies the person asserting control as:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The person to which the document was issued; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the authoritative copy indicates that the document has been transferred, the person to which the document was most recently transferred;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The authoritative copy is communicated to and maintained by the person asserting control or its designated custodian;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Copies or amendments that add or change an identified assignee of the authoritative copy can be made only with the consent of the person asserting control;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Each copy of the authoritative copy and any copy of a copy is readily identifiable as a copy that is not the authoritative copy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any amendment of the authoritative copy is readily identifiable as authorized or unauthorized.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 9, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-103, § 28:4-104, § 28:9-102, § 28:9-203, § 28:9-207, § 28:9-314, and § 28:9-601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:7-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
