<level type="section">
  <num>8-417</num>
  <heading>Unlawful acts.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 6-751.17</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Make a pesticide recommendation or use a pesticide in a manner inconsistent with the labeling thereof, or in violation of the restrictions imposed by the Environmental Protection Agency or the Mayor on the use of that pesticide;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Falsify, or refuse or neglect to maintain or make available, records required to be kept by this chapter and by the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Use fraud or misrepresentation in applying for certification or a license;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Refuse or neglect to comply with any limitations or restrictions on his certification or license;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Make false or fraudulent claims through any media which misrepresent the effect of a pesticide or the method to be utilized in the application of a pesticide;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Apply any known ineffective or improper pesticide;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Operate faulty or unsafe equipment;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Use or supervise the use of a pesticide in a faulty, careless, or negligent manner;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Make false or fraudulent records, invoices, or reports;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Aid, abet, or conspire with any other person to evade the provisions of this chapter;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>Make fraudulent or misleading statements during or after an inspection concerning a pest infestation;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>Impersonate any federal, state, or District inspector or official;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(m)</num>
    <text>Distribute any pesticide which is adulterated or misbranded, or any device which is misbranded;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(n)</num>
    <text>Fail to register a pesticide in accordance with the provisions of this chapter;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(o)</num>
    <text>Violate any other provision of this chapter or of any rule or regulation promulgated by the Mayor pursuant thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 18, 1978, D.C. Law 2-70, ยง 18, 24 DCR 6867.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 6-751.17.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-70, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 8-401.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
