<level type="section">
  <num>1-619.02</num>
  <heading>Limitation upon awards.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-620.2</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>A cash award authorized under the provisions of § 1-619.01(a) may not exceed $5,000 or 10% of the employee's scheduled rate of basic pay, whichever is greater; except, that in the case of suggestions or inventions resulting in a tangible monetary savings or increased revenues, an award shall be based on a percentage formula of the estimated savings or revenues, not to exceed $25,000. No cash award shall be granted to an employee without a written determination by the Mayor or the employee's independent personnel authority that set forth the specific reasons the award is justified. The written determination shall be forwarded to the Council for its information within 30 days of its execution.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1902, 25 DCR 5740; Mar. 24, 1990, D.C. Law 8-97, § 3(d), 37 DCR 1046; June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(u)(2), 45 DCR 2464.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-620.2.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 1-349.2.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of § 1-620.3 [1981 Ed.], see § 2(b) of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pilot Program Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12- 120, August 1, 1997, 44 DCR 4643), and see § 2(b) of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pilot Program Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-178, October 30, 1997, 44 DCR 6946).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-139, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-601.01.</text>
        <text>Law 8-97 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 8-267, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 19, 1989, and January 16, 1990, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1990, it was assigned Act No. 8-149 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-124, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-603.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Applicability of § 101(u) of D.C. Law 12-124: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-619.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
