<level type="section">
  <num>34-1255.07</num>
  <heading>Arbitration.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Council authorizes the District to purchase a cable system at a fair market value under § 34-1255.05 or purchase the cable system at an equitable price under § 34-1255.04(b), and the District and the cable operator cannot agree upon a price, the final price shall be determined by an arbitration panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The arbitration panel shall consist of 3 members, selected as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One member shall be selected by the Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One member shall be selected by the cable operator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One member shall be selected by the Council and the cable operator acting jointly; provided, that if the Council and the cable operator fail to agree on a member, the Council or cable operator may apply to the American Arbitration Association and the American Arbitration Association shall select the member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The member selected under subsection (b)(3) of this section shall be the presiding officer of the arbitration panel, absent majority agreement to the contrary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The determination of the majority of the 3-member arbitration panel shall be binding on the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The cable operator shall bear all expenses regarding the arbitration.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 21, 1982, D.C. Law 4-142, § 507, as added Oct. 9, 2002, D.C. Law 14-193, § 2(b), 49 DCR 7334.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-193</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-193, see notes following § 34-1251.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
