<level type="section">
  <num>7-504.02</num>
  <heading>Composition; appointment.</heading>
  <text>When a vacancy develops on the Commission, the Mayor may appoint a successor to fill the unexpired portion of a term.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 29, 1975, D.C. Law 1-24, title IV, § 402, 22 DCR 2460; June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-285, § 4(i), 46 DCR 1355; Oct. 14, 1999, D.C. Law 13-49, § 5, 46 DCR 5153.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-2222.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 6-1722.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-49 rewrote this section, which previously read:</text>
      <text>"The Commission shall consist of 15 public (voting) members appointed by the Mayor. At least one-half of the membership of the Commission shall consist of actual consumers of services under this program, including low income and minority older persons, at least in proportion to the number of minority older persons in the District of Columbia. There shall also be the following ex officio members: The Directors of the Department of Human Services, the Department of Housing and Community Development, the Department of Recreation, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Employment Services, the Public Library, the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department (or the Director or Chief of such successor agencies), and a member of the Council of the District of Columbia."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(i) of the Confirmation Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-25, March 15, 1999, 46 DCR 2971).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4(i) of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999, 46 DCR 5330).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-24</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-24, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 7-501.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-285</heading>
      <text>Law 12-285, the "Confirmation Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-261, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Vetoed by the Mayor on December 29, 1998, Council overrode the veto on January 5, 1999 and the Bill was assigned Act No. 12-622 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-285 became effective on June 12, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-49</heading>
      <text>Law 13-49, the "Criminal Code and Clarifying Technical Amendments Act of 1999," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-61, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 2, 1999, and April 13, 1999, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 13, 1999, it was assigned Act No. 13-69 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-49 became effective on October 19, 1999.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
