<level type="section">
  <num>9-1003</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>In this chapter:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term "Administrator" means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term "Airports Authority" means the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, a public body to be created by the Commonwealth of Virginia and the District of Columbia consistent with the requirements of § 9-1006.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term "employees" means all permanent Federal Aviation Administration personnel employed on the date the lease under § 9-1004 takes effect by the Metropolitan Washington Airports, an organization within the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term "Metropolitan Washington Airports" means Washington National Airport and Washington Dulles International Airport.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term "Secretary" means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term "Washington Dulles International Airport" means the airport constructed under the Act entitled "An Act to authorize the construction, protection, operation, and maintenance of a public airport on or in the vicinity of the District of Columbia", and includes the Dulles Airport Access Highway and Right-of-way, including the extension between the Interstate Routes I-495 and I-66.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term "Washington National Airport" means the airport described in the Act entitled "An Act to provide for the administration of the Washington National Airport, and for other purposes".</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 30, 1986, 100 Stat. 3341-376, Pub. L. 99-591, § 6004.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 7-1503.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 9-1001.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>"An Act to authorize the construction, protection, operation, and maintenance of a public airport on or in the vicinity of the District of Columbia," referred to in paragraph (6), is 64 Stat. 770.</text>
      <text>"An Act to provide for the administration of the Washington National Airport, and for other purposes," referred to in paragraph (7), is 54 Stat. 686.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
