<level type="section">
  <num>46-303.01</num>
  <heading>Proceedings available under this chapter.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-343.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, this subchapter applies to all proceedings under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An individual petitioner or a support enforcement agency may initiate a proceeding authorized under this chapter by filing a petition in an initiating tribunal for forwarding to a responding tribunal or by filing a petition or a comparable pleading directly in a tribunal of another state which has or can obtain personal jurisdiction over the respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 301, 42 DCR 6748; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(c)(1), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-343.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137 repealed subsec. (b); and in subsec. (c), substituted "initiate" for "commence". Prior to repeal, subsec. (b) read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) This chapter provides for the following proceedings:</text>
        <text>"(1) Establishment of an order for spousal support or child support pursuant to subchapter IV of this chapter;</text>
        <text>"(2) Enforcement of a support order and income-withholding order of another state without registration pursuant to subchapter V of this chapter;</text>
        <text>"(3) Registration of an order for spousal support or child support of another state for enforcement pursuant to subchapter VI of this chapter;</text>
        <text>"(4) Modification of an order for child support or spousal support issued by a tribunal of the District pursuant to part B of subchapter II of this chapter;</text>
        <text>"(5) Registration of an order for child support of another state for modification pursuant to subchapter VI of this chapter;</text>
        <text>"(6) Determination of parentage pursuant to subchapter VII of this chapter; and</text>
        <text>"(7) Assertion of jurisdiction over nonresidents pursuant to part A of subchapter II of this chapter."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 301 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
