<level type="section">
  <num>46-303.19</num>
  <heading>Receipt and disbursement of payments.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A support enforcement agency or tribunal of the District shall disburse promptly any amounts received pursuant to a support order, as directed by the order. The agency or tribunal shall furnish to a requesting party or tribunal of another state a certified statement by the custodian of the record of the amounts and dates of all payments received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If neither the obligor, nor the obligee who is an individual, nor the child resides in the District, upon request from the support enforcement agency of the District or another state, a support enforcement agency of the District or a tribunal of the District shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Direct that the support payment be made to the support enforcement agency in the state in which the obligee is receiving services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Issue and send to the obligor's employer a conforming income-withholding order or an administrative notice of change of payee, reflecting the redirected payments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The support enforcement agency of the District receiving redirected payments from another state pursuant to a law similar to subsection (b) of this section shall furnish to a requesting party or tribunal of the other state a certified statement by the custodian of the record of the amount and dates of all payments received.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 318, 42 DCR 6748; redesignated § 319, June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(c)(19), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 46-303.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 30-343.18.</text>
      <text>2001 Ed., § 46-303.18</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-137, designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-81</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-137</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provided: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 319 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
