<level type="section">
  <num>46-303.04</num>
  <heading>Duties of initiating tribunal.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-343.4</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of a petition authorized by this chapter, an initiating tribunal of the District shall forward the petition and its accompanying documents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To the responding tribunal or appropriate support enforcement agency in the responding state; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the identity of the responding tribunal is unknown, to the state information agency of the responding state with a request that they be forwarded to the appropriate tribunal and that receipt be acknowledged.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If requested by the responding tribunal, a tribunal of the District shall issue a certificate or other document and make findings required by the law of the responding state. If the responding state is a foreign country or political subdivision, upon request, the tribunal shall specify the amount of support sought, convert that amount into the equivalent amount in the foreign currency under applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported, and provide any other documents necessary to satisfy the requirements of the responding state.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 304, 42 DCR 6748; July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-131, § 2(d), 45 DCR 2924; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(c)(4), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-343.4.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137, in subsec. (a), deleted "3 copies of" preceding "the petition"; and rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) If a responding state has not enacted the provisions of this chapter, or a law or procedure substantially similar to this chapter, a tribunal of the District may issue a certificate or other document and make findings required by the law of the responding state. If the responding state is a foreign jurisdiction, the tribunal may specify the amount of support sought and provide other documents necessary to satisfy the requirements of the responding state."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(d) of Uniform Interstate Family Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-94, April 29, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 2785).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-225, December 23, 1997, 45 DCR 151).</text>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-310, March 20, 1998, 45 DCR 1950).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-131, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 304 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
