<level type="section">
  <num>22-3225.04</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 22-3825.4</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person convicted of insurance fraud in the first degree shall be fined not more than $50,000 or imprisoned for not more than 15 years, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any person convicted of insurance fraud in the second degree shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any person convicted of insurance fraud in the second degree who has been convicted previously of insurance fraud pursuant to § 22-3225.02 or § 22- 3225.03, or a felony conviction based on similar grounds in any other jurisdiction, shall be fined not more than $20,000 or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person convicted of misdemeanor insurance fraud shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person convicted of a felony violation of this subchapter shall be disqualified from engaging in the business of insurance, subject to 18 U.S.C. § 1033(e)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 125d, as added Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-273, § 2, 46 DCR 1132; June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 12(a), 48 DCR 1873; July 25, 2006, D.C. Law 16-144, § 2(d), 53 DCR 2838.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 22-3825.4.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-313, in subsec. (b)(2), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-144 rewrote section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) Any person convicted of insurance fraud in the first degree shall be subject to a fine of not more than $50,000 or imprisonment for not more than 15 years, or both.</text>
        <text>"(b) Any person convicted of insurance fraud in the second degree shall be subject to the following:</text>
        <text>"(1) A fine of not more than $5,000 or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both; or</text>
        <text>"(2) A fine of not more than $10,000 or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, for a second or subsequent offense under § 22-3225.03 or a conviction based on similar grounds in any other jurisdiction.</text>
        <text>"(c) A person convicted of a felony violation of this subchapter shall be disqualified from engaging in the business of insurance, subject to 18 U.S.C. § 1033(e)(2)."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-273, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 22-3225.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-313, see notes following § 22-2803.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-144, see notes following § 22-3225.02.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
