<level type="section">
  <num>22-3225.03</num>
  <heading>Insurance fraud in the second degree.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 22-3825.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>A person commits the offense of insurance fraud in the second degree if that person knowingly engages in conduct specified in § 22-3225.02 with the intent to defraud or to fraudulently obtain property of another and the value of the property which is sought to be obtained is $1,000 or more.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 125c, as added Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-273, § 2, 46 DCR 1132; July 25, 2006, D.C. Law 16-144, § 2(b), 53 DCR 2838; June 3, 2011, D.C. Law 18-377, § 12(c), 58 DCR 1174.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 22-3825.3.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-144 rewrote section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"A person commits insurance fraud in the second degree if that person knowingly presents false information or conceals information regarding a material fact in any of the following:</text>
        <text>"(1) Application for, rating of, or renewal of an insurance policy or reinsurance contract;</text>
        <text>"(2) Claim for payment or benefit pursuant to an insurance policy or reinsurance contract;</text>
        <text>"(3) Premiums paid on an insurance policy or reinsurance contract;</text>
        <text>"(4) Payment made in accordance with the terms of an insurance policy or reinsurance contract;</text>
        <text>"(5) Application used in a premium finance transaction;</text>
        <text>"(6) Solicitation for sale of an insurance policy;</text>
        <text>"(7) Application for a license or certificate of authority filed with the Commissioner or the chief insurance regulatory official of another jurisdiction;</text>
        <text>"(8) Financial statement or condition of any insurer or reinsurer;</text>
        <text>"(9) Acquisition, formation, merger, affiliation, reconsolidation, dissolution, or withdrawal from one or more lines of insurance or reinsurance in the District by an insurer or reinsurer;</text>
        <text>"(10) Issuance of written evidence of insurance; or</text>
        <text>"(11) Application for reinstatement of an insurance policy."</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-377 substituted "$1,000" for "$250".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 512(c) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011, 58 DCR 640).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 512(c) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011, 58 DCR 3701).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-273, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 22-3225.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-144, see notes following § 22-3225.02.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-377, see notes under § 22-303.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
