<level type="section">
  <num>2-218.25</num>
  <heading>By-laws and internal rules.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The Commission may promulgate, amend, repeal, and enforce any by-laws and internal rules of operation, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out its responsibilities under this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The Department may promulgate, amend, repeal, and enforce any bylaws and internal rules of operation, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out its responsibilities under this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2325, 52 DCR 7503; July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(e), 55 DCR 6107.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-207 designated par. (1) and added par. (2).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Law 17-96, January 29, 2008, law notification 55 DCR 3403).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2325 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007, 54 DCR 10919).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008, 55 DCR 1259).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-33</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following § 2-218.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-207</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-207, see notes following § 2-218.02.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
