<level type="section">
  <num>2-218.22</num>
  <heading>Functions of the Commission.</heading>
  <text>The Commission shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Hear all requested appeals by business enterprises upon the denial of an application for certification by the Department; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Take such other actions as are necessary or appropriate to carry out the responsibilities of the Commission under this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2322, 52 DCR 7503; Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 2062(c), 54 DCR 7052; Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(d), 57 DCR 1485.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-218.13 and § 2-218.75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-20 rewrote pars. (1) and (2), which had read as follows: "(1) Determine a business enterprise's or joint venture's eligibility for certification under part D and review and determine the continued eligibility of business enterprises and joint ventures certified by the Commission; (2) Determine the percentage of the amount of a joint venture which may be attributed toward an agency's percentage goal; and"</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-141 rewrote the section, which had read as follows: "The Commission shall: (1) Hear all requested appeals by business enterprises upon the denial of an application for initial certification, reinstatement, or renewal by the Department; (2) Perform regular and routine aud Department's certification process through a random review of 5 applications per month; and (3) Repeal and suspend the certification of a business enterprise pursuant to § 2-218.63."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2322 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2062(c) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007, 54 DCR 7549).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-33</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following § 2-218.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-20</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-20, see notes following § 2-215.24.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-141</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-141, see notes following § 2-218.02.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
