<level type="section">
  <num>50-1802</num>
  <heading>Use of safety belts required; exceptions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 40-1602</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in Chapter 17 of this title, the driver and all passengers in a motor vehicle shall wear a properly adjusted and fastened safety belt while the driver is in control of the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to operators or passengers under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Riders in a motor vehicle manufactured before July 1, 1966;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Riders who possess a written verification from a licensed physician that the rider is unable to wear a safety belt for medical reasons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Riders who are passengers in a vehicle if all seating positions with seat belts in the vehicle are occupied by other persons. The driver shall insure that children 16 years of age and under have preference to seating positions with seat belts over persons more than 16 years of age; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Operators of taxicabs who possess valid taxicab licenses while picking up or transporting passengers for hire between the hours of 6:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Two years following June 9, 2001, the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission shall submit to the Council a report on the impact on driver safety of subsection (b)(4) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 12, 1985, D.C. Law 6-73, § 3, 32 DCR 6344; Mar. 7, 1992, D.C. Law 9-57, § 3, 38 DCR 7283; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-244, § 2(a), 44 DCR 1155; June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-307, § 4, 48 DCR 600.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 40-1602.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-307, in subsec. (b), deleted "or" at the end of par. (2), substituted "; or" for the period at the end of par. (3), and added par. (4); and added subsec. (c).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-73, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50-1801.</text>
        <text>Law 9-57, the "Child Restraint Act of 1982 Amendment Act of 1991," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-100, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 1, 1991, and November 5, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-100 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>Law 11-244, the "Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-693, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-504 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-244 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
        <text>Law 13-307, the "Taxicab Drivers Protection Act of 2000," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-638, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-515 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-307 became effective on June 9, 2001.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Expiration of Law 6-73: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50- 1801.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
