<level type="section">
  <num>50-1806</num>
  <heading>Enforcement of chapter.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 40-1606</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall not be penalties for violating the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996 during the first 6 months after December 12, 1985. Instead, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue warnings to drivers and passengers who violate the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996 during those 6 months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The penalties provisions in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section shall not be enforced until 6 months after the effective date of the Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996. The Mayor shall issue rules consistent with the purpose and regulatory scheme created by this chapter. The Mayor shall issue the rules pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (§ 2-501 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The penalty imposed by the Mayor for violating this chapter shall be $50, although the Mayor may subsequently increase the amount of the penalty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department of Motor Vehicles shall assign points, pursuant to 18 DCMR § 303, to the record of a driver found in violation of this chapter as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Two points for a single violation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A total of 3 points for simultaneous multiple violations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Violations of this chapter shall be civil infractions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The driver of the vehicle, except operators of passenger vehicles for hire, shall be responsible for ensuring that passengers comply with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 12, 1985, D.C. Law 6-73, § 7, 32 DCR 6344; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-244, § 2(c), 44 DCR 1155; Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-289, § 303, 48 DCR 2057.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 40-1606.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-289 rewrote subsec. (d) which had read:</text>
        <text>"(d) The Department of Public Works shall assign 2 points pursuant to 18 DCMR 303 to the driving record of a driver found in violation of this chapter."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-73, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50-1801.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-244, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50-1802.</text>
        <text>For D.C. Law 13-289, see notes following § 50-401.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>The "Mandatory Use of Seat Belts Amendment Act of 1996," referred to in (a), is codified as §§ 50-1802, 50-1805, and 50-1806.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to Law 6-73, see Mayor's Order 86-138, August 19, 1986.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Expiration of Law 6-73: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50- 1801.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
