<level type="section">
  <num>28:5-113</num>
  <heading>Transfer by operation of law.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:5-113</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A successor of a beneficiary may consent to amendments, sign and present documents, and receive payment or other items of value in the name of the beneficiary without disclosing its status as a successor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A successor of a beneficiary may consent to amendments, sign and present documents, and receive payment or other items of value in its own name as the disclosed successor of the beneficiary. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e) of this section, an issuer shall recognize a disclosed successor of a beneficiary as beneficiary in full substitution for its predecessor upon compliance with the requirements for recognition by the issuer of a transfer of drawing rights by operation of law under the standard practice referred to in § 28:5-108(e) or, in the absence of such a practice, compliance with other reasonable procedures sufficient to protect the issuer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An issuer is not obliged to determine whether a purported successor is a successor of a beneficiary or whether the signature of a purported successor is genuine or authorized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Honor of a purported successor's apparently complying presentation under subsection (a) or (b) of this section has the consequences specified in § 28:5-108(i) even if the purported successor is not the successor of a beneficiary. Documents signed in the name of the beneficiary or of a disclosed successor by a person who is neither the beneficiary nor the successor of the beneficiary are forged documents for the purposes of § 28:5-109.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An issuer whose rights of reimbursement are not covered by subsection (d) of this section or substantially similar law and any confirmer or nominated person may decline to recognize a presentation under subsection (b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A beneficiary whose name is changed after the issuance of a letter of credit has the same rights and obligations as a successor of a beneficiary under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 713, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 7, 29 DCR 309; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(uu), 44 DCR 1271.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text>This section affirms the result in <text i="True">Pastor v. Nat. Republic Bank of Chicago</text>, 76 Ill.2d 139, 390 N.E.2d 894 (Ill.1979) and <text i="True">Federal Deposit Insurance Co. v. Bank of Boulder</text>, 911 F.2d 1466 (10th Cir.1990).</text>
      <text>An issuer's requirements for recognition of a successor's status might include presentation of a certificate of merger, a court order appointing a bankruptcy trustee or receiver, a certificate of appointment as bankruptcy trustee, or the like. The issuer is entitled to rely upon such documents which on their face demonstrate that presentation is made by a successor of a beneficiary. It is not obliged to make an independent investigation to determine the fact of succession.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:5-113.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:5-113.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-112.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-238, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-101.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-255, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
