<level type="section">
  <num>28:5-120</num>
  <heading>Security interest of issuer or nominated person.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An issuer or nominated person has a security interest in a document presented under a letter of credit to the extent that the issuer or nominated person honors or gives value for the presentation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>So long as and to the extent that an issuer or nominated person has not been reimbursed or has not otherwise recovered the value given with respect to a security interest in a document under subsection (a), the security interest continues and is subject to Article 9, but:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A security agreement is not necessary to make the security interest enforceable under ยง 28:9-203(b)(3);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the document is presented in a medium other than a written or other tangible medium, the security interest is perfected; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the document is presented in a written or other tangible medium and is not a certificated security, chattel paper, a document of title, an instrument, or a letter of credit, the security interest is perfected and has priority over a conflicting security interest in the document so long as the debtor does not have possession of the document.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, ยง 201(f)(2), 47 DCR 7576; Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, ยง 62, 51 DCR 881.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-105 validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 15-105, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2003", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-437, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 2003, and December 2, 2003, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 6, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-291 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-105 became effective on March 13, 2004.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
