<level type="section">
  <num>28:5-117</num>
  <heading>Subrogation of issuer, applicant, and nominated person.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An issuer that honors a beneficiary's presentation is subrogated to the rights of the beneficiary to the same extent as if the issuer were a secondary obligor of the underlying obligation owed to the beneficiary and of the applicant to the same extent as if the issuer were the secondary obligor of the underlying obligation owed to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An applicant that reimburses an issuer is subrogated to the rights of the issuer against any beneficiary, presenter, or nominated person to the same extent as if the applicant were the secondary obligor of the obligations owed to the issuer and has the rights of subrogation of the issuer to the rights of the beneficiary stated in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A nominated person who pays or gives value against a draft or demand presented under a letter of credit is subrogated to the rights of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The issuer against the applicant to the same extent as if the nominated person were a secondary obligor of the obligation owed to the issuer by the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The beneficiary to the same extent as if the nominated person were a secondary obligor of the underlying obligation owed to the beneficiary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The applicant to same extent as if the nominated person were a secondary obligor of the underlying obligation owed to the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any agreement or term to the contrary, the rights of subrogation stated in subsections (a) and (b) of this section do not arise until the issuer honors the letter of credit or otherwise pays and the rights in subsection (c) of this section do not arise until the nominated person pays or otherwise gives value. Until then, the issuer, nominated person, and the applicant do not derive under this section present or prospective rights forming the basis of a claim, defense, or excuse.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 712, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1993, D.C. Law 9-196, § 3, 39 DCR 9165, renumbered and amended Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:5-103 and § 28:5-108.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:5-117.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:5-117.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-196</heading>
      <text>Law 9-196, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-20, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-321 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-196 became effective on March 16, 1993.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-238</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-238, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
