<level type="section">
  <num>28:5-116</num>
  <heading>Choice of law and forum.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The liability of an issuer, nominated person, or adviser for action or omission is governed by the law of the jurisdiction chosen by an agreement in the form of a record signed or otherwise authenticated by the affected parties in the manner provided in § 28:5-104 or by a provision in the person's letter of credit, confirmation, or other undertaking. The jurisdiction whose law is chosen need not bear any relation to the transaction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless subsection (a) of this section applies, the liability of an issuer, nominated person, or adviser for action or omission is governed by the law of the jurisdiction in which the person is located. The person is considered to be located at the address indicated in the person's undertaking. If more than one address is indicated, the person is considered to be located at the address from which the person's undertaking was issued. For the purpose of jurisdiction, choice of law, and recognition of interbranch letters of credit, but not enforcement of a judgment, all branches of a bank are considered separate juridical entities and a bank is considered to be located at the place where its relevant branch is considered to be located under this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the liability of an issuer, nominated person, or adviser is governed by any rules of custom or practice, such as the Uniform Customs and Practice for Documentary Credits, to which the letter of credit, confirmation, or other undertaking is expressly made subject. If (i) this article would govern the liability of an issuer, nominated person, or adviser under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, (ii) the relevant undertaking incorporates rules of custom or practice, and (iii) there is conflict between this article and those rules as applied to that undertaking, those rules govern except to the extent of any conflict with the nonvariable provisions specified in § 28:5-103(c).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If there is conflict between this article and Article 3, 4, 4A, or 9, this article governs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The forum for settling disputes arising out of an undertaking within this article may be chosen in the manner and with the binding effect that governing law may be chosen in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:1-301 and § 28:9-306.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:5-116.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:5-116.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-85</heading>
      <text>Law 4-85, the "Uniform Commercial Code Amendments Act of 1981," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-89, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1981, and December 8, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 18, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-139 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-238</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-238, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
