<level type="section">
  <num>28:5-103</num>
  <heading>Scope.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This article applies to letters of credit and to certain rights and obligations arising out of transactions involving letters of credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The statement of a rule in this article does not by itself require, imply, or negate application of the same or a different rule to a situation not provided for, or to a person not specified, in this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>With the exception of this subsection, subsections (a) and (d) of this section, §§ 28:5-102(a)(9) and (10), 28:5-106(d), and 28:5-114(d), and except to the extent prohibited in §§ 28:1-302 and 28:5-117(d), the effect of this article may be varied by agreement or by a provision stated or incorporated by reference in an undertaking. A term in an agreement or undertaking generally excusing liability or generally limiting remedies for failure to perform obligations is not sufficient to vary obligations prescribed by this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Rights and obligations of an issuer to a beneficiary or a nominated person under a letter of credit are independent of the existence, performance, or nonperformance of a contract or arrangement out of which the letter of credit arises or which underlies it, including contracts or arrangements between the issuer and the applicant and between the applicant and the beneficiary.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 708, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; renumbered and amended Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-238, § 2, 44 DCR 923; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 8, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:5-116.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:5-103.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:5-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 substituted "28:1-302" for "28:1-102(3)" in the first sentence of (c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-238</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-238, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:5-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
