<level type="section">
  <num>47-2885.01</num>
  <heading>Purposes; scope.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 2-2001</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The purposes of this part are:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To license pharmacies and pharmacists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To register pharmacy interns;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To regulate the practice of pharmacy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To establish a Board of Pharmacy in the District of Columbia in order to protect the public health and welfare.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This part shall not apply to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A duly licensed medical practitioner who personally dispenses or administers drugs or poisons as the practitioner deems proper in the treatment of the practitioner's patients;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The administering of drugs by a registered or licensed nurse under the direction of a medical practitioner to the practitioner's patient or patients;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Or otherwise interfere with the sale of over-the-counter drugs; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any person who is a wholesaler or manufacturer, or any employee of such person, when engaged in the discharge of his or her official duties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this part shall be construed as altering or affecting in any way laws of the District of Columbia or any federal act requiring a written prescription for controlled substances or other dangerous drugs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, ยง 2, 27 DCR 3528; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 302(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 2-2001.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171 enacted into law Part C of subchapter IV of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 3-98, the "District of Columbia Certificate of Need Act of 1980," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-129, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 17, 1980, and July 1, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 16, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-220 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 20, 2012, and April 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority under D.C. Law 3-98, the "D.C. Pharmacist and Pharmacy Regulation Act of 1980", see Mayor's Order 91-47, April 8, 1991.</text>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Law 3-98, the "District of Columbia Pharmacist and Pharmacy Regulation Act of 1980", see Mayor's Order 98-48, April 15, 1998 (45 DCR 2693).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
