<level type="section">
  <num>47-2885.17</num>
  <heading>Labeling of prescriptions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 2-2017</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale by peddling, or to offer for sale from house to house, or to offer for sale by public outcry, or by vending in the street, any drug, medicine, chemical, or controlled substance as defined in the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, or any compound or combination thereof, or any implement, appliance, or other agency for the treatment of disease, injury, or deformity; except, as may be otherwise authorized by law, no person shall throw, cast, deposit, drop, scatter, or leave, or cause to be thrown, cast, deposited, dropped, scattered, or left, any drug, medicine, chemical, or controlled substance as defined in the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, or any compound or combination thereof, upon any public highway or place, or, without the consent of the owner or occupant thereof, upon any premises in the District of Columbia. An offer for sale by peddling includes remaining or wandering about a public place and:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repeatedly beckoning to, repeatedly stopping, repeatedly attempting to stop, or repeatedly attempting to engage passers-by in conversation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repeatedly stopping or attempting to stop motor vehicles; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repeatedly interfering with the free passage of other persons for the purpose of selling any controlled substance proscribed by the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-98, § 18, 27 DCR 3528; Dec. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 4-57, § 4, 28 DCR 4642; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 2-2017.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171 enacted into law Part C of subchapter IV of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-98, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2885.01.</text>
        <text>Law 4-57, the "Control of Prostitution and Sale of Controlled Substances in Public Places Criminal Control Act of 1981," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-184, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 15, 1981, and September 29, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 19, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 4-98 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-171, see notes under § 47-2885.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>The "District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981," referred to throughout this section, is D.C. Law 4-29.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
