<level type="section">
  <num>50-2201.05a</num>
  <heading>Establishment of Ignition Interlock Device Program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days of April 20, 2013, the Mayor shall establish an Ignition Interlock Device Program applicable to persons who have been convicted of an offense pursuant to § 50-2206.11, § 50-2206.12, or § 50-2206.14, note, or any succeeding emergency act establishing those sections in substantially similar language, or pursuant to § 50-2206.11, § 50-2206.12 or § 50-2206.14, or whose operator's permit has been revoked pursuant to § 50-1403.01(a) for driving while the person's alcohol concentration is 0.08 grams or more either per 100 milliliters of blood or per 210 liters of breath or is 0.10 grams or more per 100 milliliters of urine, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor or any drug or any combination thereof, or while the ability to operate a vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, "Ignition Interlock Device" means ignition equipment designed to prevent a motor vehicle from being operated by a person whose blood alcohol level exceeds the calibrated setting on the device.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall adopt rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1124, ch. 443, § 10a, as added Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-238, § 2(b), 48 DCR 602; Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-258, § 2, 60 DCR 1080.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-258 rewrote (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-238</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 13-238, see notes following § 50-2201.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-258</heading>
      <text>Law 19-258, the "Ignition Interlock Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-673. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 9, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-610 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-258 became effective on Apr. 20, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of Authority Over an Ignition Interlock Device Program Pursuant to the D.C. Traffic Act of 1925, see Mayor's Order 2002-72, April 19, 2002 (49 DCR 3736).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
