<level type="section">
  <num>50-2201.03a</num>
  <heading>Regulations for personal mobility devices.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall promulgate regulations governing the PMD, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Exempting the personal mobility device from the regulations governing motor vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establishing a registration process, such as, for example, requiring that each PMD bear a serial number, valid registration tag, or valid registration plate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establishing a fine schedule for violations of the PMD regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Providing an adjudication process for violations of PMD law and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Regulations promulgated pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. If the proposed rules are not approved within the 45-day period of review, the rules shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 443, § 6a, as added Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-235, § 10(b), 49 DCR 9788; Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-224, § 101(b), 53 DCR 10225.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-224 revived the provisions of D.C. Law 14-235 that expired on October 1, 2005.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 10(b) of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Law 16-85, April 4, 2006, law notification 53 DCR 3344).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(b) of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-237, December 22, 2005, 53 DCR 249).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 10(b) of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-323, March 23, 2006, 53 DCR 2567).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101(b) of Personal Mobility Device Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-528, December 4, 2006, 53 DCR 9826).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-224, see notes following § 50-601.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Expiration of previous addition: Section 14 of D.C. Law 14-235 (49 DCR 9788), which previously added this section, expired on October 1, 2005.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
