<level type="section">
  <num>21-2076</num>
  <heading>Payment of debt and delivery of property to foreign conservator without local proceedings.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 21-2076</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person indebted to a protected individual or having possession of property or of an instrument evidencing a debt, stock, or chose in action belonging to a protected individual may pay or deliver it to a conservator, guardian of the estate, or other fiduciary appointed by a court of the state of residence of the protected individual upon being presented with proof of appointment and an affidavit made by or on behalf of the fiduciary stating:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That no protective proceeding relating to the protected individual is pending in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the foreign fiduciary is entitled to payment or to receive delivery.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the person to whom the affidavit is presented is not aware of any protective proceeding pending in the District, payment or delivery in response to the demand and affidavit discharges the debtor or possessor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-204, § 2(a), 34 DCR 632; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 14(x), 45 DCR 745.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 21-2076.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-204, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-2001.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-2011.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 2-330 of the Uniform Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Act (1982 Act). See 8A Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on WESTLAW.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
