<level type="section">
  <num>19-602.05</num>
  <heading>Designation of agent.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By a writing signed by all parties, the parties may designate as agent of all parties on an account a person other than a party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the terms of an agency designation provide that the authority of the agent terminates on disability or incapacity of a party, the agent's authority survives disability and incapacity. The agent may act for an incapacitated party or a party with a disability until the authority of the agent is terminated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Death of the sole party or last surviving party terminates the authority of an agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-292, ยง 302(b), 48 DCR 2087; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, ยง 33(a), 53 DCR 6198.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-305, in subsec. (b), substituted "an incapacitated party or a party with a disability" for "a disabled or incapacitated party".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For D.C. Law 13-292, see notes following ยง 19-601.01.</text>
        <text>Law 16-305, the "People First Respectful Language Modernization Act of 2006", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-664, which was referred to Committee on the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 20, 2006, and July 11, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-437 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-305 became effective on April 24, 2007.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 205 of the Uniform Nonprobate Transfers on Death Act (1991 Act). See 8B Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on WESTLAW.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
