<level type="section">
  <num>38-193</num>
  <heading>Evaluation and re-authorization.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By October 1 of each year, beginning in 2009, and every year thereafter, an evaluator shall be retained to conduct an independent evaluation of District of Columbia Public Schools ("DCPS") and of any affiliated education reform efforts. The evaluation shall be conducted according to the standard procedures of the evaluator, with full cooperation of the Council, Mayor, Chancellor, State Superintendent of Education, and other government personnel.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The annual evaluation shall include an assessment of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Business practices;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Human resources operations and human capital strategies;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All academic plans; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The annual progress made as measured against the benchmarks submitted the previous year, including a detailed description of student achievement.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The initial evaluation shall incorporate benchmarks and analysis of the best available data to assess annual achievement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On September 30, 2014, the independent evaluator shall submit to the Council, the State Board of Education, and the Mayor a 5-year assessment of the public education system established by this chapter, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A comprehensive evaluation of public education following the passage of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A determination as to whether sufficient progress in public education has been achieved to warrant continuation of the provisions and requirements of this chapter or whether a new law, and a new system of education, should be enacted by the District government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The evaluations, and assessment, required by this section shall be conducted by the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences ("NRC") for the 5-year period described in this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By December 31, 2009, prior to conducting the initial evaluation, NRC shall submit to the Council and the Mayor a compilation of data and an analysis plan, which shows:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A description of the procedures and method to be used to conduct the evaluation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The opportunities for public involvement;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The estimated release dates of interim and final evaluation reports; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A revised budget and funding plan for the evaluation.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall transfer by October 5, 2009, an amount of $325,000 in local funds through an intra-District transfer from DCPS to the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor to contract with NRC to conduct the initial evaluation required by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 204, 54 DCR 4102; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4051(b), 57 DCR 181; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 93, 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-1595.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-111 rewrote the section.</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 made a technical correction to D.C. Law 18-111 which did not affect this section as codified.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4051(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4051(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-9</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-9, see notes following § 38-191.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 38-191.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>"This act", referred to in subsec. (b) of this section, is D.C. Law 17-9.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
