<level type="section">
  <num>1-309.32</num>
  <heading>Supplementary petitions.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-266</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As soon as possible after June 19, 1976, but in no case more than 5 days after such date, the Board shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make available to any resident of a Commission area copies of petition forms for collecting signatures of registered qualified electors in such area; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Publish in the District of Columbia Register, and post in conspicuous places in each Commission area, the number of registered qualified electors in such Commission area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon certification by the Board to the Chairman of the Council that 5 percent of the registered qualified electors of a Commission area have signed a petition calling for the establishment of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission in such area, the Council shall then establish, by resolution, a nonpartisan elected Advisory Neighborhood Commission for such Commission area, with its members to be elected from the single-member districts established for such Commission area. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit an individual to sign more than 1 petition for the establishment of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 19, 1976, D.C. Law 1-72, § 3, 23 DCR 575.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-266.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 1-171n.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-309.31.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
