<level type="section">
  <num>1-309.34</num>
  <heading>Election of members; term of office; vacancies; change in residency.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-268</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Following the initial elections of members of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions in November 1976, subsequent elections of such members occurred in November of odd-numbered calendar years through 1981. Beginning in 1984, general elections of members of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions shall take place on the 1st Tuesday after the 1st Monday in November of each even-numbered calendar year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission shall serve for a term of 2 years which shall begin at noon on the 2nd day of January next following the date of election of such member, or at noon on the day after the date the Board certifies the election of such member, whichever is later.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission holding office on August 2, 1983, shall continue in office until noon on the 2nd day of January next following the date of the election provided for in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsections (c), (d), and (e) of § 1-309.06 shall apply to members elected to such Advisory Neighborhood Commissions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 19, 1976, D.C. Law 1-72, § 5, 23 DCR 576; Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-17, § 3, 30 DCR 3196; Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-116, § 2, 31 DCR 4018.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-268.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 1-171p.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-309.31.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-17, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-309.06.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-116, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-207.38.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>"Paragraph (2) of this subsection", which established the term of members elected in 1984, referred to in (b)(3), was repealed by D.C. Law 5-116, § 3(b), effective September 26, 1984.</text>
        <text>Section 1-309.06(c), referred to in subsection (c), was repealed by D.C. Law 4- 14, § 2(b), effective June 23, 1981.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
