<level type="section">
  <num>29-103.04</num>
  <heading>Registration of name.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership not registered to do business in the District under subchapter VI of this chapter may register its name, or an alternate name required by § 29-105.06, if the name is distinguishable upon the records of the Mayor from the names that are not available under § 29-103.01.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To register its name or an alternate name required by § 29-105.06, a foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership shall deliver to the Mayor for filing an application setting forth its name, or its name with any addition required by § 29-105.06, and the jurisdiction and date of its formation. If the Mayor finds that the name applied for is available, the Mayor shall register the name for the applicant's exclusive use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The registration of a name under this section shall be effective for one year after the date of registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership whose name registration is effective may renew the registration for successive one-year periods by delivering, not earlier than 3 months before the expiration of the registration, to the Mayor for filing a renewal application that complies with this section. When filed, the renewal application renews the registration for a succeeding one-year period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership with an effective name registration may register as a foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership under its registered name, or may consent in a signed record to the use of that name by another entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(a)(15), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-103.01 and § 47-2855.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "registration" for "filing" in (c); substituted "registration" for "registration year" in (d); and rewrote (e).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-101.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
