<level type="section">
  <num>29-103.01</num>
  <heading>Permitted names.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (d) of this section, the name of a domestic entity, and the name under which a foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership may register to do business in the District, shall be distinguishable on the records of the Mayor from any:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name of another domestic filing entity or limited liability partnership;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Name of a foreign entity that is registered to do business in the District under subchapter V of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Name that is reserved under § 29-103.03;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Name that is registered under § 29-103.04; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Assumed name registered under subchapter I-C of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An entity may consent in a record to the use of its name by another registered entity, but the consenting entity must, in a form satisfactory to the Mayor, change its name so that it is distinguishable from any name in any category of names in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, in determining whether a name is the same as or not distinguishable on the records of the Mayor from the name of another entity, words, phrases, or abbreviations indicating the type of entity, such as "corporation", "corp.", "incorporated", "Inc.", "professional corporation", "PC", "professional association", "PA", "Limited", "Ltd.", "limited partnership", "LP", "limited liability partnership", "LLP", "registered limited liability partnership", "RLLP", "limited liability limited partnership", "LLLP", "registered limited liability limited partnership", "RLLLP", "limited liability company", or "LLC", shall not be taken into account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An entity may consent in a record to the use of a name that is not distinguishable on the records of the Mayor from its name except for the addition of a word, phrase, or abbreviation indicating the type of entity described in subsection (c) of this section. In such a case, the entity need not change its name pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An entity name shall not contain the words "bank", "banking", "credit union", "insurance", or words of similar import, without the prior approval of the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An entity name shall not be the same as, or so deceptively similar to, the name of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or the District of Columbia so as to mislead the public or cause confusion.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(a)(13), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-103.04, § 29-105.03, § 29-105.06, § 29-105.10, § 29-106.03, § 29-302.02, § 29-402.02, § 29-407.04, § 29-610.01, § 29-610.05, § 29-702.01, § 29-802.01, § 29-802.06, § 29-1003.02, and § 29-1202.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-101.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
