<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-107</num>
  <heading>Goods to be severed from realty; recording.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A contract for the sale of minerals or the like (including oil and gas) or a structure or its materials to be removed from realty is a contract for the sale of goods within this article if they are to be severed by the seller but until severance a purported present sale thereof which is not effective as a transfer of an interest in land is effective only as a contract to sell.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A contract for the sale apart from the land of growing crops or other things attached to realty and capable of severance without material harm thereto but not described in subsection (1) or of timber to be cut is a contract for the sale of goods within this article whether the subject matter is to be severed by the buyer or by the seller even though it forms part of the realty at the time of contracting, and the parties can by identification effect a present sale before severance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section are subject to any third party rights provided by the law relating to realty records, and the contract for sale may be executed and recorded as a document transferring an interest in land and shall then constitute notice to third parties of the buyer's rights under the contract for sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 641, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 4, 29 DCR 309.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-105.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-107.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:2-107.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-85</heading>
      <text>Law 4-85, the "Uniform Commercial Code Amendment Act of 1981," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-89, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 24, 1981, and December 8, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 18, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-139 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
