<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-705</num>
  <heading>Seller's stoppage of delivery in transit or otherwise.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The seller may stop delivery of goods in the possession of a carrier or other bailee when he discovers the buyer to be insolvent (section 28:2-702) and may stop delivery of carload, truckload, planeload or larger shipments of express or freight when the buyer repudiates or fails to make a payment due before delivery or if for any other reason the seller has a right to withhold or reclaim the goods.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>As against such buyer the seller may stop delivery until</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>receipt of the goods by the buyer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>acknowledgement to the buyer by any bailee of the goods except a carrier that the bailee holds the goods for the buyer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>such acknowledgment to the buyer by a carrier by reshipment or as warehouseman; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>negotiation to the buyer of any negotiable document of title covering the goods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To stop delivery the seller must so notify as to enable the bailee by reasonable diligence to prevent delivery of the goods.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>After such notification the bailee must hold and deliver the goods according to the directions of the seller but the seller is liable to the bailee for any ensuing charges or damages.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a negotiable document of title has been issued for goods the bailee is not obliged to obey a notification to stop until surrender of possession or control of the document.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A carrier who has issued a non-negotiable bill of lading is not obliged to obey a notification to stop received from a person other than the consignor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 665, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, §§ 3(m), 3(n), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2-702, § 28:2-703, § 28:2-707, § 28:7-403, and § 28:7-504.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-705.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:2-705.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 substituted "a warehouse" for "warehouseman" in (2)(c).</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 inserted "of possession or control" following "surrender" in (3)(c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
      <text>See note to § 28:2-705.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
