<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-214</num>
  <heading>Exclusion or modification of warranties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Words or conduct relevant to the creation of an express warranty and words or conduct tending to negate or limit a warranty must be construed wherever reasonable as consistent with each other; but, subject to the provisions of § 28:2A-202 on parol or extrinsic evidence, negation or limitation is inoperative to the extent that the construction is unreasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, to exclude or modify the implied warranty of merchantability or any part of it the language must mention "merchantability", be by a writing, and be conspicuous. Subject to subsection (c) of this section, to exclude or modify any implied warranty of fitness the exclusion must be by a writing and be conspicuous. Language to exclude all implied warranties of fitness is sufficient if it is in writing, is conspicuous and states, for example, "There is no warranty that the goods will be fit for a particular purpose".</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, but subject to subsection (d) of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>unless the circumstances indicate otherwise, all implied warranties are excluded by expressions like "as is," or "with all faults," or by other language that in common understanding calls the lessee's attention to the exclusion of warranties and makes plain that there is no implied warranty, if in writing and conspicuous;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>if the lessee before entering into the lease contract has examined the goods or the sample or model as fully as desired or has refused to examine the goods, there is no implied warranty with regard to defects that an examination ought in the circumstances to have revealed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>an implied warranty may also be excluded or modified by course of dealing, course of performance, or usage of trade.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To exclude or modify a warranty against interference or against infringement (§ 28:2A-211) or any part of it, the language must be specific, be by a writing, and be conspicuous, unless the circumstances, including course of performance, course of dealing, or usage of trade, give the lessee reason to know that the goods are being leased subject to a claim or interest of any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(pp), 44 DCR 1271.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2A-214.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-128</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:2A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-255</heading>
      <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
