<level type="section">
  <num>2-1401.05</num>
  <heading>Discrimination based on pregnancy, childbirth, related medical conditions, or breastfeeding.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of interpreting this chapter, discrimination on the basis of sex shall include, but not be limited to, discrimination on the basis of pregnancy, childbirth, related medical conditions, or breastfeeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Women affected by pregnancy, childbirth, related medical conditions, or breastfeeding shall be treated the same for all employment-related purposes, including receipt of benefits under fringe benefit programs, as other persons not so affected but similar in their ability or inability to work, and this requirement shall include, but not be limited to, a requirement that an employer must treat an employee temporarily unable to perform the functions of her job because of her pregnancy-related condition in the same manner as it treats other employees with temporary disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, title I, § 105, as added July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-8, § 2, 32 DCR 2959; Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 10, 53 DCR 6198; Dec. 11, 2007, D.C. Law 17-58, § 2(a), 54 DCR 10714.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2505.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-305, in subsec. (b), substituted "employees with temporary disabilities" for "temporarily disabled employees".</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-58, in the section heading and subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted "related medical conditions, or breastfeeding" for "or related medical conditions".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-8</heading>
      <text>Law 6-8, the "Pregnancy Anti-Discrimination Act of 1985," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-45, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Cable Television. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 16, 1985 and April 30, 1985, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 16, 1985, it was assigned Act No. 6-21 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-305</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-305, see notes following § 2-301.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-58</heading>
      <text>Law 17-58, the "Child's Right to Nurse Human Rights Amendment Act of 2007", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-133 which was referred to the Committee on Workforce Development and Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 10, 2007, and October 2, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 17, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-132 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-58 became effective on December 11, 2007.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
