<level type="section">
  <num>31-4106</num>
  <heading>Purchasing groups - Exemption from certain laws.</heading>
  <text>A purchasing group and its insurer or insurers shall be subject to all applicable laws of the District, except that a purchasing group and its insurer or insurers shall be exempt, in regard to liability insurance for the purchasing group, from any law that would:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Prohibit the establishment of a purchasing group;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Make it unlawful for an insurer to provide, or offer to provide, insurance on a basis providing to a purchasing group or its members advantages based on their loss and expense experience not afforded to other persons with respect to rates, policy forms, coverages, or other matters;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Prohibit a purchasing group or its members from purchasing insurance on a group basis described in paragraph (2) of this section;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Prohibit a purchasing group from obtaining insurance on a group because the group has not been in existence for a minimum period of time or because any member has not belonged to the group for a minimum period of time;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Require that a purchasing group must have a minimum number of common ownership or affiliation, or certain legal form;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Require that a certain percentage of a purchasing group must obtain insurance on a group basis;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Otherwise discriminate against a purchasing group or any of its members; or</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Require that any insurance policy issued to a purchasing group or any of its members be countersigned by an insurance agent or broker residing in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-46, ยง 7, 40 DCR 6082.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 35-2906.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-46</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-46, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 31-4101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
