<level type="section">
  <num>31-4111</num>
  <heading>Duty of agents or brokers to obtain license.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person, firm, association, or corporation shall act or aid in any manner in soliciting, negotiating, or procuring liability insurance in the District from a risk retention group unless the person, firm, association, or corporation is licensed as an insurance agent or broker in accordance with the District of Columbia insurance licensing laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No person, firm, association, or corporation shall act or aid in any manner in soliciting, negotiating, or procuring liability insurance in the District for a purchasing group from an authorized insurer or a risk retention group chartered in a state unless the person, firm, association, or corporation is licensed as an insurance agent or broker in accordance with the District of Columbia insurance licensing laws.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No person, firm, association, or corporation shall act or aid in any manner in soliciting, negotiating, or procuring liability insurance coverage in the District for any member of a purchasing group under a purchasing group's policy unless the person, firm, association, or corporation is licensed as an insurance agent or broker in accordance with the District of Columbia insurance licensing laws.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No person, firm, association, or corporation shall act or aid in any manner in soliciting, negotiating, or procuring liability insurance from an insurer not authorized to do business in the District on behalf of a purchasing group located in this state unless the person, firm, association, or corporation is licensed as a surplus lines agent or excess line broker in accordance with the District of Columbia insurance licensing laws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of acting as an agent or broker for a risk retention or purchasing group pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the requirement of residence in the District shall not apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Every person, firm, association, or corporation licensed pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 28 of Title 47, on business placed with risk retention groups or written through a purchasing group, shall inform each prospective insured of the provisions of the notice required by § 31-4108(b) in the case of a risk retention group and § 31-4107(c) in the case of a purchasing group.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-46, § 12, 40 DCR 6082; Feb. 27, 1996, D.C. Law 11-90, § 3(g), 42 DCR 7155.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 31-4103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 35-2911.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(g) of Insurance Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Law 11-36, September 8, 1995, law notification 42 DCR 5305).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(g) of the Insurance Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-48, May 15, 1995, 42 DCR 2544) and § 3(g) of the Insurance Omnibus Congressional Recess Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-97, July 19, 1995, 42 DCR 3844).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-46</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-46, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-4101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-90</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-90, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-4101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
