<level type="section">
  <num>8-105.14</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-964</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this subchapter or the rules issued pursuant to this subchapter shall be liable for a civil fine not exceeding $10,000 for each day during which each violation continues, and shall be required to perform any other action needed to correct any harm caused by any violation or to ensure that future violations do not occur. All prosecutions under this provision shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia, and shall be instituted by the Office of the Attorney General.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, any person who intentionally, willfully, or recklessly violates any provision of this subchapter or the rules issued pursuant to this subchapter shall be punished by a criminal fine not to exceed $10,000 for each day each violation continues, or imprisonment not to exceed one year for each day each violation continues, or both, and to perform any other action needed to correct any harm caused by any violation or to ensure that future violations do not occur. All prosecutions pursuant to this provision shall be in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this subchapter or the rules issued pursuant to this subchapter shall be liable to the District and WASA for all expenses, losses, or damages incurred by the District and WASA by reason of the violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 1986, D.C. Law 6-95, § 15, 33 DCR 577; May 8, 1998, D.C. Law 12-106, § 2(i), 45 DCR 1724; Oct. 26, 2010, D.C. Law 18-256, § 2(l), 57 DCR 8082.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-964.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-256, in subsec. (a), substituted "Office of the Attorney General" for "Corporation Counsel"; and, in subsec. (c), substituted "the District and WASA" for "the District".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-76, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-105.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-95, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-105.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-106, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-105.02.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-256, see notes under § 8-105.02.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
