<level type="section">
  <num>1-204.52</num>
  <heading>Annual budget for the Board of Education.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 803, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 452; Apr. 17, 1995, 109 Stat. 116, Pub. L. 104-8, § 202(g)(2); Oct. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2228, Pub. L. 108-386, § 2; June 1, 2007, 121 Stat. 223, Pub. L. 110-33, § 1(a)(1).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 38-2651.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 31-104.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 31-104-1.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For a proposed temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 352 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003, 50 DCR 5613).</text>
      <text>For a proposed temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 352 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003, 50 DCR 8360).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <text>Section 9 of Pub. L. 108-386, 118 Stat. 2228, the 2004 District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act, provided: "The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>In sections 901 to 903 of Law 17-9 the Council of the District of Columbia requested that Congress repeal this section.</text>
      <text>Section 353 of D.C. Law 15-39, as amended by D.C. Law 15-354, § 80, provided: "Section 352 of this subtitle shall take effect upon enactment into law by the United States Congress." Public Law 108-386 represents the enactment of § 352 of D.C. Law 15-39.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
