<level type="section">
  <num>28:4-301</num>
  <heading>Deferred posting; recovery of payment by return of items; time of dishonor; return of items by payor bank.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a payor bank settles for a demand item other than a documentary draft presented otherwise than for immediate payment over the counter before midnight of the banking day of receipt, the payor bank may revoke the settlement and recover the settlement if, before it has made final payment and before its midnight deadline, it</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Returns the item; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Returns an image of the item, if the party to which the return is made has entered into an agreement to accept an image as a return of the item and the image is returned in accordance with that agreement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sends a record providing notice of dishonor or nonpayment if the item is unavailable for return.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a demand item is received by a payor bank for credit on its books, it may return the item or send notice of dishonor and may revoke any credit given or recover the amount thereof withdrawn by its customer, if it acts within the time limit and in the manner specified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless previous notice of dishonor has been sent, an item is dishonored at the time when, for purposes of dishonor, it is returned or notice sent in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An item is returned:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As to an item presented through a clearing house, when it is delivered to the presenting or last collecting bank or to the clearing house or is sent or delivered in accordance with clearing-house rules; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In all other cases, when it is sent or delivered to the bank's customer or transferor or pursuant to instructions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 704, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(e), 42 DCR 467; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 6(h), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:3-502 and § 28:4-214.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:4-301.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:4-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 rewrote (a)(2); and added (a)(3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-249</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-249, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:4-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
