<level type="section">
  <num>6-101.07</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in this subchapter and subchapter II of this chapter:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term "alley" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any court, thoroughfare, or passage, private or public, less than 30 feet wide at any point; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any court, thoroughfare, or passage, private or public, 30 feet or more in width, that does not open directly with a width of at least 30 feet upon a public street that is at least 40 feet wide from building line to building line.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term "inhabited alley" means an alley in or appurtenant to which there are 1 or more alley dwellings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term "alley dwelling" means any dwelling fronting upon or having its principal means of ingress from an alley. This definition does not include an accessory building, such as a garage, with living rooms for servants or other employees, if the principal entrance to the living rooms of the accessory building is from the street property to which it is accessory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term "dwelling" means any building or structure used or designed to be used in whole or in part as a living or a sleeping place by 1 or more human beings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term "person" includes any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 1934, 48 Stat. 933, ch. 465, ยง 7.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 22-1321.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 5-108.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., ยง 5-109.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
