<level type="section">
  <num>8-1006</num>
  <heading>Recyclable materials recovery targets.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-3406</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall adhere to recovery targets for recyclable materials which shall include, at a minimum, the following schedule:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The recycling of at least 10% of the total commercial solid waste stream of the prior year by the end of the first full year that the mandatory source separation requirements of § 8-1007(a) are in effect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The recycling of at least 15% of the total solid waste stream of the prior year by the end of the first full year that the mandatory source separation requirements of § 8-1007(c) are in effect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The recycling of at least 35% of the total solid waste stream of the District by October 1, 1992; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The recycling of at least 45% of the total solid waste stream of the District by October 1, 1994.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, the term "total solid waste stream" means the sum of the residential and commercial solid waste stream disposed of as solid waste, measured in tons, plus the total number of residential and commercial recyclable materials recycled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The calculation of the recyclable materials recovery targets shall consist of the sum of the total solid waste stream divided by the sum of the residential and commercial recyclable materials recycled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-226, § 7, 36 DCR 595; Sept. 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-178, § 3(c), 41 DCR 5205.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-3406.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-226, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1001.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-178, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1003.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Law 7-226, the "D.C. Solid Waste Management &amp; Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988", see Mayor's Order 89-160, July 20, 1989.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
