<level type="section">
  <num>8-1014</num>
  <heading>Annual reporting requirements; submission of plan.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-3414</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning on January 15, 1991, and on each January 15th of each subsequent year, the Mayor shall submit a recycling report to the Council for review, which shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tonnage of solid waste generated, disposed of, and recycled by the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of the mandatory recycling program established pursuant to this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The tonnage of paper collected and recycled from District government offices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The revenue generated through the disposition of recycled materials for the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The approximate cost avoidance achieved through the District's mandatory recycling program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The overall success of meeting the recovery targets set forth in § 8- 1006;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of markets for recycled materials and how District policies have stimulated markets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of the educational and promotional campaign on the mandatory source separation program as developed by the District of Columbia Recycling Coordinator pursuant to § 8-1008.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 1989, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a plan for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The recovery of tires from the solid waste stream for reuse, recycling, or other disposition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The segregation, treatment, labeling, tracking, transportation, and disposition of medical, infectious, and hazardous waste;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The recycling and reuse of construction and demolition wastes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The provision of tax incentives and low interest loans to District businesses and residents that use recycled products or purchase or lease recycling equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The recycling of plastic polystyrene and polyvinyl chloride containers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-226, § 15, 36 DCR 595; Sept. 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-178, § 3(g), 41 DCR 5205.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-3414.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-226, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1001.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-178, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1003.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
        <text>Delegation of authority pursuant to D.C. Law 7-226, the "D.C. Solid Waste Management &amp; Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988", see Mayor's Order 89-160, July 20, 1989.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
