<level type="section">
  <num>8-1002</num>
  <heading>Purposes.</heading>
  <text>In enacting this subchapter, the Council supports the following purposes:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To increase the life expectancy of the Interstate 95 Landfill and decrease the need for future expansion of alternative refuse disposal facilities through a comprehensive program of solid waste stream reduction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To develop alternative methods of recovering resources from solid waste, recommend uses for the recovered resources, and determine the impact of the distribution of the resources in existing markets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To identify methods of collection, reduction, and separation that will promote more efficient use of solid waste disposal facilities and contribute to more effective programs for the reuse of solid waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>To employ District government procurement procedures to develop market demand for recovered resources, with special emphasis on maximum District government use of recycled paper.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To encourage public agencies, private organizations, and individuals to participate in the reclamation and recycling of resources from solid wastes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>To promote policies of energy conservation, environmental protection, economic productivity, and cost-effectiveness in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-226, ยง 3, 36 DCR 595.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 8-1004.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 6-3402.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-226</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 7-226, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 8-1001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
