<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-209</num>
  <heading>Duties of secured party if account debtor has been notified of assignment.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), this section applies if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is no outstanding secured obligation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The secured party is not committed to make advances, incur obligations, or otherwise give value.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days after receiving an authenticated demand by the debtor, a secured party shall send to an account debtor that has received notification of an assignment to the secured party as assignee under ยง 28:9-406(a) an authenticated record that releases the account debtor from any further obligation to the secured party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to an assignment constituting the sale of an account, chattel paper, or payment intangible.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, ยง 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:9-625.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following ยง 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text>1. Source. New.</text>
      <text>2. Scope and Purpose. Like Sections 9-208 and 9-513, which require a secured party to relinquish control of collateral and to file or provide a termination statement for a financing statement, this section requires a secured party to free up collateral when there no longer is any outstanding secured obligation or any commitment to give value in the future. This section addresses the case in which account debtors have been notified to pay a secured party to whom the receivables have been assigned. It requires the secured party (assignee) to inform the account debtors that they no longer are obligated to make payment to the secured party. See subsection (b). It does not apply to account debtors whose obligations on an account, chattel paper, or payment intangible have been sold. See subsection (c).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
