<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-210</num>
  <heading>Request for accounting; request regarding list of collateral or statement of account.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Request" means a record of a type described in paragraph (2), (3), or (4).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Request for an accounting" means a record authenticated by a debtor requesting that the recipient provide an accounting of the unpaid obligations secured by collateral and reasonably identifying the transaction or relationship that is the subject of the request.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Request regarding a list of collateral" means a record authenticated by a debtor requesting that the recipient approve or correct a list of what the debtor believes to be the collateral securing an obligation and reasonably identifying the transaction or relationship that is the subject of the request.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Request regarding a statement of account" means a record authenticated by a debtor requesting that the recipient approve or correct a statement indicating what the debtor believes to be the aggregate amount of unpaid obligations secured by collateral as of a specified date and reasonably identifying the transaction or relationship that is the subject of the request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f), a secured party, other than a buyer of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes or a consignor, shall comply with a request within 14 days after receipt:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of a request for an accounting, by authenticating and sending to the debtor an accounting; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the case of a request regarding a list of collateral or a request regarding a statement of account, by authenticating and sending to the debtor an approval or correction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A secured party that claims a security interest in all of a particular type of collateral owned by the debtor may comply with a request regarding a list of collateral by sending to the debtor an authenticated record including a statement to that effect within 14 days after receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person that receives a request regarding a list of collateral, claims no interest in the collateral when it receives the request, and claimed an interest in the collateral at an earlier time shall comply with the request within 14 days after receipt by sending to the debtor an authenticated record:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Disclaiming any interest in the collateral; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If known to the recipient, providing the name and mailing address of any assignee of or successor to the recipient's interest in the collateral.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person that receives a request for an accounting or a request regarding a statement of account, claims no interest in the obligations when it receives the request, and claimed an interest in the obligations at an earlier time shall comply with the request within 14 days after receipt by sending to the debtor an authenticated record:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Disclaiming any interest in the obligations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If known to the recipient, providing the name and mailing address of any assignee of or successor to the recipient's interest in the obligations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A debtor is entitled without charge to one response to a request under this section during any 6-month period. The secured party may require payment of a charge not exceeding $25 for each additional response.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, ยง 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:9-602 and ยง 28:9-625.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following ยง 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
