<level type="section">
  <num>1-1433</num>
  <heading>Technology Infrastructure Services Support Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Technology Infrastructure Services Support Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Chief Technology Officer in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall consist of the revenue from payments by independent District government agencies and federal agencies for services provided by the Office of the Chief Technology Officer in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used solely to defray operational costs of programs of the Office of the Chief Technology Officer, other than the DC-Net program, that the Chief Technology Officer shall designate based on the use of such programs to provide services to independent agencies of the District and agencies of the federal government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization by Congress, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 1004, 54 DCR 7052; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1042(b), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote the section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1004 of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007, 54 DCR 7549).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1042(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1042(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-20</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-20, see notes following § 1-1431.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-1431.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 1041 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle E of Title I of the act may be cited as the "Technology Services Support Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
