<level type="section">
  <num>8-703</num>
  <heading>Disposal by feeding to livestock.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-503</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Should the Mayor of the District of Columbia find that the garbage in the District can be disposed of in a sanitary manner and as economically by feeding it to pigs, livestock, and poultry on the land of the Home for the Aged and Infirm, located at Blue Plains, District of Columbia, or on the land of the Workhouse and Reformatory of the District of Columbia, located at Occoquan and Lorton, Virginia, or both, or on such other land as the said Mayor may be able to acquire by purchase or lease in the States of Virginia or Maryland, the said Mayor is authorized to use either or all of said designated lands, or to purchase or lease land in the States of Virginia or Maryland for the purpose, and to adopt the pig, livestock, or poultry-feeding method of disposal.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 6, 1918, 40 Stat. 541, ch. 67, § 6.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-503.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-503.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Change in Government</heading>
        <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
