<level type="section">
  <num>29-104.07</num>
  <heading>Change of registered agent by entity.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A represented entity may change the information on file under § 29- 104.04(a) by delivering to the Mayor for filing a statement of change signed by an authorized person on behalf of the entity which states the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name of the entity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Information that is to be in effect as a result of the filing of the statement of change.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The interest holders or governors of a domestic entity need not approve the filing of a:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Statement of change under this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Similar filing changing the registered agent or registered office of the entity in any other jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A statement of change under this section appointing a new registered agent shall be an affirmation under § 29-102.09 by the represented entity that the agent has consented to serve.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A statement of change under this section shall be effective on delivery to the Mayor for filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>As an alternative to using the procedure in this section, a represented entity may change the information on file under § 29-104.04(a) by amending its most recent registered agent filing in a manner provided by law of the District other than this title for amending the filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
