<level type="section">
  <num>29-604.01</num>
  <heading>Partner's rights and duties.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 41-154.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 33-104.01</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each partner shall deemed to have an account that is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Credited with an amount equal to the money plus the value of any other property, net of the amount of any liabilities, the partner contributes to the partnership and the partner's share of the partnership profits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Charged with an amount equal to the money plus the value of any other property, net of the amount of any liabilities, distributed by the partnership to the partner and the partner's share of the partnership losses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each partner shall be entitled to an equal share of the partnership profits and shall be chargeable with a share of the partnership losses in proportion to the partner's share of the profits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A partnership shall reimburse a partner for payments made, and indemnify a partner for liabilities incurred, by the partner in the ordinary course of the business of the partnership or for the preservation of its business or property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A partnership shall reimburse a partner for an advance to the partnership beyond the amount of capital the partner agreed to contribute.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A payment or advance made by a partner which gives rise to a partnership obligation under subsection (c) or (d) of this section shall constitute a loan to the partnership which accrues interest from the date of the payment or advance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Each partner shall have equal rights in the management and conduct of the partnership business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A partner shall use or possess partnership property only on behalf of the partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A partner shall not be entitled to remuneration for services performed for the partnership, except for reasonable compensation for services rendered in winding up the business of the partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A person shall become a partner only with the consent of all of the partners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subchapter IX of this chapter or Chapter 2 of this title, a person shall become a partner only with the consent of all of the partners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>A difference arising as to a matter in the ordinary course of business of a partnership shall be decided by a majority of the partners. An act outside the ordinary course of business of a partnership and an amendment to the partnership agreement shall be undertaken only with the consent of all of the partners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>This section shall not affect the obligations of a partnership to other persons under § 29-603.01.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 41-154.1.</text>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 33-104.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 401 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act). See Vol. 6, Part I , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
