<level type="section">
  <num>29-604.09</num>
  <heading>Continuation of partnership beyond definite term or particular undertaking.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, all partners shall be liable jointly and severally for all obligations of the partnership unless otherwise agreed by the claimant or provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person admitted as a partner into an existing partnership shall not be personally liable for any partnership obligation incurred before the person's admission as a partner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An obligation of a partnership incurred while the partnership is a limited liability partnership, whether arising in contract, tort, or otherwise, shall be solely the obligation of the partnership. A partner shall not be personally liable, directly or indirectly, by way of contribution or otherwise, for such an obligation solely by reason of being or so acting as a partner. This subsection shall apply notwithstanding anything inconsistent in the partnership agreement that existed immediately before the vote required to become a limited liability partnership under § 29-610.01(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(4)(C), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 41-154.6.</text>
      <text>2001 Ed., § 33-104.06.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 redesignated former § 20-604.06 as § 29-604.09.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-601.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 406 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
