<level type="section">
  <num>1-204.24a</num>
  <heading>In general.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-317.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Establishment.</text> -- There is hereby established within the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia an Office of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the "Office"), which shall be headed by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the "Chief Financial Officer").</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Organizational analysis.</text> --</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text><text i="True">Office of Budget and Planning.</text> -- The name of the Office of Budget and Management, established by Commissioner's Order 69-96, issued March 7, 1969, is changed to the Office of Budget and Planning.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text><text i="True">Office of Tax and Revenue.</text> -- The name of the Department of Finance and Revenue, established by Commissioner's Order 69-96, issued March 7, 1969, is changed to the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text><text i="True">Office of Finance and Treasury.</text> -- The name of the Office of Treasurer, established by Mayor's Order 89-244, dated October 23, 1989, is changed to the Office of Finance and Treasury.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text><text i="True">Office of Financial Operations and Systems.</text> -- The Office of the Controller, established by Mayor's Order 89-243, dated October 23, 1989, and the Office of Financial Information Services, established by Mayor's Order 89- 244, dated October 23, 1989, are consolidated into the Office of Financial Operations and Systems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Transfers.</text> -- Effective with the appointment of the first Chief Financial Officer under § 1-204.24b, the functions and personnel of the following offices are established as subordinate offices within the Office:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of Budget and Planning, headed by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer for the Office of Budget and Planning.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue, headed by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer for the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Office of Research and Analysis, headed by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer for the Office of Research and Analysis.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Office of Financial Operations and Systems, headed by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer for the Office of Financial Operations and Systems.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Office of Finance and Treasury, headed by the District of Columbia Treasurer.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board, established by Chapter 13 of Title 3.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Supervisor.</text> -- The heads of the offices listed in subsection (c) of this section shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Appointment and removal of office employees.</text> -- The Chief Financial Officer shall appoint the heads of the subordinate offices designated in subsection (c) of this section, after consultation with the Mayor and the Council. The Chief Financial Officer may remove the heads of the offices designated in subsection (c) of this section, after consultation with the Mayor and the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Annual budget submission.</text> -- The Chief Financial Officer shall prepare and annually submit to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, for inclusion in the annual budget of the District of Columbia government for a fiscal year, annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the year for the operation of the Office and all other District of Columbia accounting, budget, and financial management personnel (including personnel of executive branch independent agencies) that report to the Office pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 774, Pub. L. 93-198, § 424(a), as added Apr. 17, 1995, 109 Stat. 142, Pub. L. 104-8, § 302(a); Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2029, Pub. L. 109-356, § 201(a).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-317.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>Pub. L. 109-356 rewrote the section which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) <text i="True">In general.</text> -- There is hereby established within the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia an Office of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the "Office"), which shall be headed by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the "Chief Financial Officer").</text>
        <text>"(b) <text i="True">Office of the Treasurer.</text> -- The Office shall include the Office of the Treasurer, which shall be headed by the Treasurer of the District of Columbia, who shall be appointed by the Chief Financial Officer and subject to the Chief Financial Officer's direction and control.</text>
        <text>"(c) <text i="True">Transfer of other offices.</text> -- Effective with the appointment of the first Chief Financial Officer under § 1-204.24b, the functions and personnel of the following offices are transferred to the Office:</text>
        <text>"(1) The Controller of the District of Columbia;</text>
        <text>"(2) The Office of the Budget;</text>
        <text>"(3) The Office of Financial Information Services; and</text>
        <text>"(4) The Department of Finance and Revenue.</text>
        <text>"(d) <text i="True">Service of heads of other offices.</text> --</text>
        <text>"(1) <text i="True">Office heads appointed by Mayor.</text> -- With respect to the head of the Office of the Budget and the head of the Department of Finance and Revenue:</text>
        <text>"(A) The Mayor shall appoint such individuals with the advice and consent of the Council, subject to the approval of the Authority during a control year; and</text>
        <text>"(B) During a control year, the Authority may remove such individuals from office for cause, after consultation with the Mayor.</text>
        <text>"(2) <text i="True">Office heads appointed by Chief Financial Officer.</text> -- With respect to the Controller of the District of Columbia and the head of the Office of Financial Information Services:</text>
        <text>"(A) The Chief Financial Officer shall appoint such individuals subject to the approval of the Mayor; and</text>
        <text>"(B) The Chief Financial Officer may remove such individuals from office for cause, after consultation with the Mayor."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 12-81, the "Technical Amendments Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-408, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1997, and December 4, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-246 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-81 became effective on March 24, 1998.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer's "Notice of Public Interest" published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register (44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner's Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, <text i="True">nunc pro tunc</text>.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
