<level type="section">
  <num>29-905</num>
  <heading>Powers of association.</heading>
  <text>An association shall have the capacity to act possessed by individuals and the authority to do anything required or permitted by this chapter. In addition, an association has the power to:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Continue as a corporation for the time specified in its articles;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Have a corporate seal and to alter the same at pleasure;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Sue and be sued in its corporate name;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Make bylaws for the government and regulation of its affairs;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Acquire, own, hold, sell, lease, pledge, mortgage, or otherwise dispose of any property incident to its purposes and activities and affairs;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Own and hold:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Membership in, and share capital, of other associations and any other corporations;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Any types of bonds or other obligations; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>While the owner of the items set forth in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, to exercise all the rights of ownership;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Borrow money, contract debts, and make contracts, including agreements of mutual aid or federation with other associations, other groups organized on a cooperative basis, and other nonprofit groups;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Conduct its affairs within or without the District;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Exercise, in addition, any power granted to ordinary business corporations, except those powers inconsistent with this chapter; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Exercise all powers not inconsistent with this chapter which may be necessary, convenient, or expedient for the accomplishment of its purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(i)(2), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-902.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>2001 Ed., § 29-904.</text>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 29-1104.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 29-804.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "activities and affairs" for "activities" in (5).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>Law 19-210, the "'District of Columbia Official Code Title 29 Technical and Harmonizing Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-532. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 10, 2012, and Oct. 2, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Oct. 31, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-512 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-210 became effective on Mar. 5, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
