<level type="section">
  <num>24-905</num>
  <heading>Determination that youth offender will derive no further benefit; appeal.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 24-805</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Director of the Department of Corrections ("Director") determines that a youth offender will derive no further benefit from the treatment pursuant to this subchapter, the Director shall notify the youth offender of this determination in a written statement that includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notice that the youth offender may appeal the Director's determination to the sentencing judge in writing within 30 days of the youth offender's receipt of the Director's statement required by this section;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Specific reasons for the Director's no further benefit determination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Notice that an appeal by the youth offender to the sentencing judge will stay any action by the Director regarding a change in the youth offender's status until the sentencing judge makes a determination on the appeal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The decision of the sentencing judge on the appeal of the youth offender shall be considered a final disposition of the appeal and shall preclude further action by the Director to change the status of a youth offender for a 6-month period from the date of the sentencing judge's decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall not apply to a youth offender convicted of any offense committed on or after August 5, 2000.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 7, 1985, D.C. Law 6-69, § 6, 32 DCR 4587; June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-302, § 9(d), 47 DCR 7249.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 24-805.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 13-302 added subsec. (c).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(d) of the Sentencing Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-410, August 11, 2000, 47 DCR 7271).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(d) of the Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 13-462, November 7, 2000, 47 DCR 9443).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(d) of Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-2, February 2, 2001, 48 DCR 2239).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(d) of Sentencing Reform Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-51, May 2, 2001, 48 DCR 4370).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-69, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 24-901.</text>
        <text>For Law 13-302, see notes following § 24-403.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
