<level type="section">
  <num>38-1207.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Eligible caretaker relative" means an individual as defined in § 4-205.15(2)(B), who has primary responsibility for the care of a dependent child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Eligible legal guardian" means any individual:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Appointed as a testamentary or appointive guardian pursuant to Chapter 1 of Title 21; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Necessary for the maintenance of a household as provided in § 4-205.15(2)(D).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Eligible parent" means a child's natural or adoptive parent in a family eligible for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families or Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility pursuant to Chapter 2 of Title 4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Tuition grant" means a sum equal to the basic instructional charge for a full- or part-time program at the University and includes all required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"State" means any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 1974, Pub. L. 93-471, title VII, § 701, as added Feb. 18, 1988, D.C. Law 7-74, § 2, 34 DCR 7946; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 14, 46 DCR 905.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 31-1571.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 14 of D.C. Law 12-230 substituted "Temporary Assistance for Needy Families or Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility pursuant to Chapter 2 of Title 3" [Chapter 2 of Title 4, 2001 Ed.] for "the Aid to Families with Dependent Children category of public assistance as defined in § 3-201.1(1) [§ 4-201.01, 2001 Ed.] " in (3).</text>
      <text>Section 18(b) of D.C. Law 12-230 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 14 of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998, 45 DCR 4270), § 14 of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998, 45 DCR 5682), § 14 of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998, 45 DCR 521), and § 15 of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. 13-19, February 17, 1999, 46 DCR 4292).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 7-74</heading>
      <text>Law 7-74, "Tuition Grant for Parents, Caretaker Relatives, and Legal Guardians Eligible for AFDC Benefits Amendment Act of 1987," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 7-58, which was referred to the Committee on Education and Libraries. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 27, 1987, and November 10, 1987, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 24, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 7-108 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-230</heading>
      <text>Law 12-230, the "Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-557. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 5, 1998, and July 30, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 18, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-443 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-230 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-241</heading>
      <text>Law 12-241, the "Self-Sufficiency Promotion Amendment Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-558, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 23, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-573 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-241 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Mayor's orders</heading>
      <text>Establishment of the D.C. Tuition Assistance Grant Program Office and Delegation of Authority under Public Law 106-98, the "District of Columbia College Access Act of 1999", see Mayor's Order 2000-138, September 7, 2000 (47 DCR 8247).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
