<level type="section">
  <num>24-284</num>
  <heading>Inmate Welfare Fund Committee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Inmate Welfare Fund Committee is established for the purpose of administering and supervising the operations of and the expenditures from the Inmate Welfare Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall be composed of the following 5 members:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The General Counsel of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Warden of the Central Detention Facility, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Manager of the Office of Internal Controls, Compliance, and Accreditation of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Office of Management Information and Technological Services of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall maintain a record of its authorization and approval for all expenditures from the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Committee may promulgate regulations governing the use and expenditures of the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 3005, 53 DCR 6899.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3005 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006, 53 DCR 7068).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3005 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006, 53 DCR 8845).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3005 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007, 54 DCR 1165).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-192, see notes following § 24-281.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
