<level type="section">
  <num>21-319</num>
  <heading>Accounting by and determination of liability of custodian.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 21-319</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A minor who has reached the age of 14 years, the minor's guardian of the person or legal representative, an adult member of the minor's family, a transferor, or a transferor's legal representative may petition the court for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For an accounting by the custodian or the custodian's legal representative; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a determination of responsibility, as between the custodial property and the custodian personally, for claims against the custodial property unless the responsibility has been adjudicated in an action under section 21-317 to which the minor or the minor's legal representative was a party.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A successor custodian may petition the court for an accounting by the predecessor custodian.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court, in a proceeding under this act or in any other proceeding, may require or permit the custodian or the custodian's legal representative to give an accounting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a custodian is removed under section 21-318(f), the court shall require an accounting and order delivery of the custodial property and records to the successor custodian and the execution of the instruments required for transfer of the custodial property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 1986, D.C. Law 6-87, § 2(a), 33 DCR 278; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 14(f), 45 DCR 745.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 21-319.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-87, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-301.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-302.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>"This act," referred to in subsection (c), is the District of Columbia Uniform Transfers to Minors Act, D.C. Law 6-87 which is codified primarily as § 21-301 et seq.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 9 of the Uniform Transfers to Minors Act. See 8B Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on WESTLAW.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
