<level type="section">
  <num>21-314</num>
  <heading>Use of custodial property.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 21-314</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A custodian may deliver or pay to the minor or expend for the minor's benefit as much of the custodial property as the custodian considers advisable for the use and benefit of the minor, without court order and without regard to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The duty or the ability of the custodian personally or of another person to support the minor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Other income or property of the minor which may be applicable or available for that purpose.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On petition of an interested person or of the minor, if the minor has reached the age of 14 years, the court may order the custodian to deliver or pay to the minor or to expend for the minor's benefit as much of the custodial property as the court considers advisable for the use and the benefit of the minor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A delivery, a payment, or an expenditure under this section is in addition to, not in substitution for, and does not affect any obligation of a person to support the minor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 1986, D.C. Law 6-87, § 2(a), 33 DCR 278.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 21-314.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-87, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-301.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 14 of the Uniform Transfers to Minors Act. See 8B Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on WESTLAW.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
