<level type="section">
  <num>21-317</num>
  <heading>Liability to third persons.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 21-317</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A claim may be asserted against the custodial property by proceeding against the custodian in the custodial capacity, whether or not the custodian or the minor is personally liable, if a claim is based on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A contract entered into by a custodian acting in a custodial capacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An obligation arising from the ownership or control of custodial property; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A tort committed during the custodianship.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A custodian is not personally liable in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On a contract properly entered into in the custodial capacity unless the custodian fails to reveal that capacity and to identify the custodianship in the contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For an obligation arising from control of custodial property or for a tort committed during the custodianship unless the custodian is personally at fault.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A minor is not personally liable for an obligation arising from ownership of custodial property or for a tort committed during the custodianship unless the minor is personally at fault.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 1986, D.C. Law 6-87, § 2(a), 33 DCR 278; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 14(d), 45 DCR 745.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 21-317.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-87, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-301.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-302.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 17 of the Uniform Transfers to Minors Act. See 8B Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on WESTLAW.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
