<level type="section">
  <num>27-131</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Contract" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A construction contract that is an agreement of any kind of nature, express or implied, to provide labor or materials, or both, for demolition, building, renovation, alteration, or maintenance of buildings, roadways, and structures; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A food service contract that is an agreement of any kind of nature, express or implied, for doing work or furnishing materials, or both.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Contractor" means a person, entity, or business that has a contract with an owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Subcontractor" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A person, entity, or business that has a contract with a contractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A person, entity, or business that has a contract with a subcontractor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A person, entity, or business that performs work on a construction site for a contractor or another subcontractor or that fabricates materials off-site, from plans and specifications unique to the project, for installation on the construction site.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Owner" means an owner of the property or a tenant; provided, that the tenant enters into contract with a contractor. The term "owner" does not include a District agency as that term is defined in ยง 2-221.01(3).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Undisputed amount" means an amount owed on a contract or a subcontract for which there is no good-faith dispute, including any retainage withheld.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 20-34, ยง 2, 60 DCR 11812.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-34</heading>
      <text>Law 20-34, the "Private Contractor and Subcontractor Prompt Payment Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-145. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 26, 2013, and July 10, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-148 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-34 became effective on November 5, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
