<level type="section">
  <num>2-1217.33c</num>
  <heading>Creation of the City Market at O Street TIF Area.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is created a TIF area designated as the City Market at O Street TIF Area. The City Market at O Street TIF Area is defined as the real property located in Lots 829 and 830, Square 398. As provided under § 2-1217.33b, the Available Tax Increment from the City Market at O Street TIF Area shall be deposited in the City Market at O Street Fund and may be used for the purposes set forth in § 2-1217.33b.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The base year for determination of Available Sales Tax Revenues from locations within the City Market at O Street TIF Area shall be the tax year preceding the year in which this subpart becomes effective.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The base year for determination of Available Real Property Tax Revenues shall be the tax year of the District preceding the year in which this subpart becomes effective and the initial assessed value to be used in making the determination of Available Real Property Tax Revenues shall be the assessed value of each lot of taxable real property in the City Market at O Street TIF Area for the preceding tax year in which this subpart becomes effective.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-278, § 4, 55 DCR 11050; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 20, 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-171, in subsec. (b)(2), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-278, see notes following § 2-1217.33a.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-171, see notes under § 2-218.13.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
