<level type="section">
  <num>18-705</num>
  <heading>International will; certificate.</heading>
  <level type="form">
    <text> The authorized person shall attach to the will a certificate, to be signed by him or her, establishing that the requirements of this chapter for valid execution of an international will have been complied with. The authorized person shall keep a copy of the certificate and deliver another to the testator. The certificate shall be substantially in the following form: 




 

 "CERTIFICATE 


 

 "(Convention of October 26, 1973) 


 "1. I, ________ ________ (name, address and capacity), a person authorized to act in connection with international wills 


 "2. Certify that on ________ ________ (date) at ________ ________ (place) 


 "3. (testator) ________ ________ 


 "(name, address, date and place of birth) in my presence and that of the witnesses 


 "4. (a) ________ ________ (name, address, date and place of birth) 


 "(b) ________ ________ (name, address, date and place of birth) 


 "has declared that the attached document is his or her will and that he knows the contents thereof. 


 "5. I furthermore certify that: 


 "6. (a) in my presence and in that of the witnesses 


 "(1) the testator has signed the will or has acknowledged his signature previously affixed. 


 "(2) [to be completed if appropriate] following a declaration of the testator stating that he or she was unable to sign his will for the following reason ________ ________, I have mentioned this declaration on the will and the signature has been affixed by ________ ________ (name and address) 


 "7. (b) the witnesses and I have signed the will; 


 "8. (c) [to be completed if appropriate] each page of the will has been signed by ________ ________ and numbered; 


 "9. (d) I have satisfied myself as to the identity of the testator and of the witnesses as designated above; 


 "10. (e) the witnesses met the conditions requisite to act as such according to the law under which I am acting; 


 "11. (f) [to be completed if appropriate] the testator has requested me to include the following statement concerning the safekeeping of his will: 


 "12. PLACE OF EXECUTION 


 "13. DATE 


 "14. SIGNATURE and, if necessary, SEAL."</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-292, ยง 102(b), 48 DCR 2087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 18-704.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-292</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 13-292, see notes following ยง 18-701.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
