<level type="section">
  <num>25-831</num>
  <heading>Penalty for violation where no specific penalty provided; additional penalty for failure to perform certain required acts.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who violates any of the provisions of this title, or regulations under this title, for which no specific penalty is provided shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01], or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person required to file a return or report or perform any act under the provisions of this title who wilfully fails or refuses to file the return or report or perform the act within the time required shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01], or imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both. The penalty provided herein shall be in addition to other penalties provided by this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Violations of this section which are misdemeanors shall be prosecuted on information filed in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel. Violations of this subsection which are felonies shall be prosecuted by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A civil fine may be imposed as an alternative sanction for any violation of this title for which no specific penalty is provided, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this title, under Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of an infraction of this chapter shall be under Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 336, ch. 4, § 33; Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1; July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1; July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a); July 24, 1982, D.C. Law 4-131, § 301, 29 DCR 2418; Sept. 26, 1984, D.C. Law 5-106, § 3, 31 DCR 3381; Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 455(b), 32 DCR 4450; May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 284(c), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 25-831.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 25-132.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01]" for "not more than $1,000" in (a), and for "not more than $5,000" in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 284(c) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-298</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 13-298, see notes following § 25-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-131</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-131, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 25-907.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 5-106</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-106, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 25-781.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-42</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-42, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 25-1009.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
