<level type="section">
  <num>8-1774.01</num>
  <heading>Contract with a Sustainable Energy Utility.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, by, and through DDOE, shall contract with a SEU to conduct sustainable energy programs on behalf of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The SEU shall be a private entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The SEU shall conduct the sustainable energy programs under a brand name to be determined by the District Department of the Environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall provide that the SEU shall, at a minimum, achieve the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reduce per-capita energy consumption in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Increase renewable energy generating capacity in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reduce the growth of peak electricity demand in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Improve the energy efficiency of low-income housing in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Reduce the growth of the energy demand of the District of Columbia's largest energy users; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Increase the number of green-collar jobs in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall be funded by the SETF. The SEU contract may also be funded by any other source of funding available to the Mayor, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Federal funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Private funds, subject to DDOE approval; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other District funds.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>All funds used to support the SEU contract shall be managed by the Fiscal Agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall permit coordination with any similar private entity operating in an adjacent or nearby jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The use of private grant money by the SEU shall be subject to DDOE approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2, the SEU contract shall be awarded pursuant to the procedure set forth under this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-250, ยง 201, 55 DCR 9225.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 201 of Clean and Affordable Energy Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-508, September 25, 2008, 55 DCR 10856).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-250, see notes following ยง 8-1773.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
