<level type="section">
  <num>2-381.05</num>
  <heading>Limitation of actions; burden of proof.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A civil action brought pursuant to § 2-381.03 may not be brought:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>More than 6 years after the date on which the violation of § 2-381.02 is committed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>More than 3 years after the date when facts material to the right of action are known or reasonably should have been known by the official of the District charged with the responsibility to act in those circumstances, but in no event more than 10 years after the date on which the violation of § 2-381.02 is committed, whichever occurs last.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A civil action brought pursuant to § 2-381.03 may not be brought for activity prior to April 12, 1997.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In any action brought pursuant to § 2-381.03, the District or the qui tam plaintiff shall be required to prove all essential elements of the cause of action, including damages, by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a judgment of guilt in a criminal proceeding charging false statements or fraud, upon a verdict after trial or upon a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, shall estop the defendant from denying the essential elements of the offense in any action brought pursuant to § 2-308.15 which involves the same transaction as in the criminal proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the District elects to intervene and proceed with an action brought under § 2-381.03, the District may file its own complaint or amend the complaint of a qui tam plaintiff who has brought an action under § 2-381.03(b) to clarify or add detail to the claims in which the District is intervening and to add any additional claims with respect to which the District contends it is entitled to relief.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any District pleading as provided for in this subsection shall relate back to the filing date of the complaint of the qui tam plaintiff who originally brought the action, and thereby comply with the statute of limitations as provided for in this subchapter, to the extent that the claim of the District arises out of the conduct, transactions, or occurrences set forth, or attempted to be set forth, in the prior complaint of the qui tam plaintiff.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 21, 1986, D.C. Law 6-85, § 817, 32 DCR 7396, as added May 8, 1998, D.C. Law 12-104, § 2(g), 45 DCR 1687; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 10(d), 46 DCR 2118; Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-232, § 2(e), 59 DCR 13632.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-308.17.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>2001 Ed., § 2-308.17.</text>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-1188.17.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-232 rewrote (a); and added (e).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-104</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-104, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-308.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-264</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-264, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-301.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-232</heading>
      <text>See note to § 2-381.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
