<level type="section">
  <num>38-771.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Authorized personnel" means an individual who has access to Districtwide assessment materials or is directly involved in the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Districtwide assessments" shall have the same meaning as provided in ยง 38-1800.02(13).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"IEP" means a student's individualized education program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"ELL" means English language learner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Local education agency" or "LEA" means the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Test monitor" means an individual designated by a local education agency to be responsible for testing integrity and security at each individual school subject to the LEA's control during the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"OSSE" means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"Test integrity coordinator" means an individual designated by a LEA to be responsible for testing integrity and security for the LEA in its entirety during the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Testing integrity and security agreement" means an agreement developed by OSSE that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Sets forth requirements for ensuring integrity of Districtwide assessments pursuant to District law and regulation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Requires the signatory to acknowledge that he or she understands that knowingly and willingly violating a District law, regulation, or a test security plan could result in civil liability, including the loss of an OSSE granted certification or license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 17, 2013, D.C. Law 20-27, ยง 101, 60 DCR 11120.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 38-2602.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-27</heading>
      <text>Law 20-27, the "Testing Integrity Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-109. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-120 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-27 became effective on October 17, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
