<level type="section">
  <num>38-771.07</num>
  <heading>Due process.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Until rules are issued pursuant to § 38-771.06, any party aggrieved by a final decision or order of OSSE imposing sanctions following a determination by OSSE that a violation of this chapter has occurred may obtain a review of the final decision or order by filing a written notice of appeal to the Mayor within 10 calendar days from the date on which OSSE imposed the sanction being contested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The written notice of appeal shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The type and the effective date of the sanction imposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the aggrieved party or the aggrieved party's representative, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A copy of OSSE's notice of final decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether the aggrieved party or anyone acting on his or her behalf has filed an appeal under any negotiated review procedure pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement, or has filed a complaint with any other agency regarding this matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The identity of the collective bargaining unit, if any, of which the aggrieved party is a member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether the aggrieved party requests a hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A concise statement of the facts giving rise to the appeal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>An explanation as to why the aggrieved party believes OSSE's action was unwarranted and any supporting documentation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A statement of the specific relief the aggrieved party is requesting; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The signature of the aggrieved party and his or her representative, if any.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a hearing is requested, the Mayor shall hold a hearing within 30 calendar days after the receipt of the notice of appeal and hearing request and shall issue a written ruling no later than 10 calendar days after the hearing. If no hearing is requested, the Mayor shall issue a written ruling within 30 days of receipt of the notice of appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Appeals filed pursuant to this section, and any hearings held, shall be administered in accordance with § 2-501 et seq.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a notice of appeal is considered received on the date it was postmarked.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 17, 2013, D.C. Law 20-27, § 107, 60 DCR 11120.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 38-771.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-27</heading>
      <text>See note to § 38-771.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
