<level type="section">
  <num>47-1818.03</num>
  <heading>City-wide joint business activity strategy agreements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days of [October 9, 2012], the Mayor shall enter into a BAS agreement with a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company and certify the agreement as required by § 47-1818.04 and submit it to the Council as required by § 47-1818.05.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall ensure that the BAS agreement provides:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the Qualified Social E-Commerce Company will leverage its activities to assist retail businesses along disrupted corridors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the coordination of the Qualified Social E-Commerce Company's offering of technology, marketing, social media, and other training opportunities for District of Columbia small businesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For the development of engineering-related programs to recruit, train, and retain software developers in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For the Qualified Social E-Commerce Company's participation in hiring STEM students as part of the Summer Youth Employment Program established pursuant to § 32-241.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 365 days of Council approval of the BAS agreement, as required by § 47-1818.05, and annually thereafter during the term of an abatement granted pursuant to this subchapter, the Mayor shall submit a report to the Council on each BAS agreement approved by the Council detailing the level of compliance under each BAS agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 9, 2012, D.C. Law 19-174, § 2, 59 DCR 8712.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-1818.01 and § 47-1818.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-174</heading>
      <text>See note to § 47-1818.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
