<level type="section">
  <num>31-1003</num>
  <heading>Nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements need be reported pursuant to § 31-1001 if the nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions are not material.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, a material nonrenewal, cancellation, or revision is one that affects:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As respects property and casualty business, including accident and health business written by a property and casualty insurer:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>More than 50% of the insurer's total ceded written premium; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>More than 50% of the insurer's total ceded indemnity and loss adjustment reserves.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As respects life, annuity, and accident and health business, more than 50% of the total reserve credit taken for business ceded, on an annualized basis, as indicated in the insurer's most recent annual statement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>As respects either property and casualty or life, annuity, and accident and health business, either of the following events shall constitute a material revision which must be reported:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An authorized reinsurer representing more than 10% of a total cession is replaced by one or more unauthorized reinsurers; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Previously established collateral requirements that have been reduced or waived as respects one or more unauthorized reinsurers representing collectively more than 10% of a total cession.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No filing shall be required if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As respects property and casualty business, including accident and health business written by a property and casualty insurer, the insurer's total ceded written premium represents, on an annualized basis, less than 10% of its total written premium for direct and assumed business; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As respects life, annuity, and accident and health business, the total reserve credit taken for business ceded represents, on an annualized basis, less than 10% of the statutory reserve requirement prior to any cession.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The following information is required to be disclosed in any report of a material nonrenewal, cancellation, or revision of ceded reinsurance agreements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effective date of the nonrenewal, cancellation, or revision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The description of the transaction with an identification of the initiator thereof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Purpose of, or reason for, the transaction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>if applicable, the identity of the replacement reinsurers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Insurers are required to report all material nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements on a nonconsolidated basis unless the insurer is part of a consolidated group of insurers which utilizes a pooling arrangement or 100% reinsurance agreement that affects the solvency and integrity of the insurer's reserves and the insurer ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to the pool. An insurer is deemed to have ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to a pool if the insurer has less than $1,000,000 total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that $1,000,000 total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that are not subject to a pooling arrangement and the net income of the business not subject to the pooling arrangement represents less than 5% of the insurer's capital and surplus.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 24, 1996, D.C. Law 11-123, § 4, 43 DCR 1542; Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 42(b), 45 DCR 745.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 35-4103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-123</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-123, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1001.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-81</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-1001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
