<level type="section">
  <num>10-1805</num>
  <heading>Naming rights for the Waterfront Park.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subchapter IV of Unit A of Chapter 2 of Title 9 [§ 9-204.01 et seq.] shall not apply to the Waterfront Park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The authority to sell the naming rights for the Waterfront Park, including the right to sell the naming rights for portions of the Waterfront Park, is assigned to Forest City SEFC, LLC; provided, that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the park shall be subject to the approval of the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Forest City SEFC, LLC, shall transfer all income generated from the naming of the Waterfront Park to the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District is authorized to transfer the income transferred to the District pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection to the Capitol Riverfront Business Improvement District, performing services under the Maintenance Agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-105, § 6, 57 DCR 11; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 8042(d), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote (b)(3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 6 of the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Base Realignment and Closure Homeless Assistance Submission Emergency Approval Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-393, July 18, 2012, 59 DCR 8690).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8042(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8042(d) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-105</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-105, see notes following § 10-1801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 10-1801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 8041 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle E of Title VIII of the act may be cited as the "Waterfront Park at the Yards Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 8044 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that §§ 8042 and 8043 of the act shall apply as of March 3, 2010.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
