<level type="section">
  <num>47-2853.95</num>
  <heading>Scope of practice for elevator contractors, elevator mechanics, and elevator inspectors.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Elevator contractor" means any sole proprietor, firm, or corporation who, for compensation, engages in erecting, constructing, installing, altering, servicing, repairing, or performing tests of elevators, platform lifts, stairway chair lifts, manlifts, conveyors, escalators, dumbwaiters, material lifts, automated people movers, and other related conveyances.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Elevator mechanic" means any individual who engages in erecting, constructing, installing, altering, servicing, repairing, or testing elevators, platform lifts, stairway chair lifts, manlifts, conveyors, escalators, dumbwaiters, material lifts, automated people movers, and other related conveyances.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Elevator inspector" means any individual who engages in performing inspections of elevators, platform lifts, stairway chair lifts, manlifts, conveyors, escalators, dumbwaiters, material lifts, automated people movers, and other related conveyances.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This part shall not apply to an electrician licensed under part F of this subchapter if the work performed by the electrician is work for which he or she is licensed to perform under part F of this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, ยง 2151(f), 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 2151(f) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 2151(f) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>Law 18-111, the "Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-203, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 12, 2009, and September 22, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 18, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-255 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-111 became effective on March 3, 2010.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
