<level type="section">
  <num>29-610.04</num>
  <heading>Administrative revocation of statement of qualification.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may commence a proceeding under subsections (b) and (c) of this section to revoke the statement of qualification of a limited liability partnership administratively if the partnership does not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pay any fee, tax, or penalty required to be paid to the Mayor not later than 6 months after it is due;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Deliver a biennial report to the Mayor not later than 6 months after it is due; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have a registered agent in this state for 60 consecutive days. "(b) If the Mayor determines that one or more grounds exist for administratively revoking a statement of qualification, the Mayor shall serve the partnership with notice in a record of the Mayor's determination.</text>
      <level>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>If a limited liability partnership, not later than 60 days after service of the notice is effected under subsection (b) of this section, does not cure or demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor the nonexistence of each ground determined by the Mayor, the Mayor shall administratively revoke the statement of qualification by signing a statement of administrative revocation that recites the grounds for revocation and the effective date of the revocation. The Mayor shall file the statement and serve a copy on the partnership pursuant to § 29-102.10.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>An administrative revocation under subsection (c) of this section affects only a partnership's status as a limited liability partnership and is not an event causing dissolution of the partnership.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>The administrative revocation of a statement of qualification of a limited liability partnership does not terminate the authority of its registered agent.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(10), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-610.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-601.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
