<level type="section">
  <num>16-711.01</num>
  <heading>Restitution or reparation - Enforcement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An order of restitution or reparation requiring a person convicted of the criminal conduct to pay restitution or reparation constitutes a judgment and lien against all property of a liable defendant for the amount the defendant is obligated to pay under the order and may be recorded in any office for the filing of liens against real or personal property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A judgment of restitution or reparation may be enforced by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, a victim entitled under the order to receive restitution or reparation, a deceased victim's estate, or any other beneficiary of the judgment in the same manner as a civil judgment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court shall provide each victim in a criminal case with a notarized and sealed copy of the Order of Restitution or Reparation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The name and address of the victim shall not be disclosed to the defendant or any representative of the defendant.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 3, 2011, D.C. Law 18-377, § 4(2), 58 DCR 1174.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of § 16-711.01, see § 504(2) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011, 58 DCR 640).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of § 16-711.01, see § 504(2) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011, 58 DCR 3701).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-377</heading>
      <text>Law 18-377, the "Criminal Code Amendment Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-963, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 7, 2010, and December 21, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 2, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 18-722 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-377 became effective on June 3, 2011.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
