<level type="section">
  <num>4-205.33</num>
  <heading>Treatment of lump-sum payments and settlements.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 3-205.33</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For applicants for and recipients of TANF:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of a lump-sum payment or settlement shall be considered as current income of the applicant or recipient, both in the month in which it was received and, to the extent required by paragraph (2) of this subsection, in future months, irrespective of the month in which it was reported to the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the amount of the payment, when added to any other income, exceeds the standard of assistance applicable to the family of which the applicant or recipient is a member:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The family of the applicant or recipient shall be ineligible for assistance for the full number of months that equals:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The sum of the payment and all other countable income received in such month, divided by;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The standard of assistance applicable to such family; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any income remaining (which amount is less than the applicable monthly standard) shall be treated as if it were income received in the 1st month following the period of ineligibility specified in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The period of ineligibility described in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be shortened if: (A) An applicant reapplies and it is determined that the standards of assistance have been increased and the amount the assistance unit would have received has also changed; (B) the lump-sum payment or a portion of it has become unavailable to the assistance unit for a reason beyond the control of the assistance unit; or (C) a member of the assistance unit incurred and paid for medical expenses in a month during the period of ineligibility caused by receipt of a lump-sum payment. The Mayor shall establish guidelines for determining when the circumstances of an assistance unit fall within the purview of this paragraph.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 533, 29 DCR 1060; Mar. 14, 1985, D.C. Law 5-150, § 2(f), 31 DCR 6425; Sept. 10, 1985, D.C. Law 6-35, § 2(g), 32 DCR 3778; Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 701(i), 44 DCR 7378; Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(ee), 46 DCR 905.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 3-205.33.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Law 12-7, August 1, 1997, law notification 44 DCR 4639).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of General Public Assistance Program Termination Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Law 12- 21, September 23, 1997, law notification 44 DCR 5760).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 701(i) of Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Temporary Act of 1997 (D.C. Law 12-59, March 20, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 2094).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(x) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-130, July 24, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 6501).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(ee) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-230, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 4143).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-25, February 27, 1997, 44 DCR 1778), and § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-77, May 27, 1997, 44 DCR 3181).</text>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(i) of the General Public Assistance Program Termination Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-72, May 12, 1997, 44 DCR 2989).</text>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 701(i) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997, 44 DCR 6196), and see § 701(i) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998, 45 DCR 508).</text>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(x) of the Public Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-306, March 20, 1998, 45 DCR 1900).</text>
        <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(ee) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-372, June 9, 1998, 45 DCR 4270), § 2(ee) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-425, July 31, 1998, 45 DCR 5682), § 2(ee) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-552, December 24, 1998, 46 DCR 521), and § 2(ee) of the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-19, February 17, 1999, 46 DCR 2492).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-101, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-150, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-205.05.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-35, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-202.05.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-60, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-241, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Application of Law 12-60: Section 2002 of D.C. Law 12-60 provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 1997.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
