<level type="section">
  <num>4-205.72</num>
  <heading>POWER - Establishment; eligibility.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility ("POWER"), eligibility for which shall be the same as the factors, standards, and methodology for determining eligibility for TANF, as set forth in this subchapter, except as provided by subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, and §§ 4-205.73 through 4-205.77.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An assistance unit shall be eligible for POWER under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The head of the assistance unit is the parent of a minor child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The head of the assistance unit is physically or mentally incapacitated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The physical or mental incapacity of the head of the assistance unit rises to the level of incapacity outlined by subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subsection (b) of this section, physical and mental incapacity must be verified by competent medical evidence and when considered with the head of the assistance unit's age, prior work experience, education, and other factors bearing on the head of the assistance unit's ability to work, as determined relevant by the Mayor:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Substantially precludes the ability of the head of the assistance unit to work or to participate in job search or job readiness activities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is expected to last more than 30 days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person is ineligible for POWER if that person receives:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supplemental Security Income; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Unemployment Compensation benefits.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Sections 4-205.11a, 4-205.11b, 4-205.19a through 4-205.19f, 4-205.19j, and 4-205.19k, shall not apply to recipients of POWER benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 572, as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 4(g), 46 DCR 905; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 5162(d), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 4-201.01, § 4-205.72a, § 4-205.74, and § 4-205.76.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 3-205.72.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-168 substituted "4-205.11a, 4-205.11b, 4-205.19j" for "4-205.11a, and 4-205.19a" in (e).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 4(h) of Self-Sufficiency Promotion Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-230, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 4143).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>See notes to § 3-205.69.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-241</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-241, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 4-201.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>See note to § 4-202.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 5163 of D.C. Law 19-168 provided that § 5162 shall apply upon certification by the Chief Financial Officer that sufficient revenue is available in the June 2012, September 2012, or December 2012 revenue estimates to fund section 10002(a)(1) and (2)(A) of D.C. Law 19-168.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
