<level type="section">
  <num>29-702.01</num>
  <heading>Formation of limited partnership; certificate of limited partnership.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In order for a limited partnership to be formed, a certificate of limited partnership shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing. The certificate shall state:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the limited partnership, which shall comply with §§ 29- 103.01 and 29-103.02(d);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The information required by § 29-104.04;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name and the street and mailing address of each general partner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any additional information required by subchapter X of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A certificate of limited partnership may also contain any other matters but may not vary or otherwise affect the provisions specified in § 29-701.07(b) in a manner inconsistent with that section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If there has been substantial compliance with subsection (a) of this section , subject to subchapter II of Chapter 1 of this title, a limited partnership shall be formed when the Mayor files the certificate of limited partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, if any provision of a partnership agreement is inconsistent with the filed certificate of limited partnership, or with a filed statement of dissociation, termination, or change, or with filed articles of merger, or with a statement of merger, interest exchange, conversion, or domestication filed under Chapter 2 of this title:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The partnership agreement shall prevail as to partners and transferees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The filed document shall prevail as to persons, other than partners and transferees, that reasonably rely on the filed record to their detriment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 201 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
