<level type="section">
  <num>29-702.06</num>
  <heading>Liability for false information in filed record.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a record delivered to the Mayor for filing under this chapter and filed by the Mayor contains false information, a person that suffers loss by reliance on the information may recover damages for the loss from:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person that signed the record, or caused another to sign it on the person's behalf, and knew the information to be false at the time the record was signed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A general partner that has notice that the information was false when the record was filed or has become false because of changed circumstances, if the general partner has notice for a reasonably sufficient time before the information is relied upon to enable the general partner to effect an amendment under § 29-702.02, file a petition pursuant to § 29-702.05, or deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of change pursuant to § 29-104.07 or a statement of correction pursuant to § 29-102.05.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Signing a record authorized or required to be filed under this chapter shall constitute an affirmation under the penalties of perjury that the facts stated in the record are true.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 208 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
