<level type="section">
  <num>29-702.02</num>
  <heading>Amendment or restatement of certificate.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To amend its certificate of limited partnership, a limited partnership shall deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment stating:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the limited partnership;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date of filing of its initial certificate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The changes the amendment makes to the certificate as most recently amended or restated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A limited partnership shall promptly deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment to a certificate of limited partnership to reflect the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Admission of a new general partner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Dissociation of a person as a general partner; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appointment of a person to wind up the limited partnership's activities under § 29-708.03(c) or (d).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A general partner that knows that any information in a filed certificate of limited partnership was false when the certificate was filed or has become false due to changed circumstances shall promptly:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cause the certificate to be amended; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If appropriate, deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of correction pursuant to § 29-102.05 or § 29-104.07.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A certificate of limited partnership may be amended at any time for any other proper purpose as determined by the limited partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A restated certificate of limited partnership may be delivered to the Mayor for filing in the same manner as an amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Subject to § 29-102.03, an amendment or restated certificate shall be effective when filed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A certificate of limited partnership may also be amended by filing articles of merger under subchapter X of this chapter or a statement of merger, interest exchange, conversion, or domestication under Chapter 2 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 202 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
