<level type="section">
  <num>9-115.11</num>
  <heading>Re-opening of Klingle Road.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other law, the portion of Klingle Road, N.W., between Porter Street, N.W., on the east, to Cortland Place, N.W., on the west, which portion is currently closed to motor vehicle traffic, shall not be re-opened to the public for motor vehicle traffic. No funding, District, federal, or otherwise, shall be expended or accepted for the planning, design, construction, or reconstruction of this portion of Klingle Road for motor vehicle traffic.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 2402, 50 DCR 5668; Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 6017, 55 DCR 7598.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>District of Columbia administration, employment practices of contractors, First Source requirements, "beneficiary" and "government-assisted project" defined, see § 2-219.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-219 rewrote the section which had read as follows: "The portion of Klingle Road, N.W., between Porter Street, N.W., on the east to Cortland Place, N.W., on the west shall be re-opened to the public for motor vehicle traffic, with the repair and reconstruction of Klingle Road, which shall include the establishment of a District Department of Transportation storm water management plan, to commence no later than 180 days following November 13, 2003."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2302 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003, 50 DCR 5613).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2302 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003, 50 DCR 8360).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-39</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-39, see notes following § 9-111.01a.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-219</heading>
      <text>Law 17-219, the "Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Act of 2008", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-678, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 13, 2008, and June 3, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 26, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-419 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-219 became effective on August 16, 2008.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title of title XXIV of Law 15-39: Section 2401 of D.C. Law 15-39 provided that title XXIV of the act may be cited as the Klingle Road Restoration Act of 2003.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 6016 of D.C. Law 17-219 provided that subtitle F of title VI of the act may be cited as the "Klingle Road Sustainable Development Amendment Act of 2008".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>For specified funding for Klingle Road, see sections 6018 and 6019 of Law 17-219.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
