<level type="section">
  <num>15-719</num>
  <heading>Adoption court costs and fees.</heading>
  <text>Any person who files a petition pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 16 to adopt a child who is a respondent in a neglect proceeding or who has been adjudicated to be neglected as defined in Chapter 23 of Title 16 shall not be required to pay court costs or fees in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-273, § 2(c), 48 DCR 1637.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 2(b) of D.C. Law 13-208 added this section.</text>
      <text>Section 5(b) of D.C. Law 13-208 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of this section, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children's Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, November 29, 2000, 48 DCR 63).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of § 15-719, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children's Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, December 18, 2000, 48 DCR 45).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(c) of Foster Children's Guardianship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-4, February 13, 2001, 48 DCR 2254).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-208</heading>
      <text>Law 13-208, the "Foster Children's Guardianship Temporary Act of 2000", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-762, which was retained by Council. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 2000, and October 3, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 24, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-457 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-208 became effective on March 31, 2001.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-273</heading>
      <text>Law 13-273, the "Foster Children's Guardianship Act of 2000", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-763, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 5, 2000, and December 19, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 16, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 13-566 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-273 became effective on April 4, 2001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
