<level type="section">
  <num>29-514</num>
  <heading>Disposition of stock of disqualified, deceased, or legally incompetent shareholder.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 29-616</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 29-416</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to the limitations of this section, a disqualified shareholder and personal representatives, legatees, or heirs of a deceased or legally incompetent shareholder may continue to own shares of a professional corporation, but shall not participate in any decision concerning the rendering of professional services by the corporation. The articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement among the shareholders of a professional corporation may provide, consistent with this section, for the disposition of shares of a disqualified, deceased, or legally incompetent shareholder.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement among shareholders may provide that, within 90 days, or any earlier date, after the date a shareholder becomes a disqualified shareholder, the disqualified shareholder shall sell and surrender, and the corporation or any individuals qualified to be shareholders shall purchase and receive, the shareholder's shares of stock of the corporation. In the absence of such a provision, the disqualified shareholder shall sell and surrender, and the corporation shall purchase and receive, the shareholder's shares of stock of the corporation within 30 days after the date the shareholder becomes a disqualified shareholder. Unless otherwise provided by the articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement among the shareholders, payment for the shares of stock purchased pursuant to this subsection shall be made in full no later than 6 months after the expiration of the period by which the purchases must be made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement among shareholders may provide that, within one year, or any earlier date, after the date of death of a shareholder, the shareholder's personal representative, legatees, or heirs shall sell and surrender, and the corporation or any individuals qualified to be shareholders shall purchase and receive, the shares of stock of the corporation owned by the deceased shareholder. In the absence of such a provision, the personal representatives, legatees, or heirs shall sell and surrender, and the corporation shall purchase and receive, the shares of stock of the corporation within 180 days after the date of death of the shareholder. Unless otherwise provided by the articles of incorporation, bylaws, or an agreement among the shareholders, payment for the shares of stock purchased pursuant to this subsection shall be made in full no later than one year after the date of death of the shareholder.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 29-416.</text>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 29-616.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 29-1116.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
