<level type="section">
  <num>42-2851.06</num>
  <heading>Section 8 assistance considered income for non-discrimination and minimum income purposes; requirement to accept section 8 vouchers.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The monetary assistance provided to an owner of a housing accommodation under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, either directly or through a tenant, shall be considered the income of the tenant for the purposes of any minimum income qualification for a dwelling unit in the housing accommodation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The monetary assistance provided to an owner of a housing accommodation under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, either directly or through a tenant, shall be considered income and a source of income under § 2-1402.21.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The owner of a housing accommodation shall not refuse to rent a dwelling unit to a person because the person will provide his or her rental payment, in whole or in part, through a section 8 voucher.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 206, 49 DCR 1468; Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 59, 52 DCR 2638.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-354, in subsec. (b), validated previously made technical changes.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 14-114, see notes following § 42-2851.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-354, see notes following § 42-1103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>Section 8 of the United States Housing Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is Act Sept. 1, 1937, c.896, Title I, § 8, which is classified to 42 U.S.C.A. § 1437f.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
