<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section-start>42-3151.01.</section-start>
  <section-end>42-3151.13</section-end>
  <section-range-type>range</section-range-type>
  <heading>Definitions; petition for immediate taking; deposit in court of fair market value; judgment for excess of public charges over property value; title holder; assistance to certain displaced persons; inability to qualify for hardship petition; effect on other authority; condemnation and acquisition of open, hazardous residential buildings or other structures; notice; demolition, repair, or enclosure; designation of development or redevelopment plan for property acquired; limitation on actions against the District of Columbia; report to the Council required.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, §§ 401-413, 48 DCR 1888; Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 103, 49 DCR 1468.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-114</heading>
      <text>Law 14-114, the "Housing Act of 2002", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-183, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 2001, and January 8, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 6, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-267 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-114 became effective on April 19, 2002.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 601 of D.C. Law 13-281 provided: "The Mayor may issue rules to implement the Abatement and Condemnation of Nuisance Properties Omnibus Amendment Act of 2000 in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Mayor's orders</heading>
      <text>Delegation of Authority Under the Anti-Graffiti Emergency Act of 2010, see Mayor's Order 2010-139, August 20, 2010 (57 DCR 7740).</text>
      <text>Delegation of Authority Under the Anti Graffiti Act of 2010, see Mayor's Order 2010-176, November 26, 2010 (57 DCR 11421).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
