<level type="section">
  <num>20-353</num>
  <heading>Proceedings after petition.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 20-353</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Determinations on petition.</text> -- If the Court finds that the petition and any additional information filed under this subchapter is accurate, it shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>appoint a personal representative of the small estate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>direct the immediate payment of the allowable funeral expenses as provided in section 20-906 and the family allowance as provided in section 19-101;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>direct the sale of property as may be necessary to satisfy funeral expenses and the family allowance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>if it appears that there will be any property remaining after payment of funeral expenses and there is no family allowance payable, admit the will, if any, to probate and direct that notice be given in accordance with subsection (b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text><text i="True">Notice.</text> -- If the Court directs that notice be given, notice shall be given once in the form required by section 20-704; except, that the period within which claims must be filed or objection must be made to contest the validity of the will or the small estates proceeding or the appointment of the personal representative shall be 30 days from the date of publication of notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 24, 1980, D.C. Law 3-72, ยง 101, 27 DCR 2155.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 20-353.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-72, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 20-301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
