<level type="section">
  <num>5-651</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Department" means the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Director" means the medical services officer for the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Documented" means the member or EMS employee gave notice to the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, in writing, of his or her occupational exposure to blood or bodily fluids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"EMS employee" means a person that qualifies as an "emergency medical services personnel" as defined by § 7-2341.01(7), is employed by the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, and is not a sworn member of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Full range of duties" shall have the same meaning as provided in § 5-631(5).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Member " means a sworn member of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Pre-employment physical examination" means a physical examination that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is the same as or similar to the physical examination required under § 5-451;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is conducted before making any claims under this chapter that rely on a presumption in this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is conducted by a physician or physicians at the Police and Fire Clinic or as prescribed by the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Includes such appropriate laboratory and other diagnostic studies prescribed by the Police and Fire Clinic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 651, as added May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-311, § 2, 60 DCR 3425.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-311 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-311</heading>
      <text>Law 19-311, the "Fire and Emergency Medical Services Employee Presumptive Disability Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-616. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 2012, and December 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 13, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-679 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-311 became effective on May 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
