<level type="section">
  <num>5-652</num>
  <heading>Presumption as to disability or death from heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A member shall be presumed to have a performance-of-duty injury or illness that is covered by Subtitle B of Title VI of this act, section 12 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and seventeen, and for other purposes, approved September 1, 1916 (39 Stat. 718; D.C. Official Code § 5-701 passim), sections 1 through 3 of An Act To provide for the payment of the cost of medical, surgical, hospital, or related health care services provided certain retired, disabled officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the Executive Protective Service, and the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes, approved August 16, 1971 (85 Stat. 341; D.C. Official Code § 5-708), sections 204(c), 205(c), 206(b), 208(b), and 209(a)(2) of An Act To establish an actuarially sound basis for financing retirement benefits for police officers, fire fighters, teachers, and judges of the District of Columbia and to make certain changes in such benefits, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code §§ 5-711, 5-715, 5-702, 5-705, and 5-719, respectively), section 122 of An Act To increase compensation for District of Columbia policemen, firemen, and teachers; to increase annuities payable to retired teachers in the District of Columbia; to establish an equitable tax on real property in the District of Columbia; to provide for additional revenue for the District of Columbia; and for other purposes, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1041; D.C. Official Code § 5-722), sections 4,6, and 7 of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act amendments of 1957, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 399; D.C. Official Code § 5-731 et seq.), section 1 of An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of such District for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1936, and for other purposes, approved June 14, 1935 (49 Stat. 358; D.C. Official Code § 5-741), An Act To credit active service in the military or naval forces of the United States in determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits from the policemen and firemen's relief fund, District of Columbia, approved July 21, 1947 (61 Stat. 398; D.C. Official Code § 5-742), section 6 of An Act To fix the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan police force and the fire department of the District of Columbia, approved July 1, 1930 (46 Stat. 841: D.C. Official Code § 5-743), section 3 of An Act to provide increased pensions for widows and children of deceased members and retired members of the Police Department and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, approved August 4, 1949 (63 Stat. 566; D.C. Official Code § 5-744), sections 301 and 302 of An Act To adjust the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force, the United States Park Police, the White House Police, and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 20, 1953 (67 Stat. 75; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-745 and 7-746), sections 1 and 2 of An Act To extend benefits of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act Amendments of 1957 to widows and surviving children of former members of the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the White House Police force, or the United States Secret Service Division, who were retired or who died in the service of any such organization prior to the effective date of such amendments, approved August 24, 1962 (76 Stat. 402; D.C. Official Code § 5-747), section 2 of Retired Police Officer Redeployment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Official Code § 5-761), and section 2 of the Retired Police Officer Public Schools Security Personnel Deployment Amendment Act of 1994, effective July 23, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-136; D.C. Official Code § 5-762), unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to § 5-655, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The member has been diagnosed with heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease results in the member's inability to perform the full range of duties or in death;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The member has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the member was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the performance-of-duty injury or illness underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The member, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An EMS employee shall be presumed to have an occupational disease suffered in the line of duty that is covered by the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501 et seq.), unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to § 5-655, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The EMS employee has been diagnosed with heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease results in the EMS employee's disability, as defined by § 32-1501(8), or in death;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The EMS employee has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the EMS employee was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the occupational disease underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The EMS employee, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, § 652, as added May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-311, § 2, 60 DCR 3425.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-311 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-311</heading>
      <text>See note to § 5-651.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
