<level type="section">
  <num>42-2141</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Affordable housing unit" means a unit of housing that is offered for rent or for sale for residential occupancy and as a result of a federal or District subsidy is made available and affordable to households whose income levels are less than or equal to 120% of the area median income.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Area median income" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For a household of 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% for each household member exceeding 4 persons (for example, the area median income for a family of 5 shall be 110% of the area median income for a family of 4; the area median income for a household of 6 shall be 120% of the area median income for a family of 4).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Extremely low-income" means a household income equal to 30% or less of the area median income.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Homeless" means a person:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Who is lacking a fixed, regular residence that provides safe housing and the financial means to acquire such a residence immediately; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Whose primary night-time residence is:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A supervised publicly or privately operated shelter or transitional housing facility designed to provide temporary living accommodations; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A public or private place not designed for, or ordinarily used as, a regular sleeping accommodation for human beings.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Low-income" means a household income equal to, or less than, 80% of the area median income and greater than 50% of the area median income.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Very low-income" means a household income equal to, or less than, 50% of the area median income and greater than 30% of the area median income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, ยง 2092, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Short title: Section 2091 of D.C. Law 19-168 provided that subtitle J of title II of the act may be cited as "Department of Housing and Community Development Comprehensive Tracking Plan for Affordable Housing Inventory Act of 2012".</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
