<level type="section">
  <num>3-1205.12</num>
  <heading>Reinstatement of expired licenses, registrations, or certifications.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 2-3305.12</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a health professional fails for any reason to renew the license, registration, or certification issued under this subchapter, the board regulating the health occupation shall reinstate the license, registration, or certification if the health professional:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applies to the board for reinstatement of the license, registration, or certification within 5 years after the license, registration, or certification expires;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complies with current requirements for renewal of a license, registration, or certification as set forth in this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pays a reinstatement fee established by the Mayor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submits to the board satisfactory evidence of compliance with the qualifications and requirements established under this subchapter for license, registration, or certification reinstatements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The board shall not reinstate the license, registration, or certification of a health professional who fails to apply for reinstatement of a license, registration, or certification within 5 years after the license, registration, or certification expires. The health professional may become licensed, registered, or certified by meeting the requirements then in existence for obtaining an initial license, registration, or certification under this subchapter; except, that an individual applying for a license to practice nursing who has not been actively practicing for 5 years or more shall submit proof of having completed a board-approved refresher course in lieu of the requirements then in existence for obtaining an initial license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 512, 33 DCR 729; July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(13), 56 DCR 4043.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 2-3305.12.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-26, in the section heading, inserted "registrations, or certifications" following "licenses"; in subsec. (a), inserted "registration or certification," following "license,"; and rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(b) The board shall not reinstate the license of a health professional who fails to apply for reinstatement of a license within 5 years after the license expires. The health professional may become licensed by meeting the requirements then in existence for obtaining an initial license under this subchapter."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(13) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009, 56 DCR 6308).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 6-99, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 3-1201.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-26, see notes following § 3-1201.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
