<level type="section">
  <num>16-4403</num>
  <heading>When chapter applies.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This chapter governs an agreement to arbitrate made on or after [February 27, 2008].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This chapter governs an agreement to arbitrate made before [February 27, 2008] if all the parties to the agreement or to the arbitration proceeding so agree in a record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any provision in an insurance policy with a consumer that requires binding arbitration is void and unenforceable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An insurance policy with a consumer may permit the resolution of disputes through arbitration; provided, that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The decision to arbitrate is made by the parties at the time a dispute arises; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The decision whether to arbitrate is not a condition for continued policy coverage under the same terms that otherwise would apply.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the parties to an insurance policy with a consumer elect to arbitrate, the provisions of this chapter shall apply.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A provision for mandatory binding arbitration within a consumer arbitration agreement is void and unenforceable except to the extent federal law provides for its enforceability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On or after July 1, 2009, this chapter governs an agreement to arbitrate whenever made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This chapter does not apply to any arbitrator or any arbitration organization in an arbitration proceeding governed by rules adopted by a securities self-regulatory organization; provided, that the rules are approved by the United States Securities and Exchange Commission under federal law.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "securities self-regulatory organization" means:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A securities exchange registered under the federal Securities Exchange Act of 1934, approved June 6, 1934 (48 Stat. 881; 15 U.S.C. ยง 78a <text i="True">et seq.</text>) ("Securities Exchange Act");</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A national securities association of broker-dealers registered under the Securities Exchange Act;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A clearing agency registered under the Securities Exchange Act; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board established under the Securities Exchange Act.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-111, ยง 2(b), 55 DCR 1847.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-111, see notes following ยง 16-4401.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 3 of the Uniform Arbitration Act (2000). See Vol. 7, Pt. I, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
