<level type="section">
  <num>4-753.04</num>
  <heading>Fiscal years 2012 and 2013 rapid re-housing.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning in June 2012, the Department shall identify at least 200 homeless families from hotels, motels, severe-weather shelters, temporary shelters, or transitional housing, and ensure that at least 100 of these families are placed in or are residing in apartment-style housing units that meet the requirements of the Rent Supplement Program, established by § 6-226, by before [sic] September 30, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By October 1, 2012, the Department shall ensure that all homeless families that were residing in hotels or motels have been placed into shelter or housing.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Placements made by the Department pursuant to subjection (a) of this section shall be done in coordination with the District of Columbia Housing Authority ("DCHA"). The Department shall develop rules for selecting homeless families that will be converted onto the Rent Supplement Program's tenant-based vouchers and submit them to the Council within 45 days of June 19, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Once there are vacancies in temporary shelters, severe-weather shelters, or transitional housing, the Department shall use all available resources currently budgeted for homeless families to place new family-shelter applicants who cannot access other housing arrangements, as defined in § 4-753.01(c)(4) into shelters or housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2013, and for each fiscal year thereafter, an additional $4 million shall be included in the DCHA Subsidy to provide tenant-based rental assistance to between 200 and 300 eligible families in accordance with the Rent Supplement Program, established by § 6-226. DCHA shall provide tenant- based rental assistance through the Rent Supplement Program to all families placed in housing pursuant to subsection (a) of this section who meet the eligibility criteria established for sponsor-based housing assistance under the Rent Supplement Program, set forth in section 9508 of Title 14 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (14 DCMR § 9508).</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 8b, as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 5102, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-168 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of D.C. Law 19-236 added D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c to read as follows:</text>
      <text>"Sec. 8c. Placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season.</text>
      <text>"For fiscal year 2013, the Mayor and the District of Columbia Housing Authority may fill vacant Rent Supplement Program tenant-based vouchers, established by section 26c of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; D.C. Official Code § 6-228), with homeless families referred by the Department of Human Services and determined to have first priority to shelter pursuant to 29 DCMR § 2508.01(a)(1), through the end of the 2012-2013 hypothermia season. The referrals shall be made in accordance with the special eligibility criteria set forth in 29 DCMR § 2556 through 29 DCMR § 2558."</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of D.C. Law 19-236 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) addition of D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Technical Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-56, December 13, 2013, 60 DCR 15165).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 5102 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
      <text>For temporary addition of D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season, see § 2 of the Local Rent Supplement Program Voucher Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-545, November 16, 2012, 59 DCR 13590).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c, concerning placement of first priority homeless families for the 2012-2013 hypothermia season, see § 2 of the Local Rent Supplement Program Voucher Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-12, February 20, 2013, 60 DCR 3960, 20 DCSTAT 466).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of D.C. Law 16-35, § 8c, see §§ 2(a), 2(c), 3(a), and 3(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-180, October 4, 2013, 60 DCR 14949).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
