<level type="section">
  <num>29-1207.04</num>
  <heading>Filings required for merger; effective date.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After each constituent organization has approved a merger, articles of merger shall be signed on behalf of each:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Constituent statutory trust, by one or more trustees or other authorized representative; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Other constituent organization, by an authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Articles of merger under this section shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and form of each constituent organization and the jurisdiction of its governing law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name and form of the surviving organization, the jurisdiction of its governing law, and, if the surviving organization is created by the merger, a statement to that effect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the surviving organization is to be created by the merger:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If it will be a statutory trust, the trust's certificate of trust; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If it will be an organization other than a statutory trust, the organizational document that creates the organization;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the surviving organization preexisted the merger, any amendments provided for in the plan of merger for the organizational document that created the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A statement as to each constituent organization that the merger was approved as required by the organization's governing law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>If the surviving organization is a foreign organization not authorized to do business in the District, the street and mailing address of an office that the Mayor may use for the purposes of § 29-1207.05(b); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any additional information required by the governing law of any constituent organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The articles of merger shall be delivered to the office of the Mayor for filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A merger shall be effective under this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the surviving organization is a statutory trust, upon the later of:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Filing of the articles of merger by the Mayor; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subject to § 29-102.03, as specified in the articles of merger; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the surviving organization is not a statutory trust, as provided by the governing law of the surviving organization[.]</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-1207.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 704 of the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
