<level type="section">
  <num>25-125</num>
  <heading>Distillery pub permit requirements and qualifications.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall authorize the licensee to manufacture, blend, rectify, and store distilled spirits at one location from fruits, grains, neutral grain spirits, or distilled spirits transported from an area that produces distilled spirits to the licensed restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub for on-premises consumption, and for sale to licensed wholesalers for the purpose of resale to other licensees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be issued only to the licensee under an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub license, class C, in conjunction with the issuance of an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub license, class C.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The location used to manufacture or age distilled spirits shall be on or immediately adjacent to the restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub licensed to the distillery pub owner in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The holder of a distillery pub permit may also sell distilled spirits to patrons in sealed bottles or other closed containers for off-premises consumption; provided, that such sales shall be limited to the hours between 7:00 a.m. and midnight, 7 days a week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The minimum annual fee of the distillery pub permit shall be $7,500.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be cancelled or revoked if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub ceases to be operated as a restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The licensee's on-premises retailer's license, class C, is revoked or cancelled.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be automatically suspended whenever and for the same period that the licensee's on-premises retailer's license, class C, is suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-78, ยง 2(b), 61 DCR 151.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-78</heading>
      <text>Law 20-78, the "Distillery Pub Licensure Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-29. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 2013, and December 3, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-248 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-78 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
