<level type="section">
  <num>1-753</num>
  <heading>Compliance by Mayor.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-753</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall comply with the requirements of these regulations and shall give written notice of compliance therewith to the Council of the District of Columbia within 60 calendar days after July 2, 1982.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 193, as added July 2, 1982, D.C. Law 4-23, § 4, 29 DCR 2084; Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 33(e), 51 DCR 881.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-753.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-105 validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary establishment of an actuarially sound retirement replacement plan for pension benefits accrued after June 30, 1997, for police officers, fire fighters, and teachers, see §§ 101-204 of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-155, October 1, 1997, 44 DCR 5896), see §§ 101-204 of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-240, January 13, 1998, 45 DCR 531), see §§ 101-204 of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan and Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Act of 1997 Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-351, May 20, 1998, 45 DCR 3673), and see §§ 101-204 of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan and Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Act of 1997 Technical Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-432, August 6, 1998, 45 DCR 5920).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-123, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-751.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-58, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-711.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-105, see notes following § 1-751.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Retirement replacement plan: Sections 101 through 204 of D.C. Law 12-58 provide for the temporary establishment of replacement retirement plans for pension benefits accrued after June 30, 1997, for police officers, fire fighters, and teachers, and provide for the full funding and management on an actuarially sound basis of all retirement funds entrusted to the District government for the benefit of teachers, members and officers of the Metropolitan Police Department, and employees of the D.C. Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
        <text>Section 209(b) of D.C. Law 12-58 provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
