<level type="section">
  <num>50-2206.53</num>
  <heading>Prosecution and diversionary program.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General of the District of Columbia, or his or her assistants, shall prosecute violations of this subchapter, in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General may request that a person who is charged with a violation of any provision of this subchapter, as a condition to acceptance into a diversion program in lieu of prosecution, pay the District of Columbia or its agents a reasonable fee for the costs to the District of the person's participation in the diversion program; provided, that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General shall set the fee by rule and at a level which the Attorney General determines will not unreasonably discourage persons from entering the diversion program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may reduce or waive the fee if the Attorney General finds that the person is indigent; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall determine the provider, the content, and eligibility requirements for any diversion program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-145, § 3r, as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 103(e)(3), 59 DCR 12957.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-266 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 103(e)(3) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013, 60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 103(e)(3) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013, 60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-266</heading>
      <text>See note to § 50-2201.02.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
