<level type="section">
  <num>38-221</num>
  <heading>Attendance zone boundaries; establishment, modification, alteration.</heading>
  <text>Except as required due to a school closure or a consolidation of schools, upon Dec. 24, 2013, notwithstanding any other law or regulation, no approved establishment, modification, or alteration of any attendance zone boundary shall be implemented, or in any manner initiated, until the 2015-2016 school year or with less notice than a full school year to the parent or guardian of each affected student, whichever is greater; provided, that nothing in this section shall prohibit the Chancellor from proposing or implementing changes to school feeder patterns that would result in additional options in next-level schools for a feeder school.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 4072, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 4072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 4072 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 4071 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle G of Title IV of the act may be cited as the "Attendance Zone Boundaries Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
