<level type="section">
  <num>8-231.14</num>
  <heading>Denial, suspension, or revocation.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor, after notice and opportunity for hearing, may suspend, revoke, modify, or refuse to issue, renew, or restore a certificate or accreditation issued under this chapter if the Mayor finds that the applicant or holder:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has failed to comply with any provision of this chapter or rule issued pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has misrepresented facts relating to a lead-based paint activity to a client or customer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has made a false statement or misrepresentation material to the issuance, modification, or renewal of a certificate, permit, or accreditation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Has submitted a false or fraudulent record, invoice, or report;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>As a training provider, or as an instructor, has provided inaccurate information or inadequate training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Fails to meet any qualifications required by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Does not possess proof of required accreditation, as prescribed by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Has had a history of repeated violations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Has had a certificate, permit, or accreditation denied, revoked, or suspended in another state or jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-381, ยง 15, 56 DCR 1596.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-381, see notes following ยง 8-231.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
