<level type="section">
  <num>50-921.15</num>
  <heading>Sustainable Transportation Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Sustainable Transportation Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and be used by the District Department of Transportation on approved capital projects for bus-operating enhancements, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unfunded recommendations in WMATA Bus Line Studies and WMATA Service Evaluations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Other investments determined by the Mayor to enhance bus transit operational efficiency and customer service within the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Fees collected for the parking of vehicles where meters or devices are installed shall be deposited into the Fund in accordance with § 50- 2603(8)(C).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9g, as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6024(b), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of District Department of Transportation Parking Meter Fund Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-476, October 9, 2012, 59 DCR 12101).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 19-168, see notes under § 50-320.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
