<level type="section">
  <num>7-2271.02</num>
  <heading>Establishment of District of Columbia Homeland Security Commission; membership.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a District of Columbia Homeland Security Commission, which shall consist of 7 persons with expertise in security, transportation, communication, chemical safety, risk assessment, terrorism (including bioterrorism), or occupational safety and health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Commission members shall be nominated by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council for terms of 3 years, in accordance with § 1-523.01(e), except that initially 4 Commission members shall be appointed to a 3-year term and 3 Commission members shall be appointed to a 2-year term.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall establish through rulemaking that Commission members shall be subject to pre-nomination inquiries and security-clearance requirements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The terms of the members first appointed shall begin on the date a majority of the first members are sworn in, which shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Commission member's terms shall be staggered so that either 4 positions or 3 positions will expire on the year's anniversary date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members shall receive no salary for their service on the Commission but shall be reimbursed for administrative costs associated with membership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall provide staff to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-262, § 202, 54 DCR 794; June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 508, 60 DCR 3390.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-523.01 and § 7-2271.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-320 added "except that initially 4 Commission members shall be appointed to a 3-year term and 3 Commission members shall be appointed to a 2-year term" at the end of (b)(1); and made a related change.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of (b)(1), see § 508 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1017).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-262</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-262, see notes following § 7-2271.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-320</heading>
      <text>Law 19-320, the "Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-645. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 11, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-677 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-320 became effective on June 19, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
