<level type="section">
  <num>2-1215.20</num>
  <heading>Maintenance of base level of city services.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District government shall not eliminate or reduce the level of any services customarily provided in the District to any similar geographic area because such area is subject to a BID, and shall continue to provide its customary services and levels of each service to such area notwithstanding that such area is or may be encompassed in a BID unless a reduction in service is part of a District-wide pro rata reduction in services necessitated by fiscal considerations or budgetary priorities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, beginning in fiscal year 2013, the Mayor shall not issue a grant using funds from the Commercial Revitalization Assistance Fund, established by § 2-218.76, for the purpose of providing commercial revitalization services or Clean Team services, including ambassador services and the removal of trash, graffiti, illegal posters, and snow within a geographic area that is subject to a BID."</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 20, 43 DCR 1684; renumbered as § 21, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320; Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2142, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2290.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-168 added the (a) designation; and added (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Law 12-23, September 23, 1997, law notification 44 DCR 5762).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997, 44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997, 44 DCR 5054).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-134</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-134, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-26</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-26, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Expiration of law Expiration of Law 11-134</heading>
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
