<level type="section">
  <num>2-1215.10</num>
  <heading>Meetings of members and the Board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided by this subchapter, meetings of the members shall be held in accordance with the provisions of the bylaws but shall occur at least once each year after the formation of the BID. The bylaws shall specify an officer who shall send each member notice of the time, place, and purposes of the meeting. Notice shall be given at least 21 days in advance of any annual or regularly scheduled meeting and at least 7 days in advance of any other meeting. Notice shall be sent by first class mail to all members of record at the address of their respective properties and to such other address as may have been designated to such officer. Notice may also be hand delivered by the officer, or his or her agent, provided the officer certifies in writing that notice was actually delivered to the member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Board shall be open to members. Minutes shall be recorded and shall be made reasonably available to all members and the Mayor and the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 10, 43 DCR 1684; renumbered as § 11, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2280.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Law 12-23, September 23, 1997, law notification 44 DCR 5762).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997, 44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997, 44 DCR 5054).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-134</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-134, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-26</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-26, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Expiration of law Expiration of Law 11-134</heading>
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1215.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
