<level type="section">
  <num>47-391.08</num>
  <heading>Application of laws of District of Columbia to Authority.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>In general</heading>
    <text>The following laws of the District of Columbia (as in effect on April 17, 1995) shall apply to the members and activities of the Authority:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>§ 1-207.42;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>§§ 2-531 through 2-536; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>§ 1-1162.23.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>No control, supervision, oversight, or review by Mayor or Council</heading>
    <text>Neither the Mayor nor the Council may exercise any control, supervision, oversight, or review over the Authority or its activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Authority not subject to representation by Attorney General for the District of Columbia</heading>
    <text>In any action brought by or on behalf of the Authority, and in any action brought against the Authority, the Authority shall be represented by such counsel as it may select, but in no instance may the Authority be represented by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 17, 1995, 109 Stat. 107, Pub. L. 104-8, § 108; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(a)(3), 52 DCR 2638; Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 48(h)(1), 53 DCR 6794; Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 501(n)(1), 59 DCR 1862.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-391.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-391.8.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-354 substituted "Attorney General for the District of Columbia" for "Corporation Counsel".</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-191, in subsec. (c), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 19-124, in subsec. (a)(3), substituted " § 1-1162.23 " for "§ 1-1106.01".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 401(n)(1) of Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-298, January 29, 2012, 59 DCR 683).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-354</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-354, see notes following § 47-340.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-191</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-191, see notes following § 47-138.01a.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-124</heading>
      <text>Law 19-124, the "Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-511, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 6, 2011, and December 20, 2011, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 27, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-318 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-124 became effective on April 27, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
