<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-705</num>
  <heading>Effectiveness of action taken before July 1, 2001.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If action, other than the filing of a financing statement, is taken before July 1, 2001 and the action would have resulted in priority of a security interest over the rights of a person that becomes a lien creditor had the security interest become enforceable, the action is effective to perfect a security interest that attaches under this article within one year after July 1, 2001. An attached security interest becomes unperfected 1 year after July 1, 2001 unless the security interest becomes a perfected security interest under this article before the expiration of that period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The filing of a financing statement before July 1, 2001 is effective to perfect a security interest to the extent the filing would satisfy the applicable requirements for perfection under this article.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This article does not render ineffective an effective financing statement that, before July 1, 2001, is filed and satisfies the applicable requirements for perfection under the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in former § 28:9-103. However, except as otherwise provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section and § 28:9-706, the financing statement ceases to be effective at the earlier of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The time the financing statement would have ceased to be effective under the law of the jurisdiction in which it is filed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>June 30, 2006.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The filing of a continuation statement on or after July 1, 2001 does not continue the effectiveness of the financing statement filed before July 1, 2001. However, upon the timely filing of a continuation statement on or after July 1, 2001 and in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Part 3, the effectiveness of a financing statement filed in the same office in that jurisdiction before July 1, 2001 continues for the period provided by the law of that jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Subsection (c)(2) applies to a financing statement that, before July 1, 2001, is filed against a transmitting utility and satisfies the applicable requirements for perfection under the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in former § 28:9-103 only to the extent that Part 3 provides that the law of a jurisdiction other than the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed governs perfection of a security interest in collateral covered by the financing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A financing statement that includes a financing statement filed before July 1, 2001 and a continuation statement filed on or after July 1, 2001 is effective only to the extent that it satisfies the requirements of Part 5 for an initial financing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-703 and § 28:9-707.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
