<level type="section">
  <num>3-1433</num>
  <heading>Commission responsibilities and duties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Commissioners shall advise the Mayor, the Council, and Council committees concerning:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Proposals for uniform and model state laws;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The effect that the proposals would have on the laws of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other matters pertinent to the desirable uniformity in legislation between the District and other jurisdictions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each commissioner shall attend the meetings of the NCCUSL and, both within and out of the NCCUSL, do all in his or her power to promote uniformity in state laws in all subjects in which uniformity is desirable and practicable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each commissioner may:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Participate in all the activities of the NCCUSL;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Participate in the votes of the states and other votes of the NCCUSL;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Be appointed to serve on any committee of the NCCUSL; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Be appointed or elected to any office of the NCCUSL.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District may expend funds necessary to cover the costs of commissioners' attendance at the annual meeting as required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the annual dues for the NCCUSL, and any other expenses as required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The commissioners shall submit a report to the Mayor, the Chairperson of the Council, and the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia after each annual meeting, and from time to time thereafter as the commissioners consider proper, summarizing the activities of the Commission and the NCCUSL during the previous year.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-313, § 4, 57 DCR 12401; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1082, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 added (b)(3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1082 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1082 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-313</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-313, see notes under § 3-1431.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 1081 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle I of Title I of the act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
