<level type="section">
  <num>3-1432</num>
  <heading>Commission membership and organization.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall consist of the following commissioners:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three commissioners appointed by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One commissioner appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One commissioner appointed by the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The General Counsel to the Council of the District of Columbia, or his or her designee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any resident of the District of Columbia who, because of long service in the cause of the uniformity of state legislation, shall have been elected a life member of the NCCUSL.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible to serve as a member of the Commission, an individual must be a resident of the District of Columbia and must be a member in good standing of the District of Columbia Bar.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A commissioner appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(1), (2), or (3) of this section shall serve a term of 3 years, beginning on July 1 of the year of appointment, or until a successor is appointed, whichever is later. A commissioner appointed to fill a vacancy on the Commission shall serve for the unexpired portion of the term, or until a successor is appointed, whichever is later.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person serving as a NCCUSL commissioner as of March 12, 2011, may continue to serve until the expiration of his or her term, or until a successor is appointed, whichever occurs later.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-313, ยง 3, 57 DCR 12401.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-313</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-313, see notes under ยง 3-1431.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
