<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-321</num>
  <heading>C.I.F. or C. &amp; F.: "net landed weights"; "payment on arrival"; warranty of condition on arrival.</heading>
  <text>Under a contract containing a term C.I.F. or C. &amp; F.</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Where the price is based on or is to be adjusted according to "net landed weights", "delivered weights", "out turn" quantity or quality or the like, unless otherwise agreed the seller must reasonably estimate the price. The payment due on tender of the documents called for by the contract is the amount so estimated, but after final adjustment of the price a settlement must be made with commercial promptness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>An agreement described in subsection (1) or any warranty of quality or condition of the goods on arrival places upon the seller the risk of ordinary deterioration, shrinkage and the like in transportation but has no effect on the place or time of identification to the contract for sale or delivery or on the passing of the risk of loss.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise agreed where the contract provides for payment on or after arrival of the goods the seller must before payment allow such preliminary inspection as is feasible; but if the goods are lost delivery of the documents and payment are due when the goods should have arrived.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 650, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:2-513.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:2-321.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:2-321.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</heading>
      <text>None.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Purposes:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>This section deals with two variations of the C.I.F. contract which have evolved in mercantile practice but are entirely consistent with the basis C.I.F. pattern. Subsections (1) and (2), which provide for a shift to the seller of the risk of quality and weight deterioration during shipment, are designed to conform the law to the best mercantile practice and usage without changing the legal consequences of the C.I.F. or C. &amp; F. term as to the passing of marine risks to the buyer at the point of shipment. Subsection (3) provides that where under the contract documents are to be presented for payment after arrival of the goods, this amounts merely to a postponement of the payment under the C.I.F. contract and is not to be confused with the "no arrival, no sale" contract. If the goods are lost, delivery of the documents and payment against them are due when the goods should have arrived. The clause for payment on or after arrival is not to be construed as such a condition precedent to payment that if the goods are lost in transit the buyer need never pay and the seller must bear the loss.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross Reference:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>Section 2-324.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>"Agreement". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Contract". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Goods". Section 2-105.</text>
      <text>"Seller". Section 2-103.</text>
      <text>"Term". Section 1-201.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
