<level type="section">
  <num>29-1107</num>
  <heading>Statement of authority as to real property.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "statement of authority" means a statement authorizing a person to transfer an interest in real property held in the name of an unincorporated nonprofit association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An interest in real property held in the name of an unincorporated nonprofit association may be transferred by a person authorized to do so in a statement of authority filed by the association with the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A statement of authority shall set forth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the unincorporated nonprofit association;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The address in the District, including the street address, if any, of the association, or, if the association does not have an address in the District, its out-of-state address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That the association is an unincorporated nonprofit association; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The name, title, or position of a person authorized to transfer an interest in real property held in the name of the association.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A statement of authority shall be executed in the same manner as a deed by a person other than the person authorized in the statement to transfer the interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A document effecting an amendment, revocation, or cancellation of a statement of authority, or stating that the statement is unauthorized or erroneous, shall meet the requirements for execution and filing of an original statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Unless canceled earlier, a filed statement of authority and its most recent amendment shall expire 5 years after the date of the most recent filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If the record title to real property is in the name of an unincorporated nonprofit association and the statement of authority is delivered to the Mayor for filing, the authority of the person named in the statement to transfer shall be conclusive in favor of a person that gives value without notice that the person lacks authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(k)(3), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "delivered to the Mayor for filing" for "filed with the Mayor" in (g).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-1106.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 7 of the Uniform Unincorporated Nonprofit Association Act (2008 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
