<level type="section">
  <num>29-1125</num>
  <heading>Winding up and termination.</heading>
  <text>Winding up and termination of an unincorporated nonprofit association shall proceed in accordance with the following rules:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>All known debts and liabilities shall be paid or adequately provided for.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any property subject to a condition requiring return to the person designated by the donor shall be transferred to that person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Any property subject to a trust shall be distributed in accordance with the trust agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Any remaining property shall be distributed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>As required by law other than this chapter that requires assets of an association to be distributed to another person with similar nonprofit purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>In accordance with the association's governing principles or, in the absence of applicable governing principles, to the members of the association per capita or as the members direct; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>If subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph does not apply, in accordance with the law of unclaimed property in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-1122 and § 29-1124.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 29 of the Uniform Unincorporated Nonprofit Association Act (2008 Act).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
