<level type="section">
  <num>1-620.03</num>
  <heading>Minimal standards applicable.</heading>
  <text>Safe and healthful conditions shall be provided all employees of the District government in accordance with applicable standards, codes, rules and regulations, and shall be consistent with the occupational safety and health standards promulgated by the United States Department of Labor under the provisions of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, as amended (84 Stat. 1590), and applicable codes, rules and regulations including, but not limited to:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The D.C. Occupational Safety and Health Board Occupational Safety and Health Standards (11B D.C.R.R.);</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The Building Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The Electrical Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The Fire Prevention Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The Plumbing Code approved pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 2003, 25 DCR 5740; Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 13(a), 34 DCR 1072.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-621.3.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 1-350.3.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 2-139</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-139, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 1-601.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 6-216</heading>
      <text>Law 6-216 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-500, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 18, 1986 and December 16, 1986, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 2, 1987, it was assigned Act No. 6-279 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>The "Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986," referred to throughout this section, is D.C. Law 6-216.</text>
      <text>The D.C. Occupational Safety and Health Board Occupational Safety and Health Standards (11B D.C.R.R.), referred to in (1), are now found in 24 DCMR, Chapters 30-32.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
