<level type="section">
  <num>42-3131.09</num>
  <heading>Fees.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As provided in § 42-3131.06(a), the owner of a building shall register the building and pay the registration fee within 30 days after it becomes a vacant building, except if the vacant building is owned by the government of the United States or its instrumentalities or by a foreign government or its instrumentalities. The Mayor, in his or her sole discretion, may extend the time for payment for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Registrations shall be renewed annually from date of initial issuance unless there is a change in ownership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The initial registration fee shall be $250.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The renewal registration fee shall be $250.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 9, as added Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 101, 48 DCR 1888; Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-216, § 3(e), 55 DCR 7500; Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2042(c), 57 DCR 6242.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-216, in subsec. (d), substituted "§ 42-3131.08" for "§ 42-3131.11".</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-223 rewrote the section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) As provided in § 42-3131.06(a), the owner of a building shall register the building and pay the registration fee within 30 days after it becomes a vacant building. The Mayor may, in his or her sole discretion, extend the time for payment for good cause.</text>
        <text>"(b) Registrations shall be renewed annually from date of initial issuance unless there is a change in ownership.</text>
        <text>"(c) The initial registration fee shall be:</text>
        <text>"(1) Twenty dollars for each dwelling unit; and</text>
        <text>"(2) Twenty dollars for each 400 square feet of commercial space or part thereof.</text>
        <text>"(d) The renewal registration fee shall be:</text>
        <text>"(1) One-half of the initial applicable registration fee, if paid within 30 days after the renewal date established by rule;</text>
        <text>"(2) The amount equal to the amount of the applicable initial registration fee, if paid after such 30-day period but before the receipt of notice under § 42- 3131.08;</text>
        <text>"(3) Three times the amount of the applicable initial registration fee, if paid after receipt of the notice under § 42-3131.08."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(e) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Law 16-259, March 8, 2007, law notification 54 DCR 3044).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(e) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Law 17-102, February 2, 2008, law notification 55 DCR 4254).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(e) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-586, December 28, 2006, 54 DCR 353).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(e) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-173, November 2, 2007, 54 DCR 11204).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(e) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-436, July 16, 2008, 55 DCR 8272).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2042(c) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6542).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-281, see notes following § 42-3131.05.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-216, see notes following § 42-3131.05.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-223, see notes following § 42-1904.03.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
