<level type="section">
  <num>42-3131.08</num>
  <heading>Notice of denial or revocation of registration.</heading>
  <text>The owner shall be notified in writing of the denial or revocation of registration of a vacant building and the right to appeal. Upon notice of the denial or revocation, the owner shall not proceed with any operation to which the registration related. If the registration is denied or revoked, no registration fees or parts thereof shall be returned.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 8, as added Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 101, 48 DCR 1888; Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-216, § 3(d), 55 DCR 7500.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-216 rewrote the section which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"A notice of denial or revocation of registration shall be in writing and shall be served upon the owner, or his or her agent. A notice of denial or revocation of registration shall also be posted on the vacant building. Upon receipt or posting of the notice of denial or revocation of registration, a person shall not proceed with any operation to which such registration related. If an initial or renewal registration is denied, or if a registration is revoked during the registration period, no registration fees, or parts thereof, shall be returned to the owner."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Law 16-259, March 8, 2007, law notification 54 DCR 3044).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Law 17-102, February 2, 2008, law notification 55 DCR 4254).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-586, December 28, 2006, 54 DCR 353).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-173, November 2, 2007, 54 DCR 11204).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform and Real Property Classification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-436, July 16, 2008, 55 DCR 8272).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 13-281, see notes following § 42-3131.05.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-216, see notes following § 42-3131.05.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
