<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-506</num>
  <heading>Statute of limitations.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:2A-506</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An action for default under a lease contract, including breach of warranty or indemnity, must be commenced within 4 years after the cause of action accrued. By the original lease contract the parties may reduce the period of limitation to not less than 1 year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A cause of action for default accrues when the act or omission on which the default or breach of warranty is based is or should have been discovered by the aggrieved party, or when the default occurs, whichever is later. A cause of action for indemnity accrues when the act or omission on which the claim for indemnity is based is or should have been discovered by the indemnified party, whichever is later.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an action commenced within the time limited by subsection (a) of this section is so terminated as to leave available a remedy by another action for the same default or breach of warranty or indemnity, the other action may be commenced after the expiration of the time limited and within 6 months after the termination of the first action unless the termination resulted from voluntary discontinuance or from dismissal for failure or neglect to prosecute.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section does not alter the law on tolling of the statute of limitations nor does it apply to causes of action that have accrued before this article becomes effective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, ยง 2(b), 39 DCR 3830.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Uniform Statutory Source:</text> Section 2-725.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Substantially rewritten.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Purposes:</text> Subsection (1) does not incorporate the limitation found in Section 2-725(1) prohibiting the parties from extending the period of limitation. Breach of warranty and indemnity claims often arise in a lease transaction; with the passage of time such claims often diminish or are eliminated. To encourage the parties to commence litigation under these circumstances makes little sense.</text>
      <text>Subsection (2) states two rules for determining when a cause of action accrues. With respect to default, the rule of Section 2-725(2) is not incorporated in favor of a more liberal rule of the later of the date when the default occurs or when the act or omission on which it is based is or should have been discovered. With respect to indemnity, a similarly liberal rule is adopted.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Sections 2-725(1) and 2-725(2).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Action". Section 1-201(1).</text>
        <text>"Aggrieved party". Section 1-201(2).</text>
        <text>"Lease contract". Section 2A-103(1)(l).</text>
        <text>"Party". Section 1-201(29).</text>
        <text>"Remedy". Section 1-201(34).</text>
        <text>"Termination". Section 2A-103(1)(z).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:2A-506.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 28:2A-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
