<level type="section">
  <num>8-1316</num>
  <heading>Identification of major generators of hazardous waste and releasers of toxic chemicals.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days of March 8, 1991, the Mayor shall determine and present to the Council a report that identifies the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Businesses that belong to the 3 largest 3-digit United States Department of Commerce Standard Industrial Classifications ("SICs") of generators of hazardous waste in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Businesses that belong to the 3 largest 3-digit SIC users of toxic chemicals in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Businesses that belong to the 3 largest 3-digit SIC releasers of toxic chemicals in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The top 25% of businesses, including any District or United States government operations, that generate or release the largest amount of hazardous waste or toxic chemicals in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 30 days after the Mayor has presented the report specified in subsection (a) of this section to the Council, the Mayor shall notify in writing each business identified that the business is subject to the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Every 4 years following March 8, 1991, the Mayor shall reassess the findings required by subsection (a) of this section and make any change in the reporting or targeting of technical assistance indicated.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-64, § 18, as added Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-229, title I, § 102(c), 38 DCR 246.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 8-1315 and § 8-1317.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-732.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 8-229</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 8-229, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1315.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
