<level type="section">
  <num>34-2153</num>
  <heading>Eligibility criteria.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for an assistance grant from the Fund, a household must:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have an aggregate income of 60% or less than the area median income for a household of like size in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have a known lead service line.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Grants shall be awarded, to the extent reasonably possible, according to the following priority:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Households with a tap water test that shows a lead level at or above 15 parts per billion and that include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A child under the age of 6 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A pregnant woman; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A woman who is nursing;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Households with a tap water test that shows a lead level below 15 parts per billion and which include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A child under the age of 6 years;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A pregnant woman; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A woman who is nursing; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To all other eligible households.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Grants under this section shall be awarded as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District shall pay 100% of the replacement costs of lead service lines, up to $2,000, for eligible households with incomes of 20% or less of the area median income for a household of like size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District shall pay 80% of the replacement costs of lead service lines, up to $2,000, for eligible households with incomes of 21% to 30% of the area median income for a household of like size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District shall pay 60% of the replacement costs of lead service lines, up to $2,000, for eligible households with incomes of 31% to 40% of the area median income for a household of like size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The District shall pay 50% of the replacement costs of lead service lines, up to $2,000, for eligible households with incomes of 41% to 60% of the area median income for a household of like size.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If funds are not sufficient to pay for the replacement costs of lead service lines for all eligible households under this section, priority shall be given to providing grants to the eligible households with the lowest total income in the priority established under subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 6014, 51 DCR 8441; Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, §§ 23, 57, 53 DCR 6794.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 34-2154.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-191, in subsec. (a)(2), validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6014 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004, 51 DCR 8236).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6014 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004, 51 DCR 11725).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-205</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-205, see notes following § 34-2151.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-191</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-191, see notes following § 34-209.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
