<level type="section">
  <num>7-1703.04</num>
  <heading>No smoking within 25 feet of property signs.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A property owner or ground-floor commercial tenant has the authority to post signs on his or her property stating that smoking is not permitted on public space within a specified distance from and abutting the building wall. That distance shall not be greater than 25 feet or the distance to the far side of the adjacent public sidewalk, if any, whichever is less.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An authorized sidewalk cafe shall not be subject to a no-smoking sign posted pursuant to this section unless the sign has been posted by, or with the consent of, the owner or operator of the sidewalk cafe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The penalties in § 7-1721.06 shall not apply to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 28, 1979, D.C. Law 3-22, § 4d, as added July 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-189, § 2, 57 DCR 3019; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 52(a), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 redesignated D.C. Law 3-22, § 4c as D.C. Law 3-22, § 4d.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-189</heading>
      <text>Law 18-189, the "Prohibition Against Selling Tobacco Products to Minors Amendment Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-431, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 5, 2010, and February 2, 2010, respectively. Enacted without signature by the Mayor on May 11, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-352 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-189 became effective on July 23, 2010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
