<level type="section">
  <num>28-4005</num>
  <heading>Minimal procedures.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28-4005</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each hearing aid sale shall be accompanied by a receipt that includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>the name, address, and signature of the purchaser;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>the date of consummation of the sale;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>the name and address of the regular place of business, the number of the certificate of registration, and the signature of the registrant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>the make, model, serial number, and purchase price of the hearing aid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>a statement as to whether the hearing aid is "new" or "used";</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>the complete terms of the sale, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>an itemization of the total purchase price, including but not limited to the cost of the hearing aid, the earmold, any batteries or other accessories, and any service costs; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>a clear and precise statement of the terms of the trial period and the terms of any guarantee or warranty, including disclosures made pursuant to section 28-4006(a)(3)(H);</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>the title and address of the Office, with a statement that complaints which arise with respect to the transaction may be submitted to the Office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>the original of the written recommendation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>the following statements in ten (10)-point type or larger:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"This hearing aid will not restore normal hearing nor will it prevent further hearing loss";</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"No hearing aid may be sold to you without a prior medical examination"; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>"A return visit to a physician who is an ear specialist or audiologist after the purchase of this aid will help you in best adapting to it"; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>if the hearing aid sold has a telephone option, a statement that the telephone option will not work on all telephones and a statement indicating the types of telephones upon which it will work.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each registrant shall keep records for every customer to whom he or she renders services or sells a hearing aid, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>a copy of the receipt as specified in subsection (a) of this section;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>a record of services provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>any correspondence to or from the customer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>any waiver forms, as provided under section 28-4004(d). Such records shall be preserved for seven (7) years after the date of the transaction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each registrant shall post conspicuously in large print at his or her place(s) of business and make available for inspection at any sale a retail price list showing all hearing aid models for sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 1977, D.C. Law 2-33, § 6, 24 DCR 3726; enacted, Sept. 6, 1980, D.C. Law 3-85, § 3(b), (e), 27 DCR 2900; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(bb), 44 DCR 1271.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28-4005.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., T. 28, Appx., § 56.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-33, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-4001.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-4001.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-255, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28-4001.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
