<level type="section">
  <num>47-2402.01</num>
  <heading>Weight-based excise tax.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to the 12% gross sales tax imposed pursuant to § 47- 2002(6), a tax of $0.75 per ounce and a proportionate tax at the same rate on all fractional parts of an ounce shall be imposed on the possession of other tobacco products as that term is defined in § 47-2001(v-1). All funds generated pursuant to this subparagraph shall be deposited in the Community Health Care Financing Fund, established by [§ 7-1931(a)].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On or before the 21st day of each calendar quarter, every person upon whom the weight-based excise tax is imposed under the provisions of this chapter, during the preceding calendar quarter, shall file a return with the Mayor. The return shall provide:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The total amount of product subject to tax for the quarter for which the return is filed;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of tax for which the person is liable; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other information as the Mayor considers necessary for the computation and collection of the tax.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may permit or require the returns to be made for other periods and upon other dates as he may specify.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The form of returns shall be prescribed by the Mayor and shall contain such information as the Mayor may consider necessary for the proper administration of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 7241(i)(4), 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7241(i)(4) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7241(i)(4) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 47-305.02.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Section 7241(i)(5) of D.C. Law 18-111 provides:</text>
        <text>"(5) This subsection shall apply to tax periods beginning after December 31, 2009."</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
