<level type="section">
  <num>7-2508.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Correctional facility" means any building or group of buildings and concomitant services operated as a single management unit by the Department of Corrections, or a similar federal, state, county, or local government agency, or a contractor to such an agency, for the purpose of housing and providing services to persons ordered confined pending trial or sentencing, or incarcerated following sentencing for a violation of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Gun offender" means a person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Convicted at any time of a gun offense in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Convicted at any time of a gun offense who resides in the District within the registration period established pursuant to § 7-2508.02;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Who has as a mandatory condition of release a registration requirement in the District pursuant to § 7-2508.04(f).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Gun offense" means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A conviction for the sale, purchase, transfer, receipt, acquisition, possession, use, manufacture, carrying, transportation, registration, or licensing of a firearm under Chapter 45 of Title 22 [§ 22-4501 et seq.], or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A conviction for violating § 7-2502.01, § 7-2504.01, § 7-2505.01, or § 7-2506.01, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B-i)</num>
      <text>A conviction for a firearms-related violation of the provisions in section 804 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 22-402) (assault with a dangerous weapon), section 3 of An Act To prohibit the introduction of contraband into the District of Columbia penal institutions, approved December 15, 1941 (55 Stat. 800; D.C. Official Code § 22-2603.02)) (unlawful possession of contraband), or section 811a(b) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, effective May 8, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-270; D.C. Official Code § 22-2803(b)) (carjacking); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Violations in other jurisdictions of any offense with an element that involves the violations listed in subparagraphs (A), (B), or (B-i) of this paragraph.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Resides" means to stay overnight in the District of Columbia for an aggregate period of time exceeding 30 days in any calendar year.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VIII, § 801, as added Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 205, 56 DCR 7413; June 3, 2011, D.C. Law 18-377, § 2(g), 58 DCR 1174; Sept. 29, 2012, D.C. Law 19-170, § 2(r), 59 DCR 5691.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 23-1322.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-377, in pars. (2)(A) and (B), substituted "Convicted at any time" for "Convicted"; in pars. (3)(A) and (B), inserted ", or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses".</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-170 added (3)(B-i); substituted "subparagraphs (A), (B), or (B-i)" for "subparagraph (A) or (B)" in (3)(C); and made a related change.</text>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-170 added (3)(B-i); substituted "subparagraphs (A), (B), or (B-i)" for "subparagraph (A) or (B)" in (3)(C); and made a related change.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 2(a) of D.C. Law 18-255, in pars. (2)(A) and (B), substituted "Convicted at any time" for "Convicted".</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of D.C. Law 18-255 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 205 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009, 56 DCR 8668).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Gun Offender Registration Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-464, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6908).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Gun Offender Registration Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-539, October 5, 2010, 57 DCR 9610).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Gun Offender Registration Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-672, December 28, 2010, 58 DCR 126).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502(g) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-693, January 18, 2011, 58 DCR 640).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 502(g) of Public Safety Legislation Sixty-Day Layover Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-45, April 20, 2011, 58 DCR 3701).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(r) of Firearms Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-352, May 11, 2012, 59 DCR 5116).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(r) of the Firearms Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-394, July 18, 2012, 59 DCR 8694).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of (3), see § 2(r) of the Firearms Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-510, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12808).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-88</heading>
      <text>Law 18-88, the "Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Amendment Act of 2009", as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-151, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The bill as adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 31, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 26, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-189 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-88 became effective on December 10, 2009.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-377</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-377, see notes under § 7-2502.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-170</heading>
      <text>See note to § 7-2501.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
