<level type="section">
  <num>9-307</num>
  <heading>Highway Bridge.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 7-507</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The jurisdiction and control of the Highway Bridge across the Potomac River, including appropriations and employees, shall be under the Mayor of the District of Columbia. The Highway Bridge shall be for highway traffic. The entire cost of paving, repairs, or replacements incident to track repairs, replacements, or changes made at a time when the bridge is not being paved, and one-half the cost of other paving, repaving, or maintenance of paving between its track and for 2 feet outside the outer rails, and the excess cost of construction and maintenance of the bridge due to the existence or installation of its tracks thereon shall be paid by the street railway company or companies using the same under such regulations as the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall prescribe; provided, that all street railroads chartered or that may hereafter be chartered by Congress shall have the right to cross said bridge upon terms mutually agreed upon with the Washington, Alexandria, and Mount Vernon Railway Company or in case of disagreement, upon terms determined by the United States District Court for the District of Columbia which is authorized and directed to give hearing to the interested parties and to fix the terms of joint trackage.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 12, 1901, 31 Stat. 773, ch. 353, § 12; July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 598, ch. 1352; Feb. 22, 1921, 41 Stat. 1117, ch. 70, § 1; Jan. 14, 1933, 47 Stat. 759, ch. 10, § 3; June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804; June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b); May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 7-507.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 7-507.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Change in Government</heading>
        <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Replacement of Highway Bridge: See Act of October 4, 1966, 80 Stat. 875, Pub. L. 89-627.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
