<level type="section">
  <num>29-807.05</num>
  <heading>Distribution of assets in winding up limited liability company's activities and affairs.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In winding up its activities and affairs, a limited liability company shall apply its assets to discharge its obligations to creditors, including members that are creditors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After a limited liability company complies with subsection (a) of this section, any surplus shall be distributed in the following order, subject to any charging order in effect under § 29-805.03:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To each person owning a transferable interest that reflects contributions made by a member and not previously returned, an amount equal to the value of the unreturned contributions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In equal shares among members and dissociated members, except to the extent necessary to comply with any transfer effective under § 29-805.02.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a limited liability company does not have sufficient surplus to comply with subsection (b)(1) of this section, any surplus must be distributed among the owners of transferable interests in proportion to the value of their respective unreturned contributions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All distributions made under subsections (b) and (c) of this section must be paid in money.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(8)(D), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-804.04 and § 29-804.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "activities and affairs" for "activities" in the section heading and in (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-801.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 705 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
