<level type="section">
  <num>29-807.02</num>
  <heading>Winding up.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved limited liability company shall wind up its activities and affairs, and, except as otherwise provided in § 29-807.06, shall continue after dissolution only for the purpose of winding up.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In winding up its activities and affairs, a limited liability company:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Discharge the company's debts, obligations, or other liabilities, settle and close the company's activities and affairs, and marshal and distribute the assets of the company; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of dissolution stating the name of the company and that the company is dissolved; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>May:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Preserve the company activities and affairs and property as a going concern for a reasonable time;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prosecute and defend actions and proceedings, whether civil, criminal, or administrative;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Transfer the company's property;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Settle disputes by mediation or arbitration;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of termination stating the name of the company and that the company is terminated; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Perform other acts necessary or appropriate to the winding up.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a dissolved limited liability company has no members, the legal representative of the last person to have been a member may wind up the activities and affairs of the company. If the person does so, the person shall have the powers of a sole manager under § 29-804.07(c) and shall be deemed to be a manager for the purposes of § 29-803.04(a)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the legal representative under subsection (c) of this section declines or fails to wind up the company's activities and affairs, a person may be appointed to do so by the consent of transferees owning a majority of the rights to receive distributions as transferees at the time the consent is to be effective. A person appointed under this subsection:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has the powers of a sole manager under § 29-804.07(c) and shall be deemed to be a manager for the purposes of § 29-803.04(a)(2); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall promptly deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment to the company's certificate of organization to:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>State that the company has no members;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>State that the person has been appointed pursuant to this subsection to wind up the company; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provide the street and mailing addresses of the person.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may order judicial supervision of the winding up of a dissolved limited liability company, including the appointment of a person to wind up the company's activities and affairs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On application of a member, if the applicant establishes good cause;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On the application of a transferee, if:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The company does not have any members;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The legal representative of the last person to have been a member declines or fails to wind up the company's activities and affairs; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Within a reasonable time following the dissolution a person has not been appointed pursuant to subsection (d) of this section; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In connection with a proceeding under § 29-807.01(a)(4) or (5).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(h)(8)(B), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-801.03, § 29-801.07, and § 29-802.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "activities and affairs" for "activities" throughout the section; and substituted "except as otherwise provided in § 29-807.06, shall continue" for "the company shall continue" in (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-801.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 702 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
