<level type="section">
  <num>29-807.01</num>
  <heading>Events causing dissolution.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited liability company is dissolved, and its activities shall be wound up, upon the occurrence of any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An event or circumstance that the operating agreement states causes dissolution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The consent of all the members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The passage of 90 consecutive days during which the company has no members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>On application by a member, the entry by Superior Court of an order dissolving the company on the grounds that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The conduct of all or substantially all of the company's activities is unlawful; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>It is not reasonably practicable to carry on the company's activities in conformity with the certificate of organization and the operating agreement; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>On application by a member, the entry by Superior Court of an order dissolving the company on the grounds that the managers or those members in control of the company:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Have acted, are acting, or will act in a manner that is illegal or fraudulent; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have acted or are acting in a manner that is oppressive and was, is, or will be directly harmful to the applicant.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In a proceeding brought under subsection (a)(5) of this section, the Superior Court may order a remedy other than dissolution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 701 of the Uniform Limited Company Act (2006 Act). See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
