<level type="section">
  <num>29-1205.09</num>
  <heading>Indemnification, advancement, and exoneration.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A statutory trust may indemnify and hold harmless a trustee, beneficial owner, or other person with respect to any claim or demand against the person by reason of the person's relationship with the trust if the claim or demand does not arise from the person's bad faith, willful misconduct, or reckless indifference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Expenses, including reasonable attorneys' fees and costs, incurred by a trustee, beneficial owner, or other person in connection with a claim or demand against the person by reason of the person's relationship to a statutory trust may be paid by the trust before the final disposition of the claim or demand, upon an undertaking by or on behalf of the person to repay the trust if the person is ultimately determined not to be entitled to be indemnified under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A term in the governing instrument relieving or exonerating a trustee from liability is unenforceable to the extent it relieves or exonerates the trustee from liability for conduct involving bad faith, willful misconduct, or reckless indifference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 509 of the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act . See Vol. 6B , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
