<level type="section">
  <num>5-1302</num>
  <heading>Service in Armed Forces - Seniority rights.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, who served in the Armed Forces of the United States during the period beginning May 1, 1940, and ending December 31, 1946, and: (1) whose name appeared during such service (as a result of a regular or reopened competitive examination for promotion) on any civil service register with respect to such force or Department for promotion to a higher rank or grade; or (2) whose name appeared on such a register as a result of a reopened examination taken subsequent to his release, shall, for the purpose of determining his seniority rights and service in such rank or grade, be held to have been promoted to such rank or grade as of the earliest date on which an eligible standing lower on the same promotion register received a promotion either permanently or temporarily to such rank or grade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia shall be entitled to the benefits of this section who has reenlisted after June 1, 1945, in the Regular Army or Air Force or after February 1, 1945, in the Regular Navy.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 1, 1947, 61 Stat. 240, ch. 193, § 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Merit system, application to police officers and firefighters, see § 1-632.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-632.03 and § 5-1303.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 4-1102.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 4-902.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
