<level type="section">
  <num>1-181</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Emancipation Day Parade" means the parade, and associated activities, including the provision of food, snacks, entertainment, and non-alcoholic beverages to the general public, participants, and District government employees, held to celebrate and commemorate District of Columbia Emancipation Day.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Fund" means the Emancipation Day Fund.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-240, § 2, 51 DCR 11225; Feb.27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-110, § 2(a), 55 DCR 223.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-110, in par. (1), substituted "activities, including the provision of food, snacks, entertainment, and non-alcoholic beverages to the general public, participants, and District government employees, held to celebrate" for "activities, held to celebrate".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Fund Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-125, May 2, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 4400).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Emancipation Day Fund Temporary Act of 2003 (D.C. Law 15-9, June 5, 2003, law notification 50 DCR 4873).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Temporary Act of 2004 (D.C. Law 15-138, April 22, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 4922).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Fund Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-263, January 30, 2002, 49 DCR 1443).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Emancipation Day Fund Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-17, February 25, 2003, 50 DCR 1948).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-343, January 29, 2004, 51 DCR 1827).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-660, December 29, 2004, 52 DCR 797).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-61, March 17, 2005, 52 DCR 3197).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 15-240, the "District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Act of 2004", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-670, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 2004, and November 9, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 30, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-597 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-240 became effective on March 16, 2005.</text>
        <text>Law 17-110, the "District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade Clarification Amendment Act of 2007", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-187 which was referred to the Committee on Workforce Development and Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 6, 2007, and December 11, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 27, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-228 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-110 became effective on February 27, 2008.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
