<level type="section">
  <num>1-183</num>
  <heading>Emancipation Day Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Emancipation Day Fund ("Fund") to receive monies for the purposes of funding the Emancipation Day Parade and activities associated with the celebration and commemoration of District of Columbia Emancipation Day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The monies in the Fund shall not be a part of, or lapse into, the General Fund of the District of Columbia or any other fund of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>By August 1st of each year, the Secretary of the District of Columbia shall submit a report to the Council that shall include a specific accounting of the expenditure of money in the Fund and any remaining balance. The report shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of any donors or list of anonymous contributions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of each contribution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of any donated property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of the use of monies for presenting the Emancipation Day Parade; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Costs of parade-related programs, activities, purchases, and functions for which the money have been expended.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Monies shall only be expended from the Fund for the administration of the Emancipation Day Parade. A minimum of 15% of the monies in the Fund shall be used to purchase and provide educational materials. The Fund may be used to purchase food, snacks, entertainment, and non-alcoholic beverages for the general public, participants, and District government employees to celebrate Emancipation Day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-240, § 4, 51 DCR 11225; Feb.27, 2008, D.C. Law 17-110, § 2(b), 55 DCR 223.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-110, in subsec. (c)(5), substituted "activities, purchases, and functions" for "activities, and functions"; and, in subsec. (d) added the second and third sentences.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Fund Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-125, May 2, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 4400).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of Emancipation Day Fund Temporary Act of 2003 (D.C. Law 15-9, June 5, 2003, law notification 50 DCR 4873).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Temporary Act of 2004 (D.C. Law 15-138, April 22, 2004, law notification 51 DCR 4922).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Fund Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-263, January 30, 2002, 49 DCR 1443).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Emancipation Day Fund Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-17, February 25, 2003, 50 DCR 1948).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-343, January 29, 2004, 51 DCR 1827).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) use of prior budgeted reserve funds for Emancipation Day activities, see § 2 of Emancipation Day Reserve Fund Allocation Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-641, November 30, 2004, 52 DCR 1261).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of District of Columbia Emancipation Day Parade and Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-660, December 29, 2004, 52 DCR 797).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 15-240, see notes following § 1-181.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-110, see notes following § 1-181.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
