<level type="section">
  <num>29-710.08</num>
  <heading>Power of general partners and persons dissociated as general partners to bind limited partnership after merger.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An act of a person that immediately before a merger became effective was a general partner in a constituent limited partnership shall bind the surviving limited partnership after the merger becomes effective if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before the merger became effective, the act would have bound the constituent limited partnership under § 29-704.02; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the time the third party enters into the transaction, the third party:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Does not have notice of the merger; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reasonably believes that the surviving business is the constituent limited partnership and that the person is a general partner in the constituent limited partnership.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An act of a person that before a merger became effective was dissociated as a general partner from a constituent limited partnership shall bind the surviving limited partnership after the merger becomes effective if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before the merger became effective, the act would have bound the constituent limited partnership under § 29-704.02 if the person had been a general partner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the time the third party enters into the transaction, less than 2 years have passed since the person dissociated as a general partner and the third party:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Does not have notice of the dissociation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Does not have notice of the merger; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Reasonably believes that the surviving limited partnership is the constituent limited partnership and that the person is a general partner in the constituent limited partnership.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a person having knowledge of the merger causes a surviving limited partnership to incur an obligation under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the person shall be liable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To the surviving limited partnership for any damage caused to the surviving limited partnership arising from the obligation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If another person is liable for the obligation, to that other person for any damage caused to that other person arising from that liability.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 1112 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
