<level type="section">
  <num>2-1226.33</num>
  <heading>Applicability of part.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This part shall apply to all new construction and substantial improvement projects located within the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone, as defined in § 2-1226.04:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That are District-owned or District instrumentality-owned;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Where at least 15% of a project's total cost is District-financed or District instrumentality-financed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That include a gift, lease, or sale from District-owned or District instrumentality-owned property to a private entity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The requirements of § 2-1226.36 shall not apply to projects which, as of October 23, 2012, have:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applied for a first building permit; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submitted a complete stormwater management plan to DDOE.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 453, 55 DCR 1689; Oct. 23, 2012, D.C. Law 19-192, § 2(c), 59 DCR 10174.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-192 rewrote the section, which formerly read:</text>
        <text>"(a) This part shall apply as follows:</text>
        <text>"(1) To development projects located within the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone as defined in § 2-1226.04; and</text>
        <text>"(2) To publicly-owned or publicly-financed non-residential and residential new construction or substantial improvement projects, which are:</text>
        <text>"(A) Initially funded in the Fiscal Year 2008 budget or later; or</text>
        <text>"(B) Constructed or substantially improved:</text>
        <text>"(i) As a result of a property disposition by lease or sale where District-owned or District instrumentality-owned property is leased or sold to private entities; or</text>
        <text>"(ii) Where 15% or more of a project's total project cost is publicly financed in Fiscal Year 2009 or later.</text>
        <text>"(b) The requirements set forth in §§ 2-1226.34, 2-1226.35, 2-1226.37, and 2- 1226.38 shall apply to publicly-owned or publicly-financed projects beginning on March 26, 2008.</text>
        <text>"(c) The requirements set forth in § 2-1226.36 shall apply to publicly-owned or publicly-financed projects beginning on the effective date of rules issued by the Mayor to implement § 2-1226.36.</text>
        <text>"(d) The requirements set forth in §§ 2-1226.34, 2-1226.35, and 2-1226.37 shall apply to private projects beginning with projects for which the first building construction permit application is submitted to the Mayor after January 1, 2012."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-138, see notes following § 2-1226.31.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-192, see notes under § 2-1226.04.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
