<level type="section">
  <num>29-608.05</num>
  <heading>Statement of dissolution.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 41-158.5</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 33-108.05</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After dissolution, a partner that has not wrongfully dissociated may file a statement of dissolution stating the name of the partnership and that the partnership has dissolved and is winding up its business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A statement of dissolution shall cancel a filed statement of partnership authority for the purposes of § 29-603.03(d) and shall be a limitation on authority for the purposes of § 29-603.03(e).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of §§ 29-603.01 and 29-608.04, a person not a partner shall be deemed to have notice of the dissolution and the limitation on the partners' authority as a result of the statement of dissolution 90 days after it is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After filing and, if appropriate, recording a statement of dissolution, a dissolved partnership may file and, if appropriate, record a statement of partnership authority which will operate with respect to a person not a partner as provided in § 29-603.03(d) and (e) in any transaction, whether or not the transaction is appropriate for winding up the partnership business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 41-158.5.</text>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 33-108.05.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 805 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act). See Vol. 6, Part I , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
