<level type="section">
  <num>29-608.03</num>
  <heading>Right to wind up partnership business.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 41-158.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 2001 § 33-108.03</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After dissolution, a partner that has not wrongfully dissociated may participate in winding up the partnership's business, but on application of any partner, partner's legal representative, or transferee, the Superior Court, for good cause shown, may order judicial supervision of the winding up.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The legal representative of the last surviving partner may wind up a partnership's business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person winding up a partnership's business may preserve the partnership business or property as a going concern for a reasonable time, prosecute and defend actions and proceedings, whether civil, criminal, or administrative, settle and close the partnership's business, dispose of and transfer the partnership's property, discharge the partnership's liabilities, distribute the assets of the partnership pursuant to § 29-608.07, settle disputes by mediation or arbitration, and perform other necessary acts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 41-158.3.</text>
        <text>2001 Ed., § 33-108.03.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on § 803 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act). See Vol. 6, Part I , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
