<level type="section">
  <num>29-608.05</num>
  <heading>Statement of dissolution.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After dissolution, a partner that has not wrongfully dissociated may file a statement of dissolution stating the name of the partnership and that the partnership has dissolved and is winding up its activities and affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A statement of dissolution shall cancel a filed statement of partnership authority for the purposes of § 29-603.03(d) and shall be a limitation on authority for the purposes of § 29-603.03(e).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of §§ 29-603.01 and 29-608.04, a person not a partner shall be deemed to have notice of the dissolution and the limitation on the partners' authority as a result of the statement of dissolution 90 days after it is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After filing and, if appropriate, recording a statement of dissolution, a dissolved partnership may file and, if appropriate, record a statement of partnership authority which will operate with respect to a person not a partner as provided in § 29-603.03(d) and (e) in any transaction, whether or not the transaction is appropriate for winding up the partnership activities and affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(f)(8)(F), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-601.03, § 29-603.03, and § 29-608.04.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 41-158.5.</text>
      <text>2001 Ed., § 33-108.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "activities and affairs" for "business" in (a) and (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-601.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 805 of the Uniform Partnership Act (1997 Act).</text>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
