<level type="section">
  <num>47-848</num>
  <heading>Sale of tax delinquent property - Transference of ownership.</heading>
  <text>The Council is hereby authorized to establish a program whereby title to properties acquired by tax sale pursuant to §§ 47-847 and 47-1303 may, for whatever consideration or sum it deems appropriate, be transferred to persons, nonprofit organizations or nonprofit developers, meeting criteria which shall be established by the Council, and who:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Guarantee to pay taxes on the property;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Live in the property for at least 5 years (for residential property owners), or maintain active ownership and legal possession of the property for at least 10 years and provide needed community services in the District for at least 10 years (for nonprofit organizations or developers); and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Give assurance of bringing the property into reasonable compliance with the building code in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1059, Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 438; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; June 11, 1999, D.C. Law 13-11, § 3(b), 46 DCR 5487; June 12, 2003, D.C. Law 14-310, § 14(b), 50 DCR 1092.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Financial institutions, application to conduct business, loan policies and homestead development programs, see § 26-704.</text>
      <text>Savings and loan association acquisitions, applications, loan policies and homestead development programs, see § 26-1204.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 26-704 and § 26-1204.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-848.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 47-658.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-11 provided alternatively to living on the property for 5 years that one "maintain active ownership and legal possession of the property for at least 10 years and provide needed community services in the District for at least 10 years (for nonprofit organizations or developers)."</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 14-310, in the introductory paragraph, substituted "§§ 47-847 and 47-1303" for "§ 47-847".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Homestead Housing Preservation Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-245, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 4158).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3 of the Homestead Housing Preservation Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-556, January 12, 1999, 45 DCR 625).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(b) of the Homestead Housing Preservation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-62, May 10, 1999, 46 DCR 4454).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 3(d)(1) and 6(b) of the Redevelopment Land Agency Disposition Review Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-524, January 11, 2001, 48 DCR 624).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-11</heading>
      <text>Law 13-11, the "Homestead Housing Preservation Amendment Act of 1999," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-50, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 2, 1999, and March 2, 1999, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 22, 1999, it was assigned Act No. 13-48 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-11 became effective on June 11, 1999.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-310</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-310, see notes following § 47-365.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
