<level type="section">
  <num>47-825.03</num>
  <heading>Applicability of certain provisions; hearings open to public.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-825.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, § 47-825.01(d)(5), the second sentence of § 47-825.01(e), and § 47-825.02 shall not apply until the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the implementation of those provisions will have no negative fiscal impact on the Office of Tax and Revenue, the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia, or on real property tax revenues collected by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 47-821(d)(2), hearings shall be open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall expire upon notice to the Council by the Chief Financial Officer that he or she has made the determination required by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-236, § 2(a), 46 DCR 660; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-363, § 3(g)(6), 58 DCR 963.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-825.3.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-363, in subsec. (a), substituted "Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia" for "Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Real Property Tax Reassessment Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-125, June 10, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 5883).</text>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2(a) of Real Property Tax Assessment and Cold Weather Eviction Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Law 13-1, April 20, 1999, law notification 46 DCR 5301).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 12-236, the "Drug Prevention and Children at Risk Tax Check-Off, Tax Initiative Delay, and Attorney License Fee Act of 1998," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-706, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-561 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-236 became effective on April 20, 1999.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-363, see notes under § 47-412.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
