<level type="section">
  <num>47-859.01</num>
  <heading>Tax abatements for new residential developments in NoMA - Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of §§ 47-859.01 through 47-859.05, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Eligible Area" means those portions of Wards 5 and 6 which comprise the geographic area defined by a line that starts at the center of the street at the intersection of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E., and 1st Street, N.E.; continuing north along the center line of 1st Street, N.E., to the center line of H Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of H Street, N.E., to the center line of 2nd Street, N.E.; continuing north along the center line of 2nd Street, N.E., to the center line of K Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of K Street, N.E., to the center line of 3rd Street, N.E.; continuing north along the center line of 3rd Street, N.E. (and including Lot 0058, Square 0774), to the center line of M Street, N.E.; continuing east along the center line of M Street, N.E., to 4th Street, N.E.; continuing along the center line of 4th Street, N.E., to the center line of Florida Avenue, N.E.; continuing northwest along the center line of Florida Avenue, N.E., until it crosses the WMATA rail line; continuing northeast along the boundary of the WMATA rail line until it crosses R Street, N.E.; continuing west along the center line of R Street, N.E., to Eckington Place, N.E.; continuing south along the center line of Eckington Place, N.E., to the center line of Q Street, N.E.; continuing west along the center line of Q Street, N.E. (and including Lots 0043, 0063, and 0070, Square 3519), to the center line of North Capitol Street (but excluding Lots 0104 through 0114, 0118 through 0133, and 0807, Square 3516,); continuing south along the center line of North Capitol Street to the center line of Eye Street, N.W.; continuing west along the center line of Eye Street, N.W., to the center line of New Jersey Avenue, N.W.; continuing southeast along the center line of New Jersey Avenue, N.W., to the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., continuing southeast along Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., to the center line of 1st Street, N.E. (the starting point).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Eligible Real Property" means real property that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is located in an Eligible Area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is classified, in whole or in part, as Class 1 or Class 2 property under § 47-813(c-6);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is improved by a new structure or by a previously uninhabitable structure which undergoes substantial renovation for residential use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Has 10 or more units devoted to residential use.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 7, 2009, D.C. Law 18-10, § 2(b), 56 DCR 3598.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-857.09a, § 47-859.04a, and § 47-859.05.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of D.C. Act 18-54, see § 7034 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of D.C. Act 18-54, see § 7034 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-10</heading>
      <text>Law 18-10, the "NoMA Residential Development Tax Abatement Act of 2009", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-18 which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 17, 2009, and April 7, 2009, respectively. Approved without the signature of the Mayor on April 29, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-54 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-10 became effective on July 7, 2009.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <text>Delegation of Authority Pursuant to D.C. Law 18-10, the NOMA Residential Development Tax Abatement Act of 2009, see Mayor's Order 2010-111, July 9, 2010 (57 DCR 5997).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of D.C. Law 18-10 provided that this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <text>Section 7034 of D.C. Law 18-111 repealed section 3 of D.C. Law 18-10.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
