<level type="section">
  <num>39-304</num>
  <heading>Board of Directors--Established; composition; term of office; nonvoting ex officio members.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 31-2104</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A self-perpetuating Board of Directors is established to manage the affairs of the Museum. The Board shall have a minimum of 10 and a maximum of 23 members. Members of the Board shall include representatives of various geographical areas of the City, business people, and community leaders known for their interest in the arts, culture, and humanities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each member of the initial Board, as established by this chapter, shall serve a term of 1 year. A successor Board shall be established according to the requirements of this chapter and those bylaws adopted by the initial Board. Each member of a successor Board shall serve a 3-year term.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The initial Board shall have a minimum of 10 members and shall be composed at a minimum of the following individuals:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Ms. Leslie Buhler;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ms. Charlotte Chapman;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ms. Marcia Greenlee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Mr. Earl James;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Mr. Leroi Johnson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Mr. Tom Lodge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Ms. Betty Monkman;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Mr. Harris Snettel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Dr. Frank Taylor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Dr. James Walker.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The initial Board shall appoint such additional or replacement members up to a maximum of 23 individuals, so that the initial Board meets the representational requirements of subsection (a) of this section. The members shall be appointed according to the bylaws adopted by the Board members listed in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The following individuals shall be nonvoting ex officio members of the initial Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Dr. John Kinard, Anacostia Neighborhood Museum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Dr. Phillip Ogilvie, D.C. Foundation for Creative Space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Mr. William H. Press, Columbia Historical Society;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Mr. Fred Schwengel, J.S. Capitol Historical Society;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Dr. Michael R. Winston, Moorland-Spingarn Research Center and Museum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Mr. Don Wolpe, Jewish Historical Society;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Martin Luther King Library representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Ms. Marion Dockery, Cultural Alliance of Greater Washington; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Ms. Cathy Smith, D.C. Public Schools.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 26, 1980, D.C. Law 3-79, ยง 5, 27 DCR 2546.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 31-2104.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-79, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 39-301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
