<level type="section">
  <num>47-2887.13</num>
  <heading>Prohibited conduct.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An athlete agent, with the intent to induce a student-athlete to enter into an agency contract, may not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Give any materially false or misleading information or make a materially false promise or representation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Furnish anything of value to a student-athlete before the student-athlete enters into the agency contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Furnish anything of value to any individual other than the student-athlete or another registered athlete agent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An athlete agent may not intentionally:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Initiate contact with a student-athlete unless registered under this part;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Refuse or fail to retain or permit inspection of the records required to be retained by § 47-2887.12;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fail to register when required by § 47-2887.03;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide materially false or misleading information in an application for registration or renewal of registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Predate or postdate an agency contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Fail to notify a student-athlete before the student-athlete signs or otherwise authenticates an agency contract for a particular sport that the signing or authentication may make the student-athlete ineligible to participate as a student-athlete in that sport.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 13, 2002, D.C. Law 14-107, § 3, 49 DCR 1193).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-2887.05 and § 47-2887.14.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-107</heading>
      <text>For D.C. Law 14-107, see notes following § 47-2887.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 14 of the Uniform Athlete Agents Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
