<level type="section">
  <num>29-309.06</num>
  <heading>Articles of merger or share exchange.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After a plan of merger or a plan of share exchange involving a domestic acquired corporation has been adopted and approved as required by this chapter, articles of merger or share exchange shall be signed on behalf of each party to the merger or the acquired corporation in the share exchange by any officer or other duly authorized representative. The articles shall set forth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The names of the parties to the merger or share exchange;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the articles of incorporation of the survivor of a merger are amended, or if a new corporation is created as a result of a merger, the amendments to the survivor's articles of incorporation or the articles of incorporation of the new corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the plan of merger or share exchange required approval by the shareholders of a domestic corporation that was a party to the merger or share exchange, a statement that the plan was duly approved by the shareholders and, if voting by any separate voting group was required, by each such separate voting group, in the manner required by this chapter and the articles of incorporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the plan of merger or share exchange did not require approval by the shareholders of a domestic corporation that was a party to the merger or share exchange, a statement to that effect; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>As to each foreign corporation that was a party to the merger or share exchange, a statement that the participation of the foreign corporation was duly authorized as required by the laws of the foreign jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Articles of merger or share exchange shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing by the survivor of the merger or the acquiring corporation in a share exchange and shall be effective at the effective time provided in § 29-102.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720; Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(c)(24), 59 DCR 13171.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-210 substituted "signed" for "executed" in (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-210</heading>
      <text>See note to § 29-301.03.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of D.C. Law 19-210 provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
