<level type="placeholder">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <section>3-801</section>
  <heading>Created; composition; duties; Chairman; meetings.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 101, ch. 159, § 401; July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1; July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a), 157(f); June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 513, 60 DCR 3390.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 2-1001.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 2-1901.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary repeal of section, see § 514 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1017).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-320</heading>
      <text>Law 19-320, the "Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-645. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 11, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-677 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-320 became effective on June 19, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>The Act of October 17, 1968, Pub. L. 90-578, terminated the office of United States Commissioner and established in place thereof the office of United States Magistrate, referred to in subsection (b)(6) of this section. The Act became operative in the District on June 27, 1969, when 2 United States Magistrates assumed office pursuant to appointment by order of the District Court, dated June 20, 1969.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
