<level type="section">
  <num>7-736.01</num>
  <heading>Grant authority.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For fiscal year 2010, the Director of the Department of Health shall have the authority to issue grants to qualified community organizations for the purposes of conducting health promotion, preventing disease, and providing health services; provided, that any grant in excess of $250,000 shall be awarded through a competitive process unless otherwise authorized under law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department of Health shall submit a quarterly report to the Council on all grants issued pursuant to the authority granted in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For fiscal year 2014, the Director of the Department of Health shall have the authority to issue grants to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Qualified community organizations for the purpose of providing the following services:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Ambulatory health services for an amount not to exceed $3,236,980;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Poison control hotline and prevention education services for an amount not to exceed $350,000; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Operations and primary care services for school-based health clinics for an amount not to exceed $2,250,000; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Organizations for the purpose of providing the following programs and services:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A teen pregnancy prevention program for an amount not to exceed $400,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Programs designed to promote healthy development in girls attending public and chartered schools in grades 9 through 12 located in areas of the city possessing the highest rates of teen pregnancy and highest enrollment in state-funded health programs in the District of Columbia, not to exceed $400,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Farmers market incentive programs, not to exceed $200,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Food-pantry services, not to exceed $52,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Wildlife rehabilitation services, not to exceed $250,000;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Mother-to-child (vertical) HIV transmission programs and services, not to exceed $50,000; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Nonprofit organizations dedicated to preventing any of the following chronic diseases, not to exceed $850,000:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Asthma;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Cancer;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Diabetes;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Hypertension;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Kidney disease; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Obesity.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All grants issued pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ 1-328.11 et seq.].</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Health shall submit a quarterly report to the Secretary to the Council on all grants issued pursuant to the authority granted in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4907a, as added Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 5011, 57 DCR 181; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5062, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 added (c) and (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of D.C. Law 18-304 amended subsec. (a) to read as follows: "(a) For fiscal years 2011 through 2014, the Director of the Department of Health shall have the authority to issue grants to Unity Health Care, Incorporated, for the purposes of conducting health promotion, preventing disease, and providing health-care services."; and repealed subsec. (b).</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of D.C. Law 18-304 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      <text>Section 2 of D.C. Law 19-197 added subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
      <text>"(c)(1) For fiscal year 2012, the Director of the Department of Health shall have the authority to issue grants to existing District of Columbia HIV prevention programs in the amount of $331,000 for a combination of HIV prevention interventions that include HIV screening in clinical and non-clinical settings, as well as effective behavioral approaches critical in the fight against HIV/AIDS and, through fiscal year 2014, HIV prevention grants in the amount of $1.2 million for a combination of HIV prevention interventions that include:</text>
      <text>"(A) HIV screening;</text>
      <text>"(B) Harm reduction;</text>
      <text>"(C) Social network HIV screening;</text>
      <text>"(D) Partner services;</text>
      <text>"(E) Faith-based initiatives;</text>
      <text>"(F) Youth peer education; and</text>
      <text>"(G) Other health-education services for adolescents and older adults.</text>
      <text>"(2) For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <text>"(A) 'AIDS' means acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</text>
      <text>"(B) 'Faith-based initiative' means a program to engage places of worship in delivering HIV prevention messages that promote safe-sex practices, educate people about HIV, and promote HIV screening.</text>
      <text>"(C) 'Harm reduction' means a model of behavior change that proposes an incremental approach to reduce the harm posed by certain behavior that can be applied to substance abuse or HIV.</text>
      <text>"(D) 'HIV' means human immunodeficiency virus.</text>
      <text>"(E) 'Partner services' means public-health intervention performed by disease- intervention specialists who follow up with a person newly diagnosed with a sexually transmitted disease to share information on persons who may have been exposed to the same infection with which the patient has been diagnosed."</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of D.C. Law 19-197 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Department of Health Grant-Making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-10, July 13, 2013, 60 DCR 7234, 20 DCSTAT 1755).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Department of Health Grant-Making Authority for Clinical Nutritional Home Services Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Law 20-70, February 22, 2014, 61 DCR 24).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5011 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5011 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Department of Health Functions Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-601, November 17, 2010, 57 DCR 11037).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Department of Health Functions Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-258, December 21, 2011, 58 DCR 11226).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Department of Health Functions Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-391, July 13, 2012, 59 DCR 8501).</text>
      <text>For temporary addition of (c), see § 2 of (D.C. Act 19-503, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12759), applicable October 11, 2012.</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Dept. of Health Grant Making Authority Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-53, April 17, 2013, 60 DCR 6386, 20 DCSTAT 1401).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5062 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 5062 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Department of Health Grant-Making Authority for Clinical Nutritional Home Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-217, November 20, 2013, 60 DCR 16524, 20 STAT 2607).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-111</heading>
      <text>Law 18-111, the "Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-203, which was referred to the Committee on the Whole. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 12, 2009, and September 22, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 18, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-255 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-111 became effective on March 3, 2010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 5010 of D.C. Law 18-111 provided that subtitle B of title V of the act may be cited as the "Department of Health Grant Authority Amendment Act of 2009".</text>
      <text>Section 5061 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle G of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Department of Health Functions Clarification Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
