<level type="section">
  <num>7-245</num>
  <heading>Civil penalties for unlawful use or disclosure.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person who negligently uses or discloses health and human services information in a manner not authorized by this chapter or other District law shall be liable in an amount of $500 for each violation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "negligently" means that a person guided by ordinary considerations should have known, and by exercising reasonable diligence would have known, that the use or disclosure was not authorized.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person who willfully uses or discloses health and human services information in a manner not authorized by this chapter or other District law shall be liable in an amount of $1,000 for each violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to disclosures of information authorized pursuant to other District law or to federal law.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 4, 2010, D.C. Law 18-273, § 105, 57 DCR 7171; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 53(a), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 105 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-530, August 6, 2010, 57 DCR 8099).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 105 of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-582, October 20, 2010, 57 DCR 10118).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 211(b) of Data-Sharing and Information Coordination Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-582, October 20, 2010, 57 DCR 10118).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-273</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-273, see notes following § 7-241.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>See note to § 7-242.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
