<level type="section">
  <num>19-1303.03</num>
  <heading>Representation by fiduciaries and parents.</heading>
  <text>To the extent there is no conflict of interest between the representative and the person represented or among those being represented with respect to a particular question or dispute:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A conservator may represent and bind the estate that the conservator controls;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A guardian may represent and bind the ward if a conservator of the ward's estate has not been appointed;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>An agent having authority to act with respect to the particular question or dispute may represent and bind the principal;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A trustee may represent and bind the beneficiaries of the trust;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>A personal representative of a decedent's estate may represent and bind persons interested in the estate;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>A parent may represent and bind the parent's minor or unborn child if a conservator or guardian for the child has not been appointed;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>An individual may represent a grandchild or a more remote descendent, whether born or unborn, whom a parent may not represent and bind under paragraph (6) of this subsection; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>A qualified beneficiary may represent and bind any beneficiary who may succeed to the qualified beneficiary's interest under the terms of the trust or pursuant to the exercise of a power of appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-104, § 2(b), 51 DCR 208.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-104</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-104, see notes following § 19-1301.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 303 of the Uniform Trust Code.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
