<level type="section">
  <num>25-333</num>
  <heading>Limitation on the distance between off-premises retailer's licenses.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No new off-premises retailers license, class A, shall be issued for an establishment which is located within 400 feet from another establishment operating under an off-premises retailer's license, class A.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No new off-premises retailers license, class B, shall be issued for an establishment which is located within 400 feet from another establishment operating under an off-premises retailer's license, class B.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not prohibit the issuance of a license for an off-premises retailer's license, Class B, for the sale of alcoholic beverages in an establishment if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The primary business and purpose is the sale of a full range of fresh, canned, and frozen food items, and the sale of alcoholic beverages is incidental to the primary purpose;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sale of alcoholic beverages constitutes no more than 15% of the total volume of gross receipts on an annual basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The establishment is located in a C-1, C-2, C-3, C-4, or C-5 zone or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The establishment is a full service grocery store which is newly constructed with a certificate of occupancy issued after January 1, 2000, or is an existing store which has undergone renovations in excess of $500,000 in the calendar year in which an application is made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The opinion of the ANC, if any, has been given great weight.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959; Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(m), 51 DCR 6525; Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-23, § 2(f), 58 DCR 6509.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-298 amended and enacted into law Title 25 of the District of Columbia Official Code.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-187 rewrote par. (5) of subsec. (c) which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(5) The opinion of the ANC in which the establishment is located has been given great weight as specified in Chapter 4."</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 19-23, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted "or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;" for a semicolon.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>Section 2(f) of D.C. Law 18-346, in subsec. (c)(3), substituted "or, if located within the Southeast Federal Center, in the SEFC/C-R zone;" for a semicolon at the end.</text>
        <text>Section 4(b) of D.C. Law 18-346 provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(f) of Southeast Federal Center/Yards Non-Discriminatory Grocery Store Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-674, December 28, 2010, 58 DCR 130).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For D.C. Law 13-298, see notes following § 25-101.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-187, see notes following § 25-101.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 19-23, see notes under § 25-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
