<level type="section">
  <num>48-903.04</num>
  <heading>Registration--Suspension; revocation; forfeiture of substances.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 33-534</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A registration issued under § 48-903.03 to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance may be suspended or revoked by the Mayor upon a finding that the registrant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has been convicted of a felony under any District of Columbia, state, or federal law relating to any controlled substance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has had his or her federal or state registration suspended or revoked to manufacture, distribute, or dispense controlled substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has had his or her practitioner's license suspended or revoked in the District of Columbia by the appropriate authority; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>has violated any provisions of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A registration issued under § 48-903.03 to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance may be suspended by the Mayor upon a finding that the registrant has been convicted of a misdemeanor under any District of Columbia, state, or federal law relating to any controlled substance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may limit revocation or suspension of a registration to the particular controlled substance with respect to which grounds for revocation or suspension exist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor suspends or revokes a registration, all controlled substances owned or possessed by the registrant at the time of suspension or the effective date of the revocation order may be placed under seal. No disposition may be made of substances under seal until the time for taking an appeal has elapsed or until all appeals have been concluded unless a court orders the sale of perishable substances and the deposit of the proceeds of the sale with the court. Upon a revocation order becoming final, all controlled substances may be forfeited in accordance with the provisions of § 48-905.03(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall promptly notify the D.E.A. of all orders suspending or revoking registration and all forfeitures of controlled substances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 304, 28 DCR 3081; July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-136, § 2(c), 45 DCR 2942.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 33-534.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-29, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 48-901.02.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-136, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 48-903.02.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
