<level type="section">
  <num>5-1501.07</num>
  <heading>Impaired driving program; certification and testing of breath alcohol equipment.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department shall be responsible for testing and certifying the accuracy of any District instrument utilized by District law enforcement personnel to test the alcohol content of breath. A District breath test instrument shall only be used by District law enforcement personnel if it has been certified by the Department, or the Department's designee, to be accurate. Certification of the accuracy of each breath test instrument shall occur at least once every 180 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Develop a program for District law enforcement personnel to become trained and certified as a breath test instrument operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop policies and procedures for the operation and maintenance of all breath test instruments utilized by District law enforcement personnel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop policies and procedures for the maintenance of records demonstrating that the breath test instruments utilized by District law enforcement personnel are in proper operating condition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall issue regulations to meet the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director may delegate by memorandum of agreement some or all of the responsibilities of this section, as well as some or all of the responsibilities for providing forensic science services pertaining to breath testing as provided by § 5-1501.08(a)(1) to the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply as of October 1, 2012.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 17, 2011, D.C. Law 19-18, § 8, 58 DCR 5403; Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-260, § 3, 60 DCR 1292; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 201, 59 DCR 12957.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 5-1419 and § 50-2206.52.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-260 substituted "180 days" for "3 months" in (a).</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-266 rewrote this section; and added "Impaired driving program; certification and" to the section heading.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 201 of Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-429, July 30, 2012, 59 DCR 9387).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 201 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C Act 19-508, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 13325).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 201 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013, 60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 201 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013, 60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-18</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-18, see notes under § 5-1501.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-260</heading>
      <text>Law 19-260, the "Breath Test Admissibility in Criminal Proceedings Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-828. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 9, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-612 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-260 became effective on Apr. 20, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-266</heading>
      <text>Law 19-266, the "Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-777. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 10, 2012, and Sept. 19, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Oct. 24, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-489 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-266 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 5 of D.C. Law 19-260 provided that the act shall apply as of the effective date of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Breath Testing Program Amendment Act of 2012, signed by the Mayor on October 24, 2012 (D.C. Act 19-489; 59 DCR 12957), which became D.C. Law 19-266, effective April 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
