<level type="section">
  <num>5-1501.12</num>
  <heading>Functions of the Board.</heading>
  <text>The Board shall:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Review all reports of allegations of professional negligence, misconduct, or misidentification or other testing error that occurred in the provision of forensic science services at the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Periodically review the program standards and protocols related to Department operations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At least once every 3 years, conduct a review of relevant scientific literature to determine whether modification of any of the manuals and procedures referenced in ยง 5-1501.04(b) is desirable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Review and make recommendations as necessary to the Director concerning:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The quality and timeliness of the forensic science services at the Department;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>New scientific programs, protocols, methods of testing, and forensic technologies;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Plans for:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The implementation of new programs;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Sustaining existing programs;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Improving programs, where possible; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The elimination of programs no longer needed;</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Qualification standards for analyst positions within the Department; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any other matters related to the scientific operation of the Department; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Advise the Director or the Mayor and Council, when it considers appropriate, on matters relating to the Department or forensic science.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 17, 2011, D.C. Law 19-18, ยง 13, 58 DCR 5403.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 19-18, see notes under ยง 5-1501.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
