<level type="section">
  <num>5-1501.11</num>
  <heading>Science Advisory Board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Science Advisory Board, which shall consist of 9 voting members to be appointed pursuant to § 1-523.01(f), as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Five scientists with experience in scientific research and methodology, who have published in peer-reviewed scientific journals, and who are not currently employed by the Department or by a law enforcement laboratory or agency, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One statistician; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One with expertise in quality assurance; and</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Four forensic scientists not currently employed by the Department or by a law enforcement laboratory or agency that provides forensic science services to the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director and Deputy Director shall be ex officio, non-voting members of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each voting member shall be appointed for a 3-year term. Whenever a vacancy occurs in an unexpired term, the Mayor shall appoint a replacement to fill that unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The initial term of each member shall be staggered so that 3 members are appointed for one year, 3 members are appointed for 2 years, and 3 members are appointed for 3 years. The members to serve the one-year term, 2-year term, and 3-year term shall be determined by the Mayor at the time of nomination.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The initial terms shall begin on the date a majority of the voting members have been sworn in, which shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall elect a chairperson from among its voting members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The presence of a majority of the voting members holding office shall constitute a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Board shall hold no fewer than 4 regular meetings per year. The chairperson of the Board shall fix the time and place of each meeting. Additional meetings may be called either by the chairperson or upon the written request of the Director or of any 3 members of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Minutes shall be prepared for each meeting. A transcript or detailed summary shall meet this requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 17, 2011, D.C. Law 19-18, § 12, 58 DCR 5403; June 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-320, § 507, 60 DCR 3390.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-523.01 and § 5-1501.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-320 inserted "and who are not currently employed by the Department or by a law enforcement laboratory or agency" in (a)(1).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of (a)(1), see § 507 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-599, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1017).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 507 of the Omnibus Criminal Code Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-44, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5381, 20 DCSTAT 1281).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-18</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-18, see notes under § 5-1501.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-320</heading>
      <text>Law 19-320, the "Omnibus Criminal Code Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-645. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 11, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-677 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-320 became effective on June 19, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
