<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-201</num>
  <heading>Person that may issue a warehouse receipt; storage under bond.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A warehouse receipt may be issued by any warehouse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If goods, including distilled spirits and agricultural commodities, are stored under a statute requiring a bond against withdrawal or a license for the issuance of receipts in the nature of warehouse receipts, a receipt issued for the goods is deemed to be a warehouse receipt even if issued by a person that is the owner of the goods and is not a warehouse.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, ยง 9, 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-201.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>Law 19-299, the "Uniform Commercial Code Revision Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-136. The Bill was adopted on first reading on Dec. 4, 2012. Signed by the Mayor on Feb. 8, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-667 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-299 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</heading>
      <text>Section 1, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes:</heading>
      <text>Provision added to cover storage under government bond or under licensing statute.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Purposes:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>It is not intended by reenactment of subsection (1) to repeal any provisions of special licensing or other statutes regulating who may become a warehouseman. See Section 10-103. Subsection (2) covers receipts issued by the owner for whiskey or other goods stored in bonded warehouses under such statutes as 26 U.S.C. Chapter 26. Limitations on the transfer of the receipts and criminal sanctions for violation of such limitations are not impaired. Section 7-103. Compare Section 7-401(d) on the liability of the issuer in such cases.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>Sections 7-103, 7-401, 10-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text/>
      <text>"Warehouse receipt". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Warehouseman". Section 7-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</heading>
      <text>Former Section 7-201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Changes:</heading>
      <text>Update for style only.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Purposes:</heading>
      <text>It is not intended by re-enactment of subsection (a) to repeal any provisions of special licensing or other statutes regulating who may become a warehouse. Limitations on the transfer of the receipts and criminal sanctions for violation of such limitations are not impaired. Section 7-103. Compare Section 7-401(4) on the liability of the issuer in such cases. Subsection (b) covers receipts issued by the owner for whiskey or other goods stored in bonded warehouses under such statutes as 26 U.S.C. Chapter 51.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References:</heading>
      <text>Sections 7-103, 7-401.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
      <text>"Warehouse receipt". Section 1-201.</text>
      <text>"Warehouse". Section 7-102.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
