<level type="section">
  <num>1-623.02b</num>
  <heading>Functions - Disability compensation.</heading>
  <text>The functions of the program shall be to:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Establish appropriate systems and procedures for the reporting of occupational accidents and illnesses;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Maintain and analyze records of all occupational accidents and illnesses occurring within agencies;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Study safety problems and recommend actions to correct undesirable conditions or unsafe practices;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Monitor and evaluate adequacy and effectiveness of safety procedures and practices of District agencies through inspection;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Make determinations and awards for, or against payment of compensation under this chapter;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Pay compensation to employees for work related disability or death resulting from personal injury sustained in the performance of their duty, as specified in this section;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Conduct promotional campaigns to stimulate employees' interest in accident prevention and to train and motivate supervisors in accident prevention concepts, practices and techniques;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Develop and maintain working agreements with designated physicians and other public or private organizations, as required; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Monitor the adequacy and effectiveness of medical services under this section, and develop guidelines for the determination of disabilities and professional fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, ยง 2302b, as added Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, ยง 1203(b), 48 DCR 6981.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see ยง 1103(b) of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001, 48 DCR 7861).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-28</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-28, see notes following ยง 1-604.06.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
