<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-309</num>
  <heading>Security interest perfected upon attachment.</heading>
  <text>The following security interests are perfected when they attach:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A purchase-money security interest in consumer goods, except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-311(b) with respect to consumer goods that are subject to a statute or treaty described in § 28:9-311(a);</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>An assignment of accounts or payment intangibles which does not by itself or in conjunction with other assignments to the same assignee transfer a significant part of the assignor's outstanding accounts or payment intangibles;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A sale of a payment intangible;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A sale of a promissory note;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>A security interest created by the assignment of a health-care-insurance receivable to the provider of the health-care goods or services;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>A security interest arising under § 28:2-401, 2-505, 2-711(3), or 2A-508(5), until the debtor obtains possession of the collateral;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>A security interest of a collecting bank arising under § 28:4-210;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>A security interest of an issuer or nominated person arising under § 28:5-118;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>A security interest arising in the delivery of a financial asset under § 28:9-206(c);</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>A security interest in investment property created by a broker or securities intermediary;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>A security interest in a commodity contract or a commodity account created by a commodity intermediary;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>An assignment for the benefit of all creditors of the transferor and subsequent transfers by the assignee thereunder;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>A security interest created by an assignment of a beneficial interest in a decedent's estate; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>A sale by an individual of an account that is a right to payment of winnings in a lottery or other game of chance.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(g), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-308, § 28:9-310, and § 28:9-323.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 added (14); and made related changes.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-301.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
