<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-310</num>
  <heading>When filing required to perfect security interest or agricultural lien; security interests and agricultural liens to which filing provisions do not apply.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) and § 28:9-312(b), a financing statement must be filed to perfect all security interests and agricultural liens.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The filing of a financing statement is not necessary to perfect a security interest:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That is perfected under § 28:9-308(d), (e), (f), or (g);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That is perfected under § 28:9-309 when it attaches;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In property subject to a statute, regulation, or treaty described in § 28:9-311(a);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In goods in possession of a bailee which is perfected under § 28:9-312(d)(1) or (2);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>In certificated securities, documents, goods, or instruments which is perfected without filing or possession under § 28:9-312(e), (f), or (g);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>In collateral in the secured party's possession under § 28:9-313;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>In a certificated security which is perfected by delivery of the security certificate to the secured party under § 28:9-313;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>In deposit accounts, electronic chattel paper, electronic documents, investment property, or letter-of-credit rights which is perfected by control under § 28:9-314;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>In proceeds which is perfected under § 28:9-315; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>That is perfected under § 28:9-316.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a secured party assigns a perfected security interest or agricultural lien, a filing under this article is not required to continue the perfected status of the security interest against creditors of and transferees from the original debtor.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 11(h), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-102, § 28:9-308, and § 28:9-311.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 inserted "electronic documents" in (b)(8).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:9-301.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
