<level type="section">
  <num>16-4015</num>
  <heading>Coercive or violent relationship.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before a prospective party signs a collaborative law participation agreement, a prospective collaborative lawyer shall make reasonable inquiry whether the prospective party has a history of a coercive or violent relationship with another prospective party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Throughout a collaborative law process, a collaborative lawyer reasonably and continuously shall assess whether the party the collaborative lawyer represents has a history of a coercive or violent relationship with another party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a collaborative lawyer reasonably believes that the party the lawyer represents or the prospective party who consults the lawyer has a history of a coercive or violent relationship with another party or prospective party, the lawyer may not begin or continue a collaborative law process unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The party or the prospective party requests beginning or continuing the process; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The collaborative lawyer reasonably believes that the safety of the party or prospective party can be protected adequately during the process.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 9, 2012, D.C. Law 19-125, ยง 2(b), 59 DCR 1928.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 19-125, see notes under ยง 16-4001.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 15 of the Uniform Collaborative Law Act. See Vol. 7 , Part 1B, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
