<level type="section">
  <num>34-2202.15</num>
  <heading>Merit personnel system inapplicable.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section and in § 34-2202.17(b), no provision of § 1-601.01 et seq., shall apply to employees of the Authority except as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subchapters V and XVII of Chapter 6 of Title 1 shall apply to all employees of the Authority; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subchapters XII, XXI, XXII, and XXVI of Chapter 6 of Title 1 shall apply to employees transferred to the Authority who are covered under the Civil Service Retirement System and the District of Columbia Defined Contribution Pension Plan; provided, that all Authority employees continuously employed by the District government since December 31, 1979, shall be guaranteed rights and benefits at least equal to those currently applicable to such persons under provisions of law and rules and regulations in force prior to April 18, 1996.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An employee of the Authority who is covered under the District of Columbia Defined Contribution Pension Plan, who meets the minimum requirements for participation in a retirement plan established by the Authority, may, upon written notice to the Authority, elect, instead, to be covered by the Authority's plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-111, § 215, 43 DCR 548; Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 213(b), 54 DCR 10993; July 15, 2008, 122 Stat. 2491, Pub. L. 110-273, § 4(a).)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 34-2202.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 43-1685.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-108 added subsec. (c).</text>
      <text>Pub. L. 110-273 repealed subsec. (c), as added by D.C. Law 17-108.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-111</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-111, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 34-2201.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-108</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-108, see notes following § 34-804.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <text>Section 4(b) of Pub. L. 110-273 provided that subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of D.C. Law 17-172.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
