<level type="section">
  <num>24-468</num>
  <heading>Medical and geriatric reduction of sentence.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 24-268</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon a motion by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons, the court may reduce the sentence of any person convicted of a felony under the District of Columbia Official Code committed on or after August 5, 2000, and sentenced to a determinate term of imprisonment which is not subject to parole, and shall impose an adequate period of supervision to follow release, based upon a finding that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The inmate is permanently incapacitated or terminally ill because of a medical condition which was not known to the court at the time of sentencing, and the release of the inmate under supervision is not incompatible with public safety; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The inmate is 65 years or older and has a chronic infirmity, illness, or disease related to aging, and the release of the inmate under supervision is not incompatible with public safety.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The court shall act expeditiously on any motion submitted by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons. If the court receives a request directly from an inmate or a representative of an inmate, the court may refer the matter to the Federal Bureau of Prisons for a motion or a statement of reasons as to why a motion will not be filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 15, 1993, D.C. Law 9-271, § 8a, as added Oct. 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12- 165, § 5, 45 DCR 2980.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 24-268.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-165, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 24-403.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
