<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-620</num>
  <heading>Acceptance of collateral in full or partial satisfaction of obligation; compulsory disposition of collateral.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), a secured party may accept collateral in full or partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The debtor consents to the acceptance under subsection (c);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The secured party does not receive, within the time set forth in subsection (d), a notification of objection to the proposal authenticated by:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A person to which the secured party was required to send a proposal under § 28:9-621; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any other person, other than the debtor, holding an interest in the collateral subordinate to the security interest that is the subject of the proposal;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the collateral is consumer goods, the collateral is not in the possession of the debtor when the debtor consents to the acceptance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Subsection (e) of this section does not require the secured party to dispose of the collateral or the debtor waives the requirement pursuant to § 28:9-624.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A purported or apparent acceptance of collateral under this section is ineffective unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The secured party consents to the acceptance in an authenticated record or sends a proposal to the debtor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The conditions of subsection (a) of this section are met.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A debtor consents to an acceptance of collateral in partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if the debtor agrees to the terms of the acceptance in a record authenticated after default; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A debtor consents to an acceptance of collateral in full satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if the debtor agrees to the terms of the acceptance in a record authenticated after default or the secured party:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Sends to the debtor after default a proposal that is unconditional or subject only to a condition that collateral not in the possession of the secured party be preserved or maintained;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the proposal, proposes to accept collateral in full satisfaction of the obligation it secures; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Does not receive a notification of objection authenticated by the debtor within 20 days after the proposal is sent.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To be effective under subsection (a)(2), a notification of objection must be received by the secured party:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of a person to which the proposal was sent pursuant to § 28:9-621, within 20 days after notification was sent to that person; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In other cases:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within 20 days after the last notification was sent pursuant to § 28:9-621; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If a notification was not sent, before the debtor consents to the acceptance under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A secured party that has taken possession of collateral shall dispose of the collateral pursuant to § 28:9-610 within the time specified in subsection (f) if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>60 percent of the cash price has been paid in the case of a purchase-money security interest in consumer goods; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>60 percent of the principal amount of the obligation secured has been paid in the case of a non-purchase-money security interest in consumer goods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>To comply with subsection (e), the secured party shall dispose of the collateral:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days after taking possession; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within any longer period to which the debtor and all secondary obligors have agreed in an agreement to that effect entered into and authenticated after default.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>In a consumer transaction, a secured party may not accept collateral in partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:6-103, § 28:9-102, § 28:9-406, § 28:9-408, § 28:9-602, and § 28:9-624.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
