<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-611</num>
  <heading>Notification before disposition of collateral.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this section, "notification date" means the earlier of the date on which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A secured party sends to the debtor and any secondary obligor an authenticated notification of disposition; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The debtor and any secondary obligor waive the right to notification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), a secured party that disposes of collateral under § 28:9-610 shall send to the persons specified in subsection (c) a reasonable authenticated notification of disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To comply with subsection (b), the secured party shall send an authenticated notification of disposition to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The debtor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any secondary obligor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the collateral is other than consumer goods:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any other person from which the secured party has received, before the notification date, an authenticated notification of a claim of an interest in the collateral;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any other secured party or lienholder that, 10 days before the notification date, held a security interest in or other lien on the collateral perfected by the filing of a financing statement that:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Identified the collateral;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Was indexed under the debtor's name as of that date; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Was filed in the office in which to file a financing statement against the debtor covering the collateral as of that date; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other secured party that, 10 days before the notification date, held a security interest in the collateral perfected by compliance with a statute, regulation, or treaty described in § 28:9-311(a).</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subsection (b) does not apply if the collateral is perishable or threatens to decline speedily in value or is of a type customarily sold on a recognized market.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A secured party complies with the requirement for notification prescribed by subsection (c)(3)(B) if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not later than 20 days or earlier than 30 days before the notification date, the secured party requests, in a commercially reasonable manner, information concerning financing statements indexed under the debtor's name in the office indicated in subsection (c)(3)(B); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Before the notification date, the secured party:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Did not receive a response to the request for information; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Received a response to the request for information and sent an authenticated notification of disposition to each secured party or other lienholder named in that response whose financing statement covered the collateral.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-602 and § 28:9-624.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
