<level type="section">
  <num>50-405</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 40-1805</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor has reason to believe that a person has violated any of the requirements in § 50-403 or § 50-404, the alleged violation shall be enforced in accordance with Chapter 23 of this title, and rules issued by the Mayor pursuant to § 50-409. Any person who is determined by the Mayor, after notice and opportunity to be heard, to have violated § 50-403 or § 50-404, shall be liable to the District for a civil fine of not less than $100 nor more than $1000 for the first violation, of not less than $500 nor more than $2000 for the second violation, or of not less than $1000 nor more than $5000 for the third or a subsequent violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As an alternative sanction, any person who knowingly or willfully violates § 50-403 or § 50-404 shall be guilty of an offense and, upon conviction, may be:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Fined not less than $100 nor more than $1000, imprisoned for not more than 6 months, or both, for the first violation;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Fined not less than $500 nor more than $2000, imprisoned not less than 6 months nor more than 9 months, or both, for the second violation; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Fined not less than $1000 nor more than $5000, imprisoned for not less than 9 months nor more than 1 year, or both, for the third or a subsequent violation.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Prosecutions for violations of this subsection shall be brought by the Corporation Counsel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-161, § 6, 37 DCR 4665.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 40-1805.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 8-161, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 50-401.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
