<level type="section">
  <num>27-101</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Fraud" shall have the same meaning as that term is used in § 22-3221.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Juvenile" means a person under 18 years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Merchant" means a person who does or would sell, lease, or transfer, either directly or indirectly, consumer goods or services, or a person who does or would supply the goods or services which are or would be the subject matter of a trade practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Shoplifting" shall have the same meaning as that term has in § 22-3213(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Theft" shall have the same meaning as that term is used in § 22-3211.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 16, 1992, D.C. Law 9-98, § 2, 39 DCR 678.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 3-441.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <text>Temporary addition of chapter: D.C. Law 9-97 enacted this chapter.</text>
      <text>Section 8(b) of D.C. Law 9-97 provided that the act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct of 1991, whichever occurs first.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of chapter, see §§ 2-7 of the Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Emergency Act of 1991 (D.C. Act 9-110, November 25, 1991, 38 DCR 7304).</text>
      <text>For temporary addition of chapter, see §§ 2-7 of the Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1992 (D.C. Act 9-155, February 21, 1992, 39 DCR 1354).</text>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 2 of the Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Emergency Amendment Act of 1992 (D.C. Act 9-205, May 14, 1992, 39 DCR 3649).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-97</heading>
      <text>Law 9-97, the "Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Temporary Act of 1991," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-351. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-97 became effective on May 7, 1992.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-98</heading>
      <text>Law 9-98, the "Merchant's Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1992," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-152, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 1991, and January 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-138 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-98 became effective on May 16, 1992.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Because of the codification of D.C. Law 20-34 as subchapter II of this chapter, the preexisting text, §§ 27-101 through 27-106, has been designated as subchapter I; and "subchapter" has been substituted for "chapter" in the introductory language of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
