<level type="section">
  <num>44-635</num>
  <heading>Appeals.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A hospital may contest the amount of an assessment, including any interest or administrative penalties, imposed under this chapter, or by rules issued pursuant to this chapter, by filing a notice of appeal with the Office of Administrative Hearings within 60 days after the date of the notice of a determination or redetermination of an assessment based on an audit of information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall conduct a hearing on the appeal filed under subsection (a) of this section subject to the provisions of subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 governing adjudication of contested cases, and pursuant to the rules of the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before filing an appeal pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the hospital shall pay to the Mayor the assessment and any administrative penalties and interest due on the assessment. The filing of a notice of appeal shall not act as a stay on the requirement to pay payment of the assessment, interest, and administrative penalties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 5016, 57 DCR 6242.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>Section 1106 of D.C. Law 18-222 added a section to read as follows:</text>
        <text>"Sec. 1106. Appeals.</text>
        <text>"(a) A hospital may contest the amount of an assessment, including any interest or administrative penalties, imposed under this act, or by rules issued pursuant to this act, by filing a notice of appeal with the Office of Administrative Hearings within 60 days after the date of the notice of a determination or redetermination of an assessment based on an audit of information.</text>
        <text>"(b) The Office of Administrative Hearings shall conduct a hearing on the appeal filed under subsection (a) of this section subject to the provisions of Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <text i="True">et seq.</text>), governing adjudication of contested cases, and pursuant to the rules of the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
        <text>"(c) Before filing an appeal pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the hospital shall pay to the Mayor the assessment and any administrative penalties and interest due on the assessment. The filing of a notice of appeal shall not act as a stay on the requirement to pay payment of the assessment, interest, and administrative penalties."</text>
        <text>Section 2002(b) of D.C. Law 18-222 provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1106 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-450, June 28, 2010, 57 DCR 5635).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5016 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010, 57 DCR 6542).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see §§ 1106 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-531, August 6, 2010, 57 DCR 8109).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-223, see notes following § 44-631.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
