<level type="section">
  <num>29-205.04</num>
  <heading>Amendment or abandonment of plan of domestication.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A plan of domestication of a domestic domesticating entity may be amended:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the same manner as the plan was approved if the plan does not provide for the manner in which it may be amended; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By the governors or interest holders of the entity in the manner provided in the plan, but an interest holder that was entitled to vote on or consent to approval of the domestication shall be entitled to vote on or consent to any amendment of the plan that will change:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The amount or kind of interests, securities, obligations, rights to acquire interests or securities, cash, or other property, or any combination of the foregoing, to be received by any of the interest holders of the domesticating entity under the plan;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The public organic document or private organic rules of the domesticated entity that will be in effect immediately after the domestication becomes effective, except for changes that do not require approval of the interest holders of the domesticated entity under its organic law or organic rules; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other terms or conditions of the plan if the change would adversely affect the interest holder in any material respect.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After a plan of domestication has been approved by a domestic domesticating entity and before a statement of domestication becomes effective, the plan may be abandoned:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As provided in the plan; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Unless prohibited by the plan, in the same manner as the plan was approved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a plan of domestication is abandoned after a statement of domestication has been filed with the Mayor and before the filing becomes effective, a statement of abandonment, signed on behalf of the entity, shall be filed with the Mayor before the time the statement of domestication becomes effective. The statement of abandonment shall be effective upon filing, and the domestication shall be abandoned and shall not become effective. The statement of abandonment shall contain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the domesticating entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date on which the statement of domestication was filed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement that the domestication has been abandoned in accordance with this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
