<level type="section">
  <num>8-1309</num>
  <heading>Suspension and revocation of permit.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-709</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may suspend a permit issued in accordance with § 8-1303 if the holder of the permit is in violation of this chapter or the rules promulgated pursuant to the chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Written notice of the suspension shall be served upon the affected party or the party's designated agent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where a permit has been suspended, the person affected has the right to reapply for a permit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the person is able to demonstrate an ability and willingness to comply with the permit and with the provisions of this chapter and the rules, the Mayor may grant a new permit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where there is a history of repeated violations or where a permit has been previously suspended, the Mayor may revoke a permit, upon a showing of subsequent violation, and upon providing the affected party, or the party's designated agent, with written notice of the intent to revoke the permit and with an opportunity for a hearing prior to revocation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The revocation shall take effect 15 days after the notice has been given, unless a written request for a hearing is received by the Mayor within that period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may immediately revoke a permit upon an initial violation of the chapter or the rules where the violation presents an imminent and substantial endangerment to the public health, the public welfare, or the environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-64, § 10, 24 DCR 6289; Aug. 10, 1984, D.C. Law 5-103, § 2(f), 31 DCR 3032.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-709.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-529.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-64, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1301.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-103, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 8-1301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
