<level type="section">
  <num>28:3-203</num>
  <heading>Transfer of instrument; rights acquired by transfer.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An instrument is transferred when it is delivered by a person other than its issuer for the purpose of giving to the person receiving delivery the right to enforce the instrument.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Transfer of an instrument, whether or not the transfer is a negotiation, vests in the transferee any right of the transferor to enforce the instrument, including any right as a holder in due course, but the transferee cannot acquire rights of a holder in due course by a transfer, directly or indirectly, from a holder in due course if the transferee engaged in fraud or illegality affecting the instrument.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise agreed, if an instrument is transferred for value and the transferee does not become a holder because of lack of indorsement by the transferor, the transferee has a specifically enforceable right to the unqualified indorsement of the transferor, but negotiation of the instrument does not occur until the indorsement is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a transferor purports to transfer less than the entire instrument, negotiation of the instrument does not occur. In this case, the transferee obtains no rights under this article and has only the rights of a partial assignee.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 678, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-249, § 2(d), 42 DCR 467.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:3-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:3-203.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 28:3-201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-249</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-249, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:3-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
