<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.45</num>
  <heading>Annual report; review of funding priorities.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent shall submit to the Council, the Mayor, and the Board of Education, an annual report containing the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A summary of any real estate portfolio review and business plan studies for potential partnership development completed by the Superintendent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of projects developed by the Superintendent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number of projects financed by the Schools Modernization Fund that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Created additional capacity within the District of Columbia Public Schools for special education students or programs;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Created additional capacity for vocational education programs;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Created a co-location arrangement with a public charter school; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Developed a shared-use facility or site between the District of Columbia Public Schools and another District agency.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent shall review the priorities for use of revenue from the Schools Modernization Fund specified in ยง 1-325.44 every 5 years and make recommendations to the Mayor, the Council, and the Board of Education on their continued validity or propose new priorities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, ยง 4046, 52 DCR 7503.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 4046 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005, 52 DCR 7667).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-33, see notes following ยง 1-325.41.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
