<level type="section">
  <num>38-1805.52</num>
  <heading>Facilities Master Plan.</heading>
  <text>In developing the Facilities Master Plan pursuant to § 38-2803, the Mayor shall consult with the Council, the Director of the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization, the Public Charter School Board, representatives of public charter schools, and the Public School Modernization Advisory Committee, and shall consider the facilities needs of all public school students.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321 [263], Pub. L. 104-134, § 2552; Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 322, 50 DCR 5668; June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-123, § 222(b), 53 DCR 2843; June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 802(g), 54 DCR 4102.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-392.25.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 31-2853.52.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 15-39 rewrote subsec. (a)(1).</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 16-123 rewrote section.</text>
      <text>D.C. Law 17-9 substituted "Mayor shall consult with the Council, the Director of the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization," for "Superintendent and Board of Education shall consult with the Mayor, the Council".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 322 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003, 50 DCR 5613).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 322 of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003, 50 DCR 8360).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 804 of D.C. Law 17-9, see § 4043(b) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007, 54 DCR 7549).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-39</heading>
      <text>For Law 15-39, see notes following § 38-160.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-123</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-123, see notes following § 38-2971.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-9</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-9, see notes under § 38-103.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title of subtitle C of title III of Law 15-39: Section 321 of D.C. Law 15-39 provided that subtitle C of title III of the act may be cited as the Public Schools Facilities Master Plan Amendment Act of 2003.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability: Section 804 of D.C. Law 17-9 provided that section 802 shall apply upon enactment by Congress. Section 804 of D.C. Law 17-9 was repealed by section 4043(b) of D.C. Law 17-20.</text>
      <text>Establishment of Process and Time Deadlines for the Program to Revitalize Public Schools Resolution of 1996: Pursuant to Resolution 11-629, effective December 3, 1996, Council established a process and time deadline for development of a program designed to provide for the repair and improvement, and the maintenance and management of District of Columbia public school facilities, and to designate an agency or authority to administer the program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
