<level type="section">
  <num>29-1008.22</num>
  <heading>Appointment and authority of officers.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A limited cooperative association shall have the officers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provided in the organic rules; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Established by the board of directors in a manner not inconsistent with the organic rules.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The organic rules may designate or, if the rules do not designate, the board of directors shall designate, one of the association's officers for preparing all records required by § 29-1001.10 and for the authentication of records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, the board of directors shall appoint the officers of the limited cooperative association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Officers of a limited cooperative association shall perform the duties the organic rules prescribe or as authorized by the board of directors not in a manner inconsistent with the organic rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The election or appointment of an officer of a limited cooperative association shall not of itself create a contract between the association and the officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, an individual may simultaneously hold more than one office in a limited cooperative association.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-1001.09.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based on § 822 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act. Edition</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
