<level type="section">
  <num>3-1208.61</num>
  <heading>Practice of veterinary medicine; license requirement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person shall not engage in the practice of veterinary medicine without being licensed by the Board of Veterinary Medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A license shall not be required for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An employee or agent of the federal or District government while performing his or her official duties provided, that a person exempt under this paragraph shall not perform surgical operations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Experimentation and scientific research in connection with the study and the development of methods and techniques, directly or indirectly related or applicable to the problems or to the practice of veterinary medicine, when conducted by the federal or District government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A merchant or manufacturer for the sale, at his or her regular place of business, of medicine, feed, appliances, or other products used to prevent or treat animal diseases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A person engaging in scientific research that reasonably requires experimentation with animals as permitted under federal law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A licensed wildlife rehabilitator licensed in any state or the District to provide wildlife rehabilitation provided, that a rehabilitator shall not perform surgery, diagnose, or prescribe medication, and may only perform services on indigenous wild animals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 861, as added Mar. 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-96, § 102(q), 61 DCR 1184.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-96 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-96</heading>
      <text>Law 20-96, the "Omnibus Health Regulation Amendment Act of 2014," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-153. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2013 and January 7, 2014, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 5, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-273 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-96 became effective on March 26, 2014.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 401(b) of D.C. Law 20-96 provided that rules promulgated pursuant to Chapter 5 of this title shall remain in effect until the Mayor promulgates rules to implement this subchapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
