<level type="section">
  <num>38-2734</num>
  <heading>Annual reports.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall report to the Council annually regarding:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of eligible students attending each eligible institution and the amount of the grant awards paid to those institutions on behalf of eligible students;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The extent, if any, to which a ratable reduction was made in the amount of higher education assistance payments made on behalf of eligible students; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The progress made by eligible students each year in obtaining recognized academic credentials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The State Education Office shall annually make available the following information, to be solicited by the State Education Office and collected from participating institutions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The enrollment status and graduation rates of students on whose behalf funding from this program has been paid to eligible institutions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The enrollment status and graduation rates of students on whose behalf funding has been paid from the DC Tuition Assistance Grant Program, established by Chapter 27 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 4025, 53 DCR 6899.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4025 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006, 53 DCR 7068).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4025 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006, 53 DCR 8845).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4025 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007, 54 DCR 1165).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-192, see notes following § 38-2731.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
