<level type="section">
  <num>31-3303.02</num>
  <heading>Availability of health benefit plans to small employers.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 35-1032</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>In order to ensure the broadest availability of health benefit plans to small employers, the Commissioner shall set market conduct and other requirements for health insurers, agents, and third-party administrators, including requirements relating to the following:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Registration with the Commissioner by each group health insurer offering group health insurance coverage of its intention to offer health insurance coverage in the small group market under this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Publication by the Commissioner of a list of all health insurers who offer coverage in the small group market, including a potential requirement applicable to agents, third-party administrators, and health insurers that no health benefit plan may be sold to a small employer by a health insurer not identified as a health insurer in the small group market;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The availability of a broadly publicized telephone number for the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking for access by small employers to information concerning this subchapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Methods concerning periodic demonstration by health insurers offering group health insurance coverage that they are marketing and issuing health benefit plans to small employers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-209, § 302, 45 DCR 8433; June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 4(s)(2), 51 DCR 2817.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 35-1032.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-166, in par. (3), substituted "Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking" for "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-3301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>See notes to § 31-3301.01.</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(s)(2) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004, 51 DCR 2653).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-209, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 31-3301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-166, see notes following § 31-1004.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
