<level type="section">
  <num>47-1336</num>
  <heading>Energy efficiency loan foreclosure.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A special assessment pursuant to an energy efficiency loan agreement under subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of Title 47, shall be deemed an additional real property tax, and shall be deemed a tax under § 47-1330(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When delinquent on October 1 and for 6 months or more, the Chief Financial Officer may sell for one dollar or without any consideration, at the Chief Financial Officer's discretion, the real property subject to the special assessment under subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of Title 47, to the applicable energy efficiency lender or servicer of the Energy Efficient Loan, or to a third party and under terms and conditions as the Chief Financial Officer may determine, notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The transaction shall not be subject to the provisions of § 47-1353 or [Chapter 3A of Title 2, § 2-351.01 et seq.]. Additionally, the transaction shall not be subject to the notice requirements of §§ 47-1341 and 47-1342 or the costs set forth in § 47-1342(c).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Only interest at the rate set forth in § 47-811(c) shall accrue on any delinquent Special Assessment, notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The sale of the real property shall be evidenced by a sealed certificate of the Chief Financial Officer or the Chief Financial Officer's duly authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The sealed certificate shall be deemed a certificate of sale.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The certificate of sale shall be recorded in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds by the transferee.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Evidence of subsequent assignments or notice of succession in interest shall also be recorded in the Office of the Recorder of Deeds by the assignee or successor in interest, and the assignee or successor in interest shall also notify the Chief Financial Officer of the subsequent assignment or succession, including the assignee or successor's legal name, contact information, and other information that the Chief Financial Officer may require.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The holder of a sealed certificate shall have filed a business tax registration with the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The transferee of a sealed certificate and an assignee or successor in interest of the transferee shall have and possess the same rights, powers, lien status, and priority of payment at law or in equity as the District would have possessed if the real property had not been sold. Subject to the foregoing, the transferee or assignee shall have the same rights to enforce all tax liens as the District, including the right to foreclose upon the tax lien and cause the issuance of a deed in fee simple absolute by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding a provision of this chapter to the contrary, a complaint for foreclosure of the right of redemption may be filed by the transferee and an assignee or successor in interest pursuant to § 47-1370 at any time.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The transferee, or an assignee or successor in interest of the transferee, shall provide notice via both certified mail and first class mail to the property's record owner at least 60 days before a complaint for foreclosure of the right of redemption is filed. The notice shall state at a minimum that:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A foreclosure action shall be commenced in no sooner than 60 days of the date of the notice;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To avoid the lawsuit the outstanding liens shall be paid to the District and in what amount;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the owner does not redeem the property the owner may lose title to the property; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Once the complaint is filed, reasonable expenses under § 47-1377 shall be owed.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, no expenses shall be owed to redeem the property before the complaint is filed under this section. Once the complaint is filed and the owner has not redeemed the property, expenses allowable under § 47-1377 shall become owed in order to redeem.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>In a cause of action in respect of a sealed certificate, the production of an instrument executed by the Chief Financial Officer or the Chief Financial Officer's duly authorized representative shall be presumptive evidence that the real property proposed to be sold by the instrument was subject to a valid and enforceable tax lien and it was duly sold to the transferee.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 103(c), 60 DCR 1300.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-895.33 and § 47-1382.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-262</heading>
      <text>Law 19-262, the "Sustainable DC Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-756. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 16, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-615 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-262 became effective on Apr. 20, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
