<level type="section">
  <num>3-1335</num>
  <heading>Payment of prize by or on behalf of minor.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 2-2535</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>If a person entitled to a lottery prize is under 18 years of age and the prize is less than $5,000, the Board may require that payment of the prize be directed to an adult member of the minor's family or to a guardian of the minor in a check or draft payable to the order of the minor. If the person entitled to the prize is under 18 years of age and the prize is $5,000 or more, the Board may direct payment to the minor by depositing the amount of the prize in any bank, to the credit of an adult member of the minor's family or to a guardian of the minor, as custodian of the minor. The person so named as custodian shall have the same duties and powers as a custodian designated under Uniform Transfers to Minors Act, Chapter 3 of Title 21. The Board is discharged of all further liability upon payment of the prize to a minor under this section.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 4, 27 DCR 4736; Mar. 12, 1986, D.C. Law 6-87, § 3(a), 33 DCR 278.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 2-2535.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 3-172, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 3-1301.</text>
        <text>Law 6-87, the "District of Columbia Uniform Transfers to Minors Act," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 6-58, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 19, 1985, and December 3, 1985, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 30, 1985, it was assigned Act No. 6-115 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
