<level type="section">
  <num>29-1005.06</num>
  <heading>Annual meeting of members.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Members shall meet annually at a time provided in the organic rules or set by the board of directors not inconsistent with the organic rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An annual members meeting may be held inside or outside the District at the place stated in the organic rules or selected by the board of directors not inconsistent with the organic rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, members may attend or conduct an annual members meeting through any means of communication if all members attending the meeting can communicate with each other during the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The board of directors shall report, or cause to be reported, at the association's annual members meeting the association's business and financial condition as of the close of the most recent fiscal year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, the board of directors shall designate the presiding officer of the association's annual members meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Failure to hold an annual members meeting shall not affect the validity of any action by the limited cooperative association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 506 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act . See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
