<level type="section">
  <num>47-1380</num>
  <heading>Judgment setting aside sale.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Superior Court shall set aside a sale, the amount required to redeem is: (A) the amount required by this chapter, as may be adjusted by the court, and (B) the reasonable value, on the date the judgment is set aside, of all reasonable improvements made on the real property by the purchaser and the purchaser's successors in interest subject to § 47-1363.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A sale shall not be set aside unless the real property is redeemed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the Superior Court sets aside a sale in the absence of fraud on the part of the purchaser, the Mayor shall repay to the purchaser:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount paid to the Mayor on account of the purchase price of the property sold, with interest thereon except surplus;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All taxes accrued after the date of sale that were paid by the purchaser under this chapter, with interest as would have been required to be paid by a redeemer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The expenses collected by the Mayor and properly incurred under § 47-1377; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amount, as collected by the Mayor, of the value of all reasonable improvements made on the real property by the purchaser and the purchaser's successors in interest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the Superior Court finds fraud on the part of the purchaser, the Superior Court shall set aside the sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 507(a)(2), 48 DCR 334; Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(ll), 50 DCR 896.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 14-282 added subsec. (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(qq) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-191, October 5, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 9549).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(qq) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (D.C. Law 14-228, March 23, 2003, law notification 50 DCR 2741).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Law 14-8, June 13, 2001, law notification 48 DCR 5916).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001, 48 DCR 2706).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(pp) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(qq) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(qq) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-305</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-305, see notes under § 47-901.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-282</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-282, see notes following § 47-902.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
