<level type="section">
  <num>29-304.04</num>
  <heading>Fractional shares.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A corporation may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue fractions of a share or pay, in money, the value of fractions of a share;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Arrange for disposition of fractional shares by the shareholders; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Issue scrip in registered or bearer form entitling the holder to receive a full share upon surrendering enough scrip to equal a full share.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each certificate representing scrip shall be conspicuously labeled "scrip" and shall contain the information required by ยง 29-304.25(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The holder of a fractional share shall be entitled to exercise the rights of a shareholder, including the right to vote, to receive dividends, and to participate in the assets of the corporation upon liquidation. The holder of scrip shall not be entitled to any of these rights unless the scrip provides for them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The board of directors may authorize the issuance of scrip subject to any condition considered desirable, including that the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Scrip will become void if not exchanged for full shares before a specified date; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shares for which the scrip is exchangeable may be sold and the proceeds paid to the scripholders.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
