<level type="section">
  <num>42-405</num>
  <heading>Notice of address and name change.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All parties with an interest in a particular real property (including owners of the real property, mortgagees, secured parties under a deed of trust, trustees, or lienholders) shall notify the Recorder of Deeds in writing in the event of a name change or address change. The notice shall identify the real property and specify the interest held in the property. A person to whom an interest in a particular real property has been transferred shall provide their full name and address when recording the interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Recorder of Deeds shall enter into its land records all updated information received according to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an owner, as defined under § 47-802(5), may notify the Office of Tax and Revenue of an address change in lieu of filing with the Recorder of Deeds. The notice shall identify the real property by square, suffix and lot, parcel and lot, or reservation and lot, and shall specify the interest held in the real property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District shall assess a fee not to exceed $300 against an interested party if the District is unable to locate the interested party using all available information in the land records at the Office of the Recorder of Deeds or other information available at the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules to implement this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 499d, as added Oct. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-34, § 2, 44 DCR 4827; Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 7(a), 50 DCR 896.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 42-3131.06.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 45-801.4.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 14-282 added subsec. (b-1); and in subsec. (c), substituted "Office of Tax and Revenue" for "Department of Finance and Revenue".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 8(a) of the Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-191, Oct. 5, 2002, law notification 49 DCR 9549).</text>
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 8(a) of the Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2002 (D.C. Law 14-228, Mar. 25, 2003, law notification 50 DCR 2741).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8(a) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002, 49 DCR 5674).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8(a) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002, 49 DCR 8107).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8(a) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002, 49 DCR 10247).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-34</heading>
      <text>Law 12-34, the "Real Property Interests Reporting Improvement Amendment Act of 1997," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-177, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 17, 1997, and July 1, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-130 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-34 became effective on October 23, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 14-282</heading>
      <text>For Law 14-282, see notes following § 42-204.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer's "Notice of Public Interest" published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register (44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner's Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
