<level type="section">
  <num>32-131.09</num>
  <heading>Posting requirement.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prescribe, and the Mayor shall provide to employers, and an employer shall post and maintain in a conspicuous place, a notice that sets forth excerpts from or summaries of the pertinent provisions of this chapter and information that pertains to the filing of a complaint under this chapter. The notice shall be published in all languages spoken by 3% of or 500 individuals in the District of Columbia population, whichever is less.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An employer who willfully violates this section shall be assessed a civil penalty not to exceed $100 for each day that the employer fails to post the notice; provided, that the total penalty shall not exceed $500.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No liability for failure to post notice will arise under this section if the Mayor has failed to provide to the business the notice required by this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An employer shall post the notice in English and all languages spoken by employees with Limited or no-English Proficiency, as defined in § 2-1931(5).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Employers shall be furnished copies or summaries of this chapter prepared by the Mayor on request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-152, § 10, 55 DCR 3452; Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 311(b), 56 DCR 1117.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-353, in subsec. (a), deleted "in languages in accordance with subchapter II of Chapter 19 of Title 2," following "provide to employers,".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-152, see notes following § 32-131.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-353, see notes following § 32-101.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
