<level type="section">
  <num>32-131.08</num>
  <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person shall not interfere with, restrain, or deny the exercise of, or the attempt to exercise, any right provided by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An employer shall not discharge or discriminate in any manner against an employee because the employee:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Opposes any practice by an employer made unlawful by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pursuant or related to this chapter:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Files or attempts to file a charge;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Institutes or attempts to institute a proceeding; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Facilitates the institution of a proceeding;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Gives any information or testimony in connection with an inquiry or proceeding related to this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Uses paid leave provided under this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit an employer from establishing and enforcing a lawful policy relating to improper use of paid leave or from seeking more frequent certifications from an employee if there is evidence of a pattern of abuse of paid leave.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-152, § 9, 55 DCR 3452; Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-89, § 2(d), 61 DCR 317.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 32-131.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-152</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-152, see notes following § 32-131.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-89</heading>
      <text>See note to § 32-131.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 2(d)(1) of D.C. Law 20-89 would have amended (b)(2) to read as follows:</text>
      <text>"(2) Pursuant or related to this act:</text>
      <text>"(A) Complains to the employer;</text>
      <text>"(B) Files a complaint with the Department of Employment Services;</text>
      <text>"(C) Files a civil complaint alleging a violation of any provision of this act;</text>
      <text>"(D) Informs any person about an employer's alleged violation of this act;</text>
      <text>"(E) Cooperates with the Department of Employment Services or another person's investigation or prosecution of any alleged violation of this act;</text>
      <text>"(F) Opposes any policy, practice, or act that is unlawful under this act; or</text>
      <text>"(G) Informs any person of his or her rights under this act.".</text>
      <text>Section 2(d)(2) of D.C. Law 20-89 would have added (d) and (e) to read as follows:</text>
      <text>"(d) An employer taking an adverse action against an employee within 90 days of any of the actions set forth in subsection (b)(2) of this section shall raise a rebuttable presumption that the employer has violated this act.</text>
      <text>"(e) It shall be unlawful for an employer's absence control policy to count paid leave taken under this act as an absence that may lead to, or result in, discipline, discharge, demotion, suspension, or other adverse action".</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-89: Section 3 of D.C. Law 20-89 provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
