<level type="section">
  <num>32-131.04</num>
  <heading>Certification.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An employer may require that paid leave under § 32-131.02(b) for 3 or more consecutive days be supported by reasonable certification.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reasonable certification may include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A signed document from a health care provider, as defined in § 32-501(5), affirming the illness of the employee;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A police report indicating that the employee was a victim of stalking, domestic violence, or sexual abuse;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A court order; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A signed statement from a victim and witness advocate, or domestic violence counselor, as defined in § 14-310(a)(2), affirming that the employee is involved in legal action related to stalking, domestic violence, or sexual abuse.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If certification is required by an employer, the employee shall provide a copy of the certification to the employer upon the employee's return to work.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This chapter shall not require a health care professional to disclose information in violation of section 1177 of the Social Security Act, approved August 21, 1996 (110 Stat. 2029; 42 U.S.C. § 1320d-6), or the regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (110 Stat. 2033; 42 U.S.C. § 1320d-2, note).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All information provided to the employer under § 32-131.02 shall not be disclosed by the employer, except to the extent that the disclosure is:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Requested or consented to by the employee;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Ordered by a court or administrative agency; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Otherwise required by applicable federal or local law.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-152, § 5, 55 DCR 3452.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-152</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-152, see notes following § 32-131.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
