<level type="section">
  <num>4-1303.09</num>
  <heading>Voluntary Foster Care Registry Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Voluntary Foster Care Registry Fund ("VFCR Fund"), into which shall be deposited all fees collected pursuant to § 4-1303.08(c)(2)(A) and any gift or appropriation intended to assist in the funding of the Voluntary Foster Care Registry, which shall be solely used to cover the costs of administering the Voluntary Foster Care Registry.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the VFCR Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the purpose set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 309, as added Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-230, § 301(b), 57 DCR 6951.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-230 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Repeal of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 110 of D.C. Law 19-226 repealed D.C. Law 18-230, § 701.</text>
      <text>Section 402(b) of D.C. Law 19-226 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary repeal of D.C. Law 18-230, § 701, see § 110 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012, 59 DCR 12478).</text>
      <text>For temporary repeal of D.C. Law 18-230, § 701, see § 110 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-230</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-230, see notes following § 4-301.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 701 of D.C. Law 18-230 provided: "Sec. 701. Applicability. Title III of this act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan."</text>
      <text>The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined, as of February 15, 2012, that the fiscal effect of Title III of D.C. Law 18-230 has not been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by title III of D.C. Law 18-230, are not in effect.</text>
      <text>The Budget Director of the Council of the District of Columbia has determined, as of October 10, 2012, that the fiscal effect of Title III of D.C. Law 18-230 has been included in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore, the provisions of this section, enacted by title III of D.C. Law 18-230, are in effect. Section 110 of emergency D.C. Act 19-482 repealed section 701 of D.C. Law 18-230.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
