<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-307</num>
  <heading>Lien of carrier.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-307</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A carrier has a lien on the goods covered by a bill of lading for charges subsequent to the date of its receipt of the goods for storage or transportation (including demurrage and terminal charges) and for expenses necessary for preservation of the goods incident to their transportation or reasonably incurred in their sale pursuant to law. But against a purchaser for value of a negotiable bill of lading a carrier's lien is limited to charges stated in the bill or the applicable tariffs, or if no charges are stated then to a reasonable charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>A lien for charges and expenses under subsection (1) on goods which the carrier was required by law to receive for transportation is effective against the consignor or any person entitled to the goods unless the carrier had notice that the consignor lacked authority to subject the goods to such charges and expenses. Any other lien under subsection (1) is effective against the consignor and any person who permitted the bailor to have control or possession of the goods unless the carrier had notice that the bailor lacked such authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A carrier loses his lien on any goods which he voluntarily delivers or which he unjustifiably refuses to deliver.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 725, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Sections 27 through 32, Uniform Warehouse Receipts Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Rewritten; lien extended to carrier. Lien of common carrier validated unless carrier had notice that consignor lacked authority to subject the goods to charges and expenses. Where the carrier is not required by law to receive the goods for transportation, lien validated against anyone who permitted the bailor to have possession even if he had no real or apparent authority.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>The section is intended to give carriers a specific statutory lien for charges and expenses similar to that given to warehousemen by the first sentence of Section 7-209. But since carriers do not commonly claim a lien for charges in relation to other goods or lend money on the security of goods in their hands, provisions for a general lien or a security interest similar to those in Section 7-209(1) and (2) are omitted. See Comment to Section 7-105. Since the lien given by this section is specific, and the storage or transportation often preserves or increases the value of the goods, subsection (2) validates the lien against anyone who permitted the bailor to have possession of the goods. Where the carrier is required to receive the goods for transportation, the owner's interest may be subjected to charges and expenses arising out of deposit of his goods by a thief. Cf. Section 9- 310. The crucial mental element is the carrier's knowledge or reason to know of the bailor's lack of authority.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Sections 7-209, 9-102(2) and 9-310.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Bill of lading". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Consignor". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Purchaser". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Value". Section 1-201.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-307.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-307.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
