<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-301</num>
  <heading>Liability for non-receipt or misdescription; "said to contain"; "shipper's load and count"; improper handling.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:7-301</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A consignee of a non-negotiable bill who has given value in good faith or a holder to whom a negotiable bill has been duly negotiated relying in either case upon the description therein of the goods, or upon the date therein shown, may recover from the issuer damages caused by the misdating of the bill or the non-receipt or misdescription of the goods, except to the extent that the document indicates that the issuer does not know whether any part or all of the goods in fact were received or conform to the description, as where the description is in terms of marks or labels or kind, quantity, or condition or the receipt or description is qualified by "contents or condition of contents of packages unknown", "said to contain", "shipper's weight, load and count" or the like, if such indication be true.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>When goods are loaded by an issuer who is a common carrier, the issuer must count the packages of goods if package freight and ascertain the kind and quantity if bulk freight. In such cases "shipper's weight, load and count" or other words indicating that the description was made by the shipper are ineffective except as to freight concealed by packages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>When bulk freight is loaded by a shipper who makes available to the issuer adequate facilities for weighing such freight, an issuer who is a common carrier must ascertain the kind and quantity within a reasonable time after receiving the written request of the shipper to do so. In such cases "shipper's weight" or other words of like purport are ineffective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The issuer may by inserting in the bill the words "shipper's weight, load and count" or other words of like purport indicate that the goods were loaded by the shipper; and if such statement be true the issuer shall not be liable for damages caused by the improper loading. But their omission does not imply liability for such damages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The shipper shall be deemed to have guaranteed to the issuer the accuracy at the time of shipment of the description, marks, labels, number, kind, quantity, condition and weight, as furnished by him; and the shipper shall indemnify the issuer against damage caused by inaccuracies in such particulars. The right of the issuer to such indemnity shall in no way limit his responsibility and liability under the contract of carriage to any person other than the shipper.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 723, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1; Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 27(ww), 44 DCR 1271.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Section 23, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Rewritten in part.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>1. The provision as to misdating in subsection (1) conforms to the policy of the amendment to the Federal Bills of Lading Act by 44 Stat. 1450 (1927), as amended 49 U.S.C. Section 102, after the holding in Browne v. Union Pac. R. Co., 113 Kan. 726, 216 P. 299 (1923), affirmed on other grounds, 267 U.S. 255, 45 S.Ct. 315, 69 L.Ed. 601 (1925). Subsections (2) and (3) conform to the policy of the Federal Bills of Lading Act, 49 U.S.C. Sections 100, 101, and the laws of several states. See, e.g., N.Y.Pers.Prop.Law Section 209; Report of N.Y. Law Revision Commission, N.Y.Leg.Doc. (1941) No. 65(F).</text>
        <text>2. The language of the old Uniform Act suggested that a carrier is ordinarily liable for damage caused by improper loading, but may relieve himself of liability by disclosing on the bill that shipper actually loaded. A more accurate statement of the law is that the carrier is not liable for losses caused by act or default of the shipper, which would include improper loading. There is some question whether under present law a carrier is liable even to a good faith purchaser of a negotiable bill for such losses, if the shipper's faulty loading in fact caused the loss. It is this doubtful liability which subsection (4) permits the carrier to bar by disclosure of shipper's loading. There is no implication that decisions such as Modern Tool Corp. v. Pennsylvania R. Co., 100 F.Supp. 595 (D.N.J.1951), are disapproved.</text>
        <text>3. This section is a simplified restatement of existing law as to the method by which a bailee may avoid responsibility for the accuracy of descriptions which are made by or in reliance upon information furnished by the depositor or shipper. The issuer is liable on documents issued by an agent, contrary to instructions of his principal without receiving goods. No disclaimer of this liability is permitted since it is not a matter either of the care of the goods or their description.</text>
        <text>4. The shipper's erroneous report to the carrier concerning the goods may cause damage to the carrier. Subsection (5) therefore provides appropriate indemnity.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross References:</heading>
        <text>Sections 7-203 and 7-309.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Bill of lading". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Consignee". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Document". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Duly negotiate". Section 7-501.</text>
        <text>"Good faith". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Holder". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Issuer". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Notice". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Party". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Purchaser". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Receipt of goods". Section 2-103.</text>
        <text>"Value". Section 1-201.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-301.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-301.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 11-255, the "Second Technical Amendments Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-905, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-519 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-255 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
