<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-305</num>
  <heading>Destination bills.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-305</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Instead of issuing a bill of lading to the consignor at the place of shipment a carrier may at the request of the consignor procure the bill to be issued at destination or at any other place designated in the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Upon request of anyone entitled as against the carrier to control the goods while in transit and on surrender of any outstanding bill of lading or other receipt covering such goods, the issuer may procure a substitute bill to be issued at any place designated in the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 725, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> None.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes:</heading>
        <text>This proposal is designed to facilitate the use of order bills in connection with fast shipments. Use of order bills on high speed shipments is impeded by the fact that the goods may arrive at destination before the documents, so that no one is ready to take delivery from the carrier. This is especially inconvenient for carriers by truck and air, who do not have terminal facilities where shipments can be held to await consignee's appearance. Order bills would be useful to take advantage of bank collection. This may be preferable to C.O.D. shipment in which the carrier, e.g. a truck driver, is the collecting and remitting agent. Financing of shipments under this plan would be handled as follows: seller at San Francisco delivers the goods to an airline with instructions to issue a bill in New York to a named bank. Seller receives a receipt embodying this undertaking to issue a destination bill. Airline wires its New York freight agent to issue the bill as instructed by the seller. Seller wires the New York bank a draft on buyer. New York bank indorses the bill to buyer when he honors the draft. Normally seller would act through his own bank in San Francisco, which would extend him credit in reliance on the airline's contract to deliver a bill to the order of its New York correspondent. This section is entirely permissive; it imposes no duty to issue such bills. Whether a connecting carrier will act as issuing agent is left to agreement between carriers.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Bill of lading". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Consignor". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Issuer". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Receipt of goods". Section 2-103.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-305.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-305.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
