<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-304</num>
  <heading>Bills of lading in a set.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:7-304</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Except where customary in overseas transportation, a bill of lading must not be issued in a set of parts. The issuer is liable for damages caused by violation of this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Where a bill of lading is lawfully drawn in a set of parts, each of which is numbered and expressed to be valid only if the goods have not been delivered against any other part, the whole of the parts constitute one bill.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Where a bill of lading is lawfully issued in a set of parts and different parts are negotiated to different persons, the title of the holder to whom the first due negotiation is made prevails as to both the document and the goods even though any later holder may have received the goods from the carrier in good faith and discharged the carrier's obligation by surrender of his part.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Any person who negotiates or transfers a single part of a bill of lading drawn in a set is liable to holders of that part as if it were the whole set.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The bailee is obliged to deliver in accordance with part 4 of this article against the first presented part of a bill of lading lawfully drawn in a set. Such delivery discharges the bailee's obligation on the whole bill.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 725, Pub. L. 88-243, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Section 6, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> This section adds to existing legislation, which merely prohibits bills in a set in ordinary domestic trade, a statement of the legal effect of a lawfully issued set.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>The statement of the legal effect of a lawfully issued set is in accord with existing commercial law relating to maritime and other overseas bills. This law has been codified in the Hague and Warsaw Conventions and in the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act, the provisions of which would ordinarily govern in situations where bills in a set are recognized by this Article.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross Reference:</heading>
        <text>Section 10-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Bailee". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Bill of lading". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Delivery". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Document". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Duly negotiate". Section 7-501.</text>
        <text>"Good faith". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Holder". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Issuer". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Overseas". Section 2-323.</text>
        <text>"Person". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Receipt of goods". Section 2-103.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:7-304.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 28:7-304.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
