<level type="section">
  <num>28:7-309</num>
  <heading>Duty of care; contractual limitation of carrier's liability.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:7-309</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>A carrier who issues a bill of lading whether negotiable or non-negotiable must exercise the degree of care in relation to the goods which a reasonably careful man would exercise under like circumstances. This subsection does not repeal or change any law or rule of law which imposes liability upon a common carrier for damages not caused by its negligence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Damages may be limited by a provision that the carrier's liability shall not exceed a value stated in the document if the carrier's rates are dependent upon value and the consignor by the carrier's tariff is afforded an opportunity to declare a higher value or a value as lawfully provided in the tariff, or where no tariff is filed he is otherwise advised of such opportunity; but no such limitation is effective with respect to the carrier's liability for conversion to its own use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Reasonable provisions as to the time and manner of presenting claims and instituting actions based on the shipment may be included in a bill of lading or tariff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 726, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text><text b="True">Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</text> Section 3, Uniform Bills of Lading Act.</text>
      <text><text b="True">Changes:</text> Consolidated and rewritten.</text>
      <level>
        <heading>Purposes of Changes:</heading>
        <text>The old uniform act provided that bills of lading could not contain terms impairing the obligation of reasonable care. Whether this is violated by a stipulation that in case of loss the bailee's liability is limited to stated amounts has been much controverted. For interstate rail transportation the matter is settled by the Carmack Amendment to the Interstate Commerce Act (See 49 U.S.C.A. § 20(11) ). The present section is a generalized version of the Interstate Commerce Act provisions. The obligation of due care is radically qualified, in the case of maritime bills and international airbills, by federal legislation and treaty. All this special legislation would remain in effect even if Congress enacts this Code, including the present Article. See Section 7-103.</text>
        <text>Subsection (1) does not impair any rule of law imposing the liability of an insurer on a common carrier in intrastate commerce. Subsection (2), however, applies to such liability as well as to liability based on negligence. The entire section is subject under Section 7-103 to applicable provisions in filed tariffs, such as the common disclaimer of responsibility for undeclared articles of extraordinary value, hidden from view. Tariffs which lawfully provide a maximum unit value beyond which goods are not taken fall within the same principle, and are expressly covered by the words "value as lawfully provided in the tariff."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Cross Reference:</heading>
        <text>Section 7-103.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Definitional Cross References:</heading>
        <text>"Action". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Bill of lading". Section 1-201.</text>
        <text>"Consignor". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Document". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Goods". Section 7-102.</text>
        <text>"Value". Section 1-201.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:7-309.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 28:7-309.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
