<level type="section">
  <num>47-1059</num>
  <heading>American College of Cardiology and American College of Cardiology Foundation.</heading>
  <text>Property owned, occupied, and used by the American College of Cardiology and the American College of Cardiology Foundation, is hereby exempt from all taxation so long as the property continues to be so owned and occupied, and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of § 47-1002 and § 47-1007, providing for exemption of certain real properties.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-186, § 2, 51 DCR 5961.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <text>For Temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2 of American College of Cardiology Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption Temporary Act of 2003 (D.C. Law 15-45, December 9, 2003, law notification 51 DCR 1780).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of the American College of Cardiology Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-120, July 29, 2003, 50 DCR 6613).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of American College of Cardiology Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-218, November 7, 2003, 50 DCR 10043).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of American College of Cardiology and American College of Cardiology Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-466, July 19, 2004, 51 DCR 7581).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 15-186</heading>
      <text>Law 15-186, the "American College of Cardiology and the American College of Cardiology Foundation Real Property Tax Exemption Act of 2004", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-307, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 20, 2004, and May 4, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 21, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-438 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-186 became effective on September 8, 2004.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7053 of D.C. Law 17-219 repealed section 3 of D.C. Law 15-186.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
