<level type="section">
  <num>46-305.02</num>
  <heading>Employer's compliance with income-withholding order of another state.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-345.2</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of an income-withholding order, the obligor's employer shall immediately provide a copy of the order to the obligor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The employer shall treat an income-withholding order issued in another state which appears regular on its face as if it had been issued by a tribunal of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section and § 46- 305.03, the employer shall withhold and distribute the funds as directed in the withholding order by complying with terms of the order which specify:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The duration and amount of periodic payments of current child support stated as a sum certain;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person designated to receive payments and the address to which the payments are to be forwarded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Medical support, whether in the form of periodic cash payment stated as a sum certain, or ordering the obligor to provide health insurance coverage for the child under a policy available through the obligor's employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amount of periodic payments of fees and costs for a support enforcement agency, the issuing tribunal, and the obligee's attorney stated as sums certain; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The amount of periodic payments of arrearages and interest on arrearages stated as sums certain.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An employer shall comply with the law of the state of the obligor's principal place of employment for withholding from income with respect to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The employer's fee for processing an income-withholding order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount permitted to be withheld from the obligor's income; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The times within which the employer must implement the withholding order and forward the child support payment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 502, as added July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-131, § 2(i), 45 DCR 2924; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(e)(2), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-345.2.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137, in par. (c)(2), deleted "or agency" following ''person".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Uniform Interstate Family Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-94, April 29, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 2785).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 2(i) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-225, December 23, 1997, 45 DCR 151), and § 2(i) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-310, March 20, 1998, 45 DCR 1950).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-131, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Application of Law 12-131: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46- 301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 502 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
