<level type="section">
  <num>46-305.03</num>
  <heading>Employer's compliance with 2 or more income-withholding orders.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-345.3</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>If an obligor's employer receives 2 or more income-withholding orders with respect to the earnings of the same obligor, the employer satisfies the terms of the orders if the employer complies with the law of the state of the obligor's principal place of employment to establish the priorities for withholding and allocating income withheld for 2 or more child-support obligees.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 503, as added July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-131, § 2(i), 45 DCR 2924; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(e)(3), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-345.3.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137 rewrote section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"§ 46-305.03. Compliance with multiple income-withholding orders.</text>
        <text>"If an obligor's employer receives multiple income-withholding orders with respect to the earnings of the same obligor, the employer satisfies the terms of the multiple orders if the employer complies with the law of the state of the obligor's principal place of employment to establish the priorities for withholding and allocating income withheld for multiple child support obligees."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Uniform Interstate Family Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-94, April 29, 1998, law notification 45 DCR 2785).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 2(i) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-225, December 23, 1997, 45 DCR 151), and § 2(i) of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-310, March 20, 1998, 45 DCR 1950).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-131, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Application of Law 12-131: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46- 301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 503 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
