<level type="section">
  <num>28:8-601</num>
  <heading>Savings clause.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 28:8-601</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>This article does not affect an action or proceeding commenced before this subtitle takes effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a security interest in a security is perfected at the date this subtitle takes effect, and the action by which the security interest was perfected would suffice to perfect a security interest under this article, no further action is required to continue perfection. If a security interest in a security is perfected at the date this article takes effect but the action by which the security interest was perfected would not suffice to perfect a security interest under this article, the security interest remains perfected for a period of four months after the effective date and continues perfected thereafter if appropriate action to perfect under this article is taken within that period. If a security interest is perfected at the date this article takes effect and the security interest can be perfected by filing under this article, a financing statement signed by the secured party instead of the debtor may be filed within that period to continue perfection or thereafter to perfect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, ยง 2, 44 DCR 1087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>UNIFORM COMMERCIAL CODE COMMENT</heading>
      <text>The revision of Article 8 should present few significant transition problems. Although the revision involves significant changes in terminology and analysis, the substantive rules are, in large measure, based upon the current practices and are consistent with results that could be reached, albeit at times with some struggle, by proper interpretation of the rules of present law. Thus, the new rules can be applied, without significant dislocations, to transactions and events that occurred prior to enactment.</text>
      <text>The enacting provisions should not, whether by applicability, transition, or savings clause language, attempt to provide that old Article 8 continues to apply to "transactions," "events," "rights," "duties," "liabilities," or the like that occurred or accrued before the effective date and that new Article 8 applies to those that occur or accrue after the effective date. The reason for revising Article 8 and corresponding provisions of Article 9 is the concern that the provisions of old Article 8 could be interpreted or misinterpreted to yield results that impede the safe and efficient operation of the national system for the clearance and settlement of securities transactions. Accordingly, it is not the case that any effort should be made to preserve the applicability of old Article 8 to transactions and events that occurred before the effective date.</text>
      <text>Only two circumstances seem to warrant continued application of rules of old Article 8. First, to avoid disruption in the conduct of litigation, it may make sense to provide for continued application of the old Article 8 rules to lawsuits pending before the effective date. Second, there are some limited circumstances in which prior law permitted perfection of security interests by methods that are not provided for in the revised version. Section 8- 313(1)(h) (1978) permitted perfection of security interests in securities held through intermediaries by notice to the intermediary. Under Revised Articles 8 and 9, security interests can be perfected in such cases by control, which requires the agreement of the intermediary, or by filing. It is likely that secured parties who relied strongly on such collateral under prior law did not simply send notices but obtained agreements from the intermediaries that would suffice for control under the new rules. However, it seems appropriate to include a provision that gives a secured creditor some opportunity after the effective date to perfect in this or any other case in which there is doubt whether the method of perfection used under prior law would be sufficient under the new version.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:8-601.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 11-240, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Revision Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-576, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-500 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-240 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>The phrase "before this subtitle takes effect," which appears in subsection (a), is a reference to the effective date of the Act of December 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 631, Pub. L. 88-243. Pursuant to ยง 16 of Pub. L. 88-243, the act became effective on January 1, 1965.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
