<level type="section">
  <num>19-1310.05</num>
  <heading>Limitation of action against trustee.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A beneficiary may not commence a proceeding against a trustee for breach of trust more than one year after the date the beneficiary or a representative of the beneficiary was sent a report that adequately disclosed the existence of a potential claim for breach of trust and informed the beneficiary of the time allowed for commencing a proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A report adequately discloses the existence of a potential claim for breach of trust if it provides sufficient information so that the beneficiary or representative knows of the potential claim or should have inquired into its existence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If subsection (a) of this section does not apply, a judicial proceeding by a beneficiary against a trustee for breach of trust must be commenced within 3 years after the first to occur of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The removal, resignation, or death of the trustee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The termination of the beneficiary's interest in the trust; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The termination of the trust.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-104, ยง 2(b), 51 DCR 208.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 15-104, see notes following ยง 19-1301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon ยง 1005 of the Uniform Trust Code. See 7C, Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
