<level type="section">
  <num>22-2511</num>
  <heading>Presence in a motor vehicle containing a firearm.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It is unlawful for a person to be voluntarily in a motor vehicle if that person knows that a firearm is in the vehicle, unless the firearm is being lawfully carried or lawfully transported.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be an affirmative defense to this offense, which the defendant must prove by a preponderance of the evidence, that the defendant, upon learning that a firearm was in the vehicle, had the specific intent to immediately leave the vehicle, but did not have a reasonable opportunity under the circumstances to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who violates this section shall be fined not more than and, in addition, may be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the violation of this section occurs after a person has been convicted in the District of Columbia of a violation of § 22-4504(a), or of a felony, either in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction, the person shall be fined not more than and, in addition, may be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No person shall be sentenced consecutively for this offense and any other firearms offense arising out of the same incident. Any conviction under this section and any conviction for carrying or possessing the same firearm on the same occasion shall be considered as one conviction for purposes of any application of repeat offender sentencing provisions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 10, 2009, D.C. Law 18-88, § 101, 56 DCR 7413; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 213(a), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" for "not more than $5,000" in (c)(1), and for "$10,000" in (c)(2).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-181, August 6, 2009, 56 DCR 6903).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-227, October 21, 2009, 56 DCR 8668).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-88</heading>
      <text>Law 18-88, the "Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Amendment Act of 2009", as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-151, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The bill as adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 31, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 26, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-189 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-88 became effective on December 10, 2009.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
