<level type="section">
  <num>29-401.04</num>
  <heading>Reference to extrinsic facts in plans or filed documents.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Filed record" means a record filed with the Mayor under any provision of this chapter except ยง 29-102.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Plan" means a plan of domestication, business conversion, entity conversion, merger or membership exchange.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever a provision of this chapter permits any of the terms of a plan or a filed record to be dependent on facts objectively ascertainable outside the plan or filed record, the following rules apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The manner in which the facts will operate upon the terms of the plan or filed record shall be set forth in the plan or filed record.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The facts may include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any of the following that is available in a nationally recognized news or information medium either in print or electronically:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Statistical or market indices;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Market prices of any security or group of securities;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Interest rates;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Currency exchange rates; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Similar economic or financial data;</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A determination or action by any person or body, including the corporation or any other party to a plan or filed record; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The terms of, or actions taken under, an agreement to which the corporation is a party, or any other agreement or record.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
