<level type="section">
  <num>1-328.14</num>
  <heading>Requirements for administration of grant programs.</heading>
  <text>A grantor administering a grant program covered by this part shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Within 30 days from the closing date of the grant application process, provide notification to all applicants of the acceptance or rejection of their applications for the grant funds; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Maintain records of any written communications as well as a description of any other communications, including telephonic or face-to-face communications, between the grantor and any District government official or staff regarding:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The development of the selection criteria or eligibility requirements;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Selection by the grantor of a grantee; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Issues with a grantee's compliance with grant-program requirements.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Records required under this paragraph shall be provided, upon request, within a reasonable time, to the Mayor, or his or her designee, or to a member of the Council.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1095, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-328.13.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1095 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 1095 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-328.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 1091 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle J of Title I of the act may be cited as the "Grant Administration Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
