<level type="section">
  <num>46-302.02</num>
  <heading>Duration of personal jurisdiction.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-342.2</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>Personal jurisdiction acquired by a tribunal of the District in a proceeding under this chapter or other law of the District relating to a support order continues as long as a tribunal of the District has continuing, exclusive jurisdiction to modify its order or continuing jurisdiction to enforce its order as provided by §§ 46-302.05, 46-302.06, and 46-302.11.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 202, 42 DCR 6748; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(b)(1)(C), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-342.2.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137 rewrote section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"§ 46-302.02. Procedure when exercising jurisdiction over nonresident.</text>
        <text>"The Family Division, if it is exercising personal jurisdiction over a nonresident under § 46-302.01, may apply § 46-303.15 (special rules of evidence and procedure) to receive evidence from another state, and § 46-303.17 (assistance with discovery) to obtain discovery through a tribunal of another state. In all other respects, subchapters III through VII of this chapter do not apply and the tribunal shall apply the procedural and substantive law of the District, including the rules on choice of law other than those established by this chapter."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 202 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
