<level type="section">
  <num>46-302.01</num>
  <heading>Bases for jurisdiction over nonresident.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-342.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In a proceeding to establish or enforce a support order or to determine parentage, the Family Division may exercise personal jurisdiction over a nonresident individual or the individual's guardian or conservator, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual is personally served with notice within the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual submits to the jurisdiction of the District by consent in a record, by entering a general appearance, or by filing a responsive document having the effect of waiving any contest to personal jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The individual resided with the child in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The individual resided in the District and provided prenatal expenses or support for the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The child resides in the District as a result of the acts or directives of the individual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The individual engaged in sexual intercourse in the District and the child may have been conceived by that act of intercourse; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>There is any other basis consistent with the laws of the District and the Constitution of the United States for the exercise of personal jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The bases of personal jurisdiction set forth in subsection (a) of this section or in any other law of the District may not be used to acquire personal jurisdiction for a tribunal of the District to modify a child support order of another state unless the requirements of §§ 46-306.11 and 46-306.15 are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 201, 42 DCR 6748; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(b)(1)(B), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-342.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137, designated the existing text as subsec. (a); in the lead-in language to subsec. (a), substituted "establish or enforce" for "establish, enforce, or modify"; in par. (a)(2), substituted "consent in a record" for "consent"; and added subsec. (b).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 201 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
