<level type="section">
  <num>46-302.06</num>
  <heading>Continuing jurisdiction to enforce child-support order.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 30-342.6</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A tribunal of the District that has issued a child-support order consistent with the law of the District may serve as an initiating tribunal to request a tribunal of another state to enforce:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The order if the order is the controlling order and has not been modified by a tribunal of another state that assumed jurisdiction pursuant to a law substantially similar to this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A money judgment for arrears of support and interest on the order accrued before a determination that an order of another state is the controlling order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A tribunal of the District having continuing jurisdiction over a support order may act as a responding tribunal to enforce the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-81, § 206, 42 DCR 6748; June 22, 2006, D.C. Law 16-137, § 2(b)(2)(D), 53 DCR 3634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 30-342.6.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 16-137 rewrote section, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"§ 46-302.06. Enforcement and modification of support order by tribunal having continuing jurisdiction.</text>
        <text>"(a) A tribunal of the District may serve as an initiating tribunal to request a tribunal of another state to enforce or modify a support order issued in that state.</text>
        <text>"(b) A tribunal of the District having continuing, exclusive jurisdiction over a support order may act as a responding tribunal to enforce or modify the order. If a party subject to the continuing, exclusive jurisdiction of the tribunal no longer resides in the issuing state, in subsequent proceedings the tribunal may apply § 46-303.15 (special rules of evidence and procedure) to receive evidence from another state and § 46-303.17 (assistance with discovery) to obtain discovery through a tribunal of another state.</text>
        <text>"(c) A tribunal of the District which lacks continuing, exclusive jurisdiction over a spousal support order may not serve as a responding tribunal to modify a spousal support order of another state."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 11-81, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 16-137, see notes following § 46-301.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
        <text>Applicability: Section 3 of D.C. Law 16-137 provides: "This act shall apply as of April 1, 2007."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law</heading>
        <text>This section is based upon § 206 of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (2001 Act). See Volume 9, Part IB Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition, or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
