<level type="section">
  <num>29-408.06</num>
  <heading>Articles of amendment.</heading>
  <text>After an amendment to the articles of incorporation has been adopted and approved in the manner required by this chapter and by the articles of incorporation, the nonprofit corporation shall deliver to the Mayor, for filing, articles of amendment, which shall set forth:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The name of the corporation;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The text of the amendment adopted;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>If the amendment provides for an exchange, reclassification, or cancellation of memberships, provisions for implementing the amendment if not contained in the amendment itself, which may be made dependent upon facts objectively ascertainable outside the articles of amendment in accordance with ยง 29-401.04;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The date of the amendment's adoption; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>If the amendment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Was adopted by the incorporators, board of directors, or a designated body without member approval, a statement that the amendment was adopted by the incorporators or by the board of directors or designated body, as the case may be, and that member approval was not required; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Required approval by the members, a statement that the amendment was duly approved by the members in the manner required by this chapter and by the articles of incorporation and bylaws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 29-408.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
