<level type="section">
  <num>29-704.04</num>
  <heading>General partner's liability.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, all general partners shall be liable jointly and severally for all obligations of the limited partnership unless otherwise agreed by the claimant or provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person that becomes a general partner of an existing limited partnership shall not be personally liable for an obligation of a limited partnership incurred before the person became a general partner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An obligation of a limited partnership incurred while the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership, whether arising in contract, tort, or otherwise, shall be solely the obligation of the limited partnership. A general partner shall not be personally liable, directly or indirectly, by way of contribution or otherwise, for such an obligation solely by reason of being or acting as a general partner. This subsection shall apply despite anything inconsistent in the partnership agreement that existed immediately before the consent required to become a limited liability limited partnership under ยง 29-704.06(b)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 404 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
