<level type="section">
  <num>29-704.08</num>
  <heading>General standards of general partner's conduct.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The only fiduciary duties that a general partner shall have to the limited partnership and the other partners are the duties of loyalty and care under subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A general partner's duty of loyalty to the limited partnership and the other partners shall be limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To account to the limited partnership and hold as trustee for it any property, profit, or benefit derived by the general partner in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership's activities or derived from a use by the general partner of limited partnership property, including the appropriation of a limited partnership opportunity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To refrain from dealing with the limited partnership in the conduct or winding up of the limited partnership's activities as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the limited partnership; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To refrain from competing with the limited partnership in the conduct or winding up of the limited partnership's activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A general partner's duty of care to the limited partnership and the other partners in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership's activities shall be limited to refraining from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A general partner shall discharge the duties to the partnership and the other partners under this chapter or under the partnership agreement and exercise any rights consistently with the obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A general partner shall not violate a duty or obligation under this chapter or under the partnership agreement merely because the general partner's conduct furthers the general partner's own interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Uniform Law:</heading>
        <text>This section is based on ยง 408 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act). See Vol. 6A , Uniform Laws Annotated, Master Edition or ULA Database on Westlaw.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
