<level type="toc">
  <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
  <num>I</num>
  <heading>Payment and Collection of Wages</heading>
  <text>
    <span style="font-weight: bold; ">§ I. Definitions.</span>
  </text>
  <text>Whenever used in this chapter:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Employer" includes every individual, partnership, firm, association, corporation, the legal representative of a deceased individual, or the receiver, trustee, or successor of an individual, firm, partnership, association, or corporation, employing any person in the District of Columbia; provided, that the word "employer" shall not include the government of the United States, the government of the District of Columbia, or any agency of either of said governments, or any employer subject to the Railway Labor Act (45 U.S.C. § 151 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Employee" shall include any person suffered or permitted to work by an employer except any person employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity (as such terms are defined and delimited by regulations promulgated by the Council of the District of Columbia).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Wages" means all monetary compensation after lawful deductions, owed by an employer, whether the amount owed is determined on a time, task, piece, commission, or other basis of calculation. The term "wages" includes a:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Bonus;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Fringe benefits paid in cash;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Overtime premium; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Other remuneration promised or owed:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Pursuant to a contract for employment, whether written or oral;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Pursuant to a contract between an employer and another person or entity; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Pursuant to District or federal law.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Mayor" means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent or agents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Working day" means any day exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, or legal holidays.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, § 1; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2062(a), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-220.08.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 36-101.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 36-601.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote (3).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2062(a) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2062(a) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 2061 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle G of Title II of the act may be cited as the "Wage Theft Prevention Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 2(a) of D.C. Law 19-300 designated the existing provisions of Chapter 13 as subchapter I, and enacted subchapter II.</text>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <text>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(285) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 (D.C. Code, § 1-207.11), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, § 1-207.14(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1302.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1303.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1304.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1305.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1306.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1307.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1308.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1309.xml"/>
  <ns0:include xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="32-1310.xml"/>
</level>
