<level type="section">
  <num>47-3410</num>
  <heading>Effect of District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 47-3410</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If any provision of the District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982, including any amendment made by the District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of the District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982, including the remaining amendments, and the application of such provisions to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The repeal or amendment by the District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982 of any provision of law shall not affect any act done or any right accrued or accruing under such provision of law before July 24, 1982, or any suit or proceeding had or commenced before July 24, 1982, but all such rights and liabilities under such acts shall continue and may be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent, as if such repeal or amendment had not been made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All offenses committed, and all penalties incurred, prior to July 24, 1982, under any provisions of law repealed or amended, may be prosecuted and punished in the same manner and with the same effect as if the District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982 had not been enacted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 24, 1982, D.C. Law 4-131, ยง 502, 29 DCR 2415; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, ยง 2, 44 DCR 1575.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 47-3410.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 4-131, the "District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-257, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 27, 1982, and May 11, 1982, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 1, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-196 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>The "District of Columbia Tax Enforcement Act of 1982," referred to throughout this section, is D.C. Law 4-131.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
