<level type="section">
  <num>47-3409</num>
  <heading>Divulging information obtained from Internal Revenue Service prohibited; penalties.</heading>
  <text>Except in accordance with proper judicial order or as otherwise provided by law, it shall be unlawful for the Mayor or any person having an administrative duty under this chapter to divulge or make known in any manner any information obtained from the Internal Revenue Service in accordance with any provisions of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, as amended. Any violation of the provisions of this section shall subject the offender to a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or imprisonment for 90 days.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 693, ch. 690, title VII, § 5; May 16, 1938, 52 Stat. 370, ch. 223, § 7; enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 286(z), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-3409.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 47-2504.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01]" for "of $300".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 286(z) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013, 60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>Law 19-317, the "Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-214. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Oct. 16, 2012, and Nov. 1, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Jan. 23, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-641 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-317 became effective on June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, referred to in this section, is 50 Stat. 673, approved August 17, 1937.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
