<level type="section">
  <num>10-551.07a</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Facilities Service Request Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a lapsing account to be known as the Facilities Service Request Fund ("Fund"). All funds received by the Department from non-District government tenants in District government facilities for facility- related services, including maintenance, janitorial, security, construction, or other services, provided by the Department in accordance with this chapter shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of each fiscal year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be administered by the Department, and shall be used for facility-related services at real property owned or leased by the District of Columbia and under the control of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, ยง 1028a, as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, ยง 1022, 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-168 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see ยง 1022 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
