<level type="section">
  <num>10-551.04</num>
  <heading>Transfers.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All functions assigned, authorities delegated, positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available to the Department of Real Estate Services and the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization are transferred to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All functions assigned, authorities delegated, positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available for capital construction and real property management functions of other subordinate executive branch agencies, except for the District Department of Transportation, as the Mayor considers necessary to effectuate this chapter, are transferred to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All functions assigned, authorities delegated, positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for its asset management program, including the DC USA Garage, are transferred to the Department; provided, that with respect to funds which are deposited or held in special purpose revenue funds and fund the asset management program, the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Department to pay for the asset management program, including the DC USA Garage, from such special purpose revenue funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, ยง 1025, 58 DCR 6226; Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, ยง 70(b), 59 DCR 6190.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-171 substituted "this subtitle" for "this act" [translated as "this chapter"] in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see ยง 1005 of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011, 58 DCR 5599).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-21</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 19-21, see notes under ยง 10-551.01</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-171</heading>
      <text>Law 19-171, the "Technical Amendments Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-397. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Mar. 20, 2012, and Apr. 17, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 23, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-376 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-171 became effective on September 26, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
