<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.51</num>
  <heading>Permissible indemnification.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a nonprofit corporation may indemnify an individual who is a party to a proceeding because he or she is or was a director against liability incurred in the proceeding if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Acted in good faith;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reasonably believed:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In the case of conduct in an official capacity, that the conduct was in the best interests of the corporation; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In all other cases, that the individual's conduct was at least not opposed to the best interests of the corporation; and</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>In the case of any criminal proceeding, had no reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was unlawful; or</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual engaged in conduct for which broader indemnification has been made permissible or obligatory under a provision of the articles of incorporation, as authorized by ยง 29-402.02(b)(8).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A director's conduct with respect to an employee benefit plan for a purpose the director reasonably believed to be in the interests of the participants in and the beneficiaries of the plan is conduct that satisfies the requirement of subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The termination of a proceeding by judgment, order, settlement, or conviction, or upon a plea of nolo contendere or its equivalent, shall not, of itself, determinative that the director did not meet the relevant standard of conduct described in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Unless ordered by a court under ยง 29-406.54(a)(3), a nonprofit corporation shall not indemnify a director:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In connection with a proceeding by or in the right of the corporation, except for reasonable expenses incurred in connection with the proceeding if it is determined that the director has met the relevant standard of conduct under subsection (a) of this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In connection with any proceeding with respect to conduct for which the director was adjudged liable on the basis that the director received a financial benefit to which the director was not entitled, whether or not involving action in an official capacity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
