<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.56</num>
  <heading>Indemnification of officers.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation may indemnify and advance expenses under this part to an officer of the corporation who is a party to a proceeding because he or she is or was an officer of the corporation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To the same extent as a director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If he or she is an officer but not a director, to such further extent as may be provided by the articles of incorporation, the bylaws, a resolution of the board of directors, or contract, except for:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Liability in connection with a proceeding by or in the right of the corporation other than for reasonable expenses incurred in connection with the proceeding; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Liability arising out of conduct that constitutes:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Receipt by the officer of a financial benefit to which the officer is not entitled;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An intentional infliction of harm on the corporation or the members; or</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>An intentional violation of criminal law.</text>
        </level>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a)(2) of this section shall apply to an officer who is also a director if the basis on which he or she is made a party to the proceeding is an act or omission solely as an officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An officer of a corporation who is not a director shall be entitled to mandatory indemnification under § 29-406.52, and may apply to a court under § 29-406.54 for indemnification or an advance for expenses, in each case to the same extent to which a director may be entitled to indemnification or advance for expenses under those provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 29-406.50.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-378</heading>
      <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
