<level type="section">
  <num>21-2402.04</num>
  <heading>Special jurisdiction.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Even if the Superior Court lacks jurisdiction under § 21-2402.03, the court has special jurisdiction to do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Appoint a guardian in an emergency for a term not exceeding 90 days for a respondent who is physically present in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Issue a protective order with respect to real or tangible personal property located in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appoint a guardian or conservator for an incapacitated or protected person for whom a provisional order to transfer the proceeding from another state has been issued under procedures similar to § 21-2403.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a petition for the appointment of a guardian in an emergency is brought in the District of Columbia and the District was not the respondent's home state on the date the petition was filed, the Superior Court shall dismiss the proceeding at the request of the court of the home state, if any, whether dismissal is requested before or after the emergency appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-270, § 2(b), 55 DCR 11018.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 21-2402.03, § 21-2402.05, and § 21-2402.09.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 17-270</heading>
      <text>For Law 17-270, see notes following § 21-2401.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 204 of the Uniform Adult Guardianship and Protective Proceedings Jurisdiction Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
