<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-518</num>
  <heading>Cover; substitute goods.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After default by a lessor under the lease contract of the type described in § 28:2A-508(a), or, if agreed, after other default by the lessor, the lessee may cover by making any purchase or lease of or contract to purchase or lease goods in substitution for those due from the lessor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§ 28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties (§ 28:1-302 and § 28:2A-503), if a lessee's cover is by a lease agreement substantially similar to the original lease agreement and the new lease agreement is made in good faith and in a commercially reasonable manner, the lessee may recover from the lessor as damages (i) the present value, as of the date of the commencement of the term of the new lease agreements, of the rent under the new lease agreement applicable to the period of the new lease which is comparable to the then remaining term of the original lease agreement minus the present value as of the same date of the total rent for the then remaining lease term of the original lease agreement, and (ii) any incidental or consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessor's default.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a lessee's cover is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under subsection (b) of this section, or is by purchase or otherwise, the lessee may recover from the lessor as if the lessee had elected not to cover and § 28:2A-519 governs.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830; Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-299, § 4(e), 60 DCR 2634.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:2A-508 and § 28:2A-519.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2A-518.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-299 substituted "§ 28:1-302" for "§ 28:1-102(3)" in (b).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-128</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:2A-101.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-299</heading>
      <text>See note to § 28:2A-501.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
