<level type="section">
  <num>28:2A-517</num>
  <heading>Revocation of acceptance of goods.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit whose nonconformity substantially impairs its value to the lessee if the lessee has accepted it:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except in the case of a finance lease, on the reasonable assumption that its nonconformity would be cured and it has not been seasonably cured; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Without discovery of the nonconformity if the lessee's acceptances was reasonably induced either by the lessor's assurances or, except in the case of a finance lease, by the difficulty of discovery before acceptance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except in the case of a financial lease that is not a consumer lease, a lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit if the lessor defaults under the lease contract and the default substantially impairs the value of that lot or commercial unit to the lessee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the lease agreement so provides, the lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit because of other defaults by the lessor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Revocation of acceptance must occur within a reasonable time after the lessee discovers or should have discovered the ground for it and before any substantial change in condition of the goods which is not caused by the nonconformity. Revocation is not effective until the lessee notifies the lessor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A lessee who so revokes has the same rights and duties with regard to the goods involved as if the lessee had rejected them.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, ยง 2(b), 39 DCR 3830.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 28:2A-508.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 28:2A-517.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 9-128</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 9-128, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 28:2A-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
