<level type="section">
  <num>28:9-625</num>
  <heading>Remedies for secured party's failure to comply with article.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If it is established that a secured party is not proceeding in accordance with this article, a court may order or restrain collection, enforcement, or disposition of collateral on appropriate terms and conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (c), (d), and (f), a person is liable for damages in the amount of any loss caused by a failure to comply with this article. Loss caused by a failure to comply may include loss resulting from the debtor's inability to obtain, or increased costs of, alternative financing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in § 28:9-628:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person that, at the time of the failure, was a debtor, was an obligor, or held a security interest in or other lien on the collateral may recover damages under subsection (b) for its loss; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the collateral is consumer goods, a person that was a debtor or a secondary obligor at the time a secured party failed to comply with this part may recover for that failure in any event an amount not less than the credit service charge plus 10% of the principal amount of the obligation or the time-price differential plus 10% of the cash price.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A debtor whose deficiency is eliminated under § 28:9-626 may recover damages for the loss of any surplus. However, a debtor or secondary obligor whose deficiency is eliminated or reduced under § 28:9-626 may not otherwise recover under subsection (b) for noncompliance with the provisions of this part relating to collection, enforcement, disposition, or acceptance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In addition to any damages recoverable under subsection (b), the debtor, consumer obligor, or person named as a debtor in a filed record, as applicable, may recover $500 in each case from a person that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fails to comply with § 28:9-208;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fails to comply with § 28:9-209;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Files a record that the person is not entitled to file under § 28:9-509(a);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Fails to cause the secured party of record to file or send a termination statement as required by § 28:9-513(a) or (c);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Fails to comply with § 28:9-616(b)(1) and whose failure is part of a pattern, or consistent with a practice, of noncompliance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Fails to comply with § 28:9-616(b)(2).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A debtor or consumer obligor may recover damages under subsection (b) and, in addition, $500 in each case from a person that, without reasonable cause, fails to comply with a request under § 28:9-210. A recipient of a request under § 28:9-210 which never claimed an interest in the collateral or obligations that are the subject of a request under that section has a reasonable excuse for failure to comply with the request within the meaning of this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If a secured party fails to comply with a request regarding a list of collateral or a statement of account under § 28:9-210, the secured party may claim a security interest only as shown in the statement included in the request as against a person that is reasonably misled by the failure.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 26, 2000, D.C. Law 13-201, § 101, 47 DCR 7576.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:9-602 and § 28:9-628.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-201</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-201, see notes following § 28:9-101.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
