<level type="section">
  <num>34-2401.17</num>
  <heading>Delivery of water--Arlington County, Virginia.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 43-1540</formerly-cited-as>
  <text>The Secretary of the Army is hereby authorized, in his discretion and subject to the approval of the Chief of Engineers, upon the request of the board of supervisors of Arlington County, Virginia, to permit the delivery of water from the federal water supply pumping station at the Dalecarlia Reservoir to the Arlington County sanitary district, created by an act of the General Assembly of the State of Virginia, of March 15, 1922, and to connect the force main of said pumping station with the water main in Arlington County at the southerly end of the Chain Bridge; provided, that all expenses of installing said connection and its appurtenances and any subsequent changes therein shall be borne by said Arlington County, which shall pay such charges for the use of such water as may be determined from time to time in advance by the Secretary of the Army, the payments to be made at such time and under such regulations as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe, all payments for the use of water to be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as other water rents collected in the District of Columbia are deposited; and provided further, that the Secretary of the Army may revoke at any time any permit for the use of said water that may have been granted.</text>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 14, 1926, 44 Stat. 251, ch. 140, ยง 1.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 43-1540.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., ยง 43-1531.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Restriction on use of funds: Section 136 of Pub. L. 102-382, 106 Stat. 1435, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1993, provided that none of the funds made available in this Act may be used by the District of Columbia to impose, implement, collect, administer, transfer, or enforce a payment in lieu of taxes on the Water and Sewer Utility Administration that would increase payments required of suburban jurisdictions in Maryland or Virginia under the Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 1985.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
