<level type="section">
  <num>28:8-501</num>
  <heading>Securities account; acquisition of security entitlement from securities intermediary.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this article, the term "securities account" means an account to which a financial asset is or may be credited in accordance with an agreement under which the person maintaining the account undertakes to treat the person for whom the account is maintained as entitled to exercise the rights that comprise the financial asset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, a person acquires a security entitlement if a securities intermediary:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Indicates by book entry that a financial asset has been credited to the person's securities account;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Receives a financial asset from the person or acquires a financial asset for the person and, in either case, accepts it for credit to the person's securities account; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Becomes obligated under other law, regulation, or rule to credit a financial asset to the person's securities account.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a condition of subsection (b) of this section has been met, a person has a security entitlement even though the securities intermediary does not itself hold the financial asset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a securities intermediary holds a financial asset for another person, and the financial asset is registered in the name of, payable to the order of, or specially indorsed to the other person, and has not been indorsed to the securities intermediary or in blank, the other person is treated as holding the financial asset directly rather than as having a security entitlement with respect to the financial asset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Issuance of a security is not establishment of a security entitlement.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-240, § 2, 44 DCR 1087.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 28:8-102, § 28:8-104, § 28:8-502, and § 28:9-102.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 28:8-501.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-240</heading>
      <text>Law 11-240, the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Revision Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-576, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-500 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-240 became effective on April 9, 1997.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
