<level type="section">
  <num>7-2034</num>
  <heading>License required.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-3624</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, no person shall, either directly or indirectly, operate a child development facility in the District without first having obtained a license to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license to operate a child development facility shall establish to the satisfaction of the Mayor, that the facility meets all requirements set forth in this subchapter and rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Submit an application to the Mayor on a form required and provided by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submit supporting documentation required by the Mayor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pay the applicable fee established by the Mayor, except that no license fee shall be required of any child development facility operated by the District government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The license shall be valid for a period of time to be determined by the Mayor and only for the premises and persons named as applicants in the application. Any change in ownership of a licensee owned by a person or in the legal or beneficial ownership of a percentage of stock established by rule of a corporate licensee shall require relicensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may authorize the issuance of provisional and restricted licenses under specific circumstances and criteria to be established by rule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-215, § 5, 46 DCR 274.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-3624.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
        <text>See notes to § 7-2031.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary addition of subchapter, see notes to § 7-2031.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-215, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 7-2031.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
