<level type="section">
  <num>42-2623</num>
  <heading>Eligibility.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be eligible for the Home Purchase Assistance Step Up Program if the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is a District of Columbia resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is the head of the household and will occupy the property to be purchased with assistance from the program as his or her primary residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has a satisfactory credit rating as shall be defined by rules deemed necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Has adequate income to qualify for a mortgage from a private lender;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Has sold or otherwise disposed of all interests in any other real property before the closing of any loan under this subchapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Has insufficient assets to pay the down payment or reasonable closing costs, or both, without assistance from this program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Would have liquid assets not exceeding the limit established by the Mayor by rulemaking, after purchasing property under this subchapter or through this program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Meets qualifying income levels as provided by regulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Property shall be eligible for the Home Purchase Assistance Step Up Program if the property:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is an existing single family residence in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Meets the requirements of the Construction Codes promulgated pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1980, effective February 2, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-216; 12 DCMR) and the Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, effective August 11, 1955 (C.O. 55-1503; 14 DCMR Chapters 1-14); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has a purchase price that neither exceeds the maximum price requirement established by rulemaking nor the appraised value of the property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-266, ยง 4, 46 DCR 948.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 45-2213.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-266</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-266, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 42-2621.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
