<level type="section">
  <num>2-1505</num>
  <heading>Duties of Director.</heading>
  <text>The Director of the Office shall:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Systematically review and evaluate the full array of programs operated by the District of Columbia impacting on children and youth, as specified in § 2-1504(a);</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Plan and develop demonstration youth programs for transfer to other operating agencies upon their validation after no more than 3 years of operation;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Present the interest of children and youth before other administrative and regulatory agencies and legislative bodies of the District of Columbia government;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Assist, advise, and cooperate with local, federal, and private agencies to promote the interest of children and youth in the District of Columbia;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Develop criteria for the validation of programs for children and youth which shall be widely disseminated and utilized in the review and evaluation of programs;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Issue an annual report on the current status of programs for children and youth on a citywide basis, both governmental and private; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Perform such other functions and duties consistent with the purpose of this subchapter which may be deemed necessary and appropriate to promote the welfare of children and youth.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 29, 1977, D.C. Law 1-93, § 6, 23 DCR 9532b.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2605.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 6-2005.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-93</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-93, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1501.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
