<level type="section">
  <num>28:2-316.01</num>
  <heading>Limitation of exclusion or modification of warranties consumers.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 28:2-316.1</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The provisions of section 28:2-316 do not apply to the sale of consumer goods, as defined by section 28:9-109, services, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any oral or written language used by a seller of consumer goods and services, which attempts to exclude or modify any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or to exclude or modify the consumer's remedies for breach of those warranties, is unenforceable. However, such merchant may recover from the manufacturer any damages resulting from breach of the implied warranty of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsection (2) do not apply to particular defects and limitations of consumer goods and services noted conspicuously in writing at the time of sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Any oral or written language used by a manufacturer of consumer goods, which attempts to limit or modify a consumer's remedies for breach of the manufacturer's express warranties is unenforceable, unless the manufacturer provided reasonable and expeditious means of performing the warranty obligations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 16, 1982, D.C. Law 4-85, § 42, 29 DCR 309.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 28:2-316.1.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-85, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 28:2-107.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Miscellaneous Notes</heading>
        <text>Section 39(c) of D.C. Law 15-354 provides that the section designation of § 28-2-316.1 of the District of Columbia Official Code is redesignated as § 28-316.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
