<level type="section">
  <num>2-1593</num>
  <heading>Purpose.</heading>
  <text>The purpose of the Commission is to promote a vision of the District of Columbia as a stable, safe, and healthy environment for children, youth, and their families by reducing juvenile and family violence and promoting social and emotional skills among children, youth, and their families through the oversight of a comprehensive, community-based integrated service delivery system aligned with the statewide strategic education and youth development plan, described in § 38-191, that includes:</text>
  <level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Comprehensive, multi-disciplinary assessments of children by school-based clinicians;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Authority over a management information system that enables the inter-agency exchange of information and protects families' privacy rights;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Facilitation of resource sharing and inter-agency collaboration on multi-disciplinary projects;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Development and implementation of proven, evidence-based preventive and interventive programs for children and families by educational, law enforcement, mental health, and social services agencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Development of integrated service plans for individual children and families that promote the delivery of services that are comprehensive, implemented without interruption, and free from duplication or redundancy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Independent evaluation of the effectiveness of the programs developed pursuant to, or in accordance with, this subchapter, including:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Their impact on academic performance, levels of violence by and against children, truancy, and delinquency;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The cost effectiveness of the programs, taking into account such factors as reductions, or potential reductions, in out-of-home placements and law enforcement expenditures; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The extent to which the Commission has developed the capacity to sustain the programs and activities.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 503, 54 DCR 4102; Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4061(b), 57 DCR 181.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-111 rewrote the lead-in language, which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"The purpose of the Commission is to address the needs of at-risk children by reducing juvenile and family violence and promoting social and emotional skills among children and youth through the oversight of a comprehensive integrated service delivery system that includes:"</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4061(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009, 56 DCR 8234).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4061(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010, 57 DCR 345).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 17-9, see notes following § 2-1591.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-111, see notes following § 2-218.50.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
