<level type="section">
  <num>7-751.06</num>
  <heading>Selection criteria.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Applicants shall be competitively reviewed and selected for participation in the Program based upon the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Professional qualifications and relevant experience, including board eligibility or certification in his or her specialty, professional achievements, and other indicators of competency received from supervisors, department chairs, and program directors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A demonstrated commitment to serve in a HPSA or MUA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Preferential consideration will be given to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Residents of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Graduates of accredited District of Columbia health professions schools or program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Residents of a HPSA or MUA within the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Applicants that are immediately eligible and available for service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Applicants that commit to longer periods of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Applicants whose service obligation site is also a qualified Medical Homes DC provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Applicants who are fluent in Spanish, Chinese, Vietnamese, Korean, or Amharic; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Applicants who have experience at a community-based primary care facility or attended a community-based health profession educational institution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For applicants practicing at a service obligation site at the time of application to the Program, preferential consideration shall be given to those individuals who have less than 3 years of employment at the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-71, ยง 7, 53 DCR 61; Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, ยง 5033(c), 55 DCR 7598.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 17-219, in subsec. (b), deleted "and" from the end of par. (5), substituted a semicolon for a period at the end of par. (6), and added pars. (7) and (8).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-71, see notes following ยง 7-751.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 17-219, see notes following ยง 7-651.17.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
