<level type="section">
  <num>7-751.11</num>
  <heading>Tax implications.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of the District of Columbia Office of Tax and Revenue, all loan repayment awards shall not be considered income and are therefore not taxable.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-71, ยง 12, 53 DCR 61; Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, ยง 532(a), 58 DCR 1008.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 18-370 repealed subsec. (a), which had read as follows: "(a) For purposes of the United Stated Internal Revenue Service, all loan repayment awards are considered income and are therefore taxable. It is the responsibility of each participant to report loan repayment awards received through the Program on all relevant tax and financial documents."</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see ยง 532(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011, 58 DCR 662).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 16-71</heading>
      <text>For Law 16-71, see notes following ยง 7-751.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-370</heading>
      <text>Law 18-370, the "Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-1100, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 7, 2010, and December 21, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 27, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 18-721 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-370 became effective on April 8, 2011.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 531 of D.C. Law 18-370 provided that subtitle D of title V of the act may be cited as "Health Professional Recruitment Program Amendment Act of 2010".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
