<level type="section">
  <num>2-1403.03</num>
  <heading>Establishment of procedure for complaints filed against District government.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 1-2543</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish rules of procedure for the investigation, conciliation, and hearing of administrative complaints filed against District government agencies, officials and employees alleging violations of this chapter. The final administrative determination in such matters shall be made by the Mayor or his designee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person claiming to be aggrieved by an unlawful discriminatory practice on the part of District government agencies, officials, or employees may elect to file an administrative complaint under the rules of procedure established by the Mayor under this section or a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction under § 2-1403.16.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, title III, § 303, 24 DCR 6038; Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-189, § 2(h), 49 DCR 6523; Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 28, 51 DCR 881.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 1-2543.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-2283.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-189, designated the section as subsec. (a); added subsec. (b); and rewrote the newly designated subsec. (a) which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Mayor shall establish rules of procedure for the investigation, conciliation, and hearing of complaints filed against District government agencies, officials and employees alleging violations of this chapter. The final determination in such matters shall be made by the Mayor or his designee."</text>
        <text>D.C. Law 15-105 validated a previously made technical correction.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-38, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-1401.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 14-189, see notes following § 2-1401.02.</text>
        <text>For Law 15-105, see notes following § 2-602.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
