<level type="section">
  <num>2-707</num>
  <heading>Authorized uses of official mail by elected officials.</heading>
  <text>The provisions of § 2-706 do not prohibit an elected official or his or her staff from mailing, as official mail, any of the following:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The whole or part of any record, speech, debate, or report of the Council or any committee thereof;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The tabulation of an official's vote or explanation thereof;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Matter which expresses condolences to a person who has suffered a loss or congratulations to a person who has achieved some personal or public distinction; provided, that mass mailings of a congratulatory nature which are substantially the same except for individualized addresses are not authorized;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Information concerning the official's schedule of meeting constituents;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Information concerning the meeting schedule and agenda for committees and subcommittees upon which the official serves;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Information concerning financial disclosure information, whether or not required by law;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Matter which consists of federal, state, or local laws, regulations or publications paid for by public funds;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Questionnaires which relate to matters respecting public policy or administration; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Matter which contains pictures of the member or biographical or autobiographical data whenever such matter is mailed in response to a specific request therefor.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 7, 1977, D.C. Law 1-118, § 8, 23 DCR 8746.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 2-704 and § 2-706.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 1-1707.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 1-1707.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 1-118</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 1-118, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 2-701.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
