<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.10</num>
  <heading>Vacancy on board.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, the articles of incorporation, or the bylaws, if a vacancy occurs on the board of directors, including a vacancy resulting from an increase in the number of directors, the vacancy may be filled by a majority of the directors remaining in office even if they constitute less than a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, a vacancy in the position of a director who is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Elected by a voting group of members, by a chapter or other organizational unit of members, or by a region or other geographic grouping of members, shall be filled during the first 3 months after the vacancy occurs only by that voting group or chapter, unit, region, or grouping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Appointed by persons other than the members, may be filled only by those persons; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Designated in the articles of incorporation or bylaws shall not be filled by action of the board of directors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A vacancy that will occur at a specific later time, by reason of a resignation effective at a later time under ยง 29-406.07(b) or otherwise, may be filled before the vacancy occurs but the new director shall not take office until the vacancy occurs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
