<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.12</num>
  <heading>Designated body.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Some, but less than all, of the powers, authority, or functions of the board of directors of a nonprofit corporation under this chapter may be vested by the articles of incorporation in a designated body. If a designated body is created:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This subchapter and other provisions of law on:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The rights, duties, and liabilities of the board of directors or directors individually shall also apply to the designated body and to the members of the designated body individually; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Meetings, notice, and the manner of acting of the board of directors shall also apply to the designated body in the absence of an applicable rule in the articles of incorporation, bylaws, or internal operating rules of the designated body;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To the extent the powers, authority, or functions of the board of directors have been vested in the designated body, the directors shall be relieved from their duties and liabilities with respect to those powers, authority, and functions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A provision of the articles of incorporation regarding indemnification of directors or limiting the liability of directors adopted pursuant to ยง 29- 402.02(b)(8) or (c) applies to members of the designated body, except as otherwise provided in the articles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Some, but less than all, of the rights or obligations of the members of a nonprofit corporation under this chapter may be vested by the articles of incorporation or bylaws in a designated body. If such a designated body is created:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This subchapter and other provisions of law on:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The rights and obligations of members shall also apply to the designated body and to the members of the designated body individually; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Meetings, notice, and the manner of acting of members shall also apply to the designated body in the absence of an applicable provision in the articles of incorporation, bylaws, or internal operating rules of the designated body;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To the extent the rights or obligations of the members have been vested in the designated body, the members shall be relieved from responsibility with respect to those rights and obligations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The articles of incorporation or bylaws may prescribe qualifications for members of a designated body. Except as otherwise provided in the articles or bylaws, a member of a designated body does not need to be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A director, officer, or member of the nonprofit corporation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A resident of the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
