<level type="section">
  <num>29-406.09</num>
  <heading>Removal of directors by judicial proceeding.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may remove a director from office in a proceeding commenced by or in the right of the corporation if the court finds that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The director engaged in fraudulent conduct with respect to the corporation or its members, grossly abused the position of director, or intentionally inflicted harm on the corporation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Considering the director's course of conduct and the inadequacy of other available remedies, removal would be in the best interests of the corporation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A member, individual director, or member of a designated body proceeding on behalf of the nonprofit corporation under subsection (a) of this section shall comply with all of the requirements of subchapter XI of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court, in addition to removing the director, may bar the director from being reelected, redesignated, or reappointed for a period prescribed by the court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section limits the equitable powers of the court to order other relief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a proceeding is commenced under this section to remove a director of a charitable corporation, the plaintiff shall give the Attorney General for the District of Columbia notice in record form of the commencement of the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
