<level type="section">
  <num>29-102.08</num>
  <heading>Certificate of good standing or registration.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On request of any person, the Mayor shall issue a certificate of good standing for a domestic filing entity or a certificate of registration for a qualified foreign entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A certificate under subsection (a) of this section shall state:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The domestic filing entity's name or the qualified foreign entity's name used in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the domestic filing entity is formed under the law of the District, the date of its formation, and the period of its duration if less than perpetual, or that the qualified foreign entity is registered to do business in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That all fees, taxes, and penalties owed to the District for entity filings collected through the Mayor have been paid if:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Payment is reflected in the records of the Mayor; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Nonpayment affects the good standing or registration of the domestic or foreign entity;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>That the entity's most recent biennial report required by ยง 29-102.11 has been delivered for filing to the Mayor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>That the entity has not been dissolved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to any qualification stated in the certificate, a certificate issued by the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section may be relied upon as conclusive evidence that the domestic filing entity is in existence or the qualified foreign entity is registered to do business in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, ยง 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under ยง 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
