<level type="section">
  <num>47-2853.21</num>
  <heading>Voluntary limitation or surrender; confidentiality.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 47-2853.21</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any registration, license, or certificate issued under this subchapter may be voluntarily limited by the licensee or certificate holder either:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Permanently;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For an indefinite period of time to be restored at the discretion of the board regulating the occupation or profession; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a definite period of time under an agreement between the licensee or certificate holder and the board.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>During the period of time that the license or certificate has been limited, the licensee or certificate holder shall not engage in the practices or activities to which the voluntary limitation of practice relates.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As a condition for accepting the voluntary limitation of practice, the board may require the licensee or certificate holder to do one or more of the following:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Accept care, counseling, or treatment by a health professional acceptable to the board;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Participate in a program of education prescribed by the board; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Practice under the direction of a licensed or certified person in the same or a similar occupation or profession acceptable to the board for a specified period of time.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any license or certificate issued under this subchapter may be voluntarily surrendered to the board by the licensee or certificate holder either:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Permanently;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For an indefinite period of time to be restored at the discretion of the board regulating the occupation or profession; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a definite period of time under an agreement between the licensee or certificate holder and the board.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>During the period of time that the license or certificate has been surrendered, the person surrendering the license or certificate shall not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice the occupation or profession for which the license or certificate is required, shall be considered as not licensed or certified, and shall not be required to pay the fees for licensing or certification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All records, communications, and proceedings of the board related to the voluntary limitation or surrender of a license under this section shall be confidential.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, ยง 1002, 46 DCR 3142.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 47-2853.21.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 47-2801.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
