<level type="section">
  <num>47-2853.11</num>
  <heading>Occupations and Professions Licensure Special Account.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 47-2853.11</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 47-131(c)(4), there is hereby established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a special account, called the Occupations and Professions Licensing Special Account to which shall be credited, without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress, the fees that are identified in this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No revenues deposited into the continuing, nonlapsing special account may be obligated or spent in any year without a Congressional appropriation. Revenues in this continuing, nonlapsing special account that are carried over into a succeeding fiscal year may not be obligated or spent in the succeeding year without a new Congressional appropriation that permits such obligation or expenditure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to the applicable laws relating to the appropriation of District funds, monies received and deposited in the Occupation and Professions Licensure Special Account shall be used to defray the expenses to discharge the administrative and regulatory duties as prescribed by this subchapter. The special account shall not be used by any other District government agency and shall be used solely to carry out the functions of this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The special account shall be continuing. Revenues deposited into the special account shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this subchapter, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2853.11.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2801.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
