<level type="section">
  <num>47-2853.11</num>
  <heading>Occupations and Professions Licensure Special Account.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 47-131(c)(4), there is hereby established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a special account, called the Occupations and Professions Licensing Special Account to which shall be credited, without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress, the fees that are identified in §§ 47-2839 and 47-2839.01, and this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No revenues deposited into the continuing, nonlapsing special account may be obligated or spent in any year without a Congressional appropriation. Revenues in this continuing, nonlapsing special account that are carried over into a succeeding fiscal year may not be obligated or spent in the succeeding year without a new Congressional appropriation that permits such obligation or expenditure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to the applicable laws relating to the appropriation of District funds, monies received and deposited in the Occupation and Professions Licensure Special Account shall be used to defray the expenses to discharge the administrative and regulatory duties as prescribed by §§ 47-2839 and 47-2839.01, and this subchapter. The special account shall not be used by any other District government agency and shall be used solely to carry out the functions of §§ 47-2839 and 47-2839.01, and this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The special account shall be continuing. Revenues deposited into the special account shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in §§ 47-2839 and 47-2839.01, and this subchapter subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 3012(c), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 47-2839, § 47-2839.01, and § 47-2853.99.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 47-2853.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 substituted "§§ 47-2839 and 47-2839.01, and this subchapter" for "this subchapter" in (a), twice in (c), and in (d).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3012(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3012(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 12-261</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-261, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 47-2801.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 3011 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle B of Title III of the act may be cited the "Security Licensing Streamlining Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
