<level type="section">
  <num>5-1031</num>
  <heading>Commencement of corrective or adverse action.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, no corrective or adverse action against any sworn member or civilian employee of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department or the Metropolitan Police Department shall be commenced more than 90 days, not including Saturdays, Sundays, or legal holidays, after the date that the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department or the Metropolitan Police Department knew or should have known of the act or occurrence allegedly constituting cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the act or occurrence allegedly constituting cause is the subject of a criminal investigation by the Metropolitan Police Department, the Office of the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, or the Office of Corporation Counsel, or an investigation by the Office of Police Complaints, the 90-day period for commencing a corrective or adverse action under subsection (a) of this section shall be tolled until the conclusion of the investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-194, ยง 502, 51 DCR 9406.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>Law 15-194, the "Omnibus Public Safety Agency Reform Amendment Act of 2004", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-32, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 6, 2004, and June 1, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 24, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-463 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-194 became effective on September 30, 2004.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
