<level type="section">
  <num>8-1706</num>
  <heading>Citizen Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <text>There is established a Citizen Advisory Committee to the Soil and Water Conservation District. The Mayor shall select, for a term of 2 years, 1 resident from each of the 8 wards of the District of Columbia, to serve on the Citizen Advisory Committee. The function of the Citizen Advisory Committee shall be to ensure communication between the Soil and Water Conservation District and the residents of the District of Columbia affected by the operation of the Soil and Water Conservation District. The members shall keep the Citizen Advisory Committee informed of its work. The Citizen Advisory Committee shall submit recommendations to the members and shall meet with the members at least semiannually.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-143, ยง 7, 29 DCR 3118; Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-235, ยง 2, 48 DCR 593.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., ยง 1-2806.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-235 substituted "resident" for "Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 4-143</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 4-143, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 8-1701.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-235</heading>
      <text>Law 13-235, the "Soil and Water Conservation Amendment Act of 2000", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 13-609, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 2000, and December 5, 2000, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 2000, it was assigned Act No. 13-512 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 13-235 became effective on April 3, 2001.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
