<level type="section">
  <num>7-1671.04</num>
  <heading>Recommending physician; protections.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A physician may recommend the use of medical marijuana to a qualifying patient if the physician:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is in a bona fide physician-patient relationship with the qualifying patient; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Makes the recommendation based upon the physician's assessment of the qualifying patient's medical history, current medical condition, and a review of other approved medications and treatments that might provide the qualifying patient with relief from a qualifying medical condition or the side effects of a qualifying medical treatment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A physician's recommendation that a qualifying patient may use medical marijuana shall be signed by the physician and include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The physician's medical license number; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A statement that the use of medical marijuana is necessary for the treatment of a qualifying medical condition or the side effects of a qualifying medical treatment.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A physician's recommendation shall be valid only if it is written on a form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 7-1671.07, a physician shall not be subject to any penalty, including arrest, prosecution, or disciplinary proceeding, or denial of any right or privilege, for advising a qualifying patient about the use of medical marijuana or recommending the use of medical marijuana to a qualifying patient pursuant to this chapter and the rules issued pursuant to § 7-1671.13.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A physician recommending the use of medical marijuana by a qualifying patient shall not have a professional office located at a dispensary or cultivation center or receive financial compensation from a dispensary or cultivation center, or a director, officer, member, incorporator, agent, or employee of a dispensary or cultivation center.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 5, as added July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-210, § 2, 57 DCR 4798.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 3-1202.03 and § 7-1671.02.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-210</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-210, see notes following § 7-1671.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
