<level type="section">
  <num>38-2907.01</num>
  <heading>DCPS budget.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The annual operating budget for DCPS shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Allocate no more than 5% of its gross budget to central administration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide each school with not less than 95% of its prior year allocation of Formula funds, excluding those Formula funds directed to a school pursuant to paragraph (3) of this section; provided, that a school may receive less than 95% of such funds if that school is eliminating one or more grade levels offered at the school, faces a budgetary reduction due to the closing or consolidation of one school into another, or is undergoing a substantial instructional or programmatic change and the Chancellor includes in the budget submission to the Council a written justification for the greater than 5% reduction; provided further, that this paragraph shall not apply if the total Formula allocation to DCPS, excluding those Formula funds generated pursuant to § 38-2905.01, is reduced by more than 5% from its prior year allocation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Direct no less than 90% of the funds allocated to DCPS pursuant to § 38-2905.01 to school-level budgets and distribute such funds to schools proportionally based upon the number of at-risk students within each school's projected student count.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds provided to schools pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section shall be available to the principal to use at the principal's discretion, in consultation with the school's local school advisory team, for the purpose of improving student achievement among at-risk students; provided, that the principal submits to the Chancellor and makes publicly available a written plan explaining with particularity how the use of the funds will improve student achievement among at-risk students before the use of any such funds. The Chancellor may review and amend the plan as submitted by a principal. If the Chancellor amends a plan as submitted by a principal, the Chancellor shall provide the principal with a written justification for the amendment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chancellor shall review the performance of each DCPS principal based upon the principal's utilization of the funds made available to the principal pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section, including a review of whether use of the funds has improved student achievement among at-risk students.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Funds allocated pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section shall be supplemental to the school's gross budget and shall not supplant any Formula, federal, or other funds to which the school is entitled.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-207, § 108a, as added Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-87, § 4(c), 61 DCR 309.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 38-2831.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2014 amendment by D.C. Law 20-87 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-87</heading>
      <text>Law 20-87, the "Fair Student Funding and School-Based Budgeting Amendment Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-309. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2013, and December 17, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 2, 2014, it was assigned Act No. 20-257 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-87 became effective on February 22, 2014.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
