<level type="section">
  <num>16-2392</num>
  <heading>Guardianship order; finality; appeals; transcripts.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Every guardianship order shall be in writing and shall recite the findings upon which such order is based, including findings pertaining to the court's jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, in all hearings and cases tried before the court pursuant to this subchapter, the judgment of the court shall be final.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In all appeals from decisions of the court with respect to an order under this subchapter, the child shall be identified only by initials in all transcripts, briefs, and other papers filed, and all necessary steps, as prescribed by rule of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, shall be taken to protect the identity of the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of a motion and supporting affidavit stating that he or she is financially unable to purchase a transcript, a party who has filed notice of appeal or of interlocutory appeal of an order under this subchapter shall be furnished, at no cost or at such part of cost as he or she is able to pay, so much of the transcript as is necessary to prepare adequately and support the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An appeal does not operate to stay the order, judgment, or decree appealed from, but whenever the case is properly before the appellate court, that court, on application and hearing, may order otherwise if suitable provision is made in the order for the care and custody of the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Apr. 4, 2001, D.C. Law 13-273, § 3(b), 48 DCR 1637.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Addition of Sections</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) addition of subchapter V, "Permanent Guardianship", consisting of §§ 16-2381 to 16-2399, see § 3(b) of the Adoption and Guardianship Subsidy Temporary Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Law 18-208, July 27, 2010, law notification 57 DCR 7547).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(b) of the Foster Children's Guardianship Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-490, December 18, 2000, 48 DCR 63).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 3(c) of Foster Children's Guardianship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14- 4, February 13, 2001, 48 DCR 2254).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For D.C. Law 13-273, see notes following § 16-2381.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
