<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.163</num>
  <heading>Eligibility for grants.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant is eligible for a grant if the applicant is a qualified senior citizen; provided, that the Director shall give priority consideration to lower-income applicants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To determine the eligibility of an applicant, the Director shall develop an application form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To apply for a grant under this part, an applicant shall complete the application form and return it to the Director at the time and in the manner in which the Director shall prescribe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director shall verify the contents of the application form to determine if the applicant is eligible for a grant and to determine if the applicant shall receive funding, or be given priority consideration pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish rules for payment to qualified home improvement contractors, which may include establishing a list of program-eligible contractors.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 12, 2010, D.C. Law 18-218, § 4, 57 DCR 5396; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2082(c), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 substituted "Director" for "Deputy Mayor" throughout the section; and rewrote (a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(c) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(c) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-218</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-218, see notes following § 1-325.161.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-325.161.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 2081 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle I of Title II of the act may be cited as the "Senior Housing Modernization Grant Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
