<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.161</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Fund" means the Senior Citizens Housing Modernization Grant Fund established by § 1-325.162.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Planned unit development" or "PUD" means a plan for the development of residential, institutional, and commercial developments, industrial parks, urban renewal projects, or a combination of these as defined in section 199 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (11 DCMR § 199).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Principal place of residence" means a single-family dwelling in which a person lives in a particular locality with the intent to make it a fixed and permanent home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Qualified senior citizen" means the owner of a single-family dwelling located in the District that is his or her principal place of residence who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is 65 years of age or older;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is a resident of the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Has resided in his or her principal place of residence for at least 3 years preceding the date of the application for assistance under this part; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Whose income does not exceed that for a household within the Section 8 low-income guidelines established by the Secretary of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development pursuant to section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved August 22, 1974 (88 Stat. 662; 42 U.S.C. § 1437f).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 12, 2010, D.C. Law 18-218, § 2, 57 DCR 5396; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2082(a), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 rewrote (1).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(a) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(a) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-218</heading>
      <text>Law 18-218, the "Senior Housing Modernization Grant Fund Act of 2010", was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-250, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 18, 2010, and June 1, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 17, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-440 and transmitted to Both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-218 became effective on August 12, 2010.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>Law 20-61, the "Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Act of 2013," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 20-199. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 22, 2013, and June 26, 2013, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Aug. 28, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 20-157 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 20-61 became effective on Dec. 24, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 2081 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle I of Title II of the act may be cited as the "Senior Housing Modernization Grant Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
