<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.162</num>
  <heading>Senior Citizens Housing Modernization Grant Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Senior Citizens Housing Modernization Grant Fund ("Fund"). All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be continually available to the Director for the purpose of providing one-time grants of up to $20,000 to qualified senior citizens to enable them to make repairs and improvements to their single-family dwellings to ensure their health and safety in their principal places of residence. Administration of grants from the Fund shall be exempt from the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of this chapter [§ 1-328.11 et seq.].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Deposits into the Fund shall consist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Payments by developers seeking relief from zoning laws by way of the PUD process, which may be considered part of the required community benefits package of the proposed PUD;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Appropriated funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other District funds; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Private gifts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 12, 2010, D.C. Law 18-218, § 3, 57 DCR 5396; Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 2082(b), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 1-325.161.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61, in (b), substituted "Director" for "Deputy Mayor," substituted "$20,000" for "$5,000," and added the last sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(b) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2082(b) and 2083 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 18-218</heading>
      <text>For Law 18-218, see notes following § 1-325.161.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 1-325.161.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 2081 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle I of Title II of the act may be cited as the "Senior Housing Modernization Grant Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
