<level type="section">
  <num>1-325.163</num>
  <heading>Eligibility for grants.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An applicant shall receive a grant if he or she is a qualified senior citizen residing within the boundaries of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which a developer, seeking relief from zoning laws by way of the PUD process, has made a payment to the Senior Citizens Housing Modernization and Grant Fund.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An applicant is eligible for a grant if he or she is a qualified senior citizen, provided, that the Deputy Mayor gives priority consideration to lower-income applicants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To determine the eligibility of an applicant, the Deputy Mayor shall develop an application form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To apply for a grant under this part, an applicant shall complete the application form and return it to the Deputy Mayor at the time and in the manner in which the Deputy Mayor shall prescribe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor shall verify the contents of the application form to determine if the applicant is eligible for a grant and to determine if the applicant shall receive funding, or be given priority consideration pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor shall establish rules for payment to qualified home improvement contractors, which may include establishing a list of program-eligible contractors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 12, 2010, D.C. Law 18-218, ยง 4, 57 DCR 5396.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-218, see notes following ยง 1-325.161.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
