<level type="section">
  <num>7-2507.06a</num>
  <heading>Seizure and forfeiture of conveyances.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "owner" means a person with an ownership interest in the specific conveyance sought to be forfeited. The term "owner" does not include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person with only a general unsecured interest in, or claim against, the conveyance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A bailee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A nominee who exercises no dominion or control over the conveyance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any conveyance, including vehicles and vessels in which any person or persons transport, possess, or conceal any firearm, as that term is defined in § 7-2501.01, or in any manner use to facilitate a violation of § 7-2502.02 or § 22-4503 or § 22-4504, shall be seized and forfeited to the District of Columbia, provided that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No conveyance used by any person as a duly licensed common carrier in the course of transacting business as a licensed common carrier is subject to forfeiture under this section unless it appears that the owner or other person in charge of the conveyance is a consenting party or has knowledge of a violation of this section; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The forfeiture of a conveyance encumbered by a bona fide security interest is subject to the interest of the secured party if the secured party neither had knowledge of, nor consented to, the illegal act giving rise to forfeiture.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An innocent owner's interest in a conveyance which has been seized shall not be forfeited under this section.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person is an innocent owner if he or she establishes, by a preponderance of the evidence:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>That he or she did not know that a person or persons in the conveyance was transporting, possessing, or concealing any firearm or that the conveyance was involved in or was being used in the commission of any illegal act involving any firearm; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>That, upon receiving knowledge of the presence of any illegal firearm in or on the conveyance or that the conveyance was being used in the commission of an illegal act involving a forfeiture, he or she took action to terminate the presence in or on the conveyance of the person, persons, or firearms.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A claimant who establishes a lack of knowledge under subsection (c)(1)(A) of this section shall be considered an innocent owner unless the government, in rebuttal, establishes the existence of facts and circumstances that should have created a suspicion that the conveyance was being or would be used for an illegal purpose. In that case, the claimant must establish that, in light of such facts and circumstances, he or she did all that reasonably could be expected to prevent the use of the conveyance in the commission of any such illegal act.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person who willfully blinds himself or herself to a fact shall be considered to have had knowledge of that fact.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise expressly provided by this section, all seizures and forfeitures of conveyances under this section shall follow the procedures set forth in § 48-905.02.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VII, § 706a, as added June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-273, § 2, 43 DCR 6168; June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-274, § 19(b), 43 DCR 1232.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 6-2376.1.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 2 of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-390, August 26, 1996, 43 DCR 4986), § 2 of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-436, December 4, 1996, 43 DCR 6651), and § 2 of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-35, March 11, 1997, 44 DCR 1928).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-273</heading>
      <text>Law 11-273, the "Zero Tolerance for Guns Amendment Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-153, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 19, 1996, and October 1, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 18, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-431 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-273 became effective on June 3, 1997.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 11-274</heading>
      <text>Law 11-274, the "Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 11-386, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted in first and second readings on November 7, 1996, and December 3, 1996, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1996, it was assigned Act No. 11-510 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 11-274 became effective on June 3, 1997.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
