<level type="section">
  <num>26-304</num>
  <heading>Form and contents of application for license.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 ยง 26-1104</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An application for a license under this chapter shall be in writing under oath in the form prescribed by the Superintendent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The application shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is an individual, the applicant's name, business address and telephone number, and residence address and telephone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is a partnership or other non-corporate business association, the business name, business address and telephone number, and the residence address and telephone number of each:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>General partner, if the applicant is a limited partnership;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>General partner who holds the interest in the partnership or more than 10% interest if the applicant is a general partnership; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Member, if the applicant is a limited liability company or other non-corporate business association;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is a corporation:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the corporate entity; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name, business telephone number, and the residence and telephone number of the president, senior vice presidents, secretary, treasurer, each director, and each stockholder owning or controlling 10% or more of any class of stock in the corporation;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The applicant's business plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The name under which the check cashing business is to be conducted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the applicant's registered agent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The location at which the applicant proposes to conduct business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>If the applicant seeks to conduct business from a mobile unit, the District registration number or other identification of the mobile unit and the area in which the applicant proposes to operate the mobile unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>If the applicant seeks to conduct business from a limited station, the group of employees that would be served and the location at which these employees would be served; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any other information that the Superintendent requires.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(May 12, 1998, D.C. Law 12-111, ยง 5, 45 DCR 1783.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., ยง 26-1104.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 12-111, see Historical and Statutory Notes following ยง 26-301.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
