<level type="section">
  <num>34-207</num>
  <heading>"Electrical company" defined.</heading>
  <text>The term "electric company" when used in this subtitle includes every corporation, company, association, joint-stock company or association, partnership, or person and doing business in the District of Columbia, their lessees, trustees, or receivers, appointed by any court whatsoever, physically transmitting or distributing electricity in the District of Columbia to retail electric customers. The term excludes any building owner, lessee, or manager who, respectively, owns, leases, or manages, the internal distribution system serving the building and who supplies electricity and other related electricity services solely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants. The term also excludes a person or entity that does not sell or distribute electricity and that owns or operates equipment used exclusively for the charging of electric vehicles.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 976, ch. 150, § 8, par. 1; May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 201(b)(5), 47 DCR 1091; Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-252, § 101(a), 59 DCR 14932.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 8-1771.06, § 8-1773.01, § 34-1311.01, § 34-1501, and § 34-1561.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 43-215.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 43-115.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 13-107 rewrote this section which formerly provided: "The term 'electrical corporation' when used in Chapters 1-10 of this title includes every corporation, company, association, joint-stock company or association, partnership, or person doing business in the District of Columbia, their lessees, trustees, or receivers, appointed by any court whatsoever, owning, operating, controlling, or managing any electric plant, including any water plant, or water property, or water falls, or dam, or waterpower stations, except where electricity is made, generated, produced, or transmitted by a private person or private corporation on or through private property solely for its own use or the use of tenants of its building and not for sale to or for the use of others."</text>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-252 added the last sentence.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 13-107</heading>
      <text>For Law 13-107, see notes following § 34-201.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-252</heading>
      <text>Law 19-252, the "Energy Innovation and Savings Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-749. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Nov. 1, 2012 and Nov. 15, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on Dec. 7, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-562 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-252 became effective on Mar. 19, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 301 of D.C. Law 19-252 provided that the Mayor shall issue rules to implement the provisions of the act within 180 days of its effective date [Mar. 19, 2013].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
