<level type="section">
  <num>22-2725</num>
  <heading>Anti-Prostitution Vehicle Impoundment Proceeds Fund.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Anti-Prostitution Vehicle Impoundment Proceeds Fund ("Fund"), which shall be used for the purpose set forth in subsection (b) of this section. All funds collected from the assessment of civil penalties, booting, towing, impoundment, and storage fees pursuant to § 22-2723, and any and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund, and shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section with regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used solely to fund expenses directly related to the booting, towing, and impoundment of vehicles used in furtherance of prostitution-related activities, in violation of a prostitution-related offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as part of the annual budget, a requested appropriation for expenditures from the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 15, 1935, 49 Stat. 651, ch. 546, § 7, as added Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-306, § 211(c), 53 DCR 8610; Nov. 6, 2010, D.C. Law 18-259, § 4(2), 57 DCR 5591.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-259 rewrote subsec. (a), which had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) There is established a fund designated as the Anti-Prostitution Vehicle Impoundment Proceeds Fund ('Fund'), which shall be used for the purpose set forth in subsection (b) of this section. All funds collected from the assessment of civil penalties, booting, towing, impoundment, and storage fees pursuant to § 22-2723, and any and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund, and shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section, subject to authorization by Congress, except that any unused funds remaining in the Fund on September 30th of each fiscal year shall revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 211(c) of Omnibus Public Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-445, July 19, 2006, 53 DCR 6443).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 211(c) of Omnibus Public Safety Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-490, October 18, 2006, 53 DCR 8686).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 211(c) of Omnibus Public Safety Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-10, January 16, 2007, 54 DCR 1479).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 211(c) of Omnibus Public Safety Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-25, April 19, 2007, 54 DCR 4036).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 16-306, see notes following § 22-404.</text>
        <text>For history of Law 18-259, see notes under § 22-2724.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
