<level type="section">
  <num>2-1217.73b</num>
  <heading>Retail Priority Area corridor revitalization programs.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any tax increment financing that may be available, all funds allocated for Great Streets within the budgets of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development and the District Department of Transportation shall be used to support the following corridor revitalization programs in designated Retail Priority Areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Small business retention and attraction programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Neighborhood branding and marketing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Blighted and vacant property mitigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Redevelopment of private property through financial incentives, technical assistance, temporary urbanism initiatives, and property acquisition and disposition, among other mechanisms identified by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Streetscape and roadway infrastructure improvements to enhance walkability, pedestrian safety, lighting, and transportation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Beautification and greening of the public realm, including public art, landscaping, storm water retention, and litter control.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>With respect to the small business retention and attraction program referenced in subsection (a)(1) of this section, the Mayor shall publish, no later than 30 days after October 1, 2013, and no less than annually after that date, a notice of funding availability to make grants or loans in certain Retail Priority Areas selected by the Mayor. All awards issued with Great Streets funds shall be made on a competitive basis, and the Mayor shall publish online the application criteria and evaluation rubric for Great Streets grants and loans.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Eligible retailers and service providers shall include:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Retail businesses engaged in the sale of home furnishings, apparel, books, art, groceries, and general merchandise goods to specialized customers;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Businesses providing goods or services geared toward the enrichment of children, families, and adults; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Sit-down restaurants, bakeries, coffee shops, and other specialty food retailers.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for small business retention and attraction grants or loans referenced in subsection (a)(1) of this section, a project shall:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be within a designated Retail Priority Area;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Maintain site control of the property either through fee simple ownership of the site or through an executed contract or lease with the property owner;</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Execute a First Source Agreement with the Department of Employment Services; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Adhere to all design, construction, and rehabilitation requirements defined by the Mayor, or his or her designee.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-185, § 4b, as added Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 8032(c), 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 20-61 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 8032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 8032(c) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 2-1217.72.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 8031 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle D of Title VIII of the act may be cited as the "Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Area Amendment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
