<level type="section">
  <num>22-1514</num>
  <heading>Fraudulent interference or collusion in jury selection.</heading>
  <text>If any person shall fraudulently tamper with any box or wheel used or intended by the jury commission for the names of prospective jurors, or of prospective condemnation jurors or commissioners, or shall fraudulently tamper with the contents of any such box or wheel, or with any jury list, or be guilty of any fraud or collusion with respect to the drawing of jurors or condemnation jurors or commissioners, or if any jury commissioner shall put in or leave out of any such box or wheel the name of any person at the request of such person, or at the request of any other person, or if any jury commissioner shall wilfully draw from any such box or wheel a greater number of names than is required by the court, any such person or jury commissioner so offending shall for each offense be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01 or imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1223, ch. 854, § 213; Apr. 19, 1920, 41 Stat. 560, ch. 153, § 213; Mar. 27, 1968, 82 Stat. 63, Pub. L. 90-274, § 103(f); Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 105(f), 41 DCR 2608; June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 201(a), 60 DCR 2064.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <text>Proof of intent to defraud, see § 23-322.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <text>1981 Ed., § 22-1414.</text>
      <text>1973 Ed., § 22-1414.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-317 substituted "not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01" for "not more than $1,000".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 105(f) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994, 41 DCR 4286).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 10-151</heading>
      <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 10-151, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 22-1502.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-317</heading>
      <text>See note to § 22-1502.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 19-317: Section 401 of D.C. Law 19-317 provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
