<level type="section">
  <num>7-1141.07</num>
  <heading>Transfer of authority, functions, property, and personnel.</heading>
  <text>The following powers, duties, functions, and responsibilities are hereby transferred to the Department of Behavioral Health, effective October 1, 2013:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>All real and personal property, Career and Excepted Service, Management Supervisory Service, trainee positions, assets, records, obligations, unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available to the Department of Mental Health and the Department of Health Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration, or relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration set forth in § 7-1141.06;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>All of the functions assigned and authorities granted and delegated to the Director of the Department of Mental Health, and the Department of Mental Health, as set forth in Chapter 11A of this title [§ 7-1131.01 et seq.]; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>All of the functions assigned and authorities granted and delegated to the Department of Health Addiction Prevention and Recovery as set forth in section IV(A)(3) of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996, effective July 17, 1996 (D.C. Official Code, Vol. 3) [Part A of subchapter XIV of Chapter 15 of Title 1].</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5118, 60 DCR 12472.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5118 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013, 60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</text>
      <text>For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5118 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013, 60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 20-61</heading>
      <text>See note to § 7-1141.01.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Section 5111 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that Subtitle J of Title V of the act may be cited as the "Department of Behavioral Health Establishment Act of 2013".</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Editor’s Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of D.C. Law 20-61: Section 11001 of D.C. Law 20-61 provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
