<level type="section">
  <num>21-561</num>
  <heading>Mail privileges; censored mail; return to sender; visiting hours.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 21-561</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person hospitalized in a public or private hospital pursuant to this chapter, or committed under sections 21-545, 21-545.01, or 21-548, may exercise the right to communicate with others as set forth in the Mental Health Consumers' Rights Protection Act of 2001, effective December 18, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-56; D.C. Official Code § 7-1231.01 <text i="True">et seq.</text>).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section does not prohibit the administrator of a hospital from making reasonable rules regarding visitation hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 758, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1; Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 11(a)(15), 30 DCR 5778; Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-283, § 2(aa), 50 DCR 917.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 21-561.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 21-561.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-283 rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c); and repealed subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, subsecs. (a), (b), and (c) had read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) A person hospitalized in a public or private hospital pursuant to this chapter may:</text>
        <text>"(1) communicate by sealed mail or otherwise with an individual or official agency inside or outside the hospital; and</text>
        <text>"(2) receive uncensored mail from his attorney, personal physician, or personal qualified psychologist.</text>
        <text>"(b) All incoming mail or communications other than mail or communications referred to in subsection (a) of this section may be read before being delivered to the patient, if the chief of service believes the action is necessary for the medical welfare of the patient who is the intended recipient. Mail or other communication which is not delivered to the patient for whom it is intended shall be immediately returned to the sender.</text>
        <text>"(c) This section does not prohibit the administrator from making reasonable rules regarding visitation hours and the use of telephone and telegraph facilities."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>Section 2(z) of D.C. Law 14-131 repealed subsec. (b) and rewrote subsecs. (a) and (c) to read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(a) A person hospitalized in a public or private hospital pursuant to this chapter, or committed under sections 21-545, 21-545.01, or 21-548, may exercise the right to communicate with others as set forth in the Mental Health Consumers' Rights Protection Act of 2001, effective December 18, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-56; 48 DCR 7674)."</text>
        <text>"(c) This section does not prohibit the administrator of a hospital from making reasonable rules regarding visitation hours."</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(z) of Mental Health Commitment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-265, January 30, 2002, 49 DCR 1450).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(z) of Mental Health Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-350, April 24, 2002, 49 DCR 4417).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(aa) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-546, December 12, 2002, 50 DCR 199).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(aa) of Mental Health Civil Commitment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-41, March 24, 2003, 50 DCR 2784).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>References in Text</heading>
        <text>Section 21-545.01, referred to in subsec. (a), is enacted only upon enactment of certain legislation by the United States Congress.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 5-48, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 21-501.</text>
        <text>For Law 14-283, see notes following § 21-501.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
