<level type="section">
  <num>32-1331.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <level>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Construction services" includes, without limitation, all building or work on buildings, structures, and improvements of all types such as bridges, dams, plants, highways, parkways, streets, tunnels, sewers, mains, power lines, pumping stations, heaving generators, railways, airports, terminals, docks, piers, wharves, buoys, jetties, breakwaters, levees, canals, dredging, shoring, rehabilitation and reactivation of plants, scaffolding, drilling, blasting, excavating, clearing and landscaping. The term "construction services" shall also include moving construction-related materials on the job site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Employee" means every person, other than an exempt person or an independent contractor, providing construction services to another person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Employer" means any individual, partnership, firm, association, joint stock company, trust, limited liability company, corporation, the administrator or executor of the estate of a deceased individual or the receiver, trustee, or successor of any of the same, or any other legal entity permitted to do business within the District of Columbia employing a person to provide services, or any person or group of persons acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Exempt person" means an individual who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <level>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Performs services in a personal capacity and who employs no individuals other than a spouse, child, or immediate family member of the individual; or</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Performs services free from direction and control over the means and manner of providing the services, subject only to the right of the person or entity for whom services are provided to specify the desired result;</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Furnishes the tools and equipment necessary to provide the service; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Operates a business that is considered inseparable from the individual for purposes of taxes, profits, and liabilities, in which the individual exercises complete control over the management and operations of the business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Interested party" means a person with an interest in compliance with this subchapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Knowingly" means having actual knowledge of, or acting with deliberate ignorance or reckless disregard for, the prohibition involved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Mayor" mean the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his or her designated agent or agents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"Stop work order" means written notice from the Mayor to an employer to cease or hold work until the employer is given notice by the Mayor to resume work.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, ยง 201, as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, ยง 2(b), 60 DCR 2679.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 2-359.07.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-300 added this subchapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-300</heading>
      <text>Law 19-300, the "Workplace Fraud Amendment Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-169, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on Dec. 4, 2012, and Dec. 18, 2012, respectively. Returned without the Mayor's signature on Feb. 11, 2013, it was assigned Act No. 19-668 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-300 became effective on Apr. 27, 2013.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
