<level type="section">
  <num>32-1331.09</num>
  <heading>Private right of action.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person aggrieved by a violation of this subchapter, or any rule issued pursuant to this subchapter, by an employer or entity may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction within 3 years after the occurrence of the alleged violation of [this] subchapter. A person whose rights have been violated under this subchapter by an employer or entity is entitled to collect:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of any wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied or lost to the person by reason of the violation, plus an additional equal amount in liquidated damages;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Compensatory damages and an amount up to $500 for each violation of this subchapter or any rule issued pursuant to this subchapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of unlawful retaliation, all legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A court may order the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reinstatement and the payment of back wages;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fringe benefits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Seniority rights;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Treble damages for lost wages or benefits; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Any combination of the remedies set forth in paragraphs (1) through (4) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The court shall allow for reasonable attorneys fees and costs of the action to be paid by the defendant.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(Aug. 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 976, ch. 924, ยง 209, as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-300, ยง 2(b), 60 DCR 2679.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in ยง 32-1331.11.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2013 amendment by D.C. Law 19-300 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-300</heading>
      <text>See note to ยง 32-1331.01.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
