<level type="section">
  <num>29-105.10</num>
  <heading>Transfer of registration.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A foreign filing entity or foreign limited liability partnership registered to do business in the District that merges with or converts to a foreign entity required to register with the Mayor to do business in the District shall deliver to the Mayor for filing an application for transfer of registration. The application shall state the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name of the applicant entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Type of entity it was before the merger or conversion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Name of the entity into which it has merged or to which it has been converted and, if the name does not comply with § 29-103.01, an alternate name adopted pursuant to § 29-105.06(a);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Type of entity into which it has merged or to which it has been converted and the jurisdiction whose law governs its internal affairs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Following information regarding the entity into which it has merged or to which it has been converted, if different than the information for the applicant entity:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The street and mailing address of the principal office of the entity and, if the law of the entity's jurisdiction of formation requires it to maintain an office in that jurisdiction, the street and mailing address of that office; and</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name and street and mailing address of its registered agent in the District.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An application for transfer of registration shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing and takes effect at the time provided in § 29-102.03.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>When an application for transfer of registration takes effect, the registration of the applicant entity to do business in the District shall be transferred without interruption to the entity into which it has merged or to which it has been converted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For history of Law 18-378, see notes under § 29-101.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
