<level type="section">
  <num>2-218.64</num>
  <heading>Identification of certified business enterprises in bids or proposals; false statements on certification; penalties.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided by law, a contractor or business enterprise may not:</text>
      <level>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Identify a certified business enterprise in a bid or proposal unless it:</text>
        <level>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Has obtained authorization from the certified business enterprise to identify the certified business enterprise in its bid or proposal;</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Has notified the certified business enterprise before execution of the contract of its inclusion in the bid or proposal; and</text>
        </level>
        <level>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Uses the certified business enterprise in the performance of the contract; or</text>
        </level>
      </level>
      <level>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Pay the certified business enterprise solely for the use of its name in the bid or proposal.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a felony and, upon conviction, subject to a fine not to exceed $15,000, imprisonment not to exceed 5 years, or both.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person may not make false statements about whether an entity has business enterprise certification.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, subject to a fine not to exceed $5,000, imprisonment not to exceed one year, or both.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2364, as added Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(p), 57 DCR 1485; May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-159, § 2(f), 57 DCR 3006.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 18-159 rewrote subsec. (a)(1)(A)(i); and, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted "imprisonment not to exceed 5 years," for "imprisonment,". Prior to amendment, subsec. (a)(1)(A)(i) read as follows:</text>
        <text>"(i) Has requested, received, or otherwise obtained authorization from the certified business enterprise to identify the certified business enterprise in its bid or proposal;".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For Law 18-141, see notes following § 2-218.02.</text>
        <text>For Law 18-159, see notes following § 2-218.46.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
