<level type="section">
  <num>7-1202.07</num>
  <heading>Limited disclosure to 3rd-party payors.</heading>
  <formerly-cited-as>DC ST 1981 § 6-2017</formerly-cited-as>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A mental health professional or mental health facility may disclose to a 3rd-party payor mental health information necessary to determine the client's entitlement to, or the amount of, payment benefits for professional services rendered; provided, that the disclosure is pursuant to a valid authorization, or for participating providers, a joint consent, and that the information to be disclosed is limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Administrative information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Diagnostic information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The status of the client (voluntary or involuntary);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The reason for admission or continuing treatment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A prognosis limited to the estimated time during which treatment might continue.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the event the 3rd-party payor questions the client's entitlement to or the amount of payment benefits following disclosure under subsection (a) of this section, the 3rd-party payor may, pursuant to a valid authorization, or for participating providers, a joint consent, request an independent review of the client's record of mental health information by a mental health professional or professionals. Mental health information disclosed for the purpose of review shall not be disclosed to the 3rd-party payor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>CREDIT(S)</heading>
      <text>(Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-136, § 207, 25 DCR 5055; Dec. 18, 2001, D.C. Law 14-56, § 116(f)(3), 48 DCR 7674.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL AND STATUTORY NOTES</heading>
      <level>
        <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
        <text>1981 Ed., § 6-2017.</text>
        <text>1973 Ed., § 6-1621.</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
        <text>D.C. Law 14-56, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted ", or for participating providers, a joint consent," after "a valid authorization".</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Temporary Amendments of Section</heading>
        <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 16(f)(3) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Law 14-51, October 30, 2001, law notification 48 DCR 10807).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Emergency Act Amendments</heading>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(f)(3) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-55, May 2, 2001, 48 DCR 4390).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 16(f)(3) of Department of Mental Health Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-101, July 23, 2001, 48 DCR 7123).</text>
        <text>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 116(f)(3) of Mental Health Service Delivery Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-144, October 23, 2001, 48 DCR 9947).</text>
      </level>
      <level>
        <heading>Legislative History of Laws</heading>
        <text>For legislative history of D.C. Law 2-136, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § 7-1201.01.</text>
        <text>For Law 14-56, see notes following § 7-1131.01.</text>
      </level>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
