<level type="section">
  <num>39-114</num>
  <heading>Books and Other Library Materials Account.</heading>
  <level>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing account the Books and Other Library Materials Account ("Account") into which shall be deposited:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All receipts from the sale of used books and other library materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Proceeds from the sale of library-related merchandise;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Gifts, grants, and donations designated for collections; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Such amounts as may be appropriated for books and other library materials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Account shall be used solely for the purpose of procuring books and other library materials, including compact disks, electronic materials, or other records and materials, to maintain and enhance the collection of the District of Columbia Public Library.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Account, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level type="annotations">
    <level>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <text>(June 3, 1896, 29 Stat. 244, ch. 315, § 14, as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4022(b), 59 DCR 8025.)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <text>This section is referenced in § 39-107.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <text>The 2012 amendment by D.C. Law 19-168 added this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <text>Section 101(b) of D.C. Law 19-226 amended this section by striking the phrase "Books and Other Library Materials" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "Library Collections" in its place.</text>
      <text>Section 402(b) of D.C. Law 19-226 provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 4022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
      <text>For temporary addition of section, see § 4022(b) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012, 59 DCR 9290).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(b) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-482, October 12, 2012, 59 DCR 12478).</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(b) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</text>
      <text>For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(b) of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Technical Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-604, January 14, 2013, 60 DCR 1045), applicable as of January 10, 2013.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>Legislative History of Law 19-168</heading>
      <text>Law 19-168, the "Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Act of 2012," was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-743. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 15, 2012, and June 5, 2012, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 2012, it was assigned Act No. 19-385 and transmitted to Congress for its review. D.C. Law 19-168 became effective on September 20, 2012.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>
